<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05091372</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-0201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05091372</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Minimal Residual Disease Guided Maintenance Therapy With Belantamab Mafodotin and Lenalidomide After Autologous Hematopoietic Cell Transplantation in Patients With Newly Diagnosed Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Minimal Residual Disease Guided Maintenance Therapy With Belantamab Mafodotin and Lenalidomide After Autologous Hematopoietic Cell Transplantation in Patients With Newly Diagnosed Multiple Myeloma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To increase the conversion rate from MRD-positive to MRD-negative CR in patients with newly&#xD;
      diagnosed multiple myeloma (NDMM) receiving post-transplant maintenance therapy with&#xD;
      belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -To increase the conversion rate from MRD-positive to MRD-negative CR in patients with newly&#xD;
      diagnosed multiple myeloma (NDMM) receiving post-transplant maintenance therapy with&#xD;
      belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the safety and tolerability of belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide&#xD;
           maintenance therapy after auto-HCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To increase the overall MRD-negative CR rate in patients with NDMM receiving&#xD;
           post-auto-HCT maintenance therapy with belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the PFS and OS in patients who discontinue maintenance therapy after&#xD;
           achieving sustained MRD-negative CR. Sustained MRD-negative CR is defined as&#xD;
           MRD-negative status in two assessments, at least 1-year apart, without any MRD-positive&#xD;
           status in between.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the PFS with belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide maintenance therapy&#xD;
           after auto-HCT in patients with NDMM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the OS with belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide maintenance therapy&#xD;
           after auto-HCT in patients with NDMMM.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Conversion rate from MRD-positive to MRD-negative CR in patients with newly diagnosed multiple myeloma (NDMM) receiving post-transplant maintenance therapy with belantamab mafodotin plus lenalidomide.</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">94</enrollment>
  <condition>Myeloma Multiple</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Belantamab mafodotin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>belantamab mafodotin by vein over about 30 minutes on Day 1 of each cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lenalidomide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>lenalidomide by mouth every day of each cycle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Belantamab mafodotin</intervention_name>
    <description>Belantamab Mafodotin&#xD;
Belantamab mafodotin dose levels:&#xD;
Dose level -2 = 1.4 mg/kg IV every 12 weeks Dose level -1 = 1.9 mg/kg IV every 12 weeks Dose level 0 = 1.9 mg/kg IV every 8 weeks&#xD;
Cycles 1 - 6:&#xD;
All patients will start at dose level 0.&#xD;
Cycles 7 and onwards*:&#xD;
Patients previously on dose level 0 (1.9 mg/kg IV every 8 weeks) will change to dose level -1 (1.9 mg/kg IV every 12 weeks) Patients previously on dose level -1 (1.9 mg/kg IV every 12 weeks) will continue at the same dose level.&#xD;
Patients previously on dose level -2 (1.4 mg/kg IV every 12 weeks) will continue at the same dose level.&#xD;
*Reduction to a lower dose level is allowed in case of development of adverse effects or poor tolerance as determined by the treating physician.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Belantamab mafodotin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Lenalidomide dose levels:&#xD;
Dose level 0 (starting dose): Lenalidomide 10 mg/day PO continuously. Dose level -1: Lenalidomide 10 mg/day PO. One week off after every three weeks of treatment.&#xD;
Dose level -2: Lenalidomide 5 mg/day PO. One week off after every three weeks of treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lenalidomide</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CC-5013</other_name>
    <other_name>Revlimid™</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with newly diagnosed multiple myeloma status post 1st auto-HCT (day 60 - 180&#xD;
             post-transplant).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease status (MRD positive or negative), partial response, or better.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18-year and 75-year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance status 70 (Appendix A.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function (Please see Table 2. below). Participant agrees to not donate&#xD;
             blood while taking lenalidomide and for 28 days after stopping lenalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient agrees to enroll in the lenalidomide REMS program.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Woman of child-bearing potential (WOCPB) must abstain from hetersosexual sexual&#xD;
             contact or agrees to use a contraceptive method that is highly effective (with a&#xD;
             failure rate of &lt;1% per year), preferably with low user dependency (as described in&#xD;
             Appendix C), plus one additional effective method at least 28 days before starting&#xD;
             therapy (for lenalidomide), during the intervention period, at least 28 days after the&#xD;
             last dose of lenalidomide and at least 4 months after the last dose of belantamab&#xD;
             mafodotin, and agrees not to donate eggs (ova, oocytes) for reproduction during this&#xD;
             period. The investigator should evaluate the effectiveness of the contraceptive method&#xD;
             in relation to the first dose of the study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        A WOCBP must have a negative highly sensitive serum pregnancy test (as required by local&#xD;
        regulations) within 10-14 days and also within 24 hours before the first dose of the study&#xD;
        intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Nonchildbearing potential is defined as follows (by other than medical reasons):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 45 years of age and has not had menses for &gt;1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have been amenorrhoeic for &lt;2 years without a history of a hysterectomy&#xD;
             and oophorectomy must have a follicle-stimulating hormone value in the postmenopausal&#xD;
             range upon screening evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-hysterectomy, post-bilateral oophorectomy, or post-tubal ligation. 9. Male&#xD;
             participant agrees to contraceptive use that should be consistent with institutional&#xD;
             guidelines regarding the methods of contraception for those participating in clinical&#xD;
             studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Male participants are eligible to participate if they agree to the following during the&#xD;
        intervention period and for 6 months after the last dose of study treatment to allow for&#xD;
        clearance of any altered sperm:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Refrain from donating sperm during treatment (including dose interruptions) and for 4&#xD;
        weeks after their last dose of lenalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
        PLUS, either:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Be abstinent from heterosexual intercourse as their preferred and usual lifestyle&#xD;
        (abstinent on a long term and persistent basis) and agree to remain abstinent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        OR Must agree to use contraception/barrier as detailed in Appendix C.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of progressive disease at any time before starting maintenance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with smoldering MM (IMWG criteria, Appendix F.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with plasma cell leukemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with non-secretory MM (no measurable disease on electrophoresis and&#xD;
             immunofixation). Patients with a measurable disease on PET scan or bone marrow will be&#xD;
             eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have current unstable liver or biliary disease defined by the&#xD;
             presence of ascites, encephalopathy, coagulopathy, hypoalbuminemia due to underlying&#xD;
             liver disease (serum albumin &lt; 3gm/dL), esophageal or gastric varices, persistent&#xD;
             jaundice, or cirrhosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have presence of active renal condition (infection, requirement&#xD;
             for dialysis or any other condition that could affect participant's safety).&#xD;
             Participants with isolated proteinuria resulting from MM are eligible, provided they&#xD;
             fulfil inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current corneal or epithelial disease (except mild punctate keratopathy; see Appendix&#xD;
             E.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not use contact lenses while participating in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have used an investigational drug or approved systemic&#xD;
             anti-myeloma therapy (including systemic steroids) within 14 days or five half-lives,&#xD;
             whichever is shorter, preceding the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have received prior treatment with a monoclonal antibody within&#xD;
             30 days of receiving the first dose of study drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have had major surgery ≤ 4 weeks before initiating study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant must not have any evidence of active mucosal or internal bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have known immediate or delayed hypersensitivity reaction or&#xD;
             idiosyncratic reactions to belantamab mafodotin or drugs chemically related to&#xD;
             belantamab mafodotin, or any of the components of the study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have an active infection requiring treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have evidence of cardiovascular risk, including any of the&#xD;
             following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Evidence of current clinically significant uncontrolled arrhythmias, including&#xD;
                  clinically significant ECG abnormalities such as 2nd degree (Mobitz Type II) or&#xD;
                  3rd degree atrioventricular (AV) block.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. History of myocardial infarction, acute coronary syndromes (including unstable&#xD;
                  angina), coronary angioplasty, or stenting or bypass grafting within three (3)&#xD;
                  months of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Class III or IV heart failure as defined by the New York Heart Association&#xD;
                  functional classification system.16&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Uncontrolled hypertension (blood pressure that remains above goal despite the&#xD;
                  concurrent use of three antihypertensive drug classes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have known HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will Hepatitis B will be excluded unless the following criteria can be met&#xD;
             (Please, also see Appendix B):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serology Screening HbcAb+, HbsAg- • HBV DNA undetectable HBsAg+ at screen or within 3&#xD;
        months prior to first dose • HBV DNA undetectable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Highly effective antiviral treatment started at least 4 weeks prior to first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline imaging per protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with cirrhosis are excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: presence of Hep B surface antibody (HBsAb) indicating previous vaccination will not&#xD;
        exclude a participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive hepatitis C antibody test result or positive hepatitis C RNA test result at&#xD;
             screening or within 3 months prior to first dose of study treatment unless the&#xD;
             participant can meet the following criteria (Please, also see Appendix B):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  RNA test negative&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Successful anti-viral treatment (usually 8 weeks duration) is required, followed&#xD;
                  by a negative HCV RNA test after a washout period of at least 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must not have invasive malignancies other than disease under study, unless&#xD;
             the second malignancy has been medically stable for at least 2 years and, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the principal investigators, will not affect the evaluation of the effects&#xD;
             of clinical trial treatments on the currently targeted malignancy. Participants with&#xD;
             curatively treated non-melanoma skin cancer may be enrolled without a 2-year&#xD;
             restriction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must not be pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious unstable pre-existing medical condition or psychiatric disorder that can&#xD;
             interfere with safety or with obtaining informed consent or compliance with study&#xD;
             procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All prior treatment-related toxicities (defined by National Cancer Institute- Common&#xD;
             Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI-CTCAE), version 5 must be ≤ Grade 1 at the&#xD;
             time of enrolment except for alopecia.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Qaiser Bashir</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Qaiser Bashir</last_name>
    <phone>(713) 794-4422</phone>
    <email>qbashir@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77051</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Qaiser Bashir</last_name>
      <phone>713-794-4422</phone>
      <email>qbashir@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Qaiser Bashir</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>M D Anderson Cancer Center website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm, Residual</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lenalidomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

