<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05091931</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-UTI-PMAS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05091931</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Diagnosis, Antibiotic Prescribing Practices and Outcomes of cUTI in an Outpatient Setting</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective Observational Cohort Study Comparing the Effects of Guidance® UTI vs. Culture-based Testing Methods on Antibiotic Prescribing Practices in an Outpatient Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pathnostics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pathnostics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This prospective, multicenter, comparative cohort observational study is to determine if&#xD;
      Guidance® UTI pathway compared to traditional diagnostic pathways reduces the rates of&#xD;
      empiric antibiotic therapy, adverse events, and improves therapeutic accuracy of treatment&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We propose to conduct a multicenter, comparative cohort observational study to determine&#xD;
      whether the use of Guidance® UTI Clinical Pathway compared with current traditional pathways&#xD;
      for urine testing reduces the rates of empiric antibiotic therapy and improves therapeutic&#xD;
      accuracy of treatment. Comparative outpatient Urology and urogynecology office cohorts will&#xD;
      be allocated at an uneven 2:1 allocation ratio. Regardless of arm assignment, all outpatient&#xD;
      offices have the option to order ANY diagnostic test for suspected UTI, this includes urine&#xD;
      cultures and/or other molecular testing methods including Guidance® UTI. If a provider in the&#xD;
      Guidance Clinical Pathway arm decides to order urine cultures instead of using the Guidance®&#xD;
      UTI Clinical Pathway, those results will also be reported to the site lead, though TAT may&#xD;
      take up to 72 hours to result per standard culture protocols. We will be observing the&#xD;
      practice's implementation of the Clinical Pathway and reporting infrastructure to provide&#xD;
      rapid, centralized reporting to the ordering provider, allowing for efficient treatment.&#xD;
      Guidance® UTI is currently widely available, and all participating outpatient offices&#xD;
      (regardless of arm) will have the option to order this test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of outpatients seen for suspected UTI started on empiric treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if Guidance® UTI pathway compared to traditional diagnostic pathways is associated with fewer empiric antibiotic treatments for patients with Complicated UTI in outpatient setting.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of Adverse Events through 30 days</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if Guidance® UTI pathway compared to traditional diagnostic pathways is associated with lower rate in adverse events through 30 Days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resolution of the initial UTI symptoms by day 14</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if Guidance® UTI pathway compared to traditional diagnostic pathways is associated with faster symptom resolution within 14 days and higher rates of complete symptom resolution by day 30</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete Resolution of symptoms by day 30</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if Guidance® UTI pathway compared to traditional diagnostic pathways is associated higher rates of prescribed antibiotics that are concordant with sensitivity results.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1700</enrollment>
  <condition>Urinary Tract Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Guidance® UTI Pathway</arm_group_label>
    <description>Guidance® UTI testing pathway with antibiotic sensitivity and microbial testing results reporting to a clinical lead specialist at the urology office within 14 hours of lab receipt. Treatment based on local standard clinical antibiotic selection with or without empiric therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional Diagnostic Pathways</arm_group_label>
    <description>Local standard clinical practice pattern for UTI testing (e.g., urine analysis, urine culture and sensitivities or molecular testing as available) Treatment based on local standard clinical antibiotic selection with or without empiric therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Data or specimens collected in this research study might be used for future research or&#xD;
      distributed to another investigator for future research without your consent.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Individuals &gt;18 years requiring evaluation for suspected urinary tract infection in the&#xD;
        urology or urogynecology practice.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide Informed Consent in English and Spanish.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and Female Subjects &gt; 18 years of age may participate with no predetermined&#xD;
             quotas or ratios for gender participation. Presenting to urologist or urogynecologist&#xD;
             in outpatient setting with a history of complicated UTI (cUTI) and clinically&#xD;
             suspected active UTI (e.g., UA positive for L.E. or nitrites) and based on clinical&#xD;
             judgment require microbial testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Definition of cUTI- UTI is considered complicated when the individual has one or more&#xD;
             risk factors that predispose to higher treatment failure and poor outcomes6. These&#xD;
             poor outcomes include persistence of UTI, increasing severity, or occurrence of&#xD;
             complications such as urosepsis, recurrence, and perinephric abscess.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent UTI is defined as 2 infections in 6 months or 3 infections in 12 months in a&#xD;
             calendar year. A UTI at the index visit may be used towards this count.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with bladder/urologic cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with chronic pelvic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with untreated overactive bladder (either neurogenic or&#xD;
             non-neurogenic)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not meeting incl. criteria listed above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not provide written informed Consent with HIPAA authorization form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to independently provide symptom data&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must have email access to participate and complete in online surveys&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incarceration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the provider deems that a urine culture/ Guidance UTI is not necessary in clinical&#xD;
             management, the patient is not eligible for enrollment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Patrick Cacdac, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinical Trials</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Natalie Luke, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(714) 966-1221</phone>
    <phone_ext>615</phone_ext>
    <email>nluke@pathnostics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Patrick Cacdac, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(714) 966-1221</phone>
    <email>pcacdac@pathnostics.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recurrent UTI</keyword>
  <keyword>Complicated Urinary Tract Infection</keyword>
  <keyword>C Difficile</keyword>
  <keyword>Adverse Drug Event</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Tract Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

