<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05096871</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Soh-Med-21-10-18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05096871</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Association of Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor (BDNF) rs6265 Gene Polymorphism With Susceptibility to Epilepsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Association of Brain Derived Neurotrophic Factor (BDNF) rs6265 Gene Polymorphism With Susceptibility to Epilepsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sohag University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sohag University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Epilepsy is a common neurological condition that affects people of all ages.Recent studies&#xD;
      found that epilepsy is associated with several chromosomal regions, where mutations in these&#xD;
      regions cause neurological dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BDNF which is the most ample neurotropic factor in the CNS, has survival and growth promoting&#xD;
      roles in a variety of neurons. It has been shown to promote excitatory (glutamatergic)&#xD;
      synapses while weakening inhibitory (GABAergic) ones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A nonsynonymous G to A single-nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) exists at position 196 of exon 2&#xD;
      (rs6265), which results in valine (val) to methionine (met) substitution. This polymorphism&#xD;
      affects intracellular packaging of pro-BDNF, its axonal transport and in turn,&#xD;
      activity-dependent secretion of BDNF at the synapse.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Epilepsy was defined as the separate occurrence of two or more unprovoked seizures,&#xD;
      manifested by involuntary motor, sensory, or autonomic, alone or in combination, and not&#xD;
      diagnosed as neonatal or febrile seizures. Despite extensive studies, the molecular causes of&#xD;
      the disease are not yet discovered completely. A functional imbalance between excitatory&#xD;
      (transmitted by glutamate) and inhibitory signals (transmitted by γ-amino butyric acid or&#xD;
      GABA) in neural cells has been regarded as a putative contributing factor in epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The brain-derived neurotropic factor (BDNF) encodes a small dimeric protein which is the most&#xD;
      ample neurotropic factor in the CNS.It has been shown to promote excitatory (glutamatergic)&#xD;
      synapses while weakening inhibitory (GABAergic) ones.Any interference with the BDNF signaling&#xD;
      pathway may negatively affect downstream neuronal functions and cause neuronal diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A nonsynonymous G to A single-nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) exists at position 196 of exon 2&#xD;
      (rs6265), which results in valine (val) to methionine (met) substitution at codon 66&#xD;
      (val66met), changing the 5' proregion of the human BDNF protein. This polymorphism affects&#xD;
      intracellular packaging of pro-BDNF, its axonal transport and in turn, activity-dependent&#xD;
      secretion of BDNF at the synapse&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Iinvestigate the possible association between BDNF rs6265 polymorphism and epilepsy susceptibility in Egyptian patients</measure>
    <time_frame>within 3 days after collection of samples</time_frame>
    <description>Genotyping assay of ( BDNF ) rs6265 gene polymorphism by the Real- time polymerase chain reaction.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the utility of serum BDNF concentration as a diagnostic tool for Epilepsy and evaluate its relationship with disease severity</measure>
    <time_frame>within 3 days after collection of samples</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement BDNF level in serum by Sandwich enzyme linked immunosorbant assay kit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group I</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients with epilepsy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group II</arm_group_label>
    <description>apparently healthy controls with no chronic illness of matched age and sex</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Genotyping by Real Time PCR</intervention_name>
    <description>3 mL of blood will be withdrawn by venipuncture in EDTA tube. DNA extraction will be done after centrifugation and used for genotyping assay of ( BDNF ) gene with the Real- time polymerase chain reaction.&#xD;
BDNF level in serum will also be analyzed by Sandwich enzyme linked immunosorbant assay kit ( ELISA).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group I</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group II</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with epilepsy aged from 1 year to less than 15 years, in Pediatric department of&#xD;
        Sohag University Hospital and healthy control children of matched age and sex&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Epileptic patients aged more than 1 year and less than 15 year who recently had seizures&#xD;
        over a period of one year&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients &gt; 15 years old or less than 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that have epilepsy as a result of head injuries, brain tumors , exposure to&#xD;
             low oxygen during birth or infections such as meningitis or encephalitis .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that have no sufficient medical records or unreliable seizure frequency,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with developmental disorders such as Autism and Neurofibromatosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Salma K Abdelmageed, demonstrator</last_name>
    <phone>01091285241</phone>
    <email>salma011101@med.sohag.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Egan MF, Kojima M, Callicott JH, Goldberg TE, Kolachana BS, Bertolino A, Zaitsev E, Gold B, Goldman D, Dean M, Lu B, Weinberger DR. The BDNF val66met polymorphism affects activity-dependent secretion of BDNF and human memory and hippocampal function. Cell. 2003 Jan 24;112(2):257-69.</citation>
    <PMID>12553913</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen ZY, Patel PD, Sant G, Meng CX, Teng KK, Hempstead BL, Lee FS. Variant brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF) (Met66) alters the intracellular trafficking and activity-dependent secretion of wild-type BDNF in neurosecretory cells and cortical neurons. J Neurosci. 2004 May 5;24(18):4401-11.</citation>
    <PMID>15128854</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fisher RS, Acevedo C, Arzimanoglou A, Bogacz A, Cross JH, Elger CE, Engel J Jr, Forsgren L, French JA, Glynn M, Hesdorffer DC, Lee BI, Mathern GW, Moshé SL, Perucca E, Scheffer IE, Tomson T, Watanabe M, Wiebe S. ILAE official report: a practical clinical definition of epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2014 Apr;55(4):475-82. doi: 10.1111/epi.12550. Epub 2014 Apr 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24730690</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Löscher W, Potschka H, Sisodiya SM, Vezzani A. Drug Resistance in Epilepsy: Clinical Impact, Potential Mechanisms, and New Innovative Treatment Options. Pharmacol Rev. 2020 Jul;72(3):606-638. doi: 10.1124/pr.120.019539. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32540959</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sohag University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Salma Khalaf Abdelmageed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>demonstrator of Medical Biochemistry</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>BDNF in epileptic patients</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

