<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05094154</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210591</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05094154</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Antibiotic Choice On ReNal Outcomes (ACORN)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ACORN</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Antibiotic Choice On ReNal Outcomes (ACORN)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sepsis is one of the most common causes of acute illness and death in the United States.&#xD;
      Early, empiric broad-spectrum antibiotics are a mainstay of sepsis treatment. Two classes of&#xD;
      antibiotics with activity against Pseudomonas, anti-pseudomonal cephalosporins and&#xD;
      anti-pseudomonal penicillins, are commonly used for acutely ill adults with sepsis in current&#xD;
      practice. Recent observational studies, however, have raised concern that anti-pseudomonal&#xD;
      penicillins may cause renal toxicity. Anti-pseudomonal cephalosporins, by comparison, may be&#xD;
      associated with a risk of neurotoxicity. Rigorous, prospective data regarding the comparative&#xD;
      effectiveness and toxicity of these two classes of medications among acutely ill patients are&#xD;
      lacking. The investigator propose a randomized trial comparing the impact of anti-pseudomonal&#xD;
      cephalosporins and anti-pseudomonal penicillins on renal outcomes of acutely ill patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Sepsis is a common condition associated with high mortality and morbidity. Antibiotics are an&#xD;
      integral component of the management of patients with sepsis. Each hour delay in antibiotic&#xD;
      administration in sepsis is associated with an increase in mortality. Clinical guidelines&#xD;
      recommend early management bundles, including early broad-spectrum antibiotics, for patients&#xD;
      with presumed sepsis in the emergency department and intensive care unit. Since the specific&#xD;
      organism causing an infection is rarely known at clinical presentation, empiric&#xD;
      broad-spectrum antibiotics are commonly prescribed. For patients at risk for resistant&#xD;
      organisms, the most common regimens include vancomycin (to cover gram-positive organisms&#xD;
      including methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus) and an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin&#xD;
      or anti-pseudomonal penicillin (to cover gram-negative organisms including Pseudomonas).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cephalosporins and penicillins are beta-lactam antibiotics that act by inhibiting the&#xD;
      synthesis of the peptidoglycan layer of bacterial cell walls. They are commonly used for a&#xD;
      variety of infections including empiric broad spectrum coverage for sepsis and suspected&#xD;
      nosocomial infections. Several cephalosporins and penicillins have anti-pseudomonal activity,&#xD;
      including cefepime, a fourth-generation cephalosporin, ceftazidime, a third-generation&#xD;
      cephalosporin, and piperacillin-tazobactam, an extended-spectrum penicillin with&#xD;
      beta-lactamase inhibitor. Anti-pseudomonal penicillins are the preferred agents for empiric&#xD;
      broad spectrum coverage at many centers, and piperacillin-tazobactam, specifically, has the&#xD;
      added benefit of treating anaerobic organisms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acute Kidney Injury (AKI) is a common complication of ICU admission. AKI is associated with a&#xD;
      six to eight fold increase in mortality in ICU populations is therefore a common target of&#xD;
      critical care trials. Sepsis is the most common cause of AKI and accounts for 40-50% of AKI&#xD;
      in the intensive care unit (ICU). As the primary treatment for the underlying cause of&#xD;
      sepsis, antibiotics are a critical treatment for acutely ill patients, but antibiotics may&#xD;
      cause renal injury, and renally-cleared antibiotics may reach supratherapeutic levels in the&#xD;
      setting of AKI. Vancomycin has long been associated with AKI. Recently, a number of&#xD;
      retrospective observational analyses have examined a potential association between the&#xD;
      concurrent administration of vancomycin and piperacillin-tazobactam and the development of&#xD;
      AKI, compared with vancomycin alone. These data, however, are likely to be confounded by&#xD;
      indication bias and studies evaluating whether piperacillin-tazobactam causes more AKI than&#xD;
      other anti-pseudomonal antibiotics have been inconclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on this preliminary, observational data, however, some institutions have elected to&#xD;
      change their preferred broad spectrum antibiotic regimens from one including an&#xD;
      anti-pseudomonal penicillin to one including an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin. However,&#xD;
      others have argued against this approach given the lack of randomized trials comparing the&#xD;
      relative efficacy and safety of the two agents as well as observational data suggesting that&#xD;
      cephalosporins may be associated with neuro-toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tens of thousands of patients each year receive either anti-pseudomonal cephalosporins and&#xD;
      penicillins, but no randomized trials have ever compared their relative effectiveness or&#xD;
      safety. Each class of medications has been hypothesized to have toxicities that may be&#xD;
      relevant for acutely ill patients. Because the relationship between antibiotic choice&#xD;
      (anti-pseudomonal cephalosporins or anti-pseudomonal penicillins) and clinically relevant&#xD;
      outcomes, such as AKI, are unknown, clinical trial data is urgently needed. Rigorous&#xD;
      high-quality evidence that anti-pseudomonal cephalosporins, compared to anti-pseudomonal&#xD;
      penicillins, decreases, increases or has no impact on the risk of AKI would have the&#xD;
      potential to change the care received by thousands of acutely ill adults each year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This study will be performed as a pragmatic, randomized controlled clinical trial with parallel group assignment.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Patients and providers will necessarily be unblinded, but outcomes will be analyzed by a blind assessor.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute Kidney Injury (AKI) Ordinal Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days post-enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Acute Kidney Injury Score between randomization and day 14. The acute kidney injury score is an ordinal outcome containing the stages of AKI as defined by Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes (KDIGO) creatinine criteria, new renal replacement therapy (RRT), and death:&#xD;
0 = No AKI&#xD;
= Stage 1 AKI (Creatinine increase by 1.5-1.9 times baseline OR increase by &gt;= 0.3 mg/dL)&#xD;
= Stage 2 AKI (Creatinine increase by 2.0-2.9 times baseline)&#xD;
= Stage 3 AKI (Creatinine increase by &gt;= 3.0 times baseline OR increase to &gt;= 4.0 mg/dL OR New RRT)&#xD;
= Death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Post-Emergency Department Disposition</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days post-enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Patient disposition (ex. floor unit or intensive care unit) at day 14 post-enrollment from the emergency department.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2050</enrollment>
  <condition>Sepsis</condition>
  <condition>AKI</condition>
  <condition>Neurotoxicity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin arm will receive at least one dose of an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>anti-pseudomonal penicillin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the anti-pseudomonal penicillin arm will receive at least one dose of an anti-pseudomonal penicillin.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin</intervention_name>
    <description>Providers will be prompted to order an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin, such as cefepime with a dose range of 500 mg, 1,000 mg, or 2,000 mg, and frequency every 6, 8, 12, or 24 hours based on provider discretion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>anti-pseudomonal penicillin</intervention_name>
    <description>Providers will be prompted to order anti-pseudomonal penicillin, such as piperacillin-tazobactam with a dose range of 3.375 g or 4.5 g and frequency every 6, 8, or 12 hours based on provider discretion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>anti-pseudomonal penicillin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Located in a participating emergency department or medical intensive care unit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 12 hours from presentation to study hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treating clinician initiating an order for an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin or&#xD;
             anti-pseudomonal penicillin&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known receipt of &gt; 1 dose of an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin or anti-pseudomonal&#xD;
             penicillin during the last 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current documented allergy to cephalosporins or penicillin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known to be a prisoner&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treating clinicians feel that either an anti-pseudomonal cephalosporin or&#xD;
             anti-pseudomonal penicillin is required or contraindicated for the optimal treatment&#xD;
             of the patient, including for more directed antibiotic therapy against known prior&#xD;
             resistant infections or suspected sepsis with an associated central nervous system&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Edward T Qian, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cecconi M, Evans L, Levy M, Rhodes A. Sepsis and septic shock. Lancet. 2018 Jul 7;392(10141):75-87. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30696-2. Epub 2018 Jun 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29937192</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rhodes A, Evans LE, Alhazzani W, Levy MM, Antonelli M, Ferrer R, Kumar A, Sevransky JE, Sprung CL, Nunnally ME, Rochwerg B, Rubenfeld GD, Angus DC, Annane D, Beale RJ, Bellinghan GJ, Bernard GR, Chiche JD, Coopersmith C, De Backer DP, French CJ, Fujishima S, Gerlach H, Hidalgo JL, Hollenberg SM, Jones AE, Karnad DR, Kleinpell RM, Koh Y, Lisboa TC, Machado FR, Marini JJ, Marshall JC, Mazuski JE, McIntyre LA, McLean AS, Mehta S, Moreno RP, Myburgh J, Navalesi P, Nishida O, Osborn TM, Perner A, Plunkett CM, Ranieri M, Schorr CA, Seckel MA, Seymour CW, Shieh L, Shukri KA, Simpson SQ, Singer M, Thompson BT, Townsend SR, Van der Poll T, Vincent JL, Wiersinga WJ, Zimmerman JL, Dellinger RP. Surviving Sepsis Campaign: International Guidelines for Management of Sepsis and Septic Shock: 2016. Intensive Care Med. 2017 Mar;43(3):304-377. doi: 10.1007/s00134-017-4683-6. Epub 2017 Jan 18.</citation>
    <PMID>28101605</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Liu VX, Fielding-Singh V, Greene JD, Baker JM, Iwashyna TJ, Bhattacharya J, Escobar GJ. The Timing of Early Antibiotics and Hospital Mortality in Sepsis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017 Oct 1;196(7):856-863. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201609-1848OC.</citation>
    <PMID>28345952</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Damiani E, Donati A, Serafini G, Rinaldi L, Adrario E, Pelaia P, Busani S, Girardis M. Effect of performance improvement programs on compliance with sepsis bundles and mortality: a systematic review and meta-analysis of observational studies. PLoS One. 2015 May 6;10(5):e0125827. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0125827. eCollection 2015. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25946168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thakar CV, Christianson A, Freyberg R, Almenoff P, Render ML. Incidence and outcomes of acute kidney injury in intensive care units: a Veterans Administration study. Crit Care Med. 2009 Sep;37(9):2552-8. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0b013e3181a5906f.</citation>
    <PMID>19602973</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Uchino S, Kellum JA, Bellomo R, Doig GS, Morimatsu H, Morgera S, Schetz M, Tan I, Bouman C, Macedo E, Gibney N, Tolwani A, Ronco C; Beginning and Ending Supportive Therapy for the Kidney (BEST Kidney) Investigators. Acute renal failure in critically ill patients: a multinational, multicenter study. JAMA. 2005 Aug 17;294(7):813-8.</citation>
    <PMID>16106006</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoste EA, Bagshaw SM, Bellomo R, Cely CM, Colman R, Cruz DN, Edipidis K, Forni LG, Gomersall CD, Govil D, Honoré PM, Joannes-Boyau O, Joannidis M, Korhonen AM, Lavrentieva A, Mehta RL, Palevsky P, Roessler E, Ronco C, Uchino S, Vazquez JA, Vidal Andrade E, Webb S, Kellum JA. Epidemiology of acute kidney injury in critically ill patients: the multinational AKI-EPI study. Intensive Care Med. 2015 Aug;41(8):1411-23. doi: 10.1007/s00134-015-3934-7. Epub 2015 Jul 11.</citation>
    <PMID>26162677</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gómez H, Kellum JA. Sepsis-induced acute kidney injury. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2016 Dec;22(6):546-553. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27661757</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arnaud FCS, Libório AB. Attributable nephrotoxicity of vancomycin in critically ill patients: a marginal structural model study. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2020 Apr 1;75(4):1031-1037. doi: 10.1093/jac/dkz520.</citation>
    <PMID>31904834</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Filippone EJ, Kraft WK, Farber JL. The Nephrotoxicity of Vancomycin. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2017 Sep;102(3):459-469. doi: 10.1002/cpt.726. Epub 2017 Jun 5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28474732</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bellos I, Karageorgiou V, Pergialiotis V, Perrea DN. Acute kidney injury following the concurrent administration of antipseudomonal β-lactams and vancomycin: a network meta-analysis. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2020 Jun;26(6):696-705. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2020.03.019. Epub 2020 Mar 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32222460</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rutter WC, Burgess DR, Talbert JC, Burgess DS. Acute kidney injury in patients treated with vancomycin and piperacillin-tazobactam: A retrospective cohort analysis. J Hosp Med. 2017 Feb;12(2):77-82. doi: 10.12788/jhm.2684.</citation>
    <PMID>28182801</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carreno J, Smiraglia T, Hunter C, Tobin E, Lomaestro B. Comparative incidence and excess risk of acute kidney injury in hospitalised patients receiving vancomycin and piperacillin/tazobactam in combination or as monotherapy. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2018 Nov;52(5):643-650. doi: 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2018.08.001. Epub 2018 Aug 10.</citation>
    <PMID>30103003</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Downes KJ, Cowden C, Laskin BL, Huang YS, Gong W, Bryan M, Fisher BT, Goldstein SL, Zaoutis TE. Association of Acute Kidney Injury With Concomitant Vancomycin and Piperacillin/Tazobactam Treatment Among Hospitalized Children. JAMA Pediatr. 2017 Dec 4;171(12):e173219. doi: 10.1001/jamapediatrics.2017.3219. Epub 2017 Dec 4.</citation>
    <PMID>28973124</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kalligeros M, Karageorgos SA, Shehadeh F, Zacharioudakis IM, Mylonakis E. The association of acute kidney injury with the concomitant use of vancomycin and piperacillin/tazobactam in children: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2019 Oct 7. pii: AAC.01572-19. doi: 10.1128/AAC.01572-19. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>31591125</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Callaghan K, Hay K, Lavana J, McNamara JF. Acute kidney injury with combination vancomycin and piperacillin-tazobactam therapy in the ICU: A retrospective cohort study. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020 Jul;56(1):106010. doi: 10.1016/j.ijantimicag.2020.106010. Epub 2020 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>32413387</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hammond DA, Smith MN, Painter JT, Meena NK, Lusardi K. Comparative Incidence of Acute Kidney Injury in Critically Ill Patients Receiving Vancomycin with Concomitant Piperacillin-Tazobactam or Cefepime: A Retrospective Cohort Study. Pharmacotherapy. 2016 May;36(5):463-71. doi: 10.1002/phar.1738. Epub 2016 Apr 1.</citation>
    <PMID>26952639</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kang S, Park J, Yu YM, Park MS, Han E, Chang MJ. Comparison of acute kidney injury and clinical prognosis of vancomycin monotherapy and combination therapy with beta-lactams in the intensive care unit. PLoS One. 2019 Jun 5;14(6):e0217908. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0217908. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>31166993</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buckley MS, Hartsock NC, Berry AJ, Bikin DS, Richards EC, Yerondopoulos MJ, Kobic E, Wicks LM, Hammond DA. Comparison of acute kidney injury risk associated with vancomycin and concomitant piperacillin/tazobactam or cefepime in the intensive care unit. J Crit Care. 2018 Dec;48:32-38. doi: 10.1016/j.jcrc.2018.08.007. Epub 2018 Aug 11.</citation>
    <PMID>30172962</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hammond DA, Smith MN, Li C, Hayes SM, Lusardi K, Bookstaver PB. Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of Acute Kidney Injury Associated with Concomitant Vancomycin and Piperacillin/tazobactam. Clin Infect Dis. 2017 Mar 1;64(5):666-674. Epub 2016 Dec 10. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27940946</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Molina KC, Barletta JF, Hall ST, Yazdani C, Huang V. The Risk of Acute Kidney Injury in Critically Ill Patients Receiving Concomitant Vancomycin With Piperacillin-Tazobactam or Cefepime. J Intensive Care Med. 2020 Dec;35(12):1434-1438. doi: 10.1177/0885066619828290. Epub 2019 Feb 10.</citation>
    <PMID>30741072</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Luther MK, Timbrook TT, Caffrey AR, Dosa D, Lodise TP, LaPlante KL. Vancomycin Plus Piperacillin-Tazobactam and Acute Kidney Injury in Adults: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Crit Care Med. 2018 Jan;46(1):12-20. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000002769. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29088001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abanades S, Nolla J, Rodríguez-Campello A, Pedro C, Valls A, Farré M. Reversible coma secondary to cefepime neurotoxicity. Ann Pharmacother. 2004 Apr;38(4):606-8. Epub 2004 Feb 24.</citation>
    <PMID>14982986</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Balderia PG, Chandorkar A, Kim Y, Patnaik S, Sloan J, Newman GC. Dosing Cefepime for Renal Function Does Not Completely Prevent Neurotoxicity in a Patient With Kidney Transplant. J Patient Saf. 2018 Jun;14(2):e33-e34. doi: 10.1097/PTS.0000000000000225.</citation>
    <PMID>26102002</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>EDDIE QIAN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator, Clinical Fellow</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neurotoxicity Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Penicillins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cephalosporins</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data that underlie the results reported will be made available (including data dictionaries) after de-identification.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will become available 3 months following publication of outcomes and will remain available for at least 5 years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data will be made available to researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal that has been approved by the Vanderbilt Institutional Review Board and the study executive committee.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

