<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05097313</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PEC02_2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05097313</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Antioxidant and Immunomodulatory Effect of a β-glucan Fiber From Saccharomyces Cerevisiae</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Antioxidant and Immunomodulatory Effect of a β-glucan Fiber From Saccharomyces Cerevisiae in Healthy Adults, Medellín - Antioquia 2021-2022</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad de Antioquia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Levapan S.A</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad de Antioquia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Β-glucans are linear polymers of glucose of high molecular weight that are found naturally in&#xD;
      the cell wall of various living organisms such as bacteria, yeast, fungi and plants; They are&#xD;
      widely used in food companies as texturizers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Scientific studies suggest that the consumption of β-glucans would be associated with&#xD;
      benefits for human health such as reducing the risk of cardiovascular diseases and&#xD;
      strengthening the immune system. These effects depend on their source of origin; those from&#xD;
      cereals have been attributed beneficial metabolic properties and those that come from yeast&#xD;
      immunostimulating properties.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Yeast β-glucans are believed to be potent immunomodulators with effects on innate and&#xD;
      adaptive immunity. This effect could be due to the ability to stimulate receptors of the&#xD;
      immune system present in the membrane of enterocytes, M cells and dendritic cells, improving&#xD;
      the phagocytic activity of macrophages and the antimicrobial activity of mononuclear cells&#xD;
      and neutrophils.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to this property, β-glucans are being used more and more for the development of&#xD;
      functional foods in several countries of the world. However, the effect of yeast β-glucans on&#xD;
      the stimulation of the immune response has not yet been accurately documented; Therefore, the&#xD;
      present investigation aims to establish the performance of a β-glucan fiber from S.&#xD;
      cerevisiae in antioxidant and immunomodulatory activity in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Β-glucans are high molecular weight glucose polymers (polysaccharides) naturally present in&#xD;
      the cell wall of various living organisms such as bacteria, yeast, fungi and plants. Some&#xD;
      studies show that β-glucans have antioxidant activity and stimulate the immune system in&#xD;
      animals and humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the other hand, the physiological metabolism in living beings generates free radicals that&#xD;
      can endanger cell integrity if they are not controlled properly. Free radicals are&#xD;
      collectively known as Reactive Oxygen Species (ROS) and have the ability to produce&#xD;
      significant oxidative damage to cellular structures that can increase under environmental&#xD;
      stress. Free radicals impair tissue function, contribute to aging and the development of&#xD;
      chronic and chronic degenerative diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To counteract the action of free radicals, antioxidants are used whose function is to&#xD;
      maintain or restore cellular balance. An alternative for this are β-glucans since they have&#xD;
      protective properties against oxidative damage, the antioxidant effect they exert is indirect&#xD;
      and is produced by improving the expression and production of antioxidant systems by the body&#xD;
      itself.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Various studies focused on antioxidant activity indicate that β-glucans from mushrooms&#xD;
      constitute a potential natural source of antioxidants, especially associated with regular&#xD;
      consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Added to the effects caused by ROS is the constant exposure of living beings to pathogens,&#xD;
      which must be dealt with by the immune system through cells and tissues to avoid infections.&#xD;
      The immune system, made up of the innate and the adaptive systems, is essential for survival&#xD;
      as it protects the body against potentially dangerous microorganisms that constantly attack&#xD;
      the human body. Therefore, the proper functioning of the immune system must be guaranteed,&#xD;
      since limitations in it increase the possibility of contracting serious infections that&#xD;
      threaten life. In accordance with this, it is reported that changes in dietary composition&#xD;
      can improve immune function. Although studies have been reported in the literature since 1939&#xD;
      on the response of the immune system by yeast cell walls, it is in the 1960s that it is&#xD;
      established that the active substance in yeast that generates the beneficial effect is β&#xD;
      -glucan. Β-glucans are known as biological response modifiers, due to their ability to&#xD;
      activate the immune system, since they favor the participation of immune cells in a greater&#xD;
      proportion in the face of external threats.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the same way, the scientific literature indicates that there are various properties&#xD;
      attributed to the use of β-glucan, among them the decrease in allergy episodes, respiratory&#xD;
      tract infections, decreased concentrations of glycoproteins of the immune system and&#xD;
      increased potential of blood leukocytes to produce IL-2, IL-4, IL-5, and interferon (IFN-γ),&#xD;
      the foregoing, suggesting that β-glucans hold promise for modulating an individual's immunity&#xD;
      .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this sense, the company Levapan SA multilatina company of Colombian origin founded in&#xD;
      1953, which is dedicated to the production and commercialization of yeast (S. cerevisiae),&#xD;
      yeast extracts, flavor enhancers, raw materials for food industries, bakery and&#xD;
      confectionery, mass consumption products, gastronomy, agribusiness, vegetable and animal&#xD;
      proteins, has worked on the production of β-glucan from S. cerevisiae, showing potential&#xD;
      effects on health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within its portfolio, the product derived from yeast that is currently used as an ingredient&#xD;
      in different formulations of the nutraceutical industry is presented as β-glucan Plus, since&#xD;
      they offer immunostimulating properties. It is also considered that β-glucan may be a&#xD;
      promising alternative to control or mitigate the effects of the SARS-CoV-2 virus responsible&#xD;
      for the COVID-19 disease. However, it is necessary to evaluate and confirm the antioxidant&#xD;
      and immunomodulatory effect of β-glucan Plus through a clinical evaluation as proposed by&#xD;
      this research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Benefits of β-glucan&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evidence supports that the inclusion of these polysaccharides in the diet can have positive&#xD;
      effects on glycemic control, cholesterol and immunity. Due to their physical and chemical&#xD;
      characteristics, they have been used during the development of functional foods to improve&#xD;
      their texture and shelf life. Β-glucans are related to anti-inflammatory, antiviral,&#xD;
      antioxidant, and immunomodulatory activity. Antimutagenic, chemoprotective and anticancer&#xD;
      effects of these compounds have also been reported and they are reported to have positive&#xD;
      effects on cardiovascular diseases, arteriosclerosis, diabetes, wound healing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, β-glucan extracted from microorganisms is being used for the treatment of many&#xD;
      diseases in the world. Processes have been carried out to extract β-glucans from the cell&#xD;
      wall of S. cerevicie and develop products with it. However, work continues to obtain evidence&#xD;
      to demonstrate its effectiveness through clinical studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Global situation due to the COVID-19 pandemic&#xD;
&#xD;
      The spread of the COVID-19 virus) has prompted interest in boosting immunity. With this&#xD;
      perspective Kerry notes that clinical research has shown that his Wellmune β-glucan can help&#xD;
      support upper respiratory tract infections. The company says it can support the immune system&#xD;
      of people, including children, athletes, older adults and those with lifestyle stress.&#xD;
      Wellmune notes that a healthy immune system is the best defense against disease, although&#xD;
      there is no specific research demonstrating Wellmune's effectiveness against diseases like&#xD;
      COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatments with β-glucan. At present there is an interest in promoting the immune response of&#xD;
      organisms in a natural way, these facts have motivated the interest in conducting research on&#xD;
      the immunomodulatory effect derived from natural systems. These scientific studies suggest&#xD;
      that its consumption would be associated with benefits for human health such as reducing the&#xD;
      risk of cardiovascular diseases and strengthening the immune system. These effects depend on&#xD;
      their source of origin, those from cereals have been attributed beneficial metabolic&#xD;
      properties and those that come from yeast immunostimulating properties; According to this&#xD;
      theory, yeast β-glucans are believed to be potent immunomodulators with effects on innate and&#xD;
      adaptive immunity. This effect could be due to the ability to stimulate receptors of the&#xD;
      immune system present in the membrane of enterocytes, M cells and dendritic cells, improving&#xD;
      the phagocytic activity of macrophages and the antimicrobial activity of mononuclear cells&#xD;
      and neutrophils.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Β-glucan from bakery yeast produced by Levapan S.A&#xD;
&#xD;
      The β-glucan of Yeast Plus is a product of Levapan SA that contains 1,3 and 1,6 Β- Glucan&#xD;
      extracted under hydrolysis processes of the cell wall of the yeast S. cerevisiae, where at&#xD;
      the end of the process a product is obtained insoluble in water. The product is originated&#xD;
      from non-genetically modified microorganisms, baker's yeast is the primary yeast made from&#xD;
      sugar cane molasses. Annually the company produces approximately 20 Ton / month of β-glucan&#xD;
      for its use in different formulations, such as the development of nutraceutical foods for&#xD;
      human consumption, animal feed, aquaculture, among others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The β-glucan Plus is currently manufactured by Levapan S. A company that has the KOSHER,&#xD;
      HALAL and ISO 9001: 2008 certifications for the production and preparation of glucan and is&#xD;
      evaluated by PECET following the BPC protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are extensive properties attributable to β-glucans that allow evaluating their actions&#xD;
      in various fields, being used more and more for the development of functional foods in&#xD;
      various countries of the world, but with few results that demonstrate the real effect of&#xD;
      these.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to these properties there are several studies focused on the effects of β-glucans,&#xD;
      however, the effect of β-glucans from yeast S. cerevisiae on the stimulation of the immune&#xD;
      response has not yet been accurately documented, so the This research aims to establish the&#xD;
      performance of a S. cerevisiae β-glucan fiber in antioxidant and immunomodulatory activity in&#xD;
      healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the antioxidant and immunomodulatory activity of the different types of β-glucans,&#xD;
      these are being used more and more for the development of functional foods in several&#xD;
      countries of the world. However, the effect of yeast β-glucans on the stimulation of the&#xD;
      immune response has not yet been accurately documented; Therefore, the present investigation&#xD;
      aims to establish the performance of a β-glucan fiber from S. cerevisiae in antioxidant and&#xD;
      immunomodulatory activity in healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES OF THE STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
      General objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the antioxidant and immunomodulatory effect of a β-glucan fiber obtained from&#xD;
      the yeast S. cerevisiae in healthy adults.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the antioxidant activity of a β-glucan fiber obtained from S.cerevisiae&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the strengthening of the immune system of a β-glucan fiber obtained from&#xD;
           the yeast S. cerevisiae&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluate the safety and tolerability (frequency, seriousness and degree of adverse&#xD;
           events) of a β-glucan fiber obtained from the yeast S. cerevisiae&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Explore the metabolic benefit of a β-glucan fiber obtained from the yeast S. cerevisiae&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Explore the impact of the consumption of a β-glucan fiber obtained from the yeast S.&#xD;
           cerevisiae on the severity of the SARS-CoV-2 coronavirus infection&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 27, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is an interventional, randomized, non-comparative, exploratory, three-arm, double-blind, randomized study, divided into three groups (2 intervention and placebo) using an allocation ratio of 1: 1: 1.&#xD;
Treatment allocation will be made according to a random code.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double blind trial. Research product blinding will be maintained using one label for both products (fiber and placebo) and the same capsules for both.&#xD;
Subjects, who collect the data (eg, Investigator and coordinator) and those who evaluate the data (eg, Statistician) will be blinded. One or more pharmacists / vaccine administrators designated by the facility will not be blinded. These designated unblinded individuals will maintain investigational vaccine blindness and will not participate in the safety assessment of the subjects.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Antioxidant capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 140</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of antioxidant capacity of β-glucan Fiber through analysis of results of tests from Baseline level compared to day 42, day 84 and day 140.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunomodulatory capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 140</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of immunomodulatory capacity of β-glucan Fiber through analysis of results of tests from Baseline level compared to day 42, day 84 and day 140.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolic benefit</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 140</time_frame>
    <description>Changes of lipid profile in participants. Changes from Baseline level compared to day 42, day 84 and day 140 evaluations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolid benefit</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 140</time_frame>
    <description>Changes of glucose level in participants. Changes from Baseline level compared to day 42, day 84 and day 140 evaluations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Nutrition, Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>consumption of 250 mg of β-glucan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with oral consumption of 250 mg (one capsule) of β-glucan from Yeast Plus once a day for 84 days without interruption.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>consumption of 500 mg of β-glucan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with oral consumption of 500 mg (two capsules) of β-glucan from Yeast Plus once a day for 84 days without interruption.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>200 mg or 400 mg placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo patients, with oral soy protein consumption, half of the group 200 mg (one capsule) and the remaining 400 mg (two capsules) once a day for 84 days without interruption</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Yeast β-glucan fiber</intervention_name>
    <description>The study is designed to determine if β-glucan is safe and if it presents an antioxidant and immunomodulatory response in healthy adults in Colombia.</description>
    <arm_group_label>consumption of 250 mg of β-glucan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>consumption of 500 mg of β-glucan</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>β-glucan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>oral consumption of 200 mg (one capsule) or 400 mg (two capsules) of soy protein powder for 84 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>200 mg or 400 mg placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women aged ≥18 and ≤45 years without abnormal findings at the time of physical&#xD;
             examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tests of creatinine, transaminases, lipid profile, glycemia and hemogram with ranges&#xD;
             of normality according to laboratory reference values and / or at the discretion of&#xD;
             the researcher&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index (BMI) between 18.5 and 25 kg / m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the researcher, the participant is able to understand and comply&#xD;
             with the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with a positive pregnancy test during the screening process or who do not agree&#xD;
             with the use of a contraceptive method until day 90 post-treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant pathological history such as kidney disease, hypertension,&#xD;
             diabetes, anemia, autoimmune or psychiatric diseases, among others that may affect the&#xD;
             development or results of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Manifest eating styles other than the omnivore&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have food restrictions derived from allergic, metabolic, dermatological diseases,&#xD;
             lithiasis, irritable bowel and / or health conditions that imply permanent&#xD;
             modification in diet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumption of a vitamin or nutritional supplement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may affect the development of&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Iván D Vélez, MD. PhD.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Director PECET</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Program for Research and Control in Tropical Diseases - PECET</name>
      <address>
        <city>Medellín</city>
        <state>Antioquia</state>
        <zip>0004</zip>
        <country>Colombia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Colombia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://hifasdaterra.com/blog/beta-glucanos-reguladores-inmunitarios-y-protectores-cardiovasculares/</url>
    <description>TERRA HD. Beta-glucans: immune regulators and cardiovascular protectors 2019</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.nutritioninsight.com/news/lallemand-bio-ingredients-acquires-biotec-betaglucans-to-expand-beta-glucan-yeast-strategy.html</url>
    <description>nutritioninsight. Lallemand Bio-Ingredients adquiere Biotec BetaGlucans para expandir la estrategia de levadura beta-glucano 2020</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Del Cornò M, Gessani S, Conti L. Shaping the Innate Immune Response by Dietary Glucans: Any Role in the Control of Cancer? Cancers (Basel). 2020 Jan 8;12(1). pii: E155. doi: 10.3390/cancers12010155. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31936360</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pérez-Guisado J. Arguments in favor of incorporating β-D-glucans in food. Endocrinología y Nutrición. 2007;54(6):315-24.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Divya M, Gopi N, Iswarya A, Govindarajan M, Alharbi NS, Kadaikunnan S, Khaled JM, Almanaa TN, Vaseeharan B. β-glucan extracted from eukaryotic single-celled microorganism Saccharomyces cerevisiae: Dietary supplementation and enhanced ammonia stress tolerance on Oreochromis mossambicus. Microb Pathog. 2020 Feb;139:103917. doi: 10.1016/j.micpath.2019.103917. Epub 2019 Dec 10.</citation>
    <PMID>31830581</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Antioxidant Effect of Beta-glucan Extract from Saccharomyces Cerevisiae. Indian Journal of Forensic Medicine &amp; Toxicology. 2020.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vetvicka V, Vannucci L, Sima P, Richter J. Beta Glucan: Supplement or Drug? From Laboratory to Clinical Trials. Molecules. 2019 Mar 30;24(7). pii: E1251. doi: 10.3390/molecules24071251. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30935016</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carvajal Carvajal C. Reactive oxygen species: formation, function and oxidative stress. Legal Medicine of Costa Rica. 2019; 36: 91-100.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Özcan Ö, Ertan F. Beta-glucan Content, Antioxidant and Antimicrobial Activities of Some Edible Mushroom Species. Food Science and Technology. 2018;6(2):47-55.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zrnic-Ciric M, Dabetic N, Todorovic V, Djuris J, Vidovic B. Beta-glucan content and antioxidant activities of mushroom-derived food supplements. Journal of the Serbian Chemical Society. 2020;85(4):439-51.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Song H-S, Moon K-Y. In vitro antioxidant activity profiles of ${\beta} $-glucans isolated from yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae and mutant Saccharomyces cerevisiae IS2. Food Science and Biotechnology. 2006;15(3):437-40.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Volman JJ, Mensink RP, Ramakers JD, de Winther MP, Carlsen H, Blomhoff R, Buurman WA, Plat J. Dietary (1--&gt;3), (1--&gt;4)-beta-D-glucans from oat activate nuclear factor-kappaB in intestinal leukocytes and enterocytes from mice. Nutr Res. 2010 Jan;30(1):40-8. doi: 10.1016/j.nutres.2009.10.023.</citation>
    <PMID>20116659</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carpenter KC, Breslin WL, Davidson T, Adams A, McFarlin BK. Baker's yeast β-glucan supplementation increases monocytes and cytokines post-exercise: implications for infection risk? Br J Nutr. 2013 Feb 14;109(3):478-86. doi: 10.1017/S0007114512001407. Epub 2012 May 10.</citation>
    <PMID>22575076</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pizarro C S, Ronco M AM, Gotteland R M. ß-glucans: what types are there and what are their health benefits? Chilean nutrition magazine. 2014; 41: 439-46.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Talbott SM, Talbott JA, Talbott TL, Dingler E. β-Glucan supplementation, allergy symptoms, and quality of life in self-described ragweed allergy sufferers. Food Sci Nutr. 2013 Jan;1(1):90-101. doi: 10.1002/fsn3.11. Epub 2014 Jan 8.</citation>
    <PMID>24804018</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kirmaz C, Bayrak P, Yilmaz O, Yuksel H. Effects of glucan treatment on the Th1/Th2 balance in patients with allergic rhinitis: a double-blind placebo-controlled study. Eur Cytokine Netw. 2005 Jun;16(2):128-34.</citation>
    <PMID>15941684</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Espinoza-Gallardo D, Contreras-Porcia L, Ehrenfeld N. ß-glucans, their production and properties in microalgae with emphasis on the genus Nannochloropsis (Ochrophyta, Eustigmatales). Journal of Marine Biology and Oceanography. 2017; 52 (1): 33-49.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>San Mauro-Martín I, Garicano Vilar E. Role of vitamin C and β-glucans on the immune system: review. Spanish Journal of Human Nutrition and Dietetics. 2015; 19 (4): 238.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lazaridou A, Biliaderis CG. Molecular aspects of cereal β-glucan functionality: Physical properties, technological applications and physiological effects. J Cereal Sci. 2007;46(2):101-18.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vásquez-Piñeros MA, Rondón-Barragan IS, Eslava-Mocha PR. Immunostimulants in teleost fish: probiotics, B-glucans and lipopolysaccharides. Orinoquia. 2012;16(1):46-62.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brennan CS CL. The potential use of cereal (1→3,1→4)-β-d-glucans as functional food ingredients. J Cereal Sci. 2005;42(1):1-13.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>B-glucan</keyword>
  <keyword>Saccharomyces cerevisiae</keyword>
  <keyword>Antioxidant</keyword>
  <keyword>Inmunomodulador</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

