<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05095818</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00209380</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05095818</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Nursing Involvement on Implementation of HIV Prevention Services</brief_title>
  <acronym>PrEP-RN</acronym>
  <official_title>Impact of Nursing Involvement on Implementation of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) Prevention Services in an Academic Obstetric/Gynecologic (OB/GYN) Clinical Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Gilead Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Women comprise 20% of new Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) diagnoses in the United States&#xD;
      (U.S.) with 86% attributed to heterosexual contact. HIV pre-exposure prophylaxis (PrEP)&#xD;
      uptake among cisgender women (women who are assigned female at birth and identify as women)&#xD;
      is low.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized controlled trial (RCT) will assess the feasibility and effectiveness of a&#xD;
      registered nurse (RN)-led PrEP project in Obstetrics and Gynecology (OB/GYN) clinics. The&#xD;
      PrEP-RN will counsel patients about their risks for HIV acquisition via telemedicine. Under&#xD;
      protocol guidance, the PrEP-RN will order laboratory tests and initiate PrEP for at-risk&#xD;
      women. A total of 440 at-risk cisgender women will be randomized 1:1 to the standard of care&#xD;
      with electronic medical record (EMR) enhancements (e-SOC) or e-SOC with the PrEP-RN.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This project will be launched in three OB/GYN outpatient clinics of a single academic medical&#xD;
      system in Baltimore, Maryland. Baltimore City is one of the 57 jurisdictions targeted in the&#xD;
      federal government's Ending the HIV Epidemic (EHE) Initiative.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test the investigators' hypothesis that an RN can effectively counsel about PrEP, initiate&#xD;
      therapy, and follow patients with minimal practitioner involvement, the investigators plan to&#xD;
      conduct a randomized controlled trial with two arms. The control arm will include an enhanced&#xD;
      standard of care (e-SOC), which is standard of care plus electronic medical record (EMR)&#xD;
      changes. These EMR changes will include best practice alerts (BPAs) that encourage nurses and&#xD;
      practitioners to add HIV risk-related codes to patients' problem lists, as well as order sets&#xD;
      and note templates to facilitate PrEP initiation. The intervention arm will include the&#xD;
      PrEP-RN plus e-SOC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients randomized to the intervention arm will first be contacted via an electronic patient&#xD;
      portal integrated with the EMR. While most of the investigators' patients utilize this&#xD;
      patient portal, if a patient does not have access, this step will be skipped. Follow-up&#xD;
      telephone calls will then be made to counsel patients on HIV risk factors in general, the&#xD;
      patient's HIV risk factors in particular, and prevention methods, inclusive of PrEP. PrEP,&#xD;
      including same-day PrEP, will be offered. If a patient declines PrEP, no additional attempts&#xD;
      will be made by the PrEP-RN to counsel the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a patient decides to initiate PrEP, the PrEP-RN will place and order the required&#xD;
      laboratory tests. The PrEP-RN will utilize the PrEP order set in the EMR to order labs,&#xD;
      prescribe medication electronically to the patient's pharmacy, provide patient education, and&#xD;
      schedule follow-up appointments. All orders and prescriptions will be sent to the clinic's&#xD;
      Medical Director for authorization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Manual of Procedures was created for the PrEP-RN to carry out each step of PrEP initiation&#xD;
      and follow-up. The manual outlines how to respond to abnormal tests, provide prescription&#xD;
      coverage assistance, and coordinate care with other specialties as needed to address test&#xD;
      results. The PrEP-RN will be responsible for follow-up visits and will contact the patients&#xD;
      one-two weeks after medication initiation. At this time, the PrEP-RN will review the&#xD;
      importance of daily adherence to PrEP and assess for any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If successful, our PrEP intervention could be implemented in other settings and largely&#xD;
      improve current strategies for increasing PrEP utilization among at-risk cisgender women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Awareness of PrEP as assessed by percentage of at-risk women who receive HIV risk prevention counseling</measure>
    <time_frame>During the study interval, up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>Awareness of PrEP will be assessed by the percentage of at-risk women with EMR documentation of HIV risk prevention counseling.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of women at risk for HIV who initiate PrEP</measure>
    <time_frame>During the study interval, up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the number of PrEP laboratory tests and the number of PrEP prescriptions ordered.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">440</enrollment>
  <condition>Pre-Exposure Prophylaxis (PrEP)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care with EMR Enhancements</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will receive Standard of Care with EMR Enhancements.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care with EMR Enhancements and PrEP-RN</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will receive Standard of Care with EMR Enhancements and PrEP-RN.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PrEP-RN</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients randomized to the intervention arm will be counseled on HIV risk factors in general, their HIV risk factors in particular, and prevention methods, inclusive of PrEP (Emtricitabine 200 mg/Tenofovir disoproxil fumarate 300 mg).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care with EMR Enhancements and PrEP-RN</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not living with HIV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  weight &gt;35 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  receiving OB/GYN care in our preselected clinics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GYN patients: positive sexually transmitted infection (STI) diagnosis within past 6&#xD;
             months, or if seeking STI testing and a have a history of an STI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  OB patients: at least one positive answer to the following risk screen: inject illicit&#xD;
             drugs; sex with a partner who injects illicit drugs; any past STIs; sex with a partner&#xD;
             who has sex with both men and women; sex for money, drugs, other payment; sex with a&#xD;
             partner currently infected with HIV; sex with more than one partner&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  symptoms or clinical signs consistent with acute HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unknown HIV infection status&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergies to the active substances or any excipients of PrEP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  estimated creatinine clearance of &lt;60 mL/minute&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  active Hepatitis B infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  participating in other clinical studies related to HIV and/or antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Assigned female at birth</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jenell Coleman, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Erin Gingher, MS, MHS, RN</last_name>
    <phone>410-614-0364</phone>
    <email>eloew1@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Outpatient Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erin Gingher, MS, MHS, RN</last_name>
      <phone>410-614-0364</phone>
      <email>eloew1@jhmi.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jenell Coleman, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

