<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05098548</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PARIPWCLTI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05098548</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pedal Arch Revascularization in Patients With Chronic Limb Threatening Ischemia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of Pedal Arch Patency on Outcomes of Endovascular Revascularization Procedures in Patients With Chronic Limb Threatening Ischemia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic limb threatening ischemia (CLTI) is a major cause of morbidity and mortality&#xD;
      worldwide and is characterized by multilevel disease, often involving the tibiopedal vessels&#xD;
      . CLTI is an undesirable clinical consequence of peripheral arterial disease (PAD) . It&#xD;
      affected ∼8 million people in the USA and affects 12-20% of American people aged more than 65&#xD;
      years. Within 1 year of diagnosis, 25% of those patients progress to a major amputation and&#xD;
      the other 25% die due to co-morbid conditions&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Revascularization is the cornerstone of Chronic limb threatening ischemia (CLTI) treatment&#xD;
      for lower limb preservation . Endovascular revascularization is the favored approach in many&#xD;
      centers because of its lower morbidity and mortality than open surgery . In a subset of&#xD;
      patients with Chronic limb threatening ischemia, particularly in longstanding type 1 diabetic&#xD;
      patients, a predominance of disease involving the pedal vessels can exist with relative&#xD;
      sparing of the tibial vessels .The pedal arch describes the connection between the anterior&#xD;
      and posterior circulation in the foot, this typically runs from the lateral plantar artery&#xD;
      into the dorsalis pedis and represents the final arcade of outflow for the lower extremity&#xD;
      vasculature . Secondary or &quot;deep&quot; pedal plantar loops connecting the medial and lateral&#xD;
      tarsal arteries to the medial and lateral plantar arteries can also exist . A strong&#xD;
      understanding of the pedal arch anatomy and its multiple connections is important for the&#xD;
      physician performing not only pedal arch interventions, but tibial interventions as well .&#xD;
      Familiarity with the arch anatomy increases procedural success rates in tibial intervention,&#xD;
      as it gives the operator another collateral pathway to approach the target occlusion in a&#xD;
      retrograde fashion . An intact pedal arch has been associated with improved wound healing, as&#xD;
      well as a higher patency rate for bypass grafting and percutaneous interventions for inflow&#xD;
      disease . An Angio some-directed revascularization strategy, however, has clearly been shown&#xD;
      to improve wound healing and limb salvage rates in both surgical and endovascular series .&#xD;
      Pedal arch intervention should therefore be considered in patients with advanced tissue loss,&#xD;
      with a goal of restoring inline flow to the corresponding angiosomes, this could mean the&#xD;
      difference between a major and minor amputation, as the options for these patients are&#xD;
      limited and major amputation rates are high .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary Patency</measure>
    <time_frame>From December 2021 to April 2022</time_frame>
    <description>which means maintaining vessel patency without restenosis or need for re-intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Critical Ischemia of Foot</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>patients with Chronic limb threatening ischemia</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients with Chronic limb threatening ischemia present with one or more of the following:&#xD;
Rest pain (Rutherford category 4)&#xD;
Minor tissue loss (Rutherford category 5) admitted to the department of Vascular surgery for Endovascular Intervention with provided written informed consent.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>angioplasty</intervention_name>
    <description>using a balloon to stretch open a narrowed or blocked artery. However, most modern angioplasty procedures also involve inserting a short wire-mesh tube, called a stent, into the artery during the procedure. The stent is left in place permanently to allow blood to flow more freely .</description>
    <arm_group_label>patients with Chronic limb threatening ischemia</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The calculation was done using confidence interval 98 % giving a total sample size 28.&#xD;
        According to the equation for sample size for prospective study design, prevalence of&#xD;
        chronic limb threatening ischemia was 1.3 % of total population attending the Vascular&#xD;
        Surgery Department [2]. Raising the sample size will be done up to 35 to compensate for&#xD;
        dropout and refusal.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All patients with Chronic limb threatening ischemia present with one or more of the&#xD;
        following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Rest pain (Rutherford category 4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Minor tissue loss (Rutherford category 5) admitted to the department of Vascular&#xD;
             surgery for Endovascular Intervention with provided written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        i. Patients presented with proved vasculitis. ii. Patients who are not fit for angioplasty&#xD;
        as: v. Patients with Chronic liver disease if there is prolonged PT. vi. Patients with&#xD;
        Heart failure if the patient is orthopneic and cannot lay on table for long time). vii.&#xD;
        Patients with impaired renal function.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ahmed Moustafa Farouk</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

