<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05099731</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pilotstudy0818</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05099731</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Diagnostic Accuracy of Matrix Metalloproteinase-8 Test for the Discrimination of Periodontal Health and Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Diagnostic Accuracy of aMMP-8 Point-of-care Test for the Discrimination of Periodontal Health and Disease Using Different Sampling Approaches: a Pilot Study Comparing Saliva and Oral Rinse</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shanghai Ninth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shanghai Ninth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The application of point-of-care test with oral fluid-based biomarkers assisting in&#xD;
      early-detection of gum disease is highly needed. Recently, a commercially available active&#xD;
      Matrix metalloproteinase-8 (aMMP-8) point-of-care test (POCT) for detecting the risk of gum&#xD;
      disease has been developed. Currently, there is a paucity of research to assess the&#xD;
      performance of aMMP-8 POCT using different oral fluid sampling methods. This study will&#xD;
      evaluate the accuracy of aMMP-8 POCT for discriminating periodontal health from disease in&#xD;
      saliva and oral rinse.The information obtained from this study may help us understand better&#xD;
      which sample is superior for the early detection of gum disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The detection of the risk for periodontitis, one of the major global burdens of disease,&#xD;
      prior to noticeable signs and symptoms is of great importance especially in non-dental&#xD;
      settings. Oral fluids, including gingival crevicular fluid (GCF), saliva and oral rinse, have&#xD;
      received considerable critical attention in the field of periodontal diagnostics for their&#xD;
      non-invasive features and rich sources of biomarkers associated with the biological process&#xD;
      in periodontal tissues. Saliva and oral rinse are preferred for screening purposes in a&#xD;
      chair-side test, while GCF provides more site-specific information and has higher technical&#xD;
      requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) are a family of key host proteinases that regulate&#xD;
      cell-matrix composition and MMP-8 is the main type of collagenases of MMP family responsible&#xD;
      for collagen degradation of the periodontal supporting tissues. A growing body of evidence&#xD;
      have indicated that elevated MMP-8, especially active form of MMP-8 (aMMP-8), has been&#xD;
      detected in oral fluids of periodontitis (Kc et al., 2020). Currently, a commercially&#xD;
      available aMMP-8 point-of-care test (POCT) has been developed (U.S. Patent No. 10,488,415,&#xD;
      2019). A recent study has assessed the diagnostic utility of this aMMP-8 POCT using oral&#xD;
      rinse samples and showed moderate accuracy for detecting periodontitis (Deng et al., 2021).&#xD;
      So far, however, there is a paucity of research to assess the performance of aMMP-8 POCT&#xD;
      using different oral fluid sampling methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study aims: i)to compare the diagnostic accuracy of aMMP-8 POCT for the discrimination of&#xD;
      periodontal health and disease(s) in oral rinse and saliva; ii) to compare the diagnostic&#xD;
      accuracy of aMMP-8 POCT for the discrimination of periodontal health and disease(s) in oral&#xD;
      rinse during the first sampling and re-sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a cross-sectional diagnostic study.The whole study procedures will comprise the&#xD;
      collection of different oral fluid samples, the conduction of aMMP-8 POCT using these samples&#xD;
      (index test), followed by a routine full-mouth periodontal examination (reference standard).&#xD;
      The details of the sequential study events include: 1) collection of unstimulated whole&#xD;
      saliva sample by spitting method; 2) the first-time sampling of oral rinse (pure oral rinse);&#xD;
      3) re-sampling of oral rinse; 4) conduction of aMMP-8 point-of-care test using saliva and&#xD;
      oral rinse samples collected at different times; and 5) routing full-mouth periodontal&#xD;
      examinations to establish clinical case diagnosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUROC) measure</measure>
    <time_frame>1day</time_frame>
    <description>Comparing the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUROC) of aMMP-8 in different samples to correctly identify periodontitis cases at the time of completion of clinical examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Diagnostic Self Evaluation</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Consenting untreated patients seeking care at the Periodontology clinic and Implant&#xD;
        Dentistry clinic of Shanghai Ninth People's Hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability and willingness to give written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Edentulous mouth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having received professional periodontal treatment (other than supragingival cleaning)&#xD;
             within the previous 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having received antibiotic medication within the previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of xerostomia interfering with saliva sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability or unwillingness of individual to give written informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ke Deng, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+8618811780779</phone>
    <email>u3005015@connect.hku.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Implantology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <zip>200000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ke Deng, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+8618811780779</phone>
      <email>u3005015@connect.hku.hk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Shanghai Ninth People's Hospital Affiliated to Shanghai Jiao Tong University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Maurizio Tonetti</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

