<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05090579</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Q123</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05090579</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison Between Two Different Doses of Nulbuphine _bupivacaine in TAP Block in Cancer Abdominal Surgeries</brief_title>
  <official_title>Nalgesic Effect of Nulbuphine-bupivacaine Combination in Ultrasound Guided Transversus Abdominis Plane Block in Patients Undergoing Major Abdominal Cancer Surgeries .</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To compare the analgesic effect of two different doses of nulbuphine (10 mg and 20 mg) added&#xD;
      to bupivacaine in bilateral subcostal single injection in ultrasound-guided TAP block for&#xD;
      abdominal surgeries.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The ultrasound-guided TAP block will be performed before the induction of general anesthesia.&#xD;
      Upon arrival at the operating room, the patients will be place in the supine position and an&#xD;
      18-gauge intravenous (IV) cannula will be inserted for IV fluid and drug administration.&#xD;
      Basic monitoring probes (electrocardiography, non-invasive blood pressure, oxygen saturation,&#xD;
      and temperature) will be applied, and their baseline vital signs will be recorded. Lactated&#xD;
      Ringer's solution 10mL/ kg will be infused intravenously over 10 minutes before the&#xD;
      initiation of the TAP block.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The TAP block will be performed with the use of ultrasound, under complete aseptic technique.&#xD;
      A broadband linear array probe will be used with an imaging depth of 4 - 6 cm. The ultrasound&#xD;
      probe will be placed transversely to the abdomen (horizontal plane) in the midaxillary line&#xD;
      between the costal margin and the iliac crest. Three muscle layers are clearly seen in the&#xD;
      image. The needle (22-gauge x 80 mm SonoPlex stim cannula, Pajunk®, Geisingen, Germany) will&#xD;
      be inserted in a sagittal plane approximately 3 - 4 cm medial to the ultrasound probe. The&#xD;
      point of needle insertion will be closer to the probe. For optimal imaging of the needle, it&#xD;
      will be held parallel to the long axis of the probe (in-line view). The needle tip will be&#xD;
      directed into the plane below the internal oblique and above the transversus abdominis&#xD;
      muscle. A small volume of local anesthetic (2 mL) was seen to open the plane between the 2&#xD;
      muscles and was followed by insertion of the full dose of local anesthetic. If the 2 mL dose&#xD;
      appears to be within the muscle rather than between them, then needle adjustment will be&#xD;
      required. The local anesthetic injected appeared hypoechoic (black compared to the muscle&#xD;
      layers) on ultrasound image.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The TAP block will be performed with the use of ultrasound under complete aseptic technique.&#xD;
      A broadband linear array probe will be used with an imaging depth of 4 - 6 cm using a&#xD;
      22-gauge × 80 mm SonoPlex stim cannula (Pajunk®, Geisingen, Germany). Twenty minutes after&#xD;
      the TAP block, the extent of sensory blockade will be evaluated by using the pin prick test&#xD;
      (0 = no block, 1 = hyposthesia, and 2 = anesthesia) by another blinded attending anesthetist.&#xD;
      Any patients with a failed block will be excluded from the studied groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anesthetic Technique:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The anesthetic technique will be standardized in the 3 groups. No preoperative analgesics&#xD;
      will be given. After a successful TAP block, ?? general anesthesia will be induced&#xD;
      intravenously (propofol 1 - 2 mg/kg, lidocaine 1.5 mg/ kg) and fentanyl 1 μg/kg. Endotracheal&#xD;
      intubation will be facilitated by neuromuscular blockade with cisatracurium 0.3 mg/kg.&#xD;
      Anesthesia and muscle relaxation will be maintained with isoflurane in an air/oxygen mixture&#xD;
      and cisatracurium 0.15 mg/kg. The patients will be mechanically ventilated in parameters that&#xD;
      maintain the end-tidal CO2 (ETCO2) between 33 and 36 mmHg. The patients' heart rate, oxygen&#xD;
      saturation, ETCO2, and systolic and diastolic blood pressures will be measured and recorded.&#xD;
      Hypotension will be defined as a 15% decrease in systolic blood pressure from the base line,&#xD;
      bradycardia as a heart rate slower than 50 beats per minute, and hypoxia as an oxygen&#xD;
      saturation less than 90%. Hypotension will be treated with intravenous boluses of ephedrine&#xD;
      0.1 mg/kg, repeated as required. Bradycardia will be treated with intravenous atropine 0.01&#xD;
      mg/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of surgery, muscle relaxation will be reversed by neostigmine 50 μg/kg and&#xD;
      atropine 10 μg/ kg. The patients will be extubated and transferred to the post-anesthesia&#xD;
      care unit (PACU), where they will be monitored for vital signs (heart rate, non-invasive&#xD;
      blood pressure, respiratory rate, and O2 saturation) immediately postoperatively and at 2, 4,&#xD;
      6, 12, 18, and 24 hours postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The severity of pain and the presence of nausea, vomiting, and respiratory depression will be&#xD;
      assessed postoperatively at 0, 2, 4, 6, 12, 18 and 24 hours. The severity of pain will be&#xD;
      assessed using a 10 cm VAS at rest and coughing (0 = no pain and 10 = worst imaginable pain).&#xD;
      Repiratory function : FVC, FEV and FEV1 /FVC ratio will be recorded postoperatively and&#xD;
      6,12,&amp;24 hr. Postoperatively. If a patient's VAS score was ≥ 3, morphine will be administered&#xD;
      intravenously by a dose of 0.05 mg/kg at 15minute intervals until complete pain relief will&#xD;
      be achieved. Morphine administration will be ceased when the VAS score at rest and coughing&#xD;
      was &lt; 3 on assessment or when over-sedation or respiratory depression will occur (a&#xD;
      respiratory rate of &lt; 10 bpm). Rescue antiemetic will be given in the form of&#xD;
      ???metoclopramide 10 mg (Zofran 4mg) IV when patients complained of nausea or vomiting.????&#xD;
      (Our primary outcome measure will be total morphine consumption in the first 24 hours&#xD;
      postoperatively; our secondary outcome measures will be the postoperative VAS scores, the&#xD;
      time of the first request of rescue analgesia (calculated from the time of the TAP block&#xD;
      application), spirometry lung function testing and the incidence of postoperative side&#xD;
      effects)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>time of request of first analgesia</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: 24 hours post-operatively ]</time_frame>
    <description>VAS (Visual Analogue Scale, 0-100 mm; where 0 = no pain, and 100 = worst imaginable pain) will be assessed, at rest, per hour for 24 hours post operatively. Moreover, VAS will also be assessed at 12 and 24 hours post-operatively while abducting the ipsilateral arm. If the patient experiences a pain of &gt; 3, IV morphine will be given at a dose of 2.5-5 mg per dose, with a maximum dose of 10 mg, aiming for a pain score of ≤ 3. Time which will pass until the request of first analgesia shall be determined for each group and compared.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>total morphine consumption in the first 24 hours postoperatively</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: 24 hours post-operatively ]</time_frame>
    <description>If a patient's VAS score was ≥ 3, morphine will be administered intravenously by a dose of 0.05 mg/kg at 15 minute intervals until complete pain relief will be achieved. Morphine administration will be ceased when the VAS score at rest and coughing was &lt; 3 on assessment or when over-sedation or respiratory depression will occur (a respiratory rate of &lt; 10 bpm). Rescue antiemetic will be given in the form of ondasteron 4 mg IV when patients complained of nausea or vomiting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain, Postoperative</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group I (BN10)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive an ultrasound-guided TAP block with 20 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine , 1 mL of 10 mg of nulbuphine plus 4 mL of normal saline to reach 25 mL as total volume on each side of the abdominal wall.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group II (BN20)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive an ultrasound-guided TAP block with 20 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine ,2 mL of 20 mg of nulbuphine plus 3 mL of normal saline to reach 25 mL as total volume on each side of the abdominal wall.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group lll(B)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients will receive 20 mL of 0.25%bupivacaine plus 5 mL of normal saline to reach 25 mL as total volume on each side of the abdominal wall.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Group I (BN10)</intervention_name>
    <description>patients will receive an ultrasound-guided TAP block with 20 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine, 1 mL of 10 mg of nalbuphine plus 4 mL of normal saline to reach 25 mL as total volume on each side of the abdominal wall</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group I (BN10)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Active Comparator:Group ll (BN20)</intervention_name>
    <description>patients will receive an ultrasound-guided TAP block with 20 mL of 0.25% bupivacaine, 2 mL of 20 mg of nalbuphine plus 3 mL of normal saline to reach 25 mL as total volume on each side of the abdominal wall</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group II (BN20)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Active Comparator:Group lll (B)</intervention_name>
    <description>patients will receive 20 mL of 0.25%bupivacaine plus 5 mL of normal saline to reach 25 mL as total volume on each side of the abdominal wall</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group lll(B)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:-&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA classification I-ll,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged &gt;18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  weight 50-85 kg,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who will undergo abdominal cancer surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:-&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's refusal,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with a history of allergies to studied drugs,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with coagulation disorders,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with opioid dependence,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with morbid obesity (body mass index more than 40 kg/m2),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with sepsis,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with psychiatric illnesses that will interfere with the perception and&#xD;
             assessment of pain .&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rania M. Abdel -Emam</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>South Egypt cancer Institute, Assuit university hospitals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shreen M. Muhammed, A.professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>South Egypt cancer Institute, Assuit university hospitals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eman A. Ismail</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University hospitals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amira M Othman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>01098784161</phone>
    <phone_ext>+2</phone_ext>
    <email>Amiramothman8@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Eman A Ismail, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>01060223755</phone>
    <phone_ext>+1</phone_ext>
    <email>Emanismail97@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Amira Muhammed Othman</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amira Muhammed Othman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

