<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05093010</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S65541</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05093010</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Relationship Between Body Surface Gastric Mapping and Gastric Emptying Rate</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Relationship Between Body Surface Gastric Mapping (BSGM) and Gastric Emptying Rate</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Currently, a new generation of high-resolution electrogastrograms recording technology with&#xD;
      64-channel electrode array is being developed by Alimetry Limited. This BSGM provide a more&#xD;
      complete understanding of the origin and propagation of human gastric slow-wave activity&#xD;
      non-invasively, such as frequency, amplitude, velocity, and pattern, in high spatiotemporal&#xD;
      detail. The system is also capable of providing a novel meal response metric, which might&#xD;
      correlate with the gastric emptying time. The system includes an App for tracking&#xD;
      patient-reported symptoms throughout the test.The aim of the present study is to assess and&#xD;
      compare BSGM and breath-based gastric emptying parameters and to study the relation between&#xD;
      BSGM and presence or severity of individual symptoms and clinical features.The investigators&#xD;
      will perform a study in 100 subjects to record gastric bioelectrical activity by non-invasive&#xD;
      multi-channel body-surface electrode arrays during gastric emptying breathing test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Validation of body surface gastric mapping for delayed gastric emptying</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes before the meal and 4 hours after having meal.</time_frame>
    <description>The correlation of electrogastrography abnormality (in percentage) and delayed gastric emptying (t 1/2, minutes) will be determined employing a regression method.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess correlation between electrogastrography abnormality and upper gastrointestinal symptoms.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes before the meal and 4 hours after having meal.</time_frame>
    <description>Visual analogue scale (VAS) score for gastrointestinal symptoms, including pain, nausea, vomiting, bloating and flatulence will be recoded during recording gastric electrophysiological activity. The correlation of electrogastrography abnormality (in percentage) and upper gastrointestinal symptoms severity will be determined employing a regression method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Motility Disorder</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects who will receive gastric emptying breath test&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged &gt;18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients planned GEBT;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative PCR on nasopharyngeal swab 24 or 48 hours prior to the test;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of skin allergies or a history of extreme sensitivity to cosmetics or lotions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fragile skin vulnerable to skin tears.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Damaged epigastric skin (open wounds, rash, inflammation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to remain in a relaxed reclined position for the test duration&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Carson DA, O'Grady G, Du P, Gharibans AA, Andrews CN. Body surface mapping of the stomach: New directions for clinically evaluating gastric electrical activity. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2021 Mar;33(3):e14048. doi: 10.1111/nmo.14048. Epub 2020 Dec 4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33274564</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

