<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05098795</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14920</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05098795</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>FOREward Together: Training Peer Recovery Coaches to Promote Retention and Adherence to MOUD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Training Peer Recovery Coaches to Promote Retention and Adherence to Medications for Opioid Use Disorder Among Low-Income Adults</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Henry Ford Health System</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Maryland, College Park</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Henry Ford Health System</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This project aims to implement a peer-led intervention to support retention and adherence to&#xD;
      medications for opioid use disorder among low-income adults in Detroit, as well as a training&#xD;
      manual for peer recovery coaches serving similar populations. The approach will serve as a&#xD;
      guide to coaches in providing positive reinforcement and helping those in treatment to&#xD;
      schedule and engage in valued activities. Researchers will examine the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      intervention, supervision and training models, and share results with policymakers and&#xD;
      treatment programs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Low-income and racial/ethnic minorities suffer disproportionately from the opioid use&#xD;
      disorder (OUD) crisis, evidencing consistently lower rates of critical treatment outcomes,&#xD;
      including medication for OUD (MOUD) engagement and retention. While these individuals&#xD;
      exhibited a need for evidence-based care prior to the pandemic, low-income, racial/ethnic&#xD;
      minority populations have been disproportionately affected by COVID-19, as have persons with&#xD;
      SUDs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peer Recovery Coaches (PRC) are individuals with lived-experiences with substance use who&#xD;
      have been certified by the state to assist in treatment recovery. Because of similarities&#xD;
      between PRCs and substance use clients, PRCs can overcome many of the barriers that clients&#xD;
      face to engaging and staying in MOUD treatment, such as stigma. goal of the current project&#xD;
      is to conduct an open-label pilot trial to examine the feasibility, acceptability and&#xD;
      accessibility of a PRC-led intervention to support retention in MOUD care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project proposes to develop a novel and sustainable model for improving retention in&#xD;
      MOUD treatment by training PRCs to deliver an evidence-based intervention (EBI), Behavioral&#xD;
      Activation (BA). BA seeks to increase the positive reinforcement patients experience from&#xD;
      their natural environment by promoting prosocial and valued experiences. BA has been found to&#xD;
      improve substance use treatment retention and adherence, as well as medication adherence in&#xD;
      low-income individuals with HIV/AIDS. To that end, we propose the following goal: to evaluate&#xD;
      the preliminary feasibility, acceptability, and effectiveness of the PRC- delivered BA&#xD;
      approach. We will conduct an open-label clinical trial (n=40) of the adapted PRC-delivered BA&#xD;
      intervention and training protocol in a representative agency in Detroit, MI serving a&#xD;
      low-income, predominantly African-American population. Findings from this phase of the&#xD;
      project will be used to re-adapt the manual and training procedures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MOUD Retention Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured daily through study completion; up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The number of days (frequency) a participant visits the clinic for MOUD as indicated by daily clinic records.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Feasibility: percentage of patients who agree to participate in the intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at study completion; up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility, defined as the suitability and practicability of the approach, will be measured quantitatively as the percentage of patients who agree to participate in the intervention. We will also collect qualitative feedback relating to feasibility.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Acceptability: percentage of patients enrolled who attend ≥75% sessions</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at study completion; up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability, defined as satisfaction with or tolerability of the proposed approach, will be measured quantitatively by session attendance. Specifically, we will measure the % of patients enrolled who attend ≥75% sessions. We will also collect qualitative feedback relating to acceptability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Fidelity: percentage of intervention components delivered as intended</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured through study completion; up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fidelity, defined as the delivery of the intervention as intended, will be measured based on PRC adherence to the intervention delivery. A random selection of 20% of sessions will be rated for fidelity, and we will assess the percentage of intervention components delivered as intended.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Opioid Use</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Peer-delivered Behavioral Activation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adults 18 years or older on MOUD or referred to MOUD will receive Behavioral Activation (BA) an evidence-based intervention (EBI) by trained Peer Recovery Coaches (PRC)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Behavioral Activation (BA)</intervention_name>
    <description>BA seeks to increase the positive reinforcement patients experience from their natural environment by promoting prosocial and valued experiences. BA has been found to improve substance use treatment retention and adherence, as well as medication adherence in low-income individuals with HIV/AIDS.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Peer-delivered Behavioral Activation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must (1) be receiving or referred to MOUD; and (2) be over the age of 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusion criteria will be (1) demonstrating active, unstable or untreated psychiatric&#xD;
             symptoms, including mania and/or psychosis; or (2) inability to understand the study&#xD;
             and give informed consent in English Active, Unstable or Untreated Psychiatric&#xD;
             Symptoms: The study team is committed to recruiting a sample that reflects the&#xD;
             complexity and likely comorbidity of people with moderate to severe OUD in this&#xD;
             setting. Therefore, we will only exclude people whose concurrent mental health issues&#xD;
             preclude ability to participate with the procedures in this study. Throughout the&#xD;
             study, researchers will monitor for active, unstable or untreated psychiatric symptoms&#xD;
             as the presence of these symptoms during study procedures would interfere with&#xD;
             participation. Monitoring for exclusionary psychiatric symptoms can include reviewing&#xD;
             data in medical chart (per protocol-approved access to medical records), observation&#xD;
             during assessments and intervention sessions, and/or current symptoms detected on the&#xD;
             MINI modules for psychosis and mania.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inability to complete informed consent/ study in English. This study/intervention will be&#xD;
        implemented in English only. Therefore, the capacity and willingness to give written&#xD;
        informed consent in English, to understand the study and inclusion and exclusion criteria&#xD;
        in English.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Julia Felton, PhD.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Henry Ford Health System</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Morgan Anvari</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 752-7713</phone>
    <email>manvari@umd.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Henry Ford Health System</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Julia Felton</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Medications for opioid use disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Peer recovery coach</keyword>
  <keyword>Substance use</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavioral activation</keyword>
  <keyword>Task sharing</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment retention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>After all primary analyses are complete, de-identified data will be available per request of outside individual</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

