<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05092269</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR109074</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-004457-76</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CNTO1275ISD3001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05092269</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Long-term Extension Study of Ustekinumab in Pediatric Participants</brief_title>
  <acronym>UNITED</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 3, Multicenter, Open-label, Basket, Long-term Extension Study of Ustekinumab in Pediatric Clinical Study Participants (2 to &lt;18 Years of Age)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to collect long-term safety data of subcutaneous (SC)&#xD;
      ustekinumab&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 29, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/ biological agent under study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>A SAE is an AE resulting in any of the following outcomes or deemed significant for any other reason: death; initial or prolonged inpatient hospitalization; life-threatening experience (immediate risk of dying); persistent or significant disability/incapacity; congenital anomaly.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs Leading to Discontinuation of Study Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AEs leading to discontinuation of study intervention will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs of Interest</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AEs of special interest (any newly identified malignancy case of active tuberculosis [TB], or opportunistic infection occurring after the first administration of study intervention[s]) will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Abnormalities in Clinical Laboratory Parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with abnormalities in clinical laboratory parameters (such as hematology and serum chemistry) will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Injection-site Reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with injection-site reactions will be reported. An injection-site reaction is any adverse reaction at a subcutaneous (SC) study intervention injection-site.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With AEs of Worsening of the Disease</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AEs of worsening of the disease will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Concomitant Therapy due to Loss of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 years and 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with concomitant therapy due to loss of response will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">151</enrollment>
  <condition>Crohn Disease</condition>
  <condition>Colitis, Ulcerative</condition>
  <condition>Arthritis, Psoriatic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will have continued access to ustekinumab for primary study (CNTO1275CRD1001, CNTO1275PUC3001, CNTO1275CRD3004, CNTO1275JPA3001) participants who in the opinion of the investigator will continue to benefit from ustekinumab therapy. All blinded participants who enroll in the long-term extension (LTE) from blinded primary studies with both every 8 weeks (q8w) and every 12 weeks (q12w) dosing groups just prior to the end of the primary study will be assigned to the q8w dosing regimen. Participants enrolling in the LTE from an unblinded primary study will remain on the final dosing regimen that they were receiving in the primary study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ustekinumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Ustekinumab will be administered as a SC injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ustekinumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>STELARA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have completed the dosing planned in the primary pediatric ustekinumab study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Benefit of continued ustekinumab therapy (that is, a clinical response or clinical&#xD;
             remission as defined in the primary study at the final efficacy visit of the primary&#xD;
             study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent(s) (preferably both if available or as per local requirements), legal&#xD;
             guardian(s) or their legally acceptable representative must sign an informed consent&#xD;
             form (ICF) indicating that he or she understands the purpose of, and procedures&#xD;
             required for, the study and is willing to allow the child to participate in the study.&#xD;
             Assent is also required of children capable of understanding the nature of the study&#xD;
             (typically 7 years of age and older) as described in Informed Consent Process. An&#xD;
             adolescent who signs the assent form will be given the opportunity to sign an adult&#xD;
             ICF at a later visit when they reach the age of majority during the study to indicate&#xD;
             that he or she understands the purpose of, and procedures required for, the study and&#xD;
             is willing to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing and able to adhere to the lifestyle restrictions specified in this&#xD;
             protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test at&#xD;
             enrollment and prior to study intervention administration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are pregnant, nursing, or planning pregnancy or fathering a child&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have had any of (a) confirmed severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2&#xD;
             (SARS-CoV-2 [COVID-19]) infection (test positive), or (b) suspected SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
             infection (clinical features without documented test results), or (c) close contact&#xD;
             with a person with known or suspected SARS-CoV-2 infection: Exception: (i) may be&#xD;
             included with a documented negative result for a validated SARS-CoV-2 test: obtained&#xD;
             at least 2 weeks after conditions (a), (b), (c) above (timed from resolution of key&#xD;
             clinical features if present, example, fever, cough, dyspnea) and (ii) with absence of&#xD;
             all conditions (a), (b), (c) above during the period between the negative test result&#xD;
             and the baseline study visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taken any disallowed therapies as noted in the primary study, before the planned first&#xD;
             long-term extension (LTE) dose of study intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition for which, in the opinion of the investigator, participation would not&#xD;
             be in the best interest of the participant (example, compromise the well-being) or&#xD;
             that could prevent, limit, or confound the protocol-specified assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who receive a live vaccination may be permitted to remain in the study,&#xD;
             if approved by the sponsor and study intervention is held for a period of time&#xD;
             specified by the sponsor. Receipt of a live severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
             coronavirus 2 (SARS CoV-2) vaccine (against the virus that causes Coronavirus Disease&#xD;
             2019 [COVID-19]) is not automatically an exclusion criterion and must be discussed&#xD;
             with the medical monitor&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Center For Digestive Healthcare, Llc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30342</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Necker</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>WIP Warsaw IBD Point Profesor Kierkus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warszawa</city>
        <zip>00-728</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR109074</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis, Psoriatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ustekinumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

