<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05090748</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>USEG- 201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05090748</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study for the Assessment of the Quality of Echocardiographic Clips.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pivotal Study for the Assessment of the Quality of Echocardiographic Clips When Obtained by Novice Users While Using the UltraSight Echocardiography Guidance (USEG) Software.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UltraSight</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UltraSight</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study main objective is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of the USEG software.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigational product is comprised of a software that aids in automated guided&#xD;
      ultrasound image acquisition for novice users (medical professional without experience in&#xD;
      performing echocardiography, e.g., nurses, physicians assistants, medical doctors, medical&#xD;
      student etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The software provides real-time feedback during image acquisition to optimize image capture&#xD;
      and determine whether image quality is sufficient for medical evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The software is designed to be used with any echocardiographic ultrasound system. The Philips&#xD;
      Lumify hand-held ultrasound device will be used for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Images can be acquired manually by a novice user.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Each novice user will have a training course of 8 hours, before the study commences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This pivotal study is a multi-center, multi-reader multi-case (MRMC) study, primarily&#xD;
      designed to obtain the quality of the clips obtained by novice users when using the USEG&#xD;
      software.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible subject will undergo the examination twice on a single study visit (same day): once&#xD;
      by one of novice users when using the USEG software and once by one of the expert&#xD;
      sonographers without the aid of the software.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each novice user (approximately 4 per site, with minimum of 2 novice per site) will perform&#xD;
      the examination on at least 20 subjects (with the aim that the number of examinations by each&#xD;
      novice will be the same).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The assignment of the novice user and expert sonographer to subjects and their order within a&#xD;
      subject will be based upon their availability once the subject's is enrolled. In case of more&#xD;
      than 1 available novice, the exam will be assigned to the novice with the least exams&#xD;
      performed so far.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At least 20% subjects will be enrolled from each of the following three BMI groups= &lt; 25; =25&#xD;
      to &lt;30; =&gt; 30. The final number will be based on the final sample size.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the echo examination sufficiency.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year.</time_frame>
    <description>The expert cardiologists will evaluate whether the echo examination has sufficient to evaluate each of the primary endpoints:&#xD;
Sufficient quality to assess Left Ventricular (LV) size: (YES/NO)&#xD;
Sufficient quality to assess LV function: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Sufficient quality to assess Right Ventricular size: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Sufficient quality to assess presence of non-trivial pericardial effusion: (Yes/No) The null hypothesis for each of the 4 primary endpoints is that the proportion of cases with sufficient quality is ≤ 80% versus the alternative that it is &gt; 80%.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the echo examination quality.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year.</time_frame>
    <description>The expert cardiologists will evaluate whether the echo examination has sufficient quality to evaluate the following six (6) anatomic elements:&#xD;
Qualitative visual assessment of RV function: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Qualitative visual assessment of left atrium size: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Qualitative visual assessment of Aortic valve structure: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Qualitative visual assessment of Mitral valve structure: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Qualitative visual assessment of Tricuspid valve structure: (Yes/No)&#xD;
Qualitative visual assessment of IVC size: (Yes/No)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the echo examination diagnostic quality.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year.</time_frame>
    <description>The expert cardiologists will evaluate if each of the following 10 views can be considered of diagnostic quality:&#xD;
Apical 4 chamber&#xD;
Apical 2 chamber&#xD;
Apical 3 chamber&#xD;
Apical 5 chamber&#xD;
Para Sternal Long Axis&#xD;
Para Sternal short axis - Aortic Valve (AV)&#xD;
Para Sternal short axis - Mitral Valve (MV)&#xD;
Para Sternal short axis - Papillary Muscle (PM)&#xD;
Sub Costal - 4 chamber&#xD;
Sub Costal - Inferior Vena Cava (IVC)f In order to assess intra-cardiologist variability, a repeated assessment of the expert cardiologist analysis will be done in 10% of the exams.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety outcome.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year.</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">360</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac Disease</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Echocardiographic.</intervention_name>
    <description>Echocardiographic test.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Up to 360 male and female adults confirmed as eligible according to eligibility criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects willing and able to give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Emergency (non-elective) admission within 24 h prior to participating in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Female subjects who are pregnant (WOCBP* will perform a urine pregnancy test)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Unable to lie as required in all the classic positions for standard TTE exam: supine&#xD;
             on back / left decubitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects who currently participate a clinical trial, involving interventional cardiac&#xD;
             devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects who have prior Echo exam with description of Low/Poor quality exam in the&#xD;
             echo report&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with BMI above 40&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects experiencing a known or suspected acute cardiac event&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects with severe chest wall deformity as per previous medical records and physical&#xD;
             examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects who have undergone pneumonectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects whose anatomy does not lend itself to yield diagnosable echocardiography&#xD;
             clips (i.e. situs inversus with dextrocardia, single ventricle anatomy due to&#xD;
             congenital heart defect, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A woman is of childbearing potential if she is postmenarchal, has not reached a&#xD;
                  postmenopausal state (≥12 continuous months of amenorrhea with no identified&#xD;
                  cause other than menopause), and is not permanently infertile due to surgery&#xD;
                  (i.e., removal of ovaries, fallopian tubes, and/or uterus) or another cause as&#xD;
                  determined by the investigator (e.g., Müllerian agenesis.).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roberto Lang, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>U of Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Federico Asch, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medstar Health Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Praveen Mehrotra, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Thomas Jefferson University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bijoy Khandheria, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Aurora Saint Luke Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert Klampfner, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sheba Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Danny Spigelstein, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>UltraSight</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robert Klempfner, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(0)3-5302604</phone>
    <phone_ext>+972</phone_ext>
    <email>Robert.Klempfner@sheba.health.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

