<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05093569</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRT00014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05093569</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Investigation of K'Watch - Lab &amp; Home Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>GLAM</acronym>
  <official_title>Clinical Investigation of K'Watch - Lab &amp; Home Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pk vitality</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pk vitality</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study categorized as a non significant risk trial is a monocentric, prospective,&#xD;
      open-label comparative, paired-design trial aims to evaluate the performance and the&#xD;
      tolerance of K'Watch CGM system in comparison with conventional reference (YSI system, BGM&#xD;
      system and CGM systems ) . This trial will be conducted on patients with Type 1 and 2 of&#xD;
      diabetes for 8 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this prospective study is to establish the performance and the cutaneous&#xD;
      tolerance of the K'Watch device, for a Study Period of 8 hours (Lab-only study) to 8 days.&#xD;
      This prospective study is divided in two phases: a first Laboratory phase will evaluate for 8&#xD;
      hours the safety and performance of the device under test (DUT) in a clinical controlled&#xD;
      environment, then if no safety or critical performance issue occurred, the second phase will&#xD;
      aim to collect data over a longer time frame, with the subjects using the DUT at home, and to&#xD;
      get usability feedback for 7 additional consecutive days. This protocol is to evaluate a&#xD;
      series of design iterations to K'Watch CGM system and its use on various populations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients included will be followed for 28 days for safety requirements. 35 patients will&#xD;
      be included in this trial and distributed in 4 iterations. For each iteration, the device&#xD;
      tested will be improved according to the results obtained in the previous iteration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>to determine the accuracy of K'Watch Release 0.x CGM system glucose readings at day 1 as compared to standard references.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Primary endpoint in this trial is the degree of compliance with the accuracy section of the FDA Class II Integrated continuous glucose monitoring (iCGM) requirements after one entire day.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the investigational device compared to the standard reference CGM devices</measure>
    <time_frame>Between day1 and day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the investigational device compared to the standard reference CGM devices by measuring the median absolute relative difference (MARD)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number and duration of gaps in sensor data availability</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>This is intended to measure the time that the sensor was not able to measure glucose, even though the watch was connected. If the user removes the watch, then this time is not considered to be a &quot;gap&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of the K'Watch system, characterizing device-related Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Safety of the K'Watch system, characterizing device-related Adverse Events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of the K'Watch system characterizing device-related pain intensity (Visual Analogue Scale scores from 0-10) recorded during the study.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Safety of the K'Watch system characterizing device-related pain intensity (Visual Analogue Scale scores from 0-10) recorded during the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Iteration</arm_group_label>
    <description>35 patients will be included in 4 iterations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>K'watch</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>Iteration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with Type 1 and 2 of diabetes&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female or male,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject with Type 1 Diabetes, or subject with Type 2 Diabetes (depending on the study&#xD;
             iteration), - Type 1 Diabetes subjects taking insulin need to be on their current&#xD;
             insulin regimen for ≥ 3 months prior to study entry,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Adult subjects, age 18 or older and ≤80 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Phototype: I to IV according to Fitzpatrick scale,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. BMI ≤40 kg/m²,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject free from analgesics, anti-inflammatory drugs, antihistamines and/or local&#xD;
             anesthetics within 7 days before inclusion and for the duration of the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject with a sufficient hand dexterity to apply the device,&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Not practice vigorous physical exercise (running, fast cycling, aerobics) during the&#xD;
             study period,&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. For subjects with Type 1 Diabetes, subjects must already be using a CGM (Abbott /&#xD;
             Dexcom),&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Willing to comply with the requirements of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Self-administer Blood Glucose Measurements (BGM) in the frequency described in&#xD;
                  section 6.2.2 Blood Glucose Monitor (BGM),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Avoid swimming or taking a bath for the Study Period,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use logbook to record adverse events and outcomes,&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Wrist size in the range 14 - 21 cm,&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients with hairiness grade between 1 to 3&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Sufficient cooperation and understanding to comply with the study requirements,&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Speak and read the English language,&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Signed informed consent form prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject with a known allergy to the components of the K'Watch CGM system (adhesive,&#xD;
             disinfectants used during the study, ...),&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject implanted with Active Medical device (Pacemaker, Defibrillator, any kind of&#xD;
             active implantable medical devices that require active sensing to performed it&#xD;
             intended use)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject suffering or having history of carpal tunnel syndrome,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Woman of childbearing potential not using an effective contraceptive, pregnant or&#xD;
             breastfeeding,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Use of drugs that may interfere with glucose metabolism (such as steroids) unless they&#xD;
             are chronic therapies whose dosage has remained stable over the past 3 months and is&#xD;
             expected to remain stable during the study period,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject presenting, at the proposed application site, significant skin&#xD;
             fragility/alterations/diseases that could interfere with the placement of the K'Watch&#xD;
             CGM system. These conditions include, but are not limited to, history of skin&#xD;
             irritation following the use of bandages or skin adhesives, extensive psoriasis,&#xD;
             recent burns or severe sunburn, extensive eczema, extensive scars, dermatitis&#xD;
             herpetiformis, skin lesions, redness, infections or swelling,&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject exercising a professional or a daily recreational activity involving immersion&#xD;
             in the water of the K'Watch CGM system (e.g. lifeguard, plumber, …),&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject with tattoos, piercings or implants at the proposed application site,&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of alcoholism (consumption of more than 5 &quot;drinks&quot; per day. For example, 12&#xD;
             ounces (35.5 cl) of beer, 5 ounces (15 cl) of wine, or 1 oz (4.5 cl) of distilled&#xD;
             spirits,&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Use of recreational drugs which would interfere with participation in the study, as&#xD;
             determined by the PI,&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Hair removal or shaving in the area of application of the K'Watch CGM system over the&#xD;
             month prior to inclusion and throughout the duration of the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Application of cosmetics on the application area of the device the day before the Lab&#xD;
             phase and during the Study Period,&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Intensive exposure to sunlight or UV-rays within the previous month and/or foreseen&#xD;
             during the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject with a scheduled radiographic, MRI, CT or diathermy appointment during the&#xD;
             study participation period, and the appointment cannot be postponed,&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject has concomitant medical condition which, in the opinion of the investigator,&#xD;
             could interfere with the study or present a risk to the safety or welfare of the&#xD;
             subject or clinical staff,&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subject currently is participating in another clinical trial,&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. European citizen. (PK will not recruit european citizens for this trial, because the&#xD;
             sponsor prefer not to implement the additional administrative steps as required by the&#xD;
             GDPR).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Prisoners or subjects who are involuntarily incarcerated&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Timothy TB Bailey, MD</last_name>
    <phone>760.466.1530</phone>
    <email>tbailey@amcrinstitute.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>TOM TB BISHOP</last_name>
    <phone>+1 978.835.7910</phone>
    <email>tom.bishop@pkvitality.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>k'watch, diabetes,CGM</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

