<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05093114</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R42 HD075524 (Open Trial)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05093114</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Friends, Family &amp; Food: Food Allergy App for Youth ( F3A-App )</brief_title>
  <acronym>F3A-App</acronym>
  <official_title>Friends, Family and Food: Interactive Virtual Environments for Children With Food Allergies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rhode Island Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rhode Island Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objective: This Phase II STTR grant incorporated user feedback collected in an earlier&#xD;
      development project to build interactive, web-based software that helps children with food&#xD;
      allergies learn about their condition and gain self-management skills. This highly&#xD;
      interactive game allows children to progress through virtual scenes to help them learn about&#xD;
      food avoidance, symptom detection, and reaction management. In addition, this project built&#xD;
      gaming complexity, with more levels and game options, of the two interactive games &quot;Label&#xD;
      Learning: Like it or Lose it!&quot; and &quot;Reaction Action!&quot;.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The central goal of this project was to develop an interactive, game-based application (App)&#xD;
      for school-aged children (aged 8-12) with food allergies (FA) that would increase knowledge,&#xD;
      improve behavioral skills for disease management, and ultimately reduce risk of negative&#xD;
      outcomes. An effective FA intervention for children should target content areas of food&#xD;
      avoidance and reaction management, and across these areas facilitate knowledge acquisition,&#xD;
      develop behavioral skills, and provide practice using these skills in social contexts. Our&#xD;
      Friends, Family, and Food App (F3A-App), consists of four related parts: (a) an interactive,&#xD;
      game-based application that is the core of the program, (b) the experiential scenarios in&#xD;
      interactive environments (e.g., school cafeteria vignette) that target knowledge and&#xD;
      behavioral skills practice in social contexts, (c) two engaging multi-level games to build&#xD;
      skills in food avoidance (Label Learning: Like it or Lose it!) and symptom assessment&#xD;
      (Reaction Action!), and (d) a multi-tiered reward system that uses token economy-based&#xD;
      reinforcement to enhance motivation and engagement (SeaLife Spectacular). From a user&#xD;
      perspective, the interactive, game-based application provides opportunities to practice&#xD;
      behavioral skills (e.g. negotiating pressures to accept trigger foods, requesting assistance&#xD;
      from adults, responding to teasing/bullying) in role-play situations with immediate feedback&#xD;
      and reinforcement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this Phase II project, we proposed to produce a fully-developed version of the F3A-App,&#xD;
      including added content and enhanced features, and evaluate the final product in a randomized&#xD;
      clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The specific aims of Phase II were:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To refine the F3A-App based on the user feedback and data collected in Phase I.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To develop and field test additional content, including two additional interactive&#xD;
           environments (family gathering, school pot-luck); and to increase gaming complexity&#xD;
           (i.e. more levels and options) in Label Learning: Like it or Lose it! and Reaction&#xD;
           Action! We conducted a small open trial in which 40 children with FA, ages 8-12, used&#xD;
           selected segments containing the newly developed content. Children used the application&#xD;
           for 2 weeks on their home computer or tablet. Feedback about device preference and usage&#xD;
           was used to determine our focus in the Evaluation Stage (Aim 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To assess the efficacy of the F3A-App vs. Standard Care (brief office visit and&#xD;
           educational handouts) in a randomized clinical trial with 100 children with FA, ages&#xD;
           8-12. We expected the F3A-App would improve children's FA knowledge and self-efficacy to&#xD;
           manage FA (primary outcomes) and would increase parent-child communication regarding FA&#xD;
           management relative to Standard Care (secondary outcome). Our crossover design also&#xD;
           enabled us to evaluate combined effects of Standard Care and the F3A-App through typical&#xD;
           treatment channels (e.g., is the greatest efficacy found after a physician refers family&#xD;
           to use the App after an office visit?) This Phase II STTR targeted pediatric FA, a&#xD;
           critical public health problem of increasing prevalence. Our approach was innovative by&#xD;
           incorporating an emphasis on behavioral skills practice using a platform that is&#xD;
           engaging, interactive, affordable, and has high potential for broad dissemination. We&#xD;
           envision that the F3A-App will ultimately serve as a template for interactive,&#xD;
           game-based applications for children with other chronic conditions requiring&#xD;
           self-management, such as asthma, diabetes, and celiac disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This record describes only the Open Trial portion of this Phase II STTR project.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 18, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 2, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 2, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feedback interviews</measure>
    <time_frame>Session 2, about 5 weeks after Session 1 and post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>A semi-structured interview assessing child participants' opinions and feedback regarding game segments.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Food Allergy Knowledge Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (pre-intervention/control condition), and Follow up (post-intervention/control condition; approximately 5 week after baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Child report</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Food Allergy Management Efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (pre-intervention/control condition), and Follow up (post-intervention/control condition; approximately 5 week after baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Child report</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Food Allergy Independent Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (pre-intervention/control condition), and Follow up (post-intervention/control condition; approximately 5 week after baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/Caregiver report</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Food Allergy Caregiver-Child Communication</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline (pre-intervention/control condition), and Follow up (post-intervention/control condition; approximately 5 week after baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/Caregiver report</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">39</enrollment>
  <condition>Food Allergy in Children</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Children with food allergy to one of the four most common FAs that may cause anaphylaxis&#xD;
        (peanut, tree nut, milk, and egg)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  child must be 8 -12 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  child must have an active diagnosis of food allergy (FA), specifically one or more of&#xD;
             the four most common FAs that may cause anaphylaxis (peanut, tree nut, milk, and egg),&#xD;
             confirmed by a physician within the past two years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  child and parent must speak and read English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  child must have access to a computer with internet access&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  child must have access to a smartphone or tablet&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any chronic health condition requiring substantial dietary self-management (e.g.,&#xD;
             diabetes).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kathy Mann-Koepke, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health &amp; Human Development (NICHD)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Food Allergy</keyword>
  <keyword>Intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Virtual</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Food Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

