<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05096390</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PAXIPEM (ET21-023)</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>ET21-023</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05096390</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Axitinib +/- Pembrolizumab in First Line Treatment of mPRCC</brief_title>
  <acronym>PAXIPEM</acronym>
  <official_title>Multicenter Phase II Study of Axitinib +/- Pembrolizumab in First Line Treatment for Patients With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Papillary Renal Cell Carcinoma (PRCC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Leon Berard</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Leon Berard</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multicenter Phase II Study of Axitinib +/- Pembrolizumab in First Line Treatment for Patients&#xD;
      With Locally Advanced or Metastatic Papillary Renal Cell Carcinoma (PRCC)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Papillary renal cell carcinoma (PRCC) is the second most common subtype of renal carcinoma&#xD;
      accounting for approximatively 10-15% of all renal cancers. Different types of PRCC have been&#xD;
      described on the basis of two histologic subtypes, type 1 in 25 to 30% cases, and type 2,&#xD;
      with a worse prognosis reported for type 2 metastatic disease. There is currently no standard&#xD;
      of care specifically dedicated to metastatic PRCC patients (mPRCC) and treatments developed&#xD;
      for metastatic clear cell carcinomas are commonly used ; therefore, mPRCC enrollment in&#xD;
      clinical trials is encouraged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical trials investigated treatments such as sunitinib, or everolimus approved for&#xD;
      advanced clear cell carcinoma, or the dual kinase inhibitor directed both towards VEGF&#xD;
      receptors (VEGFr) and the MET pathway foretinib, or more recently, the selective MET&#xD;
      inhibitor savolitinib. Response rates (RR) were disappointing since generally below 15%,&#xD;
      except in a subset of patients with MET germline alterations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Axitinib which is indicated as second-line treatment in advanced clear cell carcinoma was&#xD;
      investigated in a recent specific trial : the Axipap trial. This multicentric phase II trial&#xD;
      was conducted after central pathology review to confirm the histologic subtype and a central&#xD;
      review was performed to assess the primary endpoint : the 24 week progression free rate&#xD;
      (24wPFR). With a median follow up time of 30 months this 24wPFR was found to be over 45%. The&#xD;
      best response rate was 28.6% according to the investigators with a median duration of&#xD;
      response near 8 months. The investigator assessed response rate was 35.7% in the type 2&#xD;
      subgroup indicating a more important effect of anti-VEGFr in this subtype than in the type 1.&#xD;
      The median PFS was around 6 months and was virtually identical in both subtypes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, some preliminary results of the use of Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors in metastatic&#xD;
      non clear cell carcinoma were made available. The PD1 directed antibody Pembrolizumab showed&#xD;
      a 28% response rate in 118 patients with papillary tumors including a 6% complete remission&#xD;
      rate ; the median duration of response was of 15.3 [2.8-21.0+] months. Atezolizumb&#xD;
      (anti-PDL1) combined with Bevacizumab and Durvalumab (anti-PDL1) combined with savolitinib&#xD;
      (Met directed TKI) obtained response rates in the same range. These preliminary results&#xD;
      demonstrated the potential interest of combining axitinib with an immune check point&#xD;
      inhibitor. The results of pembrolizumab as monotherapy were obtained in the largest subset&#xD;
      with mPRC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to these results obtained, the combination of axitinib and pembrolizumab seems&#xD;
      promising in type 2 papillary tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Multicenter, randomized, prospective, phase II study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of axitinib + pembrolizumab versus axitinib in patients with locally advanced or metastatic type 2 papillary renal carcinoma in first-line treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months for each patient</time_frame>
    <description>6-month objective response rate (6m-ORR), defined as the proportion of patients with CR or PR at 6 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, 7, 9-10, 18-19, 27-28 then Months 8, 10, 12, 14, 16, 18, 20, 22, 24</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of response in each arm, calculated from the date of first documented response to the date of first documented progression or death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Best overall response (BOR) using RECIST 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months for each patient</time_frame>
    <description>Best overall response in each arm, defined as the best response according to RECIST v1.1 recorded from baseline until the end of the study (treatment).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months for each patient</time_frame>
    <description>PFS in each arm, defined as the time from the date of first treatment administration to the date of documented progression or death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>OS in each arm, defined as the time from the date of first treatment administration to the date of death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Safety profile, determined using NCI CTC-AE grading scale v5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Papillary Renal Cell Carcinoma Type 2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>axitinib + pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Axitinib will be administrated orally 5 mg twice a day, with a dose adaptations to the manufacturer recommendations in both groups. Doses can be increased up to 10 mg twice daily.&#xD;
Pembrolizumab will be administrated intravenously (IV) over 30 minutes at the dose of 200 mg every 3 weeks according to recent summary of product characteristics (SPC) together with axitinib.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>axitinib alone (control)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Axitinib will be administrated orally 5 mg twice a day, with a dose adaptations to the manufacturer recommendations in both groups. Doses can be increased up to 10 mg twice daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Axitinib Oral Tablet [Inlyta]</intervention_name>
    <description>Axitinib 5 up to 10mg twice a day</description>
    <arm_group_label>axitinib + pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>axitinib alone (control)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab Injection [Keytruda]</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab intravenously over 30 min minutes at 200 mg every 3 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>axitinib + pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years on the day of signing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Metastatic or locally advanced (inoperable) type 2 or mixed PRCC, histologically&#xD;
             confirmed by central review: FFPE blocks (or all HES and IHC slides) with the initial&#xD;
             histology report must be sent for central reading before confirmation of inclusion in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No prior systemic treatment for renal cancer (chemotherapy, immunotherapy,&#xD;
             anti-angiogenic drugs, or treatment under evaluation) even in adjuvant setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least one measurable site of disease according to RECIST v1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) ≤ 1 evaluated within&#xD;
             7 days prior to the date of inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. In case of prior radiation therapy, discontinuation of irradiation for at least 3&#xD;
             weeks before first dose of study treatment, with at least 1 site kept/preserved for&#xD;
             evaluation. Participants must have recovered from all radiation-related toxicities,&#xD;
             not require corticosteroids, and not have had radiation pneumonitis. A 1-week washout&#xD;
             is permitted for palliative radiation (≤ 2 weeks - limited field (&lt;10% of the whole&#xD;
             body)) to non-CNS disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate bone-marrow, hepatic, and renal functions within 14 days prior to the&#xD;
             inclusion, with:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dl ou ≥ 5.6 mmol/l, neutrophils ≥ 1 000/mm3 (1.0 G/l),&#xD;
                  Platelets ≥ 100 000/mm3 (100 G/l),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 2 x ULN OR creatinine clearance ≥ 50 ml/min/1.73m2 (calculated&#xD;
                  using either MDRD or CKD-EPI formula),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST and ALT ≤ 2.5 x ULN (or ≤ 5 x ULN in case of liver metastasis),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (or direct bilirubin ≤ ULN for participants&#xD;
                  with total bilirubin levels &gt;1.5 × ULN),&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Absence of significant proteinuria (&lt;0.5 g/24h) confirmed by urinary dipstick test. If&#xD;
             the dipstick test is ≥ 2+, proteinuria will be quantitated on a complete 24h urine&#xD;
             sample (&lt; 1 g/l of protein/24h sample)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Covered by a medical/health insurance.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Willingness and ability to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plans, laboratory&#xD;
             tests, and other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients of childbearing potential accepting to use effective contraception or abstain&#xD;
             from heterosexual activity during study treatment and within 4 months after final dose&#xD;
             of study therapy or being surgically sterile. Refer to Appendix 1 for approved methods&#xD;
             of contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Signed and dated approved informed consent form before any study specific procedures&#xD;
             or assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of brain metastases on Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) or Computed&#xD;
             Tomography-scan (CT-scan) performed within 28 days prior to inclusion. Patients with a&#xD;
             history of brain metastases treated by surgery or stereotactic surgery, with normal&#xD;
             brain MRI or CT-scan are allowed to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Metastases with high risk of nervous compression or bone lesion with high risk of&#xD;
             fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior history of other malignancies other than PRCC (except for curatively treated&#xD;
             basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or in situ uterine cervix carcinoma)&#xD;
             unless the subjects has been free of the disease for at least 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or serious none healing wound within 28 days&#xD;
             prior to inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Significant cardiovascular disease, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Disorder of left ventricular function with a left ventricular ejection fraction&#xD;
                  (LVEF) &lt; 50%,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled arterial hypertension under adapted medication: systolic blood&#xD;
                  pressure ≥ 150 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥ 90 mmHg or both despite&#xD;
                  appropriate therapy, blood pressure must be monitored and controlled before&#xD;
                  inclusion, or patients under 3 antihypertensive therapies at screening,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction, severe angina, or unstable angina within 6 months prior to&#xD;
                  inclusion,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of serious ventricular arrhythmia (ie ventricular tachycardia or&#xD;
                  ventricular fibrillation),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac arrhythmias requiring anti-arrhythmic medications (except for atrial&#xD;
                  fibrillation that is well controlled with anti-arrhythmic medication),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Coronary or peripheral artery bypass graft or active coronary stent within 6&#xD;
                  months prior to inclusion,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Veinous thrombosis or pulmonary embolism within 6 months prior to inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any anti-coagulation therapy except prophylactic low dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of auto-immune disease except thyroiditis more than 6 months ago.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of any allograft.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. HIV, HBV, HCV active infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any active acute or chronic or uncontrolled infection/disorder that would impair the&#xD;
             ability to evaluate the patient or the ability for the patient to complete the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Interstitial lung disease, respiratory insuffisancy whatever the cause.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Prior (non-infectious) pneumonitis requiring systemic corticosteroid therapy or&#xD;
             current pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Inability to swallow oral medications, or presence of active inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             disease, partial or complete bowel obstruction or chronic diarrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of severe hypersensitivity to another monoclonal antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Known hypersensitivity to the active substances or to any of the excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Receiving or having received immunosuppressive therapy or corticosteroids within 1&#xD;
             month prior to inclusion (except for hydrocortisone for substitution purposes).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of study drug. Examples of live&#xD;
             vaccines include, but are not limited to, the following: measles, mumps, rubella,&#xD;
             varicella/zoster (chicken pox), yellow fever, rabies, Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG),&#xD;
             and typhoid vaccine. Seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are generally killed&#xD;
             virus vaccines and are allowed; however, intranasal influenza vaccines (eg, FluMist®)&#xD;
             are live attenuated vaccines and are not allowed. COVID-19 vaccine is allowed if&#xD;
             non-living/inactivated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Psychological, familial, sociological, or geographical conditions that would limit&#xD;
             compliance with study protocol requirements or known psychiatric or substance abuse&#xD;
             disorders that would interfere with cooperation with the requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Inclusion in another clinical trial, except for supportive care trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Pregnant or breastfeeding woman or patient expecting to conceive or father children&#xD;
             within the projected duration of the study, starting with the screening visit through&#xD;
             4 months after the last dose of study treatment (mandatory negative serum or urinary&#xD;
             pregnancy test at study entry for all women of childbearing potential).&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Under or requiring tutorship or curatorship.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sylvie NEGRIER, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre Leon Berard</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sylvie NEGRIER</last_name>
    <phone>0478782751</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>sylvie.negrier@lyon.unicancer.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ico - Paul Papin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Angers</city>
        <zip>49055</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Remy DELVA, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de BESANCON</name>
      <address>
        <city>Besançon</city>
        <zip>25030</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fabien CALCAGNO, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chu Bordeaux</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux</city>
        <zip>33000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marine GROSS-GOUPIL, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Jean Perrin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-Ferrand</city>
        <zip>63011</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hakim MAHAMMEDI, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Paoli-Calmettes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <zip>13009</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gwenaelle GRAVIS-MESCAM, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Antoine Lacassagne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nice</city>
        <zip>06189</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Delphine BORCHIELLINI, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ap-Hp Hôpital Europeen Georges Pompidou</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75004</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stéphane OUDARD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Co-Rene Gauducheau</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Herblain</city>
        <zip>44805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Iuct-Oncopole Institut Claudius Regaud</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christine CHEVREAU, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut de Cancerologie de Lorraine - Alexis Vautrin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vandœuvre-lès-Nancy</city>
        <zip>54519</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lionnel GEOFFROIS, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gustave Roussy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <zip>94805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Laurence ALBIGES, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PRCC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Axitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

