<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05098457</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>43N1EU2008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05098457</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Effectiveness of GP0112 for Cheek Augmentation and Correction</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Evaluator-blinded, Parallel Group, Comparator-controlled, Multicenter Study to Evaluate the Safety and Effectiveness of GP0112 for Cheek Augmentation and Correction of Midface Contour Deficiencies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Q-Med AB</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Q-Med AB</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A prospective, randomized, evaluator-blinded, comparator-controlled, parallel group,&#xD;
      multicenter study to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of GP0112 for cheek augmentation&#xD;
      and correction of midface contour deficiencies&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 22, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 18, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 19, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Demonstrate non-inferiority of GP0112 versus a comparator-control in cheek augmentation and correction of midface contour deficiencies</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline based on the Blinded Evaluator's live assessment of midface fullness using the 4-grade photograph-based Medicis Midface Volume Scale (MMVS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness of GP0112 and comparator-control based on the Medicis Midface Volume Scale (MMVS) assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 9, 12 and 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Responder rate based on the Blinded Evaluator's live assessment of the Medicis Midface Volume Scale (MMVS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness of GP0112 on the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9, 12 and 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of responders, defined by having at least &quot;Improved&quot; (improved, much improved or very much improved) on the Global Aesthetic Improvement Scale (GAIS) as assessed by the subject and treating investigator</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness of GP0112 and comparator-control using the FACE-Q</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9, 12 and 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in subject satisfaction using FACE-Q Satisfaction with Cheeks and Satisfaction with Outcome questionnaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness of GP0112 and comparator-control using Subject Satisfaction Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9, 12 and 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects in each response category for every question in the Subject Satisfaction Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effectiveness of GP0112 and comparator-control in returning to social engagement</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9, 12 and 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Time in hours until the subject feels comfortable returning to social engagement after treatment, based on subject diary reporting</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of GP0112 in cheek augmentation and correction of midface contour deficiencies adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence, intensity, time to onset and duration of adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of GP0112 in cheek augmentation and correction of midface contour pre-defined expected post-treatment events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 13 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence, intensity and number of days of pre-defined expected post-treatment events collected using subject diaries for 14 days following each treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">210</enrollment>
  <condition>Cheek Wrinkles</condition>
  <condition>Midface Contour Deficiencies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GP0112</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single injection and optional touch up injection with GP0112</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Restylane Lyft Lidocaine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single injection and optional touch up injection with Restylane Lyft Lidocaine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GP0112</intervention_name>
    <description>Injectable gel</description>
    <arm_group_label>GP0112</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Restylane Lyft Lidocaine</intervention_name>
    <description>Injectable gel</description>
    <arm_group_label>Restylane Lyft Lidocaine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ability to adequately understand the verbal explanations and the written subject&#xD;
             information provided in local language and ability and willingness to give consent to&#xD;
             participate in the study. Signed and dated informed consent to participate in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Men and non-pregnant, non-breastfeeding women aged 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. MMVS grade of 2, 3 or 4 (mild to substantial loss of fullness in the midface area) on&#xD;
             each side of the face as assessed by the Blinded Evaluator. The MMVS for each side of&#xD;
             the face does not need to be equal, however the difference between the two sides&#xD;
             should be limited to 1 grade.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects willing to abstain from any other facial plastic surgical or cosmetic&#xD;
             procedures below the level of the lower orbital rim for the duration of the study&#xD;
             (e.g., laser or chemical resurfacing, needling, facelift, lifting threads,&#xD;
             radiofrequency etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Intent to undergo treatment for correction of midface volume deficit.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Inclusion criteria 6-7 apply to female subjects only&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. If the subject is a female of childbearing potential, she agrees to use an acceptable&#xD;
             form of effective birth control for the duration of the study and is willing to take a&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test (UPT) at the screening/baseline visit, prior to&#xD;
             treatment/injection, and at the end of study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Negative UPT for women of childbearing potential at the screening/baseline visit and&#xD;
             all injection visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known/previous allergy or hypersensitivity to any injectable hyaluronic acid (HA) gel&#xD;
             or to gram positive bacterial proteins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known/previous allergy or hypersensitivity to local anesthetics, e.g. lidocaine or&#xD;
             other amide-type anesthetics or nerve blocking agents (if intended to be used for that&#xD;
             subject).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous or present severe or multiple allergies manifested by severe reactions, such&#xD;
             as anaphylaxis or angioedema, or family history of these conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous facial surgery (e.g. facial fat removal, facelift and sinus surgery) in or&#xD;
             near the treatment area that in the Treating Investigator´s opinion could interfere&#xD;
             with the study safety and/or effectiveness assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any previous aesthetic procedures or implants:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous use of any permanent (non-biodegradable) or semi-permanent (e.g.,&#xD;
                  calcium hydroxylapatite or Poly-L-Lactic acid) facial tissue augmentation&#xD;
                  therapy, lifting threads, permanent implants or autologous fat in the face&#xD;
                  regardless of time.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous HA filler or collagen filler in or near the treatment area within 12&#xD;
                  months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous botulinum toxin treatment in or near the treatment area within 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous energy based aesthetic procedures (e.g. laser, intense pulsed light,&#xD;
                  radiofrequency and ultrasound) in or near the treatment area within 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous mechanical (e.g. dermabrasion, needling) or chemical aesthetic&#xD;
                  procedures (e.g. chemical peel) in or near the treatment area within 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous treatment with cryotherapy in or near the treatment area within 6&#xD;
                  months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of cancer or previous radiation near or on the area to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence of any disease or lesions near or on the area to be treated, e.g.,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Inflammation, active or chronic infection (e.g., in mouth, dentals, head);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Facial psoriasis, eczema, acne, rosacea, perioral dermatitis, herpes simplex or&#xD;
                  herpes zoster;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Scars or deformities;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cancer, or precancerous conditions (e.g. actinic keratosis or actinic cheilitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Evidence of scar-related disease or delayed healing activity within 1 year prior to&#xD;
             the baseline visit, or subjects susceptible to keloid formation, hyperpigmentation or&#xD;
             hypertrophic scarring.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Presence of tattoo, piercing, beard or facial hair, which, in the Treating&#xD;
             Investigator's opinion, would interfere with the study injections and/or study&#xD;
             assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Presence of a dental, oral, or facial condition which, in the Treating Investigator's&#xD;
             opinion, would interfere with the study injections and/or study assessment; e.g. has&#xD;
             dentures or any device covering all or part of the upper palate, and/or severe&#xD;
             malocclusion or dentofacial or maxillofacial deformities. Any planned procedure (e.g.&#xD;
             dental implants, tooth extractions, orthodontia) during the study period, that would&#xD;
             make the subject unsuitable for inclusion in the opinion of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. An underlying known disease, a surgical or medical condition that would expose the&#xD;
             subject to undue risk, e.g. human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), active hepatitis,&#xD;
             autoimmune disease, history of bleeding disorders, connective tissue diseases such as&#xD;
             rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosus, polymyositis, dermatomyositis, or&#xD;
             scleroderma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Use of concomitant medication that have the potential to prolong bleeding times such&#xD;
             as anticoagulants or inhibitors of platelet aggregation (e.g. aspirin or other&#xD;
             non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs), Omega 3 or Vitamin E), within 14 days&#xD;
             prior to injection. Omega 3 and Vitamin E are acceptable only as part of a standard&#xD;
             multivitamin formulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Treatment with chemotherapy, immunosuppressive agents, immunomodulatory therapy (e.g.&#xD;
             immunosuppressive monoclonal antibodies, antiviral treatment for HIV or hepatitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Treatment with systemic corticosteroids (inhaled corticosteroids are allowed) within 3&#xD;
             months prior to Baseline visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Use of topical facial corticosteroids or prescription retinoids near or on the area to&#xD;
             be treated within 1 month of the Baseline visit or systemic retinoid treatment within&#xD;
             6 months of the Baseline visit, or plan to receive such treatment during participation&#xD;
             in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Presence of any condition or situation, which in the opinion of the Treating&#xD;
             Investigator makes the subject unable to complete the study per protocol, e.g.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject is not likely to avoid other prohibited facial cosmetic treatments;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject is not likely to complete the study because of other commitments;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject is anticipated to be unavailable for visits, incapable of understanding&#xD;
                  the investigational assessments or having unrealistic expectations of treatment&#xD;
                  result;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject who has a concomitant condition (e.g. acute viral or bacterial infection&#xD;
                  with fever) that might confuse or confound study treatments or assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Subject who plan to lose or has a medical condition that may cause them to lose a&#xD;
             significant amount of weight during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Study center personnel, close relatives of the study center personnel (e.g. parents,&#xD;
             children, siblings, or spouse), employees or close relatives of employees at the&#xD;
             Sponsor company.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Participation in any other interventional clinical study within 30 days before&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Q-Med AB</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Clinical Project Manager</last_name>
    <phone>+46 18 474 9000</phone>
    <email>aestheticclinicaltrials@galderma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cologne</city>
        <zip>50996</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Darmstadt</city>
        <zip>64283</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duesseldorf</city>
        <zip>40212</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duesseldorf</city>
        <zip>40545</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20146</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>22609</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Munich</city>
        <zip>80469</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galderma Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuppertal</city>
        <zip>42287</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lidocaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

