<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05099484</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2001678776</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05099484</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Medications in Breast Milk: A Convenience Pharmacokinetic Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>MedMilk</acronym>
  <official_title>Medications in Breast Milk: A Convenience Pharmacokinetic Study (The MedMilk Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Indiana University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Indiana University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The benefits of breastfeeding and human milk consumption by infants has been clearly&#xD;
      demonstrated.1,2 Benefits to the infant include reduction of infant and childhood diseases&#xD;
      and allergies. Benefits to the woman include more rapid return to pre-pregnancy weight and&#xD;
      reduced risk of health problems such as cardiovascular disease and diabetes in the future.&#xD;
      Many women take medications as part of their standard of care and for multiple medical&#xD;
      reasons in the postpartum period, when breastfeeding occurs.3 This creates a need for&#xD;
      information about the transfer of drugs taken by a woman into breast milk, and ultimately, to&#xD;
      the infant. Unfortunately, there are limited pharmacokinetic (PK) data on many of the&#xD;
      medications commonly taken by lactating women.4 Additionally, there are little data on how&#xD;
      the PK of drugs are impacted by lactation, and how this may vary from woman to woman or with&#xD;
      time throughout lactation. Uptake of drugs into breast milk can vary due to a number of&#xD;
      factors, including drug lipophilicity; molecular weight; drug half-life; active transport in&#xD;
      breast epithelial cells; protein binding in milk and plasma; and lipid composition of breast&#xD;
      milk.5 In silico and animal models can provide some information on transfer of drugs into&#xD;
      breast milk, however, there are large gaps remaining in our knowledge of drug transfer into&#xD;
      human milk.5-8 This information is crucial to better inform providers and patients about the&#xD;
      transfer of those drugs to human breast milk. The purpose of this study is to characterize&#xD;
      the PK of specific drugs of interest taken by lactating women as part of their standard of&#xD;
      care. The drugs of interest (DOI) will be based on medical relevance and availability&#xD;
      throughout the course of the study. The purpose of this study is to characterize the PK of&#xD;
      medications taken by lactating women as part of their standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This observational, pragmatic PK study will enroll lactating women who are taking medications&#xD;
      that were prescribed by their treating medical provider or as an over-the-counter medication.&#xD;
      Study investigators will not be prescribing or recommending medication use as part of this&#xD;
      study. Feasibility of the study is enhanced by a partnership with The Milk Bank, which will&#xD;
      refer women identified as taking medications to study investigators. Subjects will also be&#xD;
      recruited from Eskenazi Health and IU Health. Blood and breast milk samples will be collected&#xD;
      from lactating women prior to administration of a dose of drug and at varying time points&#xD;
      after dosing to characterize maternal and infant plasma PK and transfer of drug into breast&#xD;
      milk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another phase of the study will evaluate plasma concentrations of DOIs in breastfed infants&#xD;
      whose mothers are already taking the medications. Infant blood samples will be obtained by&#xD;
      heel stick or venipuncture from enrolled infants in order to determine the concentration of&#xD;
      the drug in the infant's blood. The design of this study allows for the evaluation of the use&#xD;
      of drugs in lactating women with minimal risk to participants. As blood draws and expressed&#xD;
      milk samples are obtained often during clinical care or daily postpartum life, this study is&#xD;
      not greater than minimal risk. Lactating women taking a DOI will have biospecimens collected&#xD;
      from maternal breast milk and maternal blood. Breast milk will be collected from pumped or&#xD;
      manually expressed samples.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Drug concentration in maternal blood</measure>
    <time_frame>study duration, typically up to 8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Drug concentrations in breast milk at steady state</measure>
    <time_frame>study duration, typically up to 8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline and steady-state plasma concentrations of DOI in infants</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relative infant dose- drug concentration in infant blood sample</measure>
    <time_frame>study duration, typically up to 8 hours</time_frame>
    <description>calculation of relative infant dose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The MedMilk study</intervention_name>
    <description>This observational, pragmatic PK study will enroll lactating women who are taking medications that were prescribed by their treating medical provider or as an over-the-counter medication.</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood samples will be collected from the participating mother and infant (if enrolled into&#xD;
      study). Timing of collection will be dependent on the reported half-life of the DOI.&#xD;
      Typically, 3 mL of blood will be obtained prior to dosing and at approximately 15, 30, 60,&#xD;
      and 90 minutes, and 2, 4, 6, and 8 hours after taking the drug for most medications. If a&#xD;
      woman is able to provide breast milk via a pump then approximately 3-15 mL of foremilk and&#xD;
      hindmilk from each breast will be pumped at baseline (prior to dosing of drug) then at&#xD;
      approximately 2, 4, 6, and 8 hours, or sooner if the subject experiences discomfort due to&#xD;
      her breasts becoming engorged&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Approximately 50 lactating women and 50 infants receiving mother's breast milk will&#xD;
        participate in this study. Approximately 20 to 50 eligible lactating women per DOI will be&#xD;
        enrolled. Overall, we intend to assay approximately 15-20 drugs. Participants may be&#xD;
        enrolled for one or more DOIs with a single consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are lactating, or who are admitted and/or consented for cesarean delivery&#xD;
             and planning to breastfeed postpartum, AND are receiving at least one DOI per standard&#xD;
             of care from their provider or through self-care (for over-the-counter medications).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mothers who are at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Induced lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently taking medication or supplements to increase milk production&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of any significant chronic medical condition including (but not limited to)&#xD;
             hepatitis, HIV, heart failure, liver or renal failure, or malabsorption conditions&#xD;
             (e.g. celiac disease or inflammatory bowel disease) known to alter PK of DOI, unless&#xD;
             the DOI is the indicated treatment for that disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol use within 72 hours of study visit or planned PK blood draws&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Illicit substance, other than THC, use within 1 week of study visit or planned PK&#xD;
             blood draws&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>breastfeeding female</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David M Haas, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Indiana Univesity School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>David M Haas, MD, MS</last_name>
    <phone>317-880-3954</phone>
    <email>dmhaas@iu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shelley D Dowden, BS,</last_name>
    <phone>317-880-3954</phone>
    <email>sburn@iupui.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Indiana University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shelley Dowden, BS</last_name>
      <phone>317-880-3954</phone>
      <email>sburn@iupui.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David M Haas, MD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sara K Quinney, PharmD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Indiana University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David Haas</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

