<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05090904</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INS1007-211</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05090904</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Brensocatib Tablets in Adults With Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2a, Single-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Parallel-Group Study to Assess Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Brensocatib Tablets in Adults With Cystic Fibrosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Insmed Incorporated</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Insmed Incorporated</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of the study is to evaluate the pharmacokinetics of brensocatib in&#xD;
      participants with cystic fibrosis following once daily oral administration of study drug and&#xD;
      to evaluate the safety of brensocatib compared to placebo in participants with cystic&#xD;
      fibrosis (CF) over the 4-week treatment period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 7, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 7, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 and 168 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Maximum Plasma Concentration (tmax) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 and 168 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Concentration-time Curve from Time 0 to 24 Hours Post-dose (AUC0-24) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination Half-life (t1/2) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 and 168 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Who Experience a Treatment-emergent Adverse Event (TEAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Day 56</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose-normalized Maximum Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 and 168 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose-normalized Area Under the Concentration-time Curve from Time 0 to 24 Hours Post-dose (AUC0-24) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose-normalized Area Under the Concentration-time Curve from Time 0 to the Time of Last Measurable Concentration (AUClast) of Brensocatib</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1: Predose and 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, and 24 hours postdose; Day 28: Predose and at 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 6, 8, 24 and 168 hours postdose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Cystic Fibrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 10 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered brensocatib at a dose of 10 mg once per day for 28 days. Half of the participants in the arm will have previously received and will continue to be administered cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulators (CFTRs) during the study. The other half of participants in the arm will have not previously received and will not be administered CFTRs during the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 25 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered brensocatib at a dose of 25 mg once per day for 28 days. Half of the participants in the arm will have previously received and will continue to be administered CFTRs during the study. The other half of participants in the arm will have not previously received and will not be administered CFTRs during the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 40 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered brensocatib at a dose of 40 mg once per day for 28 days. Half of the participants in the arm will have previously received and will continue to be administered CFTRs during the study. The other half of participants in the arm will have not previously received and will not be administered CFTRs during the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 65 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following review of safety and pharmacokinetic data by the safety review committee, an additional cohort of participants may be administered brensocatib at a dose of 65 mg once per day for 28 days. Half of the participants in the arm will have previously received and will continue to be administered CFTRs during the study. The other half of participants in the arm will have not previously received and will not be administered CFTRs during the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered a placebo matching brensocatib once per day for 28 days. Half of the participants in the arm will have previously received and will continue to be administered CFTRs during the study. The other half of participants in the arm will have not previously received and will not be administered CFTRs during the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Brensocatib</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 10 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 25 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 40 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Brensocatib 65 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>INS1007</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be ≥18 years of age at the time of signing the informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female participants with a confirmed diagnosis of CF related lung disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Stable CF treatment for at least 30 days and willing to remain on a stable regimen&#xD;
             throughout the treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a body mass index ≥18 kg/m^2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female participants must use contraceptives that are consistent with local&#xD;
             regulations regarding the methods of contraception for those participating in clinical&#xD;
             studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Male participants, who are not sterile, with female partners of childbearing&#xD;
                  potential must be using effective contraception from Day 1 to at least 90 days&#xD;
                  after the last dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Women must be postmenopausal (defined as no menses for 12 months without an&#xD;
                  alternative medical cause), surgically sterile, or using highly effective&#xD;
                  contraception methods (ie, methods that alone or in combination achieve &lt;1%&#xD;
                  unintended pregnancy rates per year when used consistently and correctly) from&#xD;
                  Day 1 to at least 90 days after the last dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants with pregnant or nonpregnant women of childbearing potential&#xD;
             partners must use a condom.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe or unstable CF, per Investigator's judgement. .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently being treated for allergic bronchopulmonary aspergillosis or nontuberculous&#xD;
             mycobacteria or tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active and current infection by severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2&#xD;
             (SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of malignancy in the past 5 years, except completely treated in situ carcinoma&#xD;
             of the cervix and completely treated non-metastatic squamous or basal cell carcinoma&#xD;
             of the skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Established diagnosis of hepatitis B viral infection or positive for hepatitis B&#xD;
             surface antigen (HBsAg) at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute upper or lower respiratory tract infection, pulmonary exacerbation, or changes&#xD;
             in therapy (including intravenous and oral antibiotics) for pulmonary disease within 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to Day 1 (administration of the first dose of study drug). Participants&#xD;
             meeting this criterion could be rescreened 4 weeks after resolution of symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of solid organ or hematological transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently being treated for periodontal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received any live attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks prior Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing participation in another therapeutic clinical study or prior participation in&#xD;
             an investigational drug study within 90 days prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of hypersensitivity to brensocatib or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any immunomodulatory agents within 4 weeks before the Screening Visit is&#xD;
             prohibited during the study through end of study (including, but not limited to:&#xD;
             bortezomib, ixazomib, thalidomide, cyclophosphamide, mycophenolate, Janus kinase&#xD;
             inhibitors, interferon gamma (IFN-γ], and azathioprine).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuous use of high-dose non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) is&#xD;
             prohibited during the study through end of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of alcohol, medication, or illicit drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current smoker, as defined by Centers for Disease Control and Prevention: An adult who&#xD;
             has smoked 100 cigarettes in his or her lifetime and who currently smokes cigarettes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Insmed Medical Information</last_name>
    <phone>1-844-446-7633</phone>
    <email>medicalinformation@insmed.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>USA003</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tyler</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75708</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cystic Fibrosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Brensocatib</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

