<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01432847</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>110245</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>11-EI-0245</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01432847</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cell Collection to Study Eye Diseases</brief_title>
  <official_title>Generation of Induced Pluripotent Stem (iPS) Cell Lines From Somatic Cells of Participants With Eye Diseases and From Somatic Cells of Matched Controls</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Best Vitelliform Dystrophy (Best disease), Late-Onset Retinal Degeneration (L-ORD), and&#xD;
      Age-Related Macular Degeneration (AMD) all affect the retina, the light sensing area at the&#xD;
      back of the eye. Doctors cannot safely obtain retinal cells to study these diseases. However,&#xD;
      cells collected from hair follicles, skin, and blood can be used for research. Researchers&#xD;
      want to collect cells from people with Best disease, L-ORD, and AMD, and compare their cells&#xD;
      with those of healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To collect hair, skin, and blood samples to study three eye diseases that affect the&#xD;
      retina: Best disease, L-ORD, and AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals affected with ocular condition is one year of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals affected with Best disease, L-ORD, or AMD is 18 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Unaffected individuals are seven years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study requires one visit to the National Eye Institute.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with a medical and eye disease history. They will also&#xD;
           have an eye exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will provide a hair sample, a blood sample, and a skin biopsy. The hair&#xD;
           will be collected from the back of the head, and the skin will be collected from the&#xD;
           inside of the upper arm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will establish a repository of biospecimens to generate induced pluripotent stem&#xD;
      (iPS) cells, which will be used to determine molecular mechanisms for potentially blinding&#xD;
      eye diseases including but not limited to: Best Vitelliform Dystrophy (Best Disease);&#xD;
      Late-Onset Retinal Degeneration (L-ORD); Age-Related Macular Degeneration (AMD); Leber&#xD;
      congenital amaurosis (LCA); Joubert syndrome; X-linked retinitis pigmentosa (RP);&#xD;
      oculocutaneous albinism; Stargardt s with ABCA4 gene mutations; Waardenburg syndrome,&#xD;
      coloboma, Enhanced S-Cone syndrome (ESCS), Spinocerebellar Ataxia, Type 7 (SCA7) and eye&#xD;
      diseases associated with MITF, PAX2, or PAX6 gene mutations. Skin fibroblasts, saliva, hair&#xD;
      keratinocytes, and/or blood cells may be collected from participants with retinal diseases&#xD;
      and from age, gender and ethnicity-matched healthy participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although research involving multiple different ocular cell types from these patients may be&#xD;
      performed, the vast majority of the work will be centered on the retinal pigment epithelium&#xD;
      (RPE) and neural retina. RPE and/or neural retinal cells generated from the iPS cells of&#xD;
      participants with retinal diseases and healthy volunteers will be used to analyze molecular&#xD;
      mechanisms involved in disease initiation and progression. In addition, the iPS cell-derived&#xD;
      ocular cells will be used to perform high throughput (HTP) drug screens aimed at suppressing&#xD;
      the molecular phenotypes of the disease and to identify potential therapeutic agents for&#xD;
      these diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: The primary objective of this study is to generate participant-iPS cells that can&#xD;
      be differentiated into ocular cell types, to be used to study the molecular mechanisms of and&#xD;
      to develop treatments for ocular conditions. This objective will be carried out in three&#xD;
      phases. First, this study will establish a repository of fibroblasts, keratinocytes, and/or&#xD;
      blood cells collected from participants with eye diseases and from matched controls without&#xD;
      any eye diseases. Second, the somatic cell repository will be used to generate iPS cells,&#xD;
      which will be differentiated into RPE, neural retinal and/or other ocular cells. These cells&#xD;
      will be used to elucidate molecular pathways that have led to disease pathogenesis. In the&#xD;
      third phase, the participant-specific ocular cells will be used to perform high throughput&#xD;
      drug screens to identify novel potential therapeutic compounds. The cells obtained in this&#xD;
      protocol may be genetically modified, may be transplanted into animals in the laboratory,&#xD;
      and, if used in the development of cell-based therapies, may be transplanted into humans.&#xD;
      Transplantation into humans will be done as a part of a different study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population: We plan to recruit 465 participants with ocular conditions including but&#xD;
      not limited to: degenerative retinal diseases, optic atrophy, microphthalmia/anophthalmia,&#xD;
      ciliopathy, and other ocular developmental or degenerative conditions, and 465 healthy&#xD;
      volunteers without any eye disease. If possible, unaffected siblings and relatives of&#xD;
      participants with eye diseases will be included as healthy volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: In this basic science, research-oriented study, skin, saliva, hair, and/or blood&#xD;
      samples may be collected from affected participants with the eye diseases and/or genetic&#xD;
      mutations under study, and from control participants matched for age, gender and ethnicity.&#xD;
      The sample collection procedures will incur only minimal risk to adult participants. Offsite&#xD;
      minor participants will not undergo the skin biopsy. This study will typically require only&#xD;
      one visit by each participant. Participants may be requested to return if their initial&#xD;
      sample(s) did not produce adequate cells for study in the laboratory. Participants who were&#xD;
      previously enrolled to provide samples for research-grade iPS cell generation may return for&#xD;
      an additional visit to provide samples for clinical-grade iPS cell generation, if eligible.&#xD;
      The skin fibroblast, keratinocyte, and/or blood samples will then be used to generate&#xD;
      participant-specific iPS cells, and these cells will then be differentiated into RPE, neural&#xD;
      retinal and/or other ocular cell types. iPS cells may not be made from all samples. The&#xD;
      investigators will use the samples for research studies aimed at identifying molecular and&#xD;
      signaling pathways underlying disease onset and progression and for developing potential&#xD;
      therapeutic treatments for the eye diseases under study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures: The outcome measures for this study include the creation of iPS cells from&#xD;
      at least one of the three types of somatic tissues collected from each participant, the&#xD;
      differentiation of iPS cells into RPE, neural retinal cells and/or other ocular cells, and&#xD;
      the identification of molecular and physiological phenotypes in these cells that may be&#xD;
      linked to the onset or progression of the ocular conditions being studied. This analysis may&#xD;
      lead to the discovery of therapeutic interventions for these diseases. There are no specific&#xD;
      participant-based clinical outcomes for this protocol. Participants will, in general, be seen&#xD;
      only once for this protocol, as they will be ascertained and/or receiving standard care under&#xD;
      the NEI Ocular Natural History Protocol (16-EI-0134) or other NEI protocols. In rare cases,&#xD;
      participants may be requested to return to the clinic if their initial sample(s) did not&#xD;
      produce adequate cells for study in the laboratory.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 7, 2011</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Creation of iPS cells from at least 1 type of somatic tissue collected from participants, differentiation of iPS cells into RPE and/or neural retinal The creation of iPS cells from at least one type of somatic tissue collected from participants.</measure>
    <time_frame>Ongoing</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">930</enrollment>
  <condition>Retinal Disease</condition>
  <condition>AMD</condition>
  <condition>Retinal Degeneration</condition>
  <condition>Retinitis Pigmentosa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Affected</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants affected by ocular diseases/conditions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <description>Age, gender, and ethnicity-matched to participants with ocular conditions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        465 participants with ocular conditions and 465 participants without any ocular disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible, participants must meet the following inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have the ability to understand and sign an informed consent or have a parent/legal&#xD;
             guardian to do so if they are minor children or have a legally authorized&#xD;
             representative if they are adults without consent capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant meets one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Participant has been diagnosed with an ocular condition of interest including but&#xD;
                  not limited to: degenerative retinal diseases, optic atrophy,&#xD;
                  microphthalmia/anophthalmia, ciliopathy, and other ocular developmental or&#xD;
                  degenerative conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Participant is free of eye diseases and could serve as an unaffected control.&#xD;
                  Participant s age, gender, and ethnicity must match an existing participant with&#xD;
                  one of the eye diseases under study. Control participants matched to AMD&#xD;
                  participants must not have drusen greater than 63 microns in size.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Adult participant is able to provide a punch skin biopsy and 30 mL of peripheral&#xD;
             venous blood OR child participant is able to provide a punch skin biopsy and the&#xD;
             lesser of 5 mL/kg or 30 mL of peripheral venous blood. Healthy, unaffected children&#xD;
             will only have one skin punch biopsy done 3mm or less in size. In affected&#xD;
             participants, an additional punch may be gathered if the initial sample does not&#xD;
             contain adequate cells. This will be taken from children ages seven years and older.&#xD;
             Sampling of ten occipital hairs and/or saliva may be pursued at the investigator s&#xD;
             discretion. As a rule, samples will be collected on non-sedated/anesthetized&#xD;
             participants. Sedation/anesthesia will NOT be used solely for the purpose of sample&#xD;
             collection. In rare instances where a minor requires sedation for another medically&#xD;
             indicated procedure, samples may be collected at the time of sedation/anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Because young children may not be able to cooperate with sample collection, those&#xD;
             unable to provide a skin biopsy and a blood sample may be excluded from the study,&#xD;
             based on the judgment of the examining investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant meets one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Participant affected with an ocular condition is one year of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Participant affected with Best disease, L-ORD, or AMD is 18 years of age or&#xD;
                  older.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Unaffected participant is seven years of age or older and willing and able to&#xD;
                  provide assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A participant is not eligible if any of the following exclusion criteria are present.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant is unable to comply with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant has a systemic disease that, in the opinion of the investigator,&#xD;
             compromises the ability to provide adequate samples. Examples of co-existing diseases&#xD;
             that would exclude a participant include a bleeding diathesis or a genetic&#xD;
             susceptibility to infections, particularly cutaneous infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
        ADDITIONAL CRITERIA FOR CLNICAL-GRADE CELL LINE GENERATION:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The additional eligibility criteria must be met for participants donating samples for the&#xD;
        generation of clinical-grade cell lines.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant must be greater than 18 years of age, as of the date of enrollment. There&#xD;
             is no upper age limit for donor enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant is able to provide a punch skin biopsy and 200 ml of peripheral venous&#xD;
             blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant is willing and eligible to co-enroll in NEI protocol 15-EI-0128.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant has medical history that includes any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Thrombocytopenia or other blood dyscrasias&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Bleeding diathesis&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Antibiotic use within the prior 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. History of cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. History of exposure to transfusion transmitted diseases including HIV and&#xD;
                  hepatitis B and C as defined by the Standards for Blood&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Banking and Transfusion Services, American Association of Blood Banks.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Travel to an area where malaria is endemic as defined by the CDC&#xD;
                  (www.cdc.gov/travel).&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. At risk for the possible transmission of Creuzefeldt-Jackob Disease (CJD) and&#xD;
                  Variant Creuzefeldt-Jackob Disease (vCJD) as described in the FDA Guidance for&#xD;
                  Industry, January 9, 2002, &quot;Revised Preventive Measures to Reduce the Possible&#xD;
                  Risk of Transfusion of Creuzefeldt-Jackob Disease (CJD) and Variant&#xD;
                  Creuzefeldt-Jackob Disease (vCJD) by Blood and Blood Products&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant is Febrile (temperature &gt; 38(degrees) C).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant has Hemoglobin level:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  African American women &lt;11.5 grams/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other women &lt; 12.0 grams/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men &lt;12.5 grams/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant has HCT:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  African American women &lt; 34%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other women &lt;36%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men &lt;38%&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant has plateleys &lt;150 x 10(3)/(micro)L&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participant has Absolute neutrophil count &lt;1.0 x 10(3)/microL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participant has positive tests for blood borne pathogens (as required by the Standards&#xD;
             for Blood Banks and Transfusion Services, American Association of Blood Banks. The&#xD;
             currently required tests include anti-HIV1/2, anti-HCV, anti-HBc, Anti-HTLV I/II,&#xD;
             anti-T. Cruzi, HBsAg, syphilis, and molecular testing for West Nile virus, HCV, HBV&#xD;
             and HIV-1).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert B Hufnagel, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Eye Institute (NEI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Allison T Bamji, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 451-3437</phone>
    <email>bamjia@nei.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Robert B Hufnagel, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 503-1305</phone>
    <email>robert.hufnagel@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2011-EI-0245.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu SM, Hochedlinger K. Harnessing the potential of induced pluripotent stem cells for regenerative medicine. Nat Cell Biol. 2011 May;13(5):497-505. doi: 10.1038/ncb0511-497. Review. Erratum in: Nat Cell Biol. 2011 Jun;13(6):734.</citation>
    <PMID>21540845</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stadtfeld M, Hochedlinger K. Induced pluripotency: history, mechanisms, and applications. Genes Dev. 2010 Oct 15;24(20):2239-63. doi: 10.1101/gad.1963910. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20952534</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bharti K, Miller SS, Arnheiter H. The new paradigm: retinal pigment epithelium cells generated from embryonic or induced pluripotent stem cells. Pigment Cell Melanoma Res. 2011 Feb;24(1):21-34. doi: 10.1111/j.1755-148X.2010.00772.x. Epub 2010 Oct 7.</citation>
    <PMID>20846177</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 28, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 10, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 12, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 13, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Best Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Late-Onset Retinal Degeneration (L-ORD)</keyword>
  <keyword>Age-Related Macular Degeneration (AMD)</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinal Degeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Age-Related Macular Degeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>AMD</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinitis Pigmentosa</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinal Degeneration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

