<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04874714</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DMV01-SIT-015</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2018-003715-22</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04874714</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Evaluation for the Treatment of Asthma and Allergic Rhinitis/Rhinoconjunctivitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective, Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Multi-center Trial Comparing the Efficacy and Safety of Subcutaneous Immunotherapy With a Mixture of Grasses and Mites at Adequate Doses Versus Monotherapy, for the Treatment of Allergy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Inmunotek S.L.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>BioClever 2005 S.L.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>NTS hub S.L</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Inmunotek S.L.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled, multicenter of 3 active treatment groups,&#xD;
      compared to 1 placebo group, for the determination of the efficacy and safety of subcutaneous&#xD;
      immunotherapy in patients with mild to moderate asthma and allergic&#xD;
      rhinitis/rhinoconjunctivitis (intermittent or persistent) due to hypersensitivity to house&#xD;
      dust mites (Dermatophagoides pteronyssinus and / or D. farinae) and grass pollen&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Double blind, parallel placebo-controlled study. The subjects will receive medication during&#xD;
      11 months&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, randomized, placebo-controlled, multi-center trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>During the trial, both the investigator and the included subjects will be unaware of the treatment each subject is receiving.&#xD;
The person in charge of data analysis will also not know the treatment assigned to each subject until the database has been closed.&#xD;
So that neither the subject nor the investigator knows what treatment each subject is receiving, all the trial medication is identical in terms of outer packaging and appearance.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CSMS: Combined Symptoms and Medication Score</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the number of symptoms and the consumption of medication necessary for the control of such symptoms in asthma and rhinitis / rhinoconjunctivitis of each subject during the trial, of the groups with each other and with respect to placebo.&#xD;
- The endpoint for each asthma and rhinitis / rhinoconjunctivitis symptom will be as follows: 0 = No symptoms; 1 = Mild; 2 = Moderate; 3 = Severe&#xD;
Total daily symptom score = 0-3&#xD;
The asthma medication will be scored based on the therapeutic step in which drugs are included in the GEMA 5 guide.&#xD;
The rhinitis / rhinoconjunctivitis medication score: 0 = No medication; 1 = oral or topical (eyes or nose) non-sedative H1 antihistamines (H1A); 2 = intranasal corticosteroids (INS) with / without H1A; 3 = oral corticosteroids with/without (INS), with/without H1A&#xD;
Total daily medication score = 0-3</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication-free days</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days that the subjects need no medication</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom-free days</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days that the subjects have no symptom</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory function_FEV1</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of Forced Expiratory Volume in 1 Second (FEV1) %</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiratory function_PEF</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Peak Expiratory Flow (PEF) [velocity]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asthmatic exacerbations</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time elapsed until the first appearance of asthmatic exacerbations, number, duration and severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunological parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Analyses of total and specific IgE, specific IgE index / total IgE and specific IgG4</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analogue Scale in which the subject has to indicate in a straight line of 10cm how he/she feels regarding to his allergy symptoms. Being left side (0) = very bad and right side (10) = very well</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life associated with rhinitis</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The quality of life associated with rhinitis will be measured following the test ESPRINT-15.&#xD;
The scoring of the questionnaire will be carried out as follows: The global sum of the scores (ranging from &quot;0 = nothing has bothered me&quot; to &quot;6 = it has bothered me a lot&quot;) of the 14 items plus the score given in the general questionnaire (ranging from &quot;0 = Excellent&quot; to &quot;4 = Bad&quot;). This sum is divided by the total number of items (15 items).&#xD;
The interpretation of the scores is between 0 (low impact) and 6 (high impact).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life associated with asthma</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The quality of life associated with asthma will be measured following the ACQ questionnaire.&#xD;
The ACQ questionnaire consists of 7 questions (ACQ-7) or 6 questions (ACQ-6). In questions 1-6, patients recall their experience during the last 7 days and answer using a scale of 7 points (from 0 = fully controlled to 6 = extremely poorly controlled). The seventh question, which refers to the% FEV1 of the reference value, must be completed by an employee of the site. The questionnaire score is the mean of the 7 responses (ACQ-7) or 6 responses (ACQ-6).&#xD;
The interpretation of the scores is as follows:&#xD;
Less than or equal to 0.75: Adequate control of asthma&#xD;
From 0.75 to 1.50: Partially controlled asthma&#xD;
More than 1.50: Inadequate asthma control</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Consumption of health resources</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>For each patient, the number of times that due to allergy symptoms has done the following will be counted:&#xD;
have visited the family doctor&#xD;
have made an unscheduled visit to the specialist&#xD;
has gone to the emergency room&#xD;
has been hospitalized&#xD;
have needed to contact the doctor by phone</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Security parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Global rate and severity of AE per administration and per subject</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Local Adverse Reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Local adverse reactions are those that appear at the site of the administration. They are classified into: Inmediate (it appears during the first 30 minutes from the administration of investigational product) and Late (it appears after the first 30 minutes from the administration of investigational product)&#xD;
Local adverse reactions are considered if a papule &gt; 5 cm in diameter occurs in the first 30 minutes after administration (immediate local reactions) or &gt; 10 cm if it is later (late local reactions).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Systemic Adverse Reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Systemic adverse reactions are those that appear in other parts of the body other than the site of administration.Their severity will be classified following the indications proposed by the World Allergy Organization (WAO) in 2010, measured according to the following grades:&#xD;
Grade 0: Absence of symptoms or nonspecific symptoms.&#xD;
Grade 1: Signs or symptoms present in a system / organ (cutaneous, Upper respiratory tract, Conjunctival or Other)&#xD;
Grade 2: Signs and symptoms of 2 or more organs / systems listed in Grade 1, or; Lower airway disease, or; Gastrointestinal symptoms, or; Other&#xD;
Grade 3: Lower airway disease, or; Upper airway involvement&#xD;
Grade 4: Lower or upper airway condition, or; Cardiovascular system involvement&#xD;
Grade 5: Death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adverse Reactions to any medication</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Adverse Reactions to any medication administered for the treatment of AE</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Allergic Rhinoconjunctivitis</condition>
  <condition>Perennial Allergic Rhinitis</condition>
  <condition>House Dust Mite Allergy</condition>
  <condition>Pollen Allergy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MM09-MG01(30.000-30.000)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>30,000 AU/mL of MM09 and 30,000 AU/mL of MG01 of subcutaneous immunotherapy once a month for 11 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MG01(30.000)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>30,000 AU/mL of MG01 of subcutaneous immunotherapy once a month for 11 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MM09(30.000)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>30,000 AU/mL of MM09 of subcutaneous immunotherapy once a month for 11 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo subcutaneous</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The same solution, presentation, method of administration, frequency, and duration as the active treatment, but without active ingredients.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MM09-MG01(30.000-30.000)</intervention_name>
    <description>Mite mixture (Dermatophagoides pteronyssinus and Dermatophagoides farinae) with a concentration of 30,000 AU / mL and grasses mixture (Phleum pratense, Holcus lanatus, Poa pratensis, Festuca elatior, Lolium perenne and Dactylis glomerata) with a concentration of 30,000 AU / mL: Purified allergenic extract, adsorbed in aluminum hydroxide and polymerized with glutaraldehyde</description>
    <arm_group_label>MM09-MG01(30.000-30.000)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MG01(30.000)</intervention_name>
    <description>Grasses mixture (Phleum pratense, Holcus lanatus, Poa pratensis, Festuca elatior, Lolium perenne and Dactylis glomerata) with a concentration of 30,000 AU / mL: Purified allergenic extract, adsorbed in aluminum hydroxide and polymerized with glutaraldehyde</description>
    <arm_group_label>MG01(30.000)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MM09(30.000)</intervention_name>
    <description>Mite mixture (Dermatophagoides pteronyssinus and Dermatophagoides farinae) with a concentration of 30,000 AU / mL: Purified allergenic extract, adsorbed in aluminum hydroxide and polymerized with glutaraldehyde</description>
    <arm_group_label>MM09(30.000)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo subcutaneous</intervention_name>
    <description>The same solution, presentation, method of administration, frequency, and duration as the active treatment, but without active ingredients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo subcutaneous</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who have signed the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects with a confirmed medical history of asthma (intermittent or persistent&#xD;
             mild-moderate, controlled), as defined by GEMA 5 with rhinitis/ rhinoconjunctivitis&#xD;
             (intermittent or persistent) according to the ARIA classification caused by&#xD;
             polysensitization to grass pollen and mites (D.pteronyssinus and / or D. farinae). The&#xD;
             diagnosis of asthma will be valid from 24 months prior to signing the informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with a positive prick test (major diameter of the papule ≥ to 5 mm) to a&#xD;
             standardized extract of grass pollen mixture, or to one of the components of the&#xD;
             mixture (Dactilys glomerata, Poa pratensis, Holcus lanatus, Festuca elatior, Phleum&#xD;
             pratense and Lolium perenne) and to an extract of D. pteronyssinus and / or D.&#xD;
             farinae.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Specific IgE (CAP or Immulite) against one of the components of the mixture of&#xD;
             grasses, preferably Phleum pratense or a mixture of grasses and mites (D.&#xD;
             pteronyssinus and / or D. farinae) or one or more of the molecular components of&#xD;
             allergenic sources with a value &gt; 3,5 KU / L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects aged between 18 and 65 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects capable of complying with the dosing regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Women of childbearing age (from menarche) should submit a urine pregnancy test with a&#xD;
             negative result at the time of enrolment in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing potential and men participating in the trial should commit to&#xD;
             using an adequate method of contraception. Medically acceptable methods of&#xD;
             contraception are intrauterine devices placed at least 3 months in advance, surgical&#xD;
             sterilization (for example, tubal ligation), barrier methods, or the use of oral&#xD;
             contraceptives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects who have a smartphone to record symptoms and medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects who have received prior immunotherapy treatment in the preceding 5 years for&#xD;
             any of the allergens tested or a cross-reactive allergen or are currently receiving&#xD;
             immunotherapy with any aeroallergen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects sensitized to other aeroallergens other than grass or mites pollen belonging&#xD;
             to the genus Dermatophagoides, with the exception of epithelia as long as the subject&#xD;
             has occasional exposure and symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients in whom immunotherapy may be the object of an absolute general&#xD;
             contraindication according to the criteria of the Immunotherapy Committee of the&#xD;
             Spanish Society of Allergy and Clinical Immunology and the European Allergy and&#xD;
             Clinical Immunology Immunotherapy Subcommittee cannot be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with severe or uncontrolled asthma, and / or with a FEV1 &lt;70% with respect to&#xD;
             the reference value despite adequate pharmacological treatment at the time of&#xD;
             inclusion in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects who have previously presented a serious secondary reaction during the&#xD;
             performance of diagnostic skin tests using the prick test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects under treatment with ß-blockers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects under treatment with immunosuppressive or biological drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Clinically unstable subjects at the time of inclusion in the trial (respiratory&#xD;
             infection, feverish process, acute urticaria, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with chronic urticaria in the past 2 years, severe anaphylaxis, or a history&#xD;
             of hereditary angioedema.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects who have any pathology in which the administration of adrenaline is&#xD;
             contraindicated (hyperthyroidism, HT, heart disease, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects with some other disease not related to moderate rhinoconjunctivitis or&#xD;
             asthma, but of potential severity and that may interfere with treatment and follow-up&#xD;
             (epilepsy, psychomotor disorder, diabetes, malformations, subjects who underwent&#xD;
             multiple surgeries, kidney disease...), according to investigator's criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects with autoimmune disease (thyroiditis, lupus, etc.), tumour diseases or with a&#xD;
             diagnosis of immunodeficiencies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject whose condition prevents him / her from offering cooperation and or who&#xD;
             presents severe psychiatric disorders, according to investigator criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects with known allergies to other investigational product components other than&#xD;
             grass pollen or mites.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subjects with diseases of the lower respiratory tract other than asthma such as&#xD;
             emphysema or bronchiectasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ana Isabel Tabar Purroy, MD; PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Complejo Hospitalario de Navarra</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Miguel Casanovas, MD; PhD</last_name>
    <phone>912908942</phone>
    <phone_ext>0034</phone_ext>
    <email>mcasanovas@inmunotek.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari de Bellvitge</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hospitalet de Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08907</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Marqués de Valdecilla</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santander</city>
        <state>Cantabria</state>
        <zip>39008</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Santa Bárbara</name>
      <address>
        <city>Puertollano</city>
        <state>Ciudad Real</state>
        <zip>13500</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hospital S Bárbara</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pilar Mur Gimeno, PhD; MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital el Bierzo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ponferrada</city>
        <state>León</state>
        <zip>24404</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo Hospitalario de Navarra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pamplona</city>
        <state>Navarra</state>
        <zip>31008</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario de Canarias</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Cuesta</city>
        <state>Santa Cruz De Tenerife</state>
        <zip>38320</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario A Coruña</name>
      <address>
        <city>A Coruña</city>
        <zip>15006</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro Médico ASISA Dr. Lobatón</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cádiz</city>
        <zip>11008</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>C.P.E. Virgen de la Cinta - Hospital Universitario Juan Ramón Jiménez</name>
      <address>
        <city>Huelva</city>
        <zip>21003</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Lucus Augusti</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lugo</city>
        <zip>27003</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hospital Universitario L Augusti</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francisco Javier Carballada González, PhD; MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Regional Universitario de Málaga</name>
      <address>
        <city>Málaga</city>
        <zip>29010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen Macarena</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínico Universitario de Valencia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46010</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario de Álava</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gasteiz / Vitoria</city>
        <state>Álava</state>
        <zip>01009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Subiza J, Feliú A, Subiza JL, Uhlig J, Fernández-Caldas E. Cluster immunotherapy with a glutaraldehyde-modified mixture of grasses results in an improvement in specific nasal provocation tests in less than 2.5 months of treatment. Clin Exp Allergy. 2008 Jun;38(6):987-94. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2222.2008.02995.x. Epub 2008 Apr 25.</citation>
    <PMID>18445082</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Klimek L, Uhlig J, Mösges R, Rettig K, Pfaar O. A high polymerized grass pollen extract is efficacious and safe in a randomized double-blind, placebo-controlled study using a novel up-dosing cluster-protocol. Allergy. 2014 Dec;69(12):1629-38. doi: 10.1111/all.12513. Epub 2014 Oct 6.</citation>
    <PMID>25130503</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guzmán-Fulgencio M, Caballero R, Lara B, Mena M, Tejera M, Sastre A, Subiza JL, Fernández-Caldas E, Casanovas M. Safety of immunotherapy with glutaraldehyde modified allergen extracts in children and adults. Allergol Immunopathol (Madr). 2017 Mar - Apr;45(2):198-207. doi: 10.1016/j.aller.2016.08.008. Epub 2016 Dec 7.</citation>
    <PMID>27939406</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Rhinitis/ Rhinoconjunctivitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Mild to moderate asthma</keyword>
  <keyword>Allergy</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Mite</keyword>
  <keyword>Pollen</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Perennial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic, Seasonal</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Conjunctivitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

