<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04878640</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Sleeve Gastrectomy</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04878640</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Laparoscopic Sleeve Gastrectomy With or Without Concomitant Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Laparoscopic Sleeve Gastrectomy With or Without Concomitant Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy in Morbid Obese Patients With Cholelithiasis; a Randomized Controlled Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zagazig University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Zagazig University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Obesity is an increasingly serious public health problem on a global level. Gallstones may&#xD;
      become symptomatic after sleeve gastrectomy surgery. There is a debate regarding concomitant&#xD;
      cholecystectomy during bariatric surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the study: This study analyzed outcomes of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy (LSG) with&#xD;
      and without concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy in morbid obese patients with gall&#xD;
      bladder stones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients and methods: We conducted randomized clinical study on 222 patients. These patients&#xD;
      were categorized into two equal groups (111 in each group) .Group A: underwent SG and&#xD;
      concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy in morbid obese patient with evidence of gall&#xD;
      bladder stone, Group B: SG only without concomitant LC inspite of evidence of gall bladder&#xD;
      stone. This study was performed at single institution from January 1, 2016 to January 1,&#xD;
      2019.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The WHO (World Health Organization) has already affirmed that obesity is a universal epidemic&#xD;
      that represents one of the substantial present health complications . Bariatric surgery (BS)&#xD;
      is the pillar of cure for morbid obesity with thousands of surgeries implemented each year&#xD;
      .Bariatric surgery guides patients to waste weight and correct obesity- related troubles, and&#xD;
      improves quality of life .Sleeve Gastrectomy (SG) materialized as the first part of a staged&#xD;
      duodenal switch step and afterwards changed to be a main restrictive bariatric surgery .The&#xD;
      comprehensive pervasiveness of cholelithiasis in the normal populace is 10% to 20%. The&#xD;
      pervasiveness of cholelithiasis in patients with severe obesity is 3 to 5 times greater in&#xD;
      comparison with that for gangly persons .In obese patients, gallstone is more emlematic than&#xD;
      in non-obese people .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the work, gap statement and strength of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      During laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy for morbid obesity surgery, there is no golden&#xD;
      standard of dealing with gall bladder stones, which is generally selected by the surgeon's&#xD;
      preferences or by local conditions. For many surgeons, the benefit of routine cholecystectomy&#xD;
      in patients with gall bladder stones did not justify an additional risk and the risks of&#xD;
      cholecystectomy after a laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy may be higher due to adhesion and&#xD;
      expose patients to another surgery. Others believe that concomitant cholecystectomy may&#xD;
      increase operative time, morbidity and decrease fat after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy&#xD;
      helps good identification of anatomy during later laparoscopic cholecystectomy. In this&#xD;
      study, we have designed a randomized clinical trial to compare outcomes in patients who&#xD;
      underwent laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy with or without concomitant laparoscopic&#xD;
      cholecystectomy in patients with gall bladder stones (Symptomatic or asymptomatic). The&#xD;
      primary aim was to compare the morbidity and mortality rate during and after both techniques.&#xD;
      The secondary aim was to evaluate the postoperative body weight. The tertiary aim was to&#xD;
      detect the incidence of symptomatic and asymptomatic gall bladder stone in cases with no&#xD;
      concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. Material and methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A prospective randomized controlled clinical study was conducted in bariatric surgical unit&#xD;
      of our University Hospital (single center) between January 2016 to January 2019. Patients&#xD;
      were admitted with clinical diagnosis of morbid obesity with gall bladder stone. A total of&#xD;
      222 patients were randomly divided into two groups: Group A (n=111), patients with morbid&#xD;
      obesity and gall bladder stone underwent concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy in the same&#xD;
      setting during laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Group B (n=111), patients with morbid obesity&#xD;
      and gall bladder stone underwent laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy without concomitant&#xD;
      laparoscopic cholecystectomy. it is a simple random sample with a balance. Sample size was&#xD;
      calculated to be 222 (111 in each group) according to the following data: the morbidity in&#xD;
      Group A (LSG+CC) was 18.75% compared to 6.25% in Group B (LSG) at confidence level 95%, power&#xD;
      80% using Open.Epi. The selection of patients was done by simple random technique. Each&#xD;
      included patient was taken number from one to 222 and randomization was done using random&#xD;
      table where odds numbers for Group A and even numbers for Group B to avoid bias in the this&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method of randomization: Patients were randomly allocated using a random sequence generator.&#xD;
      Random allocations were sequentially numbered in sealed opaque envelopes, which were opened&#xD;
      during surgery before carrying out the surgery. Patients were undiscerning to the assigned&#xD;
      group until the study was completed. It is done by recording service.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The work has been reported in line with consolidated standards of reporting trials (CONSORT)&#xD;
      guidelines .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient selection criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To be eligible for the study, patients had to fulfill all the consecutive principles: Male&#xD;
      and Non pregnant female, &gt;20 years old, All patients were contender for bariatric surgery in&#xD;
      conformity with National Institutes of Health consensus criteria for the management of morbid&#xD;
      obesity (BMI ≥ 40 kg/m² or BMI ≥ 35 kg/m² with compelling co-morbidities linked to obesity),,&#xD;
      had pre-operative ultrasound and patients who completed at least two-years follow up.&#xD;
      Omission criteria were younger than 20 years, History of cholecystectomy, No pre-operative&#xD;
      imaging available within 6 months, dearth of interest. Subjective mess and cognitive&#xD;
      vulnerability that halt the patient from considering the operation, Drug or alcohol junkie,&#xD;
      Patients unsuitable for general anesthesia, preceding bariatric operation, Patients with&#xD;
      calcular obstructive jaundice underwent ERCP with stenting and Cases with arduous displaying&#xD;
      of right upper quadrant or liver cirrhosis found at surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Types of outcome and measurement (study endpoints):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcomes were the total postoperative morbidities and mortality(within 30 days and 90&#xD;
      days postoperative): including time of operation (in minutes), intraoperative blood waste&#xD;
      (ml), Vascular/visceral damage at operation, Hematoma/Seroma , Length of hospital stay (in&#xD;
      days) , Wound infection at any time point , rehabilitation time to normal activity (in days),&#xD;
      In-hospital mortality , ICU/days (intensive care unit admission) and hospital length of stay&#xD;
      (days) , postoperative ileus and postoperative stricture. Secondary outcomes were&#xD;
      postoperative BMI, percent excess BMI loss (%EBL), and rate of weight loss. Tertiary outcomes&#xD;
      were to compare the incidence of symptomatic and asymptomatic gall bladder stone and timing&#xD;
      in which gallstones symptomatize.in cases with laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy with no&#xD;
      concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative work up included bariatric surgeons and nutritionists combining deliberation.&#xD;
      Preoperative ultrasonography was performed in all patients. Preoperative anesthetist's&#xD;
      appraisal. With induction of anesthesia, metronidazole 500 mg and ceftriaxone 1gm. given&#xD;
      intravenously. Thrombotic prophylaxis with Clexane 4000 UI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General anesthesia with the preservation of the air passage from soaking with heave. All&#xD;
      measures were performed in mono-center in our unit for duration of 3 years by 3 surgeons&#xD;
      competent in laparoscopic bariatric and biliary surgery ensuing the basics of bariatric and&#xD;
      biliary surgeries. Each surgeon had preceding practice of at least 100 laparoscopic sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomies. At least one of three senior surgeons was always present to certify the same&#xD;
      technique and inclusion criteria. Laparoscopic Sleeve Gastrectomy was performed in the&#xD;
      classical steps [14].Following finalization of sleeve gastrectomy, the right upper quadrant&#xD;
      was explored for the ongoing cholecystectomy. Cholecystectomy was accomplished using the same&#xD;
      trocars and instruments used for the primary procedure. No added trocar was situated.&#xD;
      Dissection of the gallbladder was performed using the ordinary monopolar diathermy. The&#xD;
      gallbladder was delivered from the abdominal cavity through the 15-mm trocar incision. After&#xD;
      completion of the procedure, tube drain was placed in the proximity of the gastric cut and&#xD;
      another one in gall bladder bed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the second day after surgery, the patients could drink a little water. On the third day,&#xD;
      upper gastrointestinal gastrograffin examinations were performed to rule out leakage. The&#xD;
      peritoneal drainage tube was removed when the volume of peritoneal drainage was less than 15&#xD;
      mL. Patients were sanctioned to eat a semi-solid diet and were gradually proceed to a normal&#xD;
      diet over the next 2-4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients were followed for 1 month, 3 month, 6 month, 12 month and 24 months after&#xD;
      hospital discharge. After discharge, patients were interacted with phone and follow up visit&#xD;
      at outpatient clinic. Methods of follow up include full history and clinical examination to&#xD;
      detect delayed drawbacks. At each office visit, body weight, body mass index (BMI), and&#xD;
      gallstone-related symptoms were supervised. No patients lost during follow up period.&#xD;
      Patients who missed the follow-up appointment in outpatient clinic were contacted via&#xD;
      telephone and/or mail.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Collected data were statistically analyzed using Statistical Package for Social Science&#xD;
      software (SPSS) (Version 20.0. Armonk, NY: IBM Corp). Continuous variables with a normal&#xD;
      distribution were reported as mean and standard deviation (SD). Categorical variables were&#xD;
      summarized as frequencies and percentages. Quantitative data with normal distribution was&#xD;
      evaluated using Independent t-test between different groups and using Repeated Measures ANOVA&#xD;
      with Paired t-test in the same group, while qualitative data was evaluated by Chi square test&#xD;
      (χ2). Regression analysis was used to determine the independent factors affecting gallstone&#xD;
      formation. Kaplan-Meier was used to analyze the survival rate of gallstone symptom-free. P&#xD;
      values ≤0.05* and ≤0.001** were considered statistically significant and highly statistical&#xD;
      significant respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Discussion Coşkun etal, revealed concomitant cholecystectomy with laparoscopic sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomy lengthens the surgical span by 18-49 min .Other repelled concomitant&#xD;
      cholecystectomy as this adds additional laparoscopy incisions .Moreover, Raziel et al,&#xD;
      believed that concomitant cholecystectomy increased surgical span without an increase in days&#xD;
      of stay after operation . Fuller etal, declared that concomitant cholecystectomy had&#xD;
      devastating complications as high as 2%to 3%of cases . In our study, we agree that prolonged&#xD;
      surgery is a drawback and we found to be nearly longer by 40.7min and increase postoperative&#xD;
      hospital stay is another disadvantage however, we do not agree as regard additional incision.&#xD;
      Although additional of 5 mm incisional is not a matter of importance but in our study we did&#xD;
      not use any additional incision. The liver retractor in epigastrium was used to retract the&#xD;
      liver and the two working instruments of laparoscopic sleeve were used to remove gall&#xD;
      bladder. We found no statistically significant difference between both groups as regard&#xD;
      intraoperative and postoperative complications in both groups. Mortality rate in group A was&#xD;
      2 % but no statistically significant difference. Also intraoperative and postoperative&#xD;
      complications in concomitant cholecysteomy and cases with delayed cholecystectomy after&#xD;
      sleeve are nearly the same with no advantages of one over the other so, no need to delay the&#xD;
      laparoscopic cholecystomy and expose patients for another operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Raziel etal commented that concomitant cholecystectomy resulted in devastating complication&#xD;
      as bile leakage . We found that bile leakage occurred in 2 cases only (2%) in group A and no&#xD;
      statistically significant difference between both groups. Moreover, bile leakage occurred in&#xD;
      2 cases (3%) in cases of group B required surgery after sleeve gastrectomy. intraoperative&#xD;
      and postoperative results are nearly the same whether cholecystectomy operated at the time of&#xD;
      lap sleeve or deferred later on when gall stone symptomatizing required laparoscopic&#xD;
      cholecystectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The incidence of complicated gall bladder stones after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy varies&#xD;
      between different studies. Sioka et al. validated to be 13.0% [17] and Festi et al. showed&#xD;
      that the incidence may be 10% . On the contrarily, Li VK etal, declared that the incidence&#xD;
      may reach up to 28% of patients However, in our study, the incidence of symptomatic gall&#xD;
      bladder stone following sleeve gastrectomy is higher than stated by previous studies (55%)&#xD;
      and 94 patients(85% of cases) occurred in the first year after sleeve and required another&#xD;
      operation of laparoscopic cholecystectomy with big burden on patients. The high incidence of&#xD;
      symptomatizing gall bladder stone after sleeve gastrectomy may be attributed to rapid weight&#xD;
      loss within one year and regular follow up with close observation and ultrasonography that&#xD;
      detect many cases with minimal symptoms. Our opinion is supported by other study .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a study of 34 patients who developed symptomatic cholelithiasis within 2 years after&#xD;
      bariatric surgery, 20 patients (58.2%) presented with acute cholecystitis. Laparoscopic&#xD;
      cholecystectomy was changed to an open approach in 6 patients (17.6%) due to extensive&#xD;
      adhesions or uncontrolled hemorrhage from the gallbladder bed . Furthermore, Amaral&#xD;
      andThompson proposed a 27.6% incidence of complications related to gallstones after bariatric&#xD;
      surgery, including common duct stones and pancreatitis. In our study, 26 cases (23%)&#xD;
      presented with the commonest presentation of acute cholecystitis not improving on&#xD;
      conservative treatment and required surgery within 72 hours. Laparoscopic cholecystectomy was&#xD;
      converted to open cholecystectomy in 3 cases(5%) mostly due to bile leakage in 2 cases(3%)&#xD;
      while tissue adhesion in one case(2%). conversion to open cholecystectomy in cases of&#xD;
      concomitant cholecysteomy with sleeve occurred also in one case(1%) and in 3 cases (3%) due&#xD;
      to biliary leakage. biliary leakage is the commonest cause of conversion due to familiarity&#xD;
      of biliary system with anatomical aberration. however, we do not agree with the opinion in&#xD;
      that adhesion post sleeve may increase morbidity of subsequent cholecystectomy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>time of operation</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>time of operation in minutes</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>hospital length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>hospital length of stay i days</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>body mass loss</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>percent excess body mass index loss</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>timing in which gallstones symptomatize</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>timing in which gallstones symptomatize</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">222</enrollment>
  <condition>Bariatric Surgery Candidate</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with morbid obesity and gall bladder stone underwent concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy in the same setting during laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with morbid obesity and gall bladder stone underwent laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy without concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>patients with morbid obesity and gall bladder stone underwent concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy in the same setting during laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>patients with morbid obesity and gall bladder stone underwent concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy in the same setting during laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>patients with morbid obesity and gall bladder stone underwent laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy without concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>patients with morbid obesity and gall bladder stone underwent laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy without concomitant laparoscopic cholecystectomy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and Non pregnant female, &gt;20 years old, All patients were contender for bariatric&#xD;
             surgery in conformity with National Institutes of Health consensus criteria for the&#xD;
             management of morbid obesity (BMI ≥ 40 kg/m² or BMI ≥ 35 kg/m² with compelling&#xD;
             co-morbidities linked to obesity),, had pre-operative ultrasound patients who&#xD;
             completed at least two-years follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  younger than 20 years, History of cholecystectomy, No pre-operative imaging available&#xD;
             within 6 months, dearth of interest. Subjective mess and cognitive vulnerability that&#xD;
             halt the patient from considering the operation, Drug or alcohol junkie, Patients&#xD;
             unsuitable for general anesthesia, preceding bariatric operation, Patients with&#xD;
             calcular obstructive jaundice underwent ERCP with stenting and Cases with arduous&#xD;
             displaying of right upper quadrant or liver cirrhosis found at surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Zagazig University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tamer Alsaied Alnaimy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant professour of general and laparoscopic surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>concomitant, cholecystectomy</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

