<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04879381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ANA-MUCO ( 29BRC18.0045)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04879381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Epidemiology of Anaerobic Bacteria in Cystic Fibrosis Patients: Descriptive and Non-interventional Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>ANA-MUCO</acronym>
  <official_title>Epidemiology of Anaerobic Bacteria in Cystic Fibrosis Patients Followed by the Perharidy Cystic Fibrosis Resource and Skills Centre, Roscoff: Descriptive and Non-interventional Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Brest</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Vaincre la Mucoviscidose</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Brest</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recently, the respiratory microbiota characterisation of a Cystic Fibrosis (CF) patients'&#xD;
      cohort has highlighted the potential role of anaerobes, and specially species belonging to&#xD;
      the genus Porphyromonas, in the first P. aeruginosa colonization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this project is to describe the bacterial anaerobic population in the respiratory&#xD;
      microbiota of a CF cohort. At the end of this study, an inventory of the anaerobic microbiota&#xD;
      in CF respiratory samples will be establish in relation to the patients' pulmonary function&#xD;
      and P. aeruginosa colonization status in order to speculate about the pulmonary anaerobes&#xD;
      roles, still unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The innovative aspect of the ANA-MUCO study is the use of a specific sample kit designed for&#xD;
      the study which allows preserving anaerobic bacteria in sputum according to the&#xD;
      recommendations of the International Human Microbiome Standards (IHMS). Extended-culture and&#xD;
      molecular approaches will be performed to identify and describe the anaerobic bacteria which&#xD;
      could be involved in the pulmonary homeostasis in CF respiratory samples.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cystic Fibrosis (CF) is a lethal genetic disease whose prognostic depends on the patients'&#xD;
      respiratory impairment. Indeed, the airways microbial chronic colonization, particularly to&#xD;
      Pseudomonas aeruginosa, leads to infectious exacerbations and to noteworthy respiratory&#xD;
      function impairment and represents the main cause of morbidity and mortality. Nowadays,&#xD;
      antibiotherapy is the main therapeutic solution to thwart bacterial development and to slow&#xD;
      respiratory function degradation. However, during the disease progression, this therapeutical&#xD;
      approach is limited by the bacteria accommodation and antibiotic resistance development.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thanks to the development of high-throughput sequencing methods, the respiratory microbiota&#xD;
      of CF patients has been mainly described and points the way to new therapeutic approaches. It&#xD;
      has been establish that, i) from an early age, the respiratory microbiota of CF children is&#xD;
      modified in comparison with the healthy children one, ii) bacterial diversity decrease&#xD;
      progressively throughout the disease evolution, iii) anaerobes represent an important part of&#xD;
      the healthy and CF respiratory microbiota. Thus pulmonary microbiota composition could be a&#xD;
      better disease progression indicator than the only detection of P. aeruginosa in CF&#xD;
      respiratory samples. Furthermore, the respiratory microbiota could influence the pathogenesis&#xD;
      through direct interactions between micro-organism/micro-organism or micro-organism/host.&#xD;
      Recently, thanks to the respiratory microbiota characterisation of a CF patients' cohort&#xD;
      (MUCOBIOME study, 2012-2015), the potential role of anaerobes (and particularly species&#xD;
      belonging to the genus Porphyromonas) in the first P. aeruginosa colonization has been&#xD;
      highlighted. Indeed, the respiratory microbiota study of 34 CF patients has revealed that if&#xD;
      patients are deprived or lowly colonized by Porphyromonas spp., the relative risk of P.&#xD;
      aeruginosa colonization is 3.7 fold higher. Conversely, the relative abundance's increase of&#xD;
      Porphyromonas spp. in CF patients receiving Ivacaftor treatment is correlated with the&#xD;
      respiratory function improvement. Thus, in addition to be used as biomarker, the&#xD;
      investigators speculate on the fact that some strict anaerobic species, such as Porphyromonas&#xD;
      spp., could act as CF pathogens (like P. aeruginosa) competitors and limit their setting up&#xD;
      in the airways.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators see here the necessity of complementary studies in order to better&#xD;
      characterise anaerobic bacteria in the airways. The aim of the ANA-MUCO study is to identify&#xD;
      and describe anaerobic bacteria in sputum of a CF patients' cohort, to characterise the&#xD;
      antibiotic resistance profiles of the anaerobic species isolated, to study the anaerobes&#xD;
      repartition within the CF population and to evaluate the interactions between anaerobes and&#xD;
      CF pathogens (P. aeruginosa, S. aureus, H. influenzae, …). In order to be the most exhaustive&#xD;
      as possible in the anaerobes description, the innovative aspect of this study is the&#xD;
      conception and the use of a specific sample kit which preserves anaerobic conditions in&#xD;
      sputum according to the recommendations of the International Human Microbiome Standards&#xD;
      (IHMS). Then, extended-culture and molecular approaches will be performed to identify the&#xD;
      anaerobic bacteria which could be involved in the pulmonary homeostasis in CF respiratory&#xD;
      samples.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 29, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 5, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 5, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of anaerobic bacteria in sputum by culture and molecular approaches</measure>
    <time_frame>Inclusion ( Day 0)</time_frame>
    <description>The presence of anaerobic bacteria will be evaluated by culture and molecular approaches with regard of the number of sputum collected.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">101</enrollment>
  <condition>Cystic Fibrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cystic Fibrosis patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Sputum samples</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sputum samples</intervention_name>
    <description>During consultation, one expectoration will be performed.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cystic Fibrosis patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Sputum&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Cystic Fibrosis patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a confirmed diagnosis of Cystic Fibrosis regardless of CFTR genotype&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons affiliated to the social security system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minor or major patients able to expectorate spontaneously or after induction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent signed by the patient or the holder of parental authority for the children&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons deprived of liberty, persons under guardianship or curatorship, persons in&#xD;
             emergency situations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons non affiliated to a social security system or not entitled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pulmonary transplant patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal to participate to the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Geneviève HERY-ARNAUD, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Brest</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU de Brest</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brest</city>
        <zip>29609</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondation Ildys</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roscoff</city>
        <zip>29250</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nixon GM, Armstrong DS, Carzino R, Carlin JB, Olinsky A, Robertson CF, Grimwood K. Clinical outcome after early Pseudomonas aeruginosa infection in cystic fibrosis. J Pediatr. 2001 May;138(5):699-704.</citation>
    <PMID>11343046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cox MJ, Allgaier M, Taylor B, Baek MS, Huang YJ, Daly RA, Karaoz U, Andersen GL, Brown R, Fujimura KE, Wu B, Tran D, Koff J, Kleinhenz ME, Nielson D, Brodie EL, Lynch SV. Airway microbiota and pathogen abundance in age-stratified cystic fibrosis patients. PLoS One. 2010 Jun 23;5(6):e11044. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0011044.</citation>
    <PMID>20585638</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Renwick J, McNally P, John B, DeSantis T, Linnane B, Murphy P; SHIELD CF. The microbial community of the cystic fibrosis airway is disrupted in early life. PLoS One. 2014 Dec 19;9(12):e109798. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0109798. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>25526264</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Klepac-Ceraj V, Lemon KP, Martin TR, Allgaier M, Kembel SW, Knapp AA, Lory S, Brodie EL, Lynch SV, Bohannan BJ, Green JL, Maurer BA, Kolter R. Relationship between cystic fibrosis respiratory tract bacterial communities and age, genotype, antibiotics and Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Environ Microbiol. 2010 May;12(5):1293-303. doi: 10.1111/j.1462-2920.2010.02173.x. Epub 2010 Feb 23.</citation>
    <PMID>20192960</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sibley CD, Surette MG. The polymicrobial nature of airway infections in cystic fibrosis: Cangene Gold Medal Lecture. Can J Microbiol. 2011 Feb;57(2):69-77. doi: 10.1139/w10-105. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21326348</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bernarde C, Keravec M, Mounier J, Gouriou S, Rault G, Férec C, Barbier G, Héry-Arnaud G. Impact of the CFTR-potentiator ivacaftor on airway microbiota in cystic fibrosis patients carrying a G551D mutation. PLoS One. 2015 Apr 8;10(4):e0124124. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0124124. eCollection 2015.</citation>
    <PMID>25853698</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guilloux CA, Lamoureux C, Héry-Arnaud G. [Anaerobic bacteria, the unknown members of the lung microbiota]. Med Sci (Paris). 2018 Mar;34(3):253-260. doi: 10.1051/medsci/20183403014. Epub 2018 Mar 16. Review. French.</citation>
    <PMID>29547112</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tunney MM, Field TR, Moriarty TF, Patrick S, Doering G, Muhlebach MS, Wolfgang MC, Boucher R, Gilpin DF, McDowell A, Elborn JS. Detection of anaerobic bacteria in high numbers in sputum from patients with cystic fibrosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2008 May 1;177(9):995-1001. doi: 10.1164/rccm.200708-1151OC. Epub 2008 Feb 8.</citation>
    <PMID>18263800</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Smyth AR, Bell SC, Bojcin S, Bryon M, Duff A, Flume P, Kashirskaya N, Munck A, Ratjen F, Schwarzenberg SJ, Sermet-Gaudelus I, Southern KW, Taccetti G, Ullrich G, Wolfe S; European Cystic Fibrosis Society. European Cystic Fibrosis Society Standards of Care: Best Practice guidelines. J Cyst Fibros. 2014 May;13 Suppl 1:S23-42. doi: 10.1016/j.jcf.2014.03.010. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24856775</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Héry-Arnaud G, Nowak E, Caillon J, David V, Dirou A, Revert K, Munck MR, Frachon I, Haloun A, Horeau-Langlard D, Le Bihan J, Danner-Boucher I, Ramel S, Pelletier MP, Rosec S, Gouriou S, Poulhazan E, Payan C, Férec C, Rault G, Le Gal G, Le Berre R. Evaluation of quantitative PCR for early diagnosis of Pseudomonas aeruginosa infection in cystic fibrosis: a prospective cohort study. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2017 Mar;23(3):203-207. doi: 10.1016/j.cmi.2016.11.016. Epub 2016 Nov 27.</citation>
    <PMID>27903460</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lamoureux C, Guilloux CA, Beauruelle C, Jolivet-Gougeon A, Héry-Arnaud G. Anaerobes in cystic fibrosis patients' airways. Crit Rev Microbiol. 2019 Feb;45(1):103-117. doi: 10.1080/1040841X.2018.1549019. Epub 2019 Jan 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30663924</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Société Française de Microbiologie. REMIC, Référentiel en Microbiologie Médicale, 2 volumes. SFM, 2015. 856 p. ISBN 9782878050325.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>CA-SFM EUCAST [En ligne]. Société Française de Microbiologie, 2013 [consulté le 11 janvier 2018]. Available on: http://www.sfmmicrobiologie.org/UserFiles/files/casfm/CASFM2013vjuin.pdf</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Héry-Arnaud et al., 2017, European patent EP17306297 Methods for predicting the risk of developping pulmonary colonization/infection by Pseudomonas aeruginosa.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keravec M, Mounier J, Guilloux CA, Fangous MS, Mondot S, Vallet S, Gouriou S, Le Berre R, Rault G, Férec C, Barbier G, Lepage P, Héry-Arnaud G. Porphyromonas, a potential predictive biomarker of Pseudomonas aeruginosa pulmonary infection in cystic fibrosis. BMJ Open Respir Res. 2019 Mar 12;6(1):e000374. doi: 10.1136/bmjresp-2018-000374. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>30956802</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All collected data that underlie results in a publication.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be available after the publication of result and ending fifteen years following the last visit of the last patient.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data access requests will be reviewed by the internal committee of Brest UH. Requestors will be required to sign and complete a data access agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

