<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04879888</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VP-CMTN-UN-2017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04879888</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personalized Vaccine for Cancer Immunotherapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Estudio clínico Fase I de Inmunoterapia Con Vacunas sintéticas Personalizadas en Pacientes Con cáncer de Mama Triple Negativo</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad Nacional de Colombia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fundación Salud de los Andes</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Instituto Colombiano para el Desarrollo de la Ciencia y la Tecnología (COLCIENCIAS)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Subred Integrada de Servicios de Salud Sur ESE - Colombia (South America)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad Nacional de Colombia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Due to their genetic instability, breast tumors that do not express receptors for Estrogens,&#xD;
      Progestagens or amplify the Her2 / neu oncogene [called triple-negative breast cancer (TNTC)]&#xD;
      and other tumors such as melanoma, non-small cell lung cancer, accumulate numerous mutations&#xD;
      that make them highly resistant to different regimens of chemo- or radiotherapy, thereby&#xD;
      generating high morbidity and mortality. However, immunology can turn the genetic instability&#xD;
      of tumors into the Achilles' tendon. Evidence of this has been revealed in Phase I clinical&#xD;
      studies in patients with melanoma and lung cancer in an advanced stage of metastasis treated&#xD;
      with Ipilimumab (anti-CTLA4) to decrease immunosuppression, in whom peptides containing&#xD;
      mutations presented in Major Complex molecules Histocompatibility of Class I (HCM I) of the&#xD;
      tumor itself results in their recognition as &quot;foreign&quot; neo-antigens leading to the efficient&#xD;
      destruction of the tumor by anti-tumor CD8 + T lymphocytes that are amplified when they are&#xD;
      vaccinated with these peptides.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this reason, the identification of non-synonymous mutations of single amino acid and&#xD;
      vaccination with 25 amino acid peptides that incorporate these mutations (synthetic vaccines)&#xD;
      is emerging today as an alternative for immunotherapy of cancers responsible for high&#xD;
      mortality in humans. In an approach that takes 16 weeks, today, it is possible to go from the&#xD;
      analysis of the tumor's transcriptome (which allows identifying the universe of tumor&#xD;
      mutations) to the patient's vaccination with a personalized vaccine that contains&#xD;
      neo-antigens of his tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TNBC is the most aggressive breast tumor, representing around 25% of breast cancers in our&#xD;
      environment. While generally, at least 30% of women with other types of metastatic breast&#xD;
      cancer survive 5 years after diagnosis, most patients diagnosed with metastatic CMTN die&#xD;
      within this time. The lack of selective therapies and the poor prognosis of patients with&#xD;
      NTMC make their therapeutic management difficult, so the implementation of new therapies for&#xD;
      this type of tumor is the main focus of researchers who seek more effective and selective&#xD;
      treatments to improve the life expectancy of patients without compromising their quality of&#xD;
      life. The genetic instability and high rate of mutations of the TNBC most likely favor the&#xD;
      generation of neo-epitopes. Still, due to the immunosuppressive environment of the tumor, it&#xD;
      escapes the immunosurveillance of the immune system. Despite the high mortality induced by&#xD;
      this tumor, a percentage of patients treated with neoadjuvant chemotherapy with agents such&#xD;
      as Doxorubicin and Cyclophosphamide (AC) + Taxanes respond to this chemotherapy regimen. In&#xD;
      particular, the anti-tumor effect of AC is attributed to two things: (i) the direct cytotoxic&#xD;
      effect on the tumor cell, (ii) the immunostimulation of T lymphocytes promoted by Immunogenic&#xD;
      Cell Death (ICM) selectively induced by these drugs. Therefore, in this project, we propose&#xD;
      to carry out the first clinical study in Colombia of vaccination of patients with TNBC with&#xD;
      synthetic peptides that contain mutations of their own tumor to evaluate the immunogenicity&#xD;
      and safety of this type of personalized vaccine as a therapeutic alternative for this tumor.&#xD;
      Achieving the specific objectives set out in this project would mean that we have been&#xD;
      validated in Colombia the experimental design necessary to identify unique epitopes in tumors&#xD;
      and demonstrate the safety and immunogenicity of these vaccines. We consider that having&#xD;
      achieved the above; we will have taken an important step towards the implementation in our&#xD;
      country of the use of this type of vaccine for immunotherapy not only of TNBC but of other&#xD;
      tumors such as glioblastoma, gastric, esophagus, and pancreas, highly fatal due to its high&#xD;
      mutation rate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of adverse effects</measure>
    <time_frame>From day 0 (vaccination 1) until 1 month after last vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of number and severity of the adverse effects in the vaccinated patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">9</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer Female</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vacuna</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Triple-negative breast cancer patients with specific tumor mutation, with six doses of peptide-pulsed autologous dendritic cells after surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peptide pulsed Dendritic cell</intervention_name>
    <description>Intradermal vaccination with peptide-pulsed autologous dendritic cells in 200 µL of patient's serum in six doses weekly after surgery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Vacuna</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a diagnosis of ductal cancer who enter the primary or neoadjuvant&#xD;
             chemotherapy regimen treated with Doxorubicin or Cyclophosphamide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with breast cancer with the HLA-A * 02: 01 haplotype.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of legal age who are not pregnant or breastfeeding (patients or controls).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have histologically confirmed primary breast carcinoma of the ductal&#xD;
             type.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky index greater than 70%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Voluntary acceptance of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a diagnosis of triple-negative breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under age or over 70 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with autoimmune diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has a Karnofsky lower than 70% or an ECOG higher than 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received some therapy as a treatment for their tumor pathology&#xD;
             (radiotherapy, chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or gene therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active autoimmune disease requiring treatment or a history of autoimmune disease that&#xD;
             could be exacerbated by treatment. Patients with endocrine disease controlled by&#xD;
             replacement therapy, including thyroid disease, adrenal disease, and vitiligo, can be&#xD;
             included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of a chronic or acute infection, such as HIV, viral hepatitis, or&#xD;
             tuberculosis, before or after signing the informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of immunosuppressants within 4 weeks before the trial (e.g., corticosteroids),&#xD;
             such as azathioprine, prednisone, or cyclosporine A. The use of local steroids&#xD;
             (topical, nasal, or inhaled) may be acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant cardiomyopathy, which requires treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Splenectomized patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who do not receive the neoadjuvant chemotherapy regimen with Doxorubicin and&#xD;
             cyclophosphamide for three cycles or receive some other type of complementary therapy&#xD;
             such as taxanes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos A Parra-López, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Full time professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Facultad de Medicina - Universidad Nacional de Colombia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bogota</city>
        <state>Cundinamarca</state>
        <zip>111321</zip>
        <country>Colombia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Colombia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://symbiosisonlinepublishing.com/immunology/immunology53.php</url>
    <description>Dendritic cell generation</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bernal-Estévez D, Sánchez R, Tejada RE, Parra-López C. Chemotherapy and radiation therapy elicits tumor specific T cell responses in a breast cancer patient. BMC Cancer. 2016 Aug 3;16:591. doi: 10.1186/s12885-016-2625-2.</citation>
    <PMID>27484900</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidad Nacional de Colombia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carlos Alberto Parra Lopez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Full Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Triple negative breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Neo-adjuvant chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Dendritic cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Peptide</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune-monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Personalized vaccines</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

