<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04877314</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Intermittent fasting immune</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04877314</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Immun Status Changes Due to Intermittent Fasting</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Intermittent Fasting on Immune System</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Training and Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Positive effects of calorie restriction on quality of life and diseases are reported.&#xD;
      Intermittent fasting, one of the calorie restriction methods, has been shown to be beneficial&#xD;
      for health with many metabolic effects, not just calorie restriction. Preclinical studies&#xD;
      show the disease-modifying effects of intermittent fasting in animal models on a wide variety&#xD;
      of chronic disorders, including obesity, diabetes, cardiovascular disease, cancers, and&#xD;
      neurodegenerative brain diseases. There are very few studies evaluating the effects of&#xD;
      intermittent fasting on the immune system, and only TNFα, IL6 and IL10 cytokines were&#xD;
      evaluated in these studies to evaluate the immune system. In this study, we aimed to evaluate&#xD;
      the conditions of inflammatory markers in peripheral blood before and after intermittent&#xD;
      fasting period in overweight volunteers with a Body Mass Index between 25 and 30. Volunteers&#xD;
      will have intermittent fasting for 3 weeks, which conforms to the 16-hour fasting and 8-hour&#xD;
      meal format.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In a 1997 article by Weindruch and Sohal, they reported that reducing food availability&#xD;
      (calorie restriction) throughout life has significant effects on aging and lifespan in&#xD;
      animals. There are many modalities for calorie restriction, one of which is intermittent&#xD;
      fasting. Intermittent fasting involves having little or no energy intake during a certain&#xD;
      period of the day, then free intake of energy for the rest of the day. Some of the modalities&#xD;
      applied in this context can be listed as 12 hours fasting-12 hours eating, 16 hours fasting-8&#xD;
      hours eating, 20 hours fasting-4 hours eating. Studies in animals and humans show that most&#xD;
      of the health benefits of intermittent fasting are not just the result of decreased free&#xD;
      radical production or weight loss. Instead, intermittent fasting elicits cellular responses&#xD;
      that can adapt to improve glucose regulation between and within organs, increase stress&#xD;
      resistance, and suppress inflammation. During intermittent fasting, cells activate pathways&#xD;
      that increase their defenses against oxidative and metabolic stress and remove or repair&#xD;
      damaged molecules.Preclinical studies show the disease-modifying effects of intermittent&#xD;
      fasting in animal models on a wide variety of chronic disorders, including obesity, diabetes,&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease, cancers, and neurodegenerative brain diseases . Periodic opening and&#xD;
      closing of metabolism with intermittent fasting not only provides the ketones necessary for&#xD;
      cells to use during the fasting period, but also elicits highly regulated systemic and&#xD;
      cellular responses to increase mental and physical performance and disease resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are very few studies evaluating the effects of intermittent fasting on the immune&#xD;
      system, and only TNFα, IL6 and IL10 cytokines were evaluated in these studies to evaluate the&#xD;
      immune system. In one of these studies, it was reported that proinflammatory cytokines of&#xD;
      TNFα, IL6, which were measured after intermittent fasting for 30 days for 14 hours, decreased&#xD;
      significantly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the investigators aimed to evaluate the effect of 16-hour fasting and 8-hour&#xD;
      intermittent fasting application on overweight volunteers with a Body Mass Index of 25-30 for&#xD;
      inflammatory markers in peripheral blood .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 7, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Cytokine levels before and after intermittent fasting period for 3 weeks</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Measuring the level of IL1, IL6, TNFα, IL10 cytokines before and after the 3 weeks intermittent fasting period for 30 overweight volunteers</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokine levels</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>IL1, IL6, TNFα, IL10 cytokine levels</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographic values</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Weight as kilograms, Height as meters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Intermittent Fasting</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent fasting</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intermittent fasting</intervention_name>
    <description>30 overweight male volunteers who will have 3 weeks intermittent fasting which has 16 hours fasting and 8 hours eating in a day period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent fasting</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bady mass index should be between 25-30&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes patients,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immune deficiency history,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cancer patients,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who did not agree to participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Hormonal factors could affect cytokine values over time</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ufuk O Idiz, Assoc.Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Istanbul Training and Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34098</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weindruch R, Sohal RS. Seminars in medicine of the Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center. Caloric intake and aging. N Engl J Med. 1997 Oct 2;337(14):986-94. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9309105</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Panda S. Circadian physiology of metabolism. Science. 2016 Nov 25;354(6315):1008-1015. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27885007</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Di Francesco A, Di Germanio C, Bernier M, de Cabo R. A time to fast. Science. 2018 Nov 16;362(6416):770-775. doi: 10.1126/science.aau2095. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30442801</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ufuk Oguz Idiz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc. Prof. MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cytokine</keyword>
  <keyword>Intermittent fasting</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>If the study complete, we could share</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

