<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04870476</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OneStep 1.0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04870476</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Feasibility and Acceptability of the Internet-delivered Treatment &quot;One Step at the Time&quot; for Bodily Distress Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>&quot;One Step at a Time&quot; - an Internet-delivered Treatment for Patients Moderately Impaired by Bodily Distress Syndrome. A Feasibility Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Aarhus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Aarhus</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This uncontrolled feasibility pilot study explores the acceptability and potential effect of&#xD;
      a 14 week, 11-module, therapist-assisted, internet-delivered treatment program, &quot;One step at&#xD;
      the time&quot;, for patients moderately affected by Bodily Distress Syndrome. The study includes&#xD;
      25 participants aged 18-60 with multiple functional somatic symptoms for a duration of&#xD;
      minimum 6 months. The focus of the feasibility trial is evaluation of treatment response,&#xD;
      treatment satisfaction, program utility, recruitment and retention rates, data completion&#xD;
      rates, and time requirement. The primary feasibility criterion is a +2.0 points change in&#xD;
      patient-rated physical health measured by the SF-36 aggregate score physical health from&#xD;
      before to after treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &quot;One Step at the Time&quot; - Internet-delivered Treatment for Patients Moderately Impaired by&#xD;
      Bodily Distress Syndrome. A Feasibility Pilot Study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lisbeth Frostholm, Andreas Schröder, Johanne Liv Agger, Heidi Frølund Pedersen&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective The objective of this uncontrolled pilot study is to test the feasibility of a&#xD;
      future RCT by exploring the acceptability and effect of an internet-delivered treatment&#xD;
      program, &quot;One step at the time&quot;, for patients moderately affected by Bodily Distress Syndrome&#xD;
      (BDS). The focus of the feasibility trial is evaluation of treatment response, treatment&#xD;
      satisfaction, program utility, recruitment and retention rates, data completion rates, and&#xD;
      time requirement. The primary feasibility criterion is an a priori defined change in&#xD;
      patient-rated physical health from before to after treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design This study is designed as an uncontrolled, single-arm, single-center feasibility pilot&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants The study includes 25 participants included from February to July 2020. The&#xD;
      participants are recruited from The Research Clinic for Functional Disorders and&#xD;
      Psychosomatics and The Pain and Headache Clinic, Aarhus University Hospital, Denmark, to&#xD;
      which patients with multiple functional somatic symptoms are consecutively referred from GPs,&#xD;
      medical specialists and hospital departments. Patients moderately affected by multiple&#xD;
      symptoms are screened for eligibility by the eligibility criteria below. They undergo&#xD;
      thorough diagnostic assessment by a medical doctor specialized in functional disorders after&#xD;
      a thorough physical and psychological assessment including diagnostic interview (Schedules&#xD;
      for Clinical Assessment in Neuropsychiatry), physical examination including blood pressure,&#xD;
      blood test and a review of all medical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Meet the diagnostic criteria for Bodily distress syndrome (BDS) with 2-3 of 4 symptom&#xD;
           clusters&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Moderate impact on daily life (self-reliant at home, can participate in activities&#xD;
           outside the home)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Symptoms lasting for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. 18-60 years at the time of inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
      8. Previous stable educational or occupational attachment until at least 2 years prior to&#xD;
      enrollment and expecting to return to occupational or educational activity 10. Motivation and&#xD;
      time to participate in a psychological treatment program for treatment of BDS 11. IT skills&#xD;
      and access to internet and computer/tablet 12. Willingness to engage in working with illness&#xD;
      perception and behavioral change&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. Presence of other physical condition if the symptoms of this condition can not clearly be&#xD;
      separated from symptoms of BDS or the condition is unstable/untreated 6. Current moderate or&#xD;
      severe psychiatric disorder that substantially impacts daily life or demands special,&#xD;
      individualized treatment, or clinical suspicion hereof, e.g. treatment-demanding depression&#xD;
      or personality disorder 7. Current continuous treatment with opioids and drugs with&#xD;
      opioid-like properties 9. Previous psychological treatment targeting BDS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention &quot;One step at the time&quot; is a newly developed internet-delivered&#xD;
      therapist-assisted treatment program for patients with BDS. The 11 modules + 1 module for&#xD;
      relatives are primarily text-based but also contain audio files with guided exercises and&#xD;
      videos with former patients. During a period of 14 weeks, patients are guided through the&#xD;
      program modules assisted by a trained psychologist or psychiatrist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Course If eligible and willing to participate, patients are included in the pilot study and&#xD;
      assigned to a therapist (a trained psychologist or psychiatrist from The Research Clinic for&#xD;
      Functional Disorders). Patients are contacted by telephone by the therapist and guided to&#xD;
      login to the program platform and initiate treatment. The therapist follows the patient&#xD;
      through the 11 treatment modules and provides guidance when needed. Patients and therapists&#xD;
      primarily communicate through asynchronously written messages, and occasionally by telephone.&#xD;
      Treatment duration is 14 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements Patient-rated outcome measures are collected through a web-based program at the&#xD;
      time of screening (before inclusion) (T0, baseline), before treatment (T1, 2 weeks), at end&#xD;
      of treatment (T3, 16 weeks) and at 3 months after treatment (follow-up, 28 months) (T4).&#xD;
      Clinician-rated outcome measures are collected at the time of diagnostic assessment and at&#xD;
      end of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient-rated measures include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  physical, mental, and social health measured by SF-36 with emphasis on the aggregate&#xD;
           score physical health&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  overall health improvement measured by the 5-point clinical global improvement scale&#xD;
           (CGI)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  symptom intensity and symptom interference measured by The Numeric Rating Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  symptoms of anxiety, depression, and somatization measured by relevant subscores of the&#xD;
           92-item Danish version of the Symptom Checklist (SCL-92)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  bodily symptoms measured by The BDS Checklist&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  illness worry measured by Whiteley-7&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  illness perception measured by Brief-IPQ&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  illness behaviour measured by BRIQ&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  sense of meaningfulness measured by The Sources of Meaning and Meaning in Life&#xD;
           Questionnaire (SoMe short version)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  treatment expectancy, rationale credibility, and treatment satisfaction measured by the&#xD;
           credibility/expectancy questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  work performance and work absence measured questionnaire for Costs associated with&#xD;
           Psychiatric Illness (TiC-P)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  demographic variables&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  negative effects of psychotherapy measured by the inventory for the assessment of&#xD;
           negative effects of psychotherapy (INEP)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  program utility measured by the Internet Evaluation and Utility Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  patients' experience and satisfaction with assessment and treatment measured by&#xD;
           questionnaires and qualitative semi-structured interviews&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other measures include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  clinician-rated improvement measured by the 5-point clinical global improvement scale&#xD;
           (CGI),&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  therapist time spent per patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  clinician-rated program utility measured by the Internet Evaluation and Utility&#xD;
           Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  recruitment and retention rates and data completeness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Feasibility outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
      1) Changes in patient-rated physical health from before to after the treatment measured by&#xD;
      the SF-36 aggregate score Physical Health.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Recruitment and retention rates, time requirements and data completeness as measured by&#xD;
           the rate of eligible patients willing to participate, the rate of included patients&#xD;
           completing the treatment program (defined as completion of at least 5 modules),&#xD;
           therapists' time spent per patient, and the rate of treatment completers providing full&#xD;
           data.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients' treatment satisfaction and assessment of program utility as measured by the&#xD;
           credibility/expectancy questionnaire, a patient satisfaction questionnaire and the&#xD;
           internet evaluation and utility questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients' and therapists' impression of treatment effect as measured by the clinical&#xD;
           global improvement 5-point Likert scale).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Feasibility criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      We regard a future study testing the treatment program &quot;One step at the time&quot; in an RCT as&#xD;
      feasible if:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A mean change in the SF-36 aggregate score Physical Health is at least +2.0 points from&#xD;
           baseline (T0, baseline) or inclusion (T1, 2 weeks) to end of treatment (T2, 16 weeks)&#xD;
           for treatment completers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 75% of the patients included in the study complete the treatment program (defined as&#xD;
           completion of at least 5 of 11 modules) and 90% of treatment completers provide full&#xD;
           data&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 27, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in physical Health</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-rated physical health measured by the SF-36 aggregate score Physical Health</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SF-36 physical health</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in physical, mental, and social health</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5-point clinical global improvement scale (CGI)</measure>
    <time_frame>after treatment (14 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Overall health improvement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Numeric Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>every 2 weeks during treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in symptom intensity and symptom interference</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relevant subscores of the 92-item Danish version of the Symptom Checklist (SCL-92)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in symptoms of anxiety, depression, and somatization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The BDS Checklist</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Symptom checklist</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Whiteley-7</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment, after treatment and at 3 month follow up</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in illness worry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief-Illness perception questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in illness perception</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Behavioural Responses to Illness Questionnaire (BRIQ) Changes in illness behaviour</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in illness behaviour</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The credibility/expectancy questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Before treatment (2 weeks) and after treatment (16 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment expectancy, rationale credibility, and treatment satisfaction</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Costs associated with Psychiatric Illness (TiC-P)</measure>
    <time_frame>Before treatment (2 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (16 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in work performance and work absence</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The inventory for the assessment of negative effects of psychotherapy (INEP)</measure>
    <time_frame>After treatment (16 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Negative effects of psychotherapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Internet Evaluation and Utility Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>after treatment (16 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Program utility</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Sources of Meaning and Meaning in Life Questionnaire (SoMe short version)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Chnages in sense of meaningfulness and crisis of meaning</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients' experience and satisfaction with assessment and treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>During treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative semi-structured interviews</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>5-point clinical global improvement scale (CGI)</measure>
    <time_frame>After treatment (16 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician-rated improvement</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Therapist time spent per patient</measure>
    <time_frame>During treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent per patient</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The Internet Evaluation and Utility Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>After treatment (16 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician-rated program utility</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Recruitment and retention rates and data completeness.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, before treatment (2 weeks), after treatment (16 weeks) and at 3 month follow up (28 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of eligible patients willing to participate, completion rate (at least 5 modules) and data completeness.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Bodily Distress Disorder Moderate</condition>
  <condition>Fibromyalgia</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Fatigue Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Somatization Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Internet-delivered treatment: &quot;One step at the time&quot;</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Internet-delivered treatment: &quot;One step at the time&quot;. All participants receive the internet-delivered therapist-assisted 11-modules treatment program &quot;One step at the time&quot;.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Internet-delivered treatment: &quot;One step at the time&quot;</intervention_name>
    <description>The guided internet treatment program consists of 11 modules (+ 1 module for relatives) activated consecutively over a period of 14 weeks. The content is written psychoeducation, patient videos, audio exercises and exposure exercises. The program is therapist-guided; hence all patients will receive support primarily from a specific therapist during the 14 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Internet-delivered treatment: &quot;One step at the time&quot;</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Meet the diagnostic criteria for Bodily distress syndrome (BDS) with 2-3 of 4 symptom&#xD;
             clusters&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Moderate impact on daily life (self-reliant at home, can participate in activities&#xD;
             outside the home)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Symptoms lasting for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. 18-60 years at the time of inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Previous stable educational or occupational attachment until at least 2 years prior to&#xD;
             enrollment and expecting to return to occupational or educational activity&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Motivation and time to participate in a psychological treatment program for treatment&#xD;
             of BDS&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. IT skills and access to internet and computer/tablet&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Willingness to engage in working with illness perception and behavioral change&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of other physical condition if the symptoms of this condition can not clearly&#xD;
             be separated from symptoms of BDS or the condition is unstable/untreated&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current moderate or severe psychiatric disorder that substantially impacts daily life&#xD;
             or demands special, individualized treatment, or clinical suspicion hereof, e.g.&#xD;
             treatment-demanding depression or personality disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current continuous treatment with opioids and drugs with opioid-like properties&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous psychological treatment targeting BDS&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisbeth Frostholm, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Aarhus University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisbeth Frostholm, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+4578464310</phone>
    <email>lisfro@rm.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatigue Syndrome, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Irritable Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Somatoform Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurasthenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

