<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04879017</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FHD-286-C-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04879017</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>FHD-286 in Subjects With Metastatic Uveal Melanoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Multicenter, Open-Label, Dose Escalation and Expansion Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamics, and Clinical Activity of Orally Administered FHD-286 in Subjects With Metastatic Uveal Melanoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Foghorn Therapeutics Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Foghorn Therapeutics Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Phase 1, multicenter, open-label, dose escalation and expansion study is designed to&#xD;
      assess the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics (PK), pharmacodynamics (PD), and&#xD;
      preliminary clinical activity of FHD-286 oral monotherapy in subjects with metastatic Uveal&#xD;
      Melanoma (UM).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is an ascending multiple dose clinical trial with expansion arms. It is primarily&#xD;
      intended to evaluate the safety and tolerability of FHD-286 when administered orally to&#xD;
      subjects with metastatic UM. The Dose Escalation Phase will allow for the determination of&#xD;
      the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) and/or maximum tolerated dose (MTD) in subjects with&#xD;
      metastatic UM. This study will also evaluate the PK/PD profiles of multiple dose&#xD;
      administration of FHD-286.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Dose Expansion Phase will allow a more robust evaluation of the safety profile of&#xD;
      FHD-286, including less frequent toxicities and an assessment of antitumor activity. The data&#xD;
      from this study in subjects with metastatic UM, including safety, tolerability, PK/PD&#xD;
      findings, and antitumor activity, will form the basis for subsequent clinical development of&#xD;
      FHD-286.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 29, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 29, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open label single arm dose escalation and two-arm expansion study in patients with metastatic UM</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 31 months</time_frame>
    <description>Dose escalation and expansion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events (AEs), serious adverse events (SAEs) including changes in safety laboratory parameters and AEs leading to discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 31 months</time_frame>
    <description>Dose escalation and expansion</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of dose limiting toxicities (DLTs) during cycle 1 (28 days)</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 (cycle length = 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Dose escalation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR is defined as the percentage of subjects with evidence of a confirmed complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) as per Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) Version 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 months</time_frame>
    <description>DOR is defined as the time from first documented evidence of CR or PR until the earliest date of documented radiological progression per RECIST 1.1. or death due to any cause among subjects who achieved a confirmed CR or PR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Response (TTR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 months</time_frame>
    <description>TTR is defined as the period of time from the date of first study drug administration until the first objective documentation of response per RECIST 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Progression (TTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 months</time_frame>
    <description>TTP is defined as the time from the date of first study drug administration until the start of disease progression per RECIST Version 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 54 months</time_frame>
    <description>PFS defined as the time from first dose of study treatment until the first date of either objective disease progression per RECIST 1.1. or death due to any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 54 months</time_frame>
    <description>OS is defined as the time from first dose of study treatment to the date of death, irrespective of the cause of death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PK parameter: Area under the plasma concentration time curve (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 and day 8 of cycle 1 (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Characterization of the PK profile of FHD-286</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma concentration vs. time profiles</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 and day 8 of cycle 1 (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma concentration of FHD-286 at the scheduled timepoints</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Uveal Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FHD-286 dose escalation and expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Up to approximately 100 patients will be enrolled in dose escalation and expansion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>FHD-286</intervention_name>
    <description>FHD-286 as a single agent</description>
    <arm_group_label>FHD-286 dose escalation and expansion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Key Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female subjects ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have a diagnosis of metastatic histologically or cytologically confirmed&#xD;
             UM. If histologic or cytologic confirmation of the tumor is not available, clinical&#xD;
             confirmation of a diagnosis of metastatic UM, as per standard practice for UM, by the&#xD;
             treating investigator can be obtained, and fall into any of the following categories:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Newly diagnosed subject who has not yet received liver-directed or systemic&#xD;
                  treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subjects ineligible for any available therapy likely to convey clinical benefit&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subjects who have disease progression after treatment with available therapies&#xD;
                  and/or who is intolerant to those treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have measurable disease by RECIST v1.1, defined as at least one lesion&#xD;
             that can be accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be&#xD;
             recorded) as ≥ 10 mm with calipers and/or CT scan. Measurable lesions cannot have&#xD;
             undergone any local treatment (including liver-directed radio- or immune- therapies)&#xD;
             or radiation nor can any local treatment or radiation involving measurable lesions be&#xD;
             anticipated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to provide newly obtained tumor tissue at baseline and on treatment unless&#xD;
             contraindicated by medical risk in the opinion of the treating physician&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of ≤ 2. a.) Arm 2&#xD;
             (Dose Expansion Phase): Subjects enrolling in Arm 2 must have an ECOG PS of ≤ 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Key Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have other malignancy which may interfere with the diagnosis and/or&#xD;
             treatment of metastatic UM.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have thrombocytopenia (platelets &lt; 50 × 109/L) or another major bleeding&#xD;
             disorder/diathesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Subjects with platelets &lt; 50 × 109/L may be permitted to enroll only in Arm 2 of the&#xD;
        Dose Expansion Phase at the discretion of the Investigator and the Medical Monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with known central nervous system (CNS) metastases are only permitted under&#xD;
             the following conditions: Brain metastases must have been stable for at least 2 months&#xD;
             since completion of most recent CNS-directed intervention. Subject may be on&#xD;
             corticosteroids so long as the dose is stable for approximately 14 days or decreasing&#xD;
             at the time of study entry. Anti-epileptic therapy is allowed so long as medications&#xD;
             are not otherwise excluded and seizures have been controlled for at least 4 weeks&#xD;
             since last anti-epileptic medication adjustment. Subjects with active brain metastases&#xD;
             and/or leptomeningeal disease are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Dose Escalation Phase: Subjects with known CNS metastases that meet the above&#xD;
                  conditions are permitted to enroll in dose escalation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Arm 1 (Dose Expansion Phase): Subjects with known or suspected CNS metastases are&#xD;
                  excluded from Arm 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Arm 2 (Dose Expansion Phase): Subjects with CNS metastases that meet the above&#xD;
                  conditions are permitted to enroll in Arm 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infections; subjects with a&#xD;
             sustained viral response to HCV treatment or immunity to prior HBV infection will be&#xD;
             permitted. Subject has known positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody&#xD;
             results or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS)-related illness; subjects with&#xD;
             CD4+ T-cell counts greater than or equal to 350 cells/µL will be permitted, as will&#xD;
             subjects who have not had an AIDS-related illness within the past 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with an active infection cannot be enrolled until any required antibiotic&#xD;
             and/or antifungal therapy has been completed and/or infection is determined to be&#xD;
             controlled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have an uncontrolled intercurrent illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known and possible risk for QT prolongation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are receiving treatment with medications that cannot be discontinued&#xD;
             prior to study entry and that are considered to be any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. known to be strong Cytochrome P450, family 3, subfamily A (CYP3A) inhibitors, are&#xD;
                  strong CYP3A inducers, or are sensitive CYP3A substrates with narrow therapeutic&#xD;
                  indices (TIs)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. known to have narrow TIs that are sensitive P glycoprotein (P gp) or breast&#xD;
                  cancer resistance protein (BCRP) substrates and are administered orally, such as&#xD;
                  digoxin known to be acid-reducing agents (ARAs) such as histamine H2-receptor&#xD;
                  antagonists (H2 blockers), and proton pump inhibitors (PPIs). Antacids are&#xD;
                  acceptable when administered in a staggered dosing manner with FHD-286&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are receiving systemic steroid therapy or any other systemic&#xD;
             immunosuppressive medication; stable doses of steroids are allowed for control of&#xD;
             chronic symptoms, as long as the dose is stable for approximately 2 weeks before study&#xD;
             start. Local steroid therapies (inhaled or topical steroids) are acceptable.&#xD;
             Appropriate steroid replacement to manage endocrine toxicities resulting from prior&#xD;
             systemic anticancer therapy is permitted. See exclusion criterion 3 for exceptions&#xD;
             regarding steroid therapy for subjects with CNS metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects have undergone any prior treatment with a BRG1/BRM inhibitor.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sarah Reilly, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Foghorn Therapeutics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah Reilly, MD</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-615-1298</phone>
    <email>sreilly@foghorntx.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Caroline Almon</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-615-1298</phone>
    <email>calmon@foghorntx.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Angeles Clinic and Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90025</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Inder Mehmi, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Miami Health System, Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Leonel F Hernandez-Aya, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kamaneh Montazeri, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University, Herbert Irving Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Richard Carvajal, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alexander Shoushtari, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sidney Kimmel Cancer Center - Jefferson Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marlana Orloff, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarah Cannon Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Meredith McKean, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sapna Patel, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>UM</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic uveal melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>advanced uveal melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>phase 1</keyword>
  <keyword>FHD-286</keyword>
  <keyword>Foghorn</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Uveal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

