<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04876781</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A3921369</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04876781</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Korean Post-marketing Surveillance for Xeljanz XR</brief_title>
  <acronym>XRPMS</acronym>
  <official_title>Korean Post-marketing Surveillance for Xeljanz XR (Registered)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pfizer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Xeljanz(tofacitinib) is a potent, oral janus kinase inhibitor. Xeljanz Tab 5mg was approved&#xD;
      by MFDS in 2014 for the treatment of adult patients with moderately to severely active&#xD;
      rheumatoid arthritis (RA) who have had an inadequate response or intolerance to methotrexate.&#xD;
      It may be used as monotherapy or in combination with methotrexate or other nonbiologic&#xD;
      disease modifying anti rheumatic drugs (DMARDs).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The dosage of Xeljanz 5mg is twice-daily immediate-release (IR) formulation, and Xeljanz XR&#xD;
      provides a once-daily (QD) dosing with extended-release (XR) formulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Xeljanz 5mg PMS collected approximately 750 patients in 6 years since it was approved in&#xD;
      Korea. Althought Xeljanz XR extended-release tablet is an addition of formulation within the&#xD;
      approved indication of Xeljanx 5mg, Pfizer Korea decided to conduct PMS of Xeljanz XR&#xD;
      extended-release tablet to establish safety and effectiveness in Korean population. At least&#xD;
      200 patients will be enrolled in this study over the next four years after Xeljanz XR is&#xD;
      approved.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Treatment Emergent Treatment-Related Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Maximum of 6 months from the time of initial administration of Xeljanz XR</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment-related AE is any untoward medical occurrence attributed to study drug in a participant who received study drug. Serious adverse event (SAE) is an AE resulting in any of the following outcomes or deemed significant for any other reason: death; initial or prolonged inpatient hospitalization; life-threatening experience (immediate risk of dying); persistent or significant disability/incapacity; congenital anomaly. Treatment-emergent are events between first dose of study drug and up to Y days after last dose that were absent before treatment or that worsened relative to pretreatment state. Relatedness to Drug X was assessed by the investigator (Yes/No). Participants with multiple occurrences of an AE within a category were counted once within the category.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Disease Activity Score based on 28-joints Count (DAS28)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 months after treatment or within 30 days after last dose of medicinal product</time_frame>
    <description>DAS28, a modified version of the original Disease Activity Score (DAS), is a quantitative measure of disease activity used to monitor the treatment of RA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With European League Against Rheumatism (EULAR) Response Based on DAS28</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 months after treatment or within 30 days after last dose of medicinal product</time_frame>
    <description>The Disease Activity Score Based on 28-joints Count based (DAS28-based) EULAR response criteria is used to measure individual response as none, good, and moderate, depending on the extent of change from baseline and the level of disease activity reached.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With an American College of Rheumatology 20% (ACR20) Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 months after treatment or within 30 days after last dose of medicinal product</time_frame>
    <description>ACR20 response: greater than or equal to (≥) 20 percent (%) improvement in tender joint count; ≥ 20% improvement in swollen joint count; and ≥ 20% improvement in at least 3 of 5 remaining ACR core measures: participant assessment of pain; participant global assessment of disease activity; physician global assessment of disease activity; self-assessed disability (disability index of the Health Assessment Questionnaire [HAQ]); and C-Reactive Protein (CRP).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment in Ankylosing Spondylitis response (ASAS20)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 months after treatment or within 30 days after last dose of medicinal product</time_frame>
    <description>The ASAS Response Criteria (ASAS 20) is defined as an improvement of at least 20% and an absolute improvement of at least 10 units on a 0-100 scale in at least three of the following domains: Patient global assessment, Pain assessment, Function (BASFI), and Inflammation (last 2 questions of BASDAI).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Active Moderate to Severe Rheumatoid Arthritis</condition>
  <condition>Active Ankylosing Spondylitis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tofacitinib XR</intervention_name>
    <description>Tofacitinib XR 11mg</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects administered with Xeljanz XR as a part of routine treatment who comply with the&#xD;
        local labeling.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have been administered Xeljanz XR for the first time according to the&#xD;
             current Korean local labeling (indication, dosage and administration)..&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have previously been given Xeljanz 5mg, who have changed Xeljanz XR, are&#xD;
             also eligible for registration in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that&#xD;
             the patient (or a legally acceptable representative) has been informed of all&#xD;
             pertinent aspects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients meeting any of the following criteria will not be included in the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with a history of hypersensitivity to any ingredients of this product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with serious infection (sepsis, etc.) or active infection including localized&#xD;
             infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with active tuberculosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with severe hepatic function disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with an absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt;1,000 cells/mm3. *&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with a lymphocyte count &lt;500 cells/mm3. *&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with a hemoglobin level &lt;9 g/dL. *&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Pregnant or possibly pregnant women. * Do not initiate Xeljanz XR in the following&#xD;
             cases: ANC; absolute neutrophil count &lt;1,000 cells/mm3 ALC; absolute lymphocyte count&#xD;
             &lt;500 cells/mm3 Hemoglobin&lt;9 g/dL&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Pfizer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>1-800-718-1021</phone>
    <email>ClinicalTrials.gov_Inquiries@pfizer.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Spondylitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Spondylitis, Ankylosing</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tofacitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Pfizer will provide access to individual de-identified participant data and related study documents (e.g. protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP), Clinical Study Report (CSR)) upon request from qualified researchers, and subject to certain criteria, conditions, and exceptions. Further details on Pfizer's data sharing criteria and process for requesting access can be found at: https://www.pfizer.com/science/clinical_trials/trial_data_and_results/data_requests.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

