<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04871139</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-0031</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-03404</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-0031</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04871139</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Imaging Technology, Contrast-Enhanced Mammography, in Predicting Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Contrast-Enhanced Mammography (CEM) for the Evaluation and Targeted Biopsy of Suspicious Mammographic Architectural Distortions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial examines a new imaging technology, contrast-enhanced mammography, in&#xD;
      predicting breast cancer. Contrast-enhanced mammography is similar to standard mammography,&#xD;
      but it includes an intravenous (by vein) injection of iodine-based contrast, which makes&#xD;
      tissue and blood vessels more visible in scans. Contrast-enhanced mammography may work better&#xD;
      in detecting cancer in the breast that is not seen on other imaging tests and may help&#xD;
      doctors find the most suspicious areas of the breast to biopsy, which could increase the&#xD;
      chances of finding breast cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the added value of contrast enhancement of contrast-enhanced mammography (CEM)&#xD;
      compared to full field digital mammography (FFDM) in predicting invasive malignancy or ductal&#xD;
      carcinoma in situ (DCIS) in patients with suspicious mammographic architectural distortion&#xD;
      (MAD)s.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To compare sensitivity, specificity, negative predictive value and positive predictive&#xD;
      value of CEM versus FFDM, digital breast tomosynthesis (DBT), and ultrasound (US) in&#xD;
      predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS in patients with suspicious MADs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To evaluate whether the presence of enhancement on CEM correlates with the visibility of&#xD;
      MAD on FFDM and DBT, or DBT only, and with the probability of malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To estimate the proportion of cases in which CEM changes the original target for a&#xD;
      stereotactic biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To evaluate the cancer detection rate and the outcomes (need for additional imaging,&#xD;
      biopsies, and final pathologic results) of incidental CEM findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the correlation of blood biomarkers and the presence of invasive cancer and&#xD;
      DCIS on pathology in the study patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To evaluate the role of CEM enhancement pattern in choosing a precise target for a&#xD;
      stereotactic biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To develop an objective method of quantifying the degree of enhancement above background&#xD;
      using AI-based digital image analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To evaluate the technical feasibility of using CEM-guided or CEM-directed stereotactic&#xD;
      biopsies in patients with suspicious MADs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. In patients who undergo CEM targeted or CEM directed biopsy we will evaluate the upgrade&#xD;
      rate of DCIS to invasive malignancy or high-risk lesions to DCIS or invasive cancer for those&#xD;
      patients who will require surgery as a part of their routine clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. To compare the performance of FFDM (obtained as a part of the recent prior screening or&#xD;
      diagnostic mammographic work-up) and LE CEM images (obtained as a part of the CEM study) in&#xD;
      terms of accuracy, sensitivity, specificity, positive predictive value (PPV) and negative&#xD;
      predictive value (NPV) for the detection of invasive cancer and high-grade DCIS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive iodine-based contrast agent intravenously (IV) and the undergo CEM over&#xD;
      10-15 minutes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 8, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of contrast-enhanced mammography (CEM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will examine the accuracy of CEM compared to full field digital mammography (FFDM) in predicting invasive malignancy or ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) in patients with mammographic architectural distortion (MAD)s.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of CEM, FFDM, digital breast tomosynthesis (DBT), and ultrasound (US) in predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will compare the sensitivity of CEM with that of FFDM, DBT, and US in predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS by using McNemar's test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Specificity of CEM, FFDM, digital breast tomosynthesis (DBT), and US in predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will compare the specificity of CEM with that of FFDM, DBT, and US in predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS by using McNemar's test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Negative predictive value of CEM, FFDM, digital breast tomosynthesis (DBT), and US in predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive predictive value of CEM, FFDM, digital breast tomosynthesis (DBT), and US in predicting invasive malignancy or DCIS</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Degree of enhancement on CEM</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will examine the degree of enhancement on CEM and its correlation with the visibility of MAD on FFDM and DBT, or DBT only, and with the probability of malignancy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of cases in which CEM changes the original target for a stereotactic biopsy</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>We will estimate the proportion of cases in which CEM changes the original target along with an exact 95% confidence interval.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cancer detection rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Will examine cancer detection rate and the outcomes (need for additional imaging, biopsies, and final pathologic results) of incidental CEM findings.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diagnostic (iodine-based contrast, CEM)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive iodine-based contrast agent IV and the undergo CEM over 10-15 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Biopsy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo biopsy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diagnostic (iodine-based contrast, CEM)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BIOPSY_TYPE</other_name>
    <other_name>Bx</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Contrast-Enhanced Mammography</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo CEM</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diagnostic (iodine-based contrast, CEM)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CEM</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diagnostic (iodine-based contrast, CEM)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radioactive Iodine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Diagnostic (iodine-based contrast, CEM)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with suspicious MADs recommended for a stereotactic biopsy who underwent their&#xD;
             diagnostic imaging work-up resulting in a biopsy recommendation at MD Anderson Cancer&#xD;
             Center (MDACC) or at an outside facility with a technically acceptable quality of&#xD;
             diagnostic mammography, and who are planning to have their biopsy at MDACC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 25-85 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to participate in the study, undergo an IV placement, able to undergo&#xD;
             iodinated contrast injection, and able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reported history of an allergic reaction to iodinated contrast&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of anaphylactic reaction to any substance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast surgery affecting the site of interest within prior 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast biopsy at the site of interest within the last 2 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Olena Weaver</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Olena Weaver</last_name>
      <phone>713-471-3613</phone>
      <email>ooweaver@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Olena Weaver</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

