<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04873830</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ainshamsUni</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04873830</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Volumetric Assessment of Volume Stable Collagen Matrix in Soft Tissue Ridge Augmentation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Volumetric Assessment of Volume Stable Collagen Matrix in Soft Tissue Ridge Augmentation at Maxillary Single Implant Site</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ain Shams University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ain Shams University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This proposal suggests the use of a collagen scaffold as a core material for GBR in the case&#xD;
      of a missing tooth between two existing teeth, in situations where there is sufficient bone&#xD;
      to place an implant but a horizontal defect is present in the ridge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The tested question is whether a thick, reinforced, resorbable collagen scaffold can provide&#xD;
      a stable basis for restoring the lost volume of a deficient ridge. As a secondary aim, a&#xD;
      positive result could present an option to replace the connective tissue interpositional&#xD;
      graft procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      • Surgical procedure and clinical measurements:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-surgical phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Full Conventional non-surgical periodontal therapy involving supra, sub gingival scaling&#xD;
           and root planning will be performed&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Oral hygiene instructions will be repeated until patients had achieved a proper degree&#xD;
           of oral hygiene where plaque index (PI) ≤ 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Four weeks later, patients will be re-evaluated in order to confirm the efficacy of&#xD;
           cause related therapy phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Clinical parameters and CBCT will be recorded prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Full arch impressions will be recorded with high viscosity impression material. Baseline&#xD;
           casts will be made to be used as a reference for volumetric measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Surgical protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Patients will undertake implant surgery under local anesthesia for the missing&#xD;
                tooth using mid crestal incision at the edentulous area and sulcular incisions at&#xD;
                the neighboring mesial and distal teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  A combined full / partial thickness flap will be made followed by implant placement&#xD;
                and healing screw is connected to the implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  For group 1 VCMX will be utilized to graft the buccal defect and primary closure&#xD;
                will be achieved using simple interrupted sutures.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  For group 2 CTG will be utilized to graft the buccal defect and primary closure&#xD;
                will be achieved using simple interrupted sutures.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Postoperative medications will include (Augmentin 1g twice/day, Flagel 500 mg twice&#xD;
                daily and 2 weeks of antiseptic mouth wash ).(Deeb et al , 2015)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Patients will be given post-operative instruction and sutures will be removed after&#xD;
                2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The final abutment will be secured to the implant within 12 weeks after gingival&#xD;
                healing for definitive crown placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperative surgical evaluation and assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The follow up period will include oral examination, plaque removal when necessary, at&#xD;
           the surgical site.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Clinical parameters will be measured, impressions redone, and models will be casted 3, 6&#xD;
           and 9 months postoperatively for both groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Radiographic examination using CBCT will be done at 9 months follow up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods of evaluation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Clinical Measurements:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Probing depth (Glavind &amp; Loe, 1967).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Plaque index (O'leary T, 1972).&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Bleeding index (Newbrun, 1996)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Volumetric changes at the augmented implant site digitally through scanning model&#xD;
                casts.&#xD;
&#xD;
           To assess the volumetric differences between the baseline, 3, 6 and 9 months&#xD;
           postoperatively and all the cast models will be transferred to digital replica using an&#xD;
           optical scanner. Digital replicas will be produced resembling various time intervals&#xD;
           during treatment. Superimposing the different replicas of each case utilizing the best&#xD;
           fit algorithm by using reference points from the tooth surfaces. The implant site region&#xD;
           will be delineated by the mucogingival line, the mesial and distal papillary midline and&#xD;
           the alveolar crest. Thus, any.alterations in volume between the digitized superimposed&#xD;
           replicas could be recorded. (Akcali et al., 2015)&#xD;
&#xD;
           • Pink esthetic score. Pink esthetic score will be recorded for five variables: &quot;mesial&#xD;
           papilla, distal papilla, curvature of the facial mucosa, level of the facial mucosa, and&#xD;
           root convexity/soft tissue color and texture at the facial aspect of the implant site&quot;.&#xD;
           A score of 2, 1, or 0 will be assigned to all five PES parameters.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The two papillary scores (mesial and distal) will be assessed for the complete presence&#xD;
           (score 2), incomplete presence (score 1) or absence (score0) of papillary tissue. The&#xD;
           curvature of the facial soft tissue line, also defined as the line of emergence of the&#xD;
           implant restoration from the soft tissues, will be evaluated as being identical (score 2&#xD;
           ), slightly different (score 1), or markedly different (score 0) compared to the natural&#xD;
           control tooth and thus, provided a natural symmetrical or disharmonious appearance and&#xD;
           in comparison to the contralateral tooth in terms of an identical vertical level (score&#xD;
           2), a slight (&lt;1 mm) discrepancy (score 1), or a major (&gt;1 mm) discrepancy (score 0).&#xD;
           Finally, the combined three additional specific soft tissue parameters as one variable:&#xD;
           the presence, partial presence, or absence of a convex profile (in analogy to a root&#xD;
           eminence) on the facial aspect, as-well-as-the-related-mucosal-color-and-surface&#xD;
           texture. To achieve a score of 2 for this-combination-variable,&#xD;
           all-three-parameters-were more-or-less-identical-compared-to-the-control-tooth. A value&#xD;
           of 1 will be given if two criteria are fulfilled, whereas a score of 0 will be given if&#xD;
           none or only one parameter matches the control site. (Tettamanti et al, 2014)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Visual analogue scale to measure postoperative pain.&#xD;
                Pain.score.reported.by.the.patient. directly.through.Visual.Analogue.Scale.score&#xD;
                (from 0 to 10. 0: no pain, 1: minimal pain, 5: moderate pain, 10: severe pain) VAS&#xD;
                will be recorded after 2 weeks (Yıldırım et al., 2017)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The OHIP (OHIP-14 questionnaire) Will be used to assess limitation of function ,&#xD;
                pain , discomfort, social , psychological ,physical disability and general&#xD;
                satisfaction. The OHIP-14 utilizes a scale with five categories (1 = never, 2 =&#xD;
                hardly ever, 3 = occasionally, 4 = fairly often, and 5 = very often).A lower score&#xD;
                in any of the five categories indicates higher satisfaction. (Al-zubeidi et al,&#xD;
                2011)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Soft tissue thickness will be measured at baseline and 9 months postoperatively&#xD;
                using.an.anesthetic.needle.with.a.rubber.stopper to pierce the gingiva horizontally&#xD;
                and perpendicular to the long axis of the tooth till bone contact 2mm coronal to&#xD;
                the MGJ and in the mid distance mesiodistally&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The part of the instrument penetrating into soft tissue will be measured in mm.&#xD;
                (Cairo et al 2017)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Radiographic Examination:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Cone Beam Computed Tomography (CBCT) will be taken at baseline before implant&#xD;
                placement and 9 months later to measure soft tissue thickness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The collected data will be revised, coded, tabulated and introduced to a PC using Statistical&#xD;
      package for Social Science (SPSS 15.0 for windows; SPSS Inc, Chicago, IL, 2001). Data will be&#xD;
      presented and suitable analysis will be done according to the type of data obtained for each&#xD;
      parameter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>volumetric changes of soft tissue at implant sites with siebert class I</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Is to evaluate the volumetric changes of soft tissues at implant sites with Siebert class I ridge defect after augmentation with volume stable collagen matrix in comparison with connective tissue grafting</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>esthetic outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>using pink esthetic score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>using a satisfaction questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Buccal Defect at Implant Sites</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group I (VCMX)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>includes 10 patients where implant placement will be performed followed by volume stable collagen matrix placement to augment the buccal defect.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group II (control)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Will include 10 patients where implant placement will be performed followed by connective tissue grafting to augment the buccal defect.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>volume stable collagen matrix placement</intervention_name>
    <description>volume stable collagen matrix placement to augment the buccal defect.in class I siebert at the same time of implant placement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group I (VCMX)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>connective tissue grafting</intervention_name>
    <description>connective tissue placement to augment the buccal defect.in class I siebert at the same time of implant placement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group II (control)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult patients in a healthy systemic condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Both genders with age ranging from 20 to 50 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients should have single missing tooth in anterior or premolar area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Seibert Class I ridge defect.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Sufficient bone height and width that doesn't necessitate bone grafting or any other&#xD;
             ridge augmentation protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Healing period of 3 months after extraction prior to surgical procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients should approve to deliver a signature to a written consent after study nature&#xD;
             explanation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with any smoking habits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant females, decisional impaired individuals, Prisoners and handicapped patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients having poor oral hygiene or not wanting to carry out oral hygiene measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with infections either periodontally or periapically.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>ahmed H mahmoud, Msc</last_name>
    <phone>00201061112512</phone>
    <email>dr-ahmedhamdy@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ain Shams Dental School</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11516</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>British University In Egypt</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>ahmed hamdy mahmoud</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant lecturer of periodontology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>siebert</keyword>
  <keyword>dental implant</keyword>
  <keyword>volume stable collagen matrix</keyword>
  <keyword>connective tissue</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

