<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04878315</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>213048</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04878315</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bioequivalence Study Between Capoten Versus Captopril Reference Product in Healthy Adult Participants Under Fasting Conditions</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Randomized Three Period, Three Sequence, Partially Replicated Crossover Bioequivalence Study of Two Oral Formulations of Captopril 50 mg Film Coated Tablets in Healthy Adult Participants Under Fasting Conditions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a bioequivalence study to compare Capoten (test product [T]) versus captopril&#xD;
      (reference product [R]) produced by Mylan Pharmaceuticals Spain, in healthy adult&#xD;
      participants under fasting condition. Capoten is the registered trademark of SmithKline&#xD;
      Beecham Egypt.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 14, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a 3-period, 2-treatment, 3-sequence, partially replicated crossover study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>It is an open-label study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed concentration (Cmax) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration-time curve from administration extrapolated to the last time of quantifiable concentration (AUC[0-t]) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the concentration-time curve from time zero extrapolated to infinite time (AUC[0-inf]) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to reach Cmax (Tmax) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination halftime (t1/2) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination rate constant (lambda-z) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of AUC(0-inf) obtained by extrapolation (%AUCex) of Captopril</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants reporting adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with abnormal hematology and biochemistry parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with abnormal electrocardiograms (ECGs) and vital signs findings</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence TRR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Capoten (T) in period 1 followed by Captopril (R) in period 2 followed by Captopril (R) in period 3.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence RTR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Captopril (R) in period 1 followed by Capoten (T) in period 2 followed by Captopril (R) in period 3.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence RRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive Captopril (R) in period 1 followed by Captopril (R) in period 2 followed by Capoten (T) in period 3.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Capoten</intervention_name>
    <description>Capoten will be administered per the treatment sequence</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence RRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence RTR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence TRR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Captopril</intervention_name>
    <description>Captopril will be administered per the treatment sequence</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence RRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence RTR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment sequence TRR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 to 50 years of age inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant does not have a known allergy to the drug under investigation, any of its&#xD;
             ingredients or any other related drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal vital signs after up to 10 minutes resting in supine position or 2 minutes in&#xD;
             sitting position: 100 millimeter of mercury (mmHg) =&lt; systolic blood pressure (SBP)&#xD;
             &lt;130 mmHg; 70 mmHg =&lt; diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &lt;90 mmHg; 60 beats per minute&#xD;
             (bpm) =&lt; Pulse rate (HR) =&lt; 100 bpm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal standard 12-lead ECG after 10 minutes resting in supine position in the&#xD;
             following ranges; 120 milliseconds (ms)&lt;PR&lt;220 ms, QRS&lt;120 ms, corrected QT interval&#xD;
             (QTc)=&lt;450 ms, and normal ECG tracing unless the Investigator considers an ECG tracing&#xD;
             abnormality to be not clinically relevant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory parameters within the normal range (or defined screening threshold for the&#xD;
             Investigator site), unless the Investigator considers an abnormality to be clinically&#xD;
             irrelevant for healthy participants; however serum creatinine, alkaline phosphatase,&#xD;
             hepatic enzymes (aspartate aminotransferase, alanine aminotransferase) should not&#xD;
             exceed 1.25 times the upper laboratory norm, and total bilirubin should not exceed the&#xD;
             upper laboratory normal (Laboratory tests are performed not longer than two weeks&#xD;
             before the initiation of the clinical study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight on 45 kilogram (kg) or more and body mass index (BMI) within the range&#xD;
             18.5-30 kilogram per meter square (kg/m^2) (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy Adult, Male and Female (woman of non-childbearing potential [WONCBP]); a) Male&#xD;
             participants are eligible to participate if they agree to the following during the&#xD;
             study intervention period and for at least 30 days after the last dose of the study&#xD;
             drug. Refrain from donating sperm PLUS, either: Be abstinent from heterosexual&#xD;
             intercourse as their preferred and usual lifestyle (abstinent on a long term and&#xD;
             persistent basis) and agree to remain abstinent OR Must agree to use&#xD;
             contraception/barrier as detailed in the protocol; Agree to use a male condom and&#xD;
             should also be advised of the benefit for a female partner to use a highly effective&#xD;
             method of contraception as a condom may break or leak when having sexual intercourse&#xD;
             with a woman of childbearing potential who is not currently pregnant, agree to use a&#xD;
             male condom when engaging in any activity that allows for passage of ejaculate to&#xD;
             another person. Contraceptive use by Men should be consistent with local regulations&#xD;
             regarding the methods of contraception for those participating in clinical studies.&#xD;
             Female Participants: is eligible to participate if: Is a WONCBP as defined in the&#xD;
             protocol. Additional requirements for testing are listed in the protocol. The&#xD;
             investigator is responsible for review of medical history, menstrual history, and&#xD;
             recent sexual activity to decrease the risk for inclusion of a woman with an early&#xD;
             undetected pregnancy. Female participants must use a double contraception method&#xD;
             including a highly effective method of birth control, except if she has undergone&#xD;
             sterilization at least 3 months earlier or is postmenopausal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of giving signed informed consent as described in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history or presence of clinically relevant cardiovascular including history of&#xD;
             hypotension and orthostatic hypotension, pulmonary, gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal,&#xD;
             metabolic, hematological, neurological, osteomuscular, articular, psychiatric,&#xD;
             systemic, ocular or infectious disease, or signs of acute illness, lactose&#xD;
             intolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Frequent headaches and/or migraine, recurrent nausea and/or vomiting (more than twice&#xD;
             a month).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood donation, any volume, within 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic postural hypotension, irrespective of the decrease in blood pressure, or&#xD;
             asymptomatic postural hypotension defined as a decrease in systolic blood pressure&#xD;
             &gt;=30 mmHg within 3 minutes when changing from supine to standing position.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of drug hypersensitivity, or allergic disease diagnosed and&#xD;
             treated by a physician. Participants with known hypersensitivity to any component of&#xD;
             the investigational medicinal product (IMP) formulation or allergic disease diagnosed&#xD;
             and treated by a physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of drug or alcohol abuse. History of regular alcohol consumption within one&#xD;
             year of the study defined as: an average weekly intake of &gt;14 drinks. One drink is&#xD;
             equivalent to 12 gram (g) of alcohol: 12 ounces (360 milliliter [mL]) of beer, 5&#xD;
             ounces (150 mL) of wine or 1.5 ounces (45 mL) of 80 proof distilled spirits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking regularly more than 5 cigarettes or equivalent per week, unable to stop&#xD;
             smoking during the study (occasional smoker can be enrolled). Excessive consumption of&#xD;
             beverages containing xanthine bases [more than 4 cups or glasses (average 100 mL) per&#xD;
             day].&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any prescribed medication, over the counter (OTC) medicines or medicinal&#xD;
             products during the last two weeks preceding the first dosing and until discharge from&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in a bioequivalence study or in a clinical study within the last 60 days&#xD;
             (2 months) before first study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive result on any of the following tests: hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg),&#xD;
             anti-hepatitis B core antibodies (anti-HBc Ab) if compound having possible immune&#xD;
             activities, anti-hepatitis C virus (anti-HCV) antibodies, anti-human immunodeficiency&#xD;
             virus 1 and 2 antibodies (anti-HIV1 and anti HIV2 Ab).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive result on urine drug screen (amphetamines/ methamphetamines, barbiturates,&#xD;
             benzodiazepines, cannabinoids, cocaine, opiates).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who has results of laboratory tests which are outside the normal range or&#xD;
             hemoglobin (Hb) or red blood cells (RBC) indices (mean corpuscular volume [MCV], mean&#xD;
             corpuscular hemoglobin [MCH] and mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration [MCHC])&#xD;
             with deviation outside 5% of the reference range at screening. (Laboratory tests are&#xD;
             performed not longer than two weeks before the initiation of the clinical study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have been on a specific/special diet during the 4 weeks before&#xD;
             screening and who cannot agree to eat the set clinical food menu during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Difficulty in swallowing tablets.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants that have a current active Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) infection,&#xD;
             either laboratory confirmed or according to the investigator's medical judgement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants known to be in contact with active COVID-19 positive individuals within&#xD;
             the past 14 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>US GSK Clinical Trials Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>877-379-3718</phone>
    <email>GSKClinicalSupportHD@gsk.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>EU GSK Clinical Trials Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0) 20 89904466</phone>
    <email>GSKClinicalSupportHD@gsk.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bioequivalence</keyword>
  <keyword>Capoten</keyword>
  <keyword>Captopril</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Captopril</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD for this study will be made available via the Clinical Study Data Request site.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>IPD will be made available within 6 months of publishing the results of the primary endpoints, a key secondary endpoints and safety data of the study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Access is provided after a research proposal is submitted and has received approval from the Independent Review Panel and after a Data Sharing Agreement is in place. Access is provided for an initial period of 12 months but an extension can be granted, when justified, for up to another 12 months.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://clinicalstudydatarequest.com</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

