<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04879212</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-1029</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04879212</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Effect of Electroacupuncture on Postoperative Analgesia After Cesarean Sectionanalgesia After Cesarean Section</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Effect of Electroacupuncture Combined With Fentanyl Patient-controlled Intravenous Analgesia on Postoperative Analgesia After Cesarean Section</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cesarean section is one of the most common operations in obstetrics. A survey shows that the&#xD;
      rate of cesarean section in China is more than 40%, and even more than 70%. At present, the&#xD;
      main analgesia methods after cesarean section are: patient controlled intravenous analgesia&#xD;
      (PCIA), single injection of opioids into spinal canal, nerve block technique, combined or&#xD;
      single oral drug for postoperative analgesia, etc. All kinds of postoperative analgesia&#xD;
      methods have their own advantages and disadvantages. At present, PCIA is widely used in&#xD;
      clinic, but it can cause side effects such as pruritus, nausea, vomiting and respiratory&#xD;
      depression. Therefore, it is urgent to find a safe, effective, economic, reliable and&#xD;
      operable treatment of PCIA for postoperative analgesia after cesarean section.&#xD;
      Electroacupuncture is a technology combining traditional acupuncture and modern&#xD;
      electrotherapy, which has a significant effect on acute and chronic pain. Studies have&#xD;
      confirmed that electroacupuncture can help parturient women to deliver and relieve pain after&#xD;
      delivery. However, there are few studies on the analgesic effect of Electroacupuncture on&#xD;
      pain after cesarean section, and there are a few reports on wrist ankle acupuncture. On the&#xD;
      basis of our previous research, we found that the frequency of 20 / 100Hz and 2Hz were the&#xD;
      best for EA analgesia, and the density wave. Electroacupuncture is an ideal choice for PCIA&#xD;
      analgesia after cesarean section because of its low price, rapid onset, long duration and no&#xD;
      adverse drug reactions. &quot;Zusanli&quot; belongs to the stomach meridian of Foot Yangming. It is the&#xD;
      meridian of multi Qi and multi blood. It has the effect of regulating meridians and&#xD;
      collaterals, dredging Qi and blood, and treating various kinds of abdominal pain. Sanyinjiao&#xD;
      belongs to the spleen meridian of foot Taiyin, which is the meeting of foot Taiyin, Jueyin&#xD;
      and Shaoyin. Since ancient times, Sanyinjiao has been a commonly used acupoint to relieve&#xD;
      labor pain. Modern studies have also shown that Sanyinjiao can relieve uterine contraction&#xD;
      pain by relieving uterine smooth muscle spasm, improving the state of uterine ischemia and&#xD;
      hypoxia, releasing a variety of central analgesic substances and so on Spleen and blood,&#xD;
      liver tonifying and kidney tonifying. Therefore, on the basis of conventional PCIA analgesia&#xD;
      combined with electroacupuncture at Zusanli and Sanyinjiao, we may play an auxiliary role in&#xD;
      analgesia for puerpera after cesarean section.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Electroacupuncture is an ideal choice for PCIA analgesia after cesarean section because of&#xD;
      its low price, rapid onset, long duration and no adverse drug reactions. &quot;Zusanli&quot; belongs to&#xD;
      the stomach meridian of Foot Yangming. It is the meridian of multi Qi and multi blood. It has&#xD;
      the effect of regulating meridians and collaterals, dredging Qi and blood, and treating&#xD;
      various kinds of abdominal pain. Sanyinjiao belongs to the spleen meridian of foot Taiyin,&#xD;
      which is the meeting of foot Taiyin, Jueyin and Shaoyin. Since ancient times, Sanyinjiao has&#xD;
      been a commonly used acupoint to relieve labor pain. Modern studies have also shown that&#xD;
      Sanyinjiao can relieve uterine contraction pain by relieving uterine smooth muscle spasm,&#xD;
      improving the state of uterine ischemia and hypoxia, releasing a variety of central analgesic&#xD;
      substances and so on Spleen and blood, liver tonifying and kidney tonifying. Therefore, on&#xD;
      the basis of conventional PCIA analgesia combined with electroacupuncture at Zusanli and&#xD;
      Sanyinjiao, we may play an auxiliary role in analgesia for puerpera after cesarean section.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>PCIA +Acupuncture group&#xD;
PCIA +2 Hz Electroacupuncture group&#xD;
PCIA +20/100 Hz Electroacupuncture group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of times PCIA is used</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours after operation</time_frame>
    <description>Number of times PCIA is used</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">153</enrollment>
  <condition>Cesarean Section</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PCIA +Acupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acupuncturing bilateral Zusanli (ST36) and Sanyinjiao (SP6) to connect Huatuo brand electroacupuncture apparatus, but no electricity. Acupuncture was given once a day. PCIA（patient controlled intravenous analgesia）.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PCIA +2 Hz Electroacupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acupuncture bilateral Zusanli (ST36) and Sanyinjiao (SP6) to connect Huatuo brand electroacupuncture apparatus, and the ipsilateral Zusanli, Sanyinjiao were respectively connected as a loop. The parameters of electroacupuncture were set as 2Hz, continuous wave, 25min, and current intensity was 0.1-5.0mA. Acupuncture was given once a day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PCIA +20/100 Hz Electroacupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acupuncture bilateral Zusanli (ST36) and Sanyinjiao (SP6) to connect Huatuo brand electroacupuncture apparatus, and the ipsilateral Zusanli, Sanyinjiao were respectively connected as a loop. The parameters of electroacupuncture were set as 20 / 100Hz, density wave, 25min, and current intensity was 0.1-5.0mA. Acupuncture was given once a day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PCIA +Acupuncture group:</intervention_name>
    <description>Acupuncturing bilateral Zusanli (ST36) and Sanyinjiao (SP6)</description>
    <arm_group_label>PCIA +2 Hz Electroacupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PCIA +20/100 Hz Electroacupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PCIA +Acupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PCIA +2 Hz Electroacupuncture group</other_name>
    <other_name>PCIA +20/100 Hz Electroacupuncture group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 22-40 years old, gestational age 31-42 weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There was no electroacupuncture treatment before cesarean section;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No food and drug allergy, no long-term use of analgesics; .They agreed and only&#xD;
             participated in one clinical project and signed the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suffering from complications after cesarean section, such as massive hemorrhage, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  There was a history of chronic pain before operation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cognitive impairment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skin lesions such as ulcers and eczema at the needling site are not suitable for&#xD;
             needling;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ying Jin</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>2nd Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, China</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ying Jin</last_name>
    <phone>+86 18806510786</phone>
    <email>yingjin666@zju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Liquan Wang</last_name>
    <phone>+86 15868448702</phone>
    <email>18806510786@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>2nd Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, China</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <state>Zhejiang</state>
        <zip>310009</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ying Jin</last_name>
      <phone>+86 1886510786</phone>
      <email>yingjin666@zju.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Analgesia, Electroacupuncture</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

