<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00326703</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Boeing001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00326703</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Aircraft Cabin Altitude on Passenger Comfort and Discomfort</brief_title>
  <official_title>Investigation to Determine the Effects of Aircraft Cabin Altitudes on Passenger Comfort and Discomfort</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Boeing Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Boeing Company</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Commercial aircraft passengers are exposed to atmospheric pressures ranging from the pressure&#xD;
      found at ground level to that encountered in the external environment at 8,000 feet. There is&#xD;
      some evidence in the medical literature that symptoms of acute mountain sickness can result&#xD;
      from ascent to altitudes of 6,300 to 10,000 feet by unacclimated persons during the first few&#xD;
      days following ascent, probably due to the hypoxia that results from breathing air at the&#xD;
      reduced ambient pressures at altitude. The logical hypothesis that follows is that exposure&#xD;
      to 8,000 feet could cause hypoxia sufficient to adversely affect the comfort and well being&#xD;
      of some commercial aircraft passengers on prolonged flights. There is insufficient data in&#xD;
      the literature to validate this hypothesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exercise at sea level and at altitude reduces arterial oxygen levels. The logical hypothesis&#xD;
      that follows is that the combination of moderate exercise and exposure to altitude could&#xD;
      cause hypoxia sufficiently severe to adversely affect the comfort and well being of some&#xD;
      people and that the combined effect of exercise and altitude on comfort and well being is&#xD;
      greater than the effect of exercise or altitude alone. Again, there is insufficient evidence&#xD;
      in the literature to substantiate this possibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this investigation is to test these hypotheses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Altitude affects human health and well being through its effect on tissue oxygenation by&#xD;
      altering the partial pressure of oxygen in the gas that enters the lungs. The partial&#xD;
      pressure of any component of a mixed gas is equal to the total pressure of the gas multiplied&#xD;
      by the fraction of the gas that is made up by the component--approximately 78% for nitrogen&#xD;
      and 21% for oxygen in air at all altitudes. As altitude increases, total air pressure&#xD;
      decreases and consequently, the partial pressures of all component gases, including oxygen,&#xD;
      decrease. As air is inhaled, it becomes saturated with water vapor from body tissues, further&#xD;
      reducing its partial pressure of oxygen. Tissue oxygenation, measured in terms of partial&#xD;
      pressure of oxygen in arterial blood (paO2), is directly related to the partial pressure of&#xD;
      oxygen in the gas entering the lungs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The United States Federal Aviation Agency requires that commercial aircraft be designed so&#xD;
      that the barometric pressure in the cabin at maximum cruise altitude exceeds that found in&#xD;
      the external atmosphere at 8,000 feet (565 mm Hg).1 The scientific basis for this limit is&#xD;
      unclear. Although there is a large body of knowledge concerning the effects of altitude on&#xD;
      humans, most of it involves healthy young people at altitudes higher than 8,000 feet. An&#xD;
      investigation of the effects of altitude on commercial airline passengers performed by&#xD;
      McFarland in 1937 found &quot;…older persons up to 72 years of age respond to moderate altitudes,&#xD;
      i.e., up to 16,000 feet, without unusual difficulties.&quot; However, the same author went on to&#xD;
      conclude, &quot;The human factors analysis presented here would suggest that the comfort and&#xD;
      well-being of airline passengers would be significantly benefited by as near sea level&#xD;
      conditions as possible. In any event, cabin altitudes of 3,000 - 5,000 feet should not be&#xD;
      exceeded.&quot; 2, 3 In 1986, the Committee on Airliner Cabin Air Quality of the National Research&#xD;
      Council (NRC) concluded, &quot;Similarly, the decrease in oxygen partial pressure (pO2) that&#xD;
      occurs at 8,000 feet is safe for normal people, but possibly hazardous for patients with&#xD;
      COPD.&quot; 4 In a report published in 2001, the NRC concluded that research into the effect of&#xD;
      cabin pressure on susceptible persons should be given high priority.5&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acute Mountain Sickness (AMS), a syndrome characterized by headache, anorexia, nausea,&#xD;
      vomiting, lassitude and sleep disturbance, the onset of which closely follows ascent to&#xD;
      altitude6 has been reported in 12 to 42% of visitors to altitudes ranging between 6,300 and&#xD;
      10,000 feet in the mountains of Colorado.7-12 The time course of these symptoms was not&#xD;
      reported in sufficient detail to allow characterization of their onset during the first&#xD;
      several hours after arrival at altitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypoxia-related medical problems during flight are rare..13-18 However, an unpublished&#xD;
      statistical model 19 predicts that at 8,000 feet a substantial proportion of persons whose&#xD;
      ages are similar to those of commercial aircraft passengers will experience paO2s below the&#xD;
      levels at which use of supplemental oxygen is recommended by various medical&#xD;
      authorities.20-24 If the recommendations for use of supplemental oxygen are valid,25, 26 it&#xD;
      is possible that exposure to these levels of hypoxia for up to 20 hours (the maximum&#xD;
      anticipated duration of commercial aircraft flight segments) could adversely affect the&#xD;
      comfort and well being of passengers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exercise has been demonstrated to reduce blood oxygenation in persons with normal&#xD;
      and abnormal pulmonary health.27-29 Some members of the aircraft crew perform moderate levels&#xD;
      of work as part of their job30-34, and exercise is recommended by some to alleviate the&#xD;
      discomfort experienced as a result of the prolonged inactivity encountered in flight. It is&#xD;
      unknown if moderate exercise has a beneficial or deleterious effect on the comfort and well&#xD;
      being of persons at altitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The terms &quot;comfort&quot; and &quot;well being&quot; are commonly used but imprecisely defined. &quot;Comfort&quot; has&#xD;
      been defined as the &quot;... circumstance under which one is able to concentrate fully on&#xD;
      selected tasks. No attention is given to the maintaining of well being.&quot; 35 &quot;Well being&quot; is&#xD;
      defined as &quot;The state of being healthy, happy, or prosperous.&quot; 36 This investigation will&#xD;
      measure the single concept of &quot;comfort and well being&quot; by using the following factors of the&#xD;
      Environmental Symptoms Questionnaire IV:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Factor 1, Cerebral Acute Mountain Sickness; Factor 2, Respiratory Acute Mountain Sickness;&#xD;
      and Factor 5, Distress.37&#xD;
&#xD;
      Low scores indicate a greater degree of comfort and well being than do high scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mild hypoxia has been reported to cause asymptomatic changes in oxygen saturation, heart&#xD;
      rate, blood pressure, visual function, short term memory, and fine motor coordination.38-41&#xD;
      Unpublished studies have found asymptomatic disorders of control of the pupillary muscles,&#xD;
      possibly due to an imbalance between sympathetic and parasympathetic nervous control.42&#xD;
&#xD;
      7. STUDY PLAN AND SCHEDULE&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.1 Study environment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because of the size of the altitude chamber, multiple &quot;runs&quot; will be required at each&#xD;
      altitude to evaluate the required number of test subjects. A &quot;run&quot; will consist of&#xD;
      appropriate test subject orientation, screening to exclude persons with temporarily&#xD;
      disqualifying health conditions (see Section 7.6.5), entry into the chamber, depressurization&#xD;
      to the selected altitude, maintenance of that pressure for a period of time not to exceed 20&#xD;
      hours during which outcome data will be collected and recorded, followed by repressurization&#xD;
      to sea level, final data collection and recording, and dismissal. A follow up telephone&#xD;
      interview will be conducted 5 to 7 days after the chamber run is completed (Attachment 6).&#xD;
      The same test subjects will not be used at multiple altitudes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the runs, test subjects will be seated in commercial aircraft seats and allowed to&#xD;
      sleep, eat, or walk about as they desire within the physical constraints of the altitude&#xD;
      chamber. Aircraft-type entertainment (magazines, books, videotapes) will be provided. Food&#xD;
      service and restroom facilities will be available in the chamber. Five test subjects will be&#xD;
      randomly selected to exercise on a treadmill ergometer at 3 mph for 10 minutes once an hour&#xD;
      for 9 hours to simulate create a the metabolic workload of 2500 to 3300 kcal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test subjects and in-chamber test personnel will be blinded to the altitude profile of the&#xD;
      run. For test altitudes equal to ground level, brief depressurization and repressurization&#xD;
      will be carried out to simulate the noise and pressure changes of a run at higher altitudes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following environmental parameters will be maintained within the specified limits for&#xD;
      each run:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pressure: Ground level Ambient +/- 2 mm Hg 2000' 707 mm Hg +/- 2 mm Hg 4000' 656 mm Hg +/- 2&#xD;
      mm Hg 6000' 609 mm Hg +/- 2 mm Hg 7000' 586 mm Hg +/- 2 mm Hg 8000' 564 mm Hg +/- 2 mm Hg&#xD;
&#xD;
      The low frequency with which medical emergencies are reported among airline passengers and&#xD;
      visitors to mountain resorts suggests that exposure to altitudes are safe. Therefore,&#xD;
      asymptomatic effects of altitude on physiologic parameters are not, a priori, considered&#xD;
      sufficiently severe to warrant consideration of design change, and are not included in the&#xD;
      altitude selection logic described in paragraph 7.3. Physiologic variables will be measured,&#xD;
      however, to demonstrate whether or not the hypoxia encountered during the test runs is&#xD;
      sufficiently severe to have any effect on the test subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.2.1 The following outcomes are of primary interest:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prevalence and severity of the following symptoms: Measured by:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fainting Observation Shortness of breath Questionnaire Chest Pain Questionnaire Nausea&#xD;
      Questionnaire Headache Questionnaire Malaise Questionnaire Short term memory dysfunction&#xD;
      Questionnaire Fatigue Questionnaire Fine Motor Coordination Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiologic/performance measures Measured by:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heart Rate Pulse oximeter Arterial oxygen saturation Pulse oximeter Visual acuity Snellen eye&#xD;
      chart Color perception FM 100 Hue Short term memory Kentucky Comprehensive Listening Test&#xD;
      Fine Motor Coordination Purdue Pegboard&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.2.2 Outcomes of secondary interest are:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prevalence and severity of the following symptoms: Measured by:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lightheadedness Questionnaire Dizziness Questionnaire Faintness Questionnaire Flushed&#xD;
      Questionnaire Chills Questionnaire Sweaty Questionnaire Shivering Questionnaire Tingling&#xD;
      Questionnaire Numbness Questionnaire Ear blockage Questionnaire Blurred vision Questionnaire&#xD;
      Tunnel vision Questionnaire Sleepiness Questionnaire Nervousness Questionnaire Irritability&#xD;
      Questionnaire Restlessness Questionnaire Depression Questionnaire Happiness Questionnaire&#xD;
      Combativeness/aggressiveness Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
      An enhanced Environmental Symptoms Questionnaire (ESQ IV) will be used to ascertain symptom&#xD;
      outcomes37. The enhancement consists of additional questions that elicit information&#xD;
      concerning the test subjects' perceptions of the chamber environment, recent food and drink&#xD;
      intake, and level of activity. It will be distributed prior to depressurization and&#xD;
      periodically throughout the run to ascertain the prevalence of symptoms, and an in-chamber&#xD;
      attendant will perform the physiologic and performance testing at selected times throughout&#xD;
      the run.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.5 Location of study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Center for Aerospace and Hyperbaric Medicine Oklahoma State University Center for Health&#xD;
      Sciences 801 East 91st Tulsa Oklahoma 74132&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6 Test subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test subjects will be recruited from Tulsa and the surrounding areas. Test subjects will be&#xD;
      given $18.00 per hour by Oklahoma State University as compensation for their participation in&#xD;
      this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following test subject selection criteria will be used to select a total of 216 test&#xD;
      subjects, 108 of whom will be randomly assigned in age strata to 0 and 8,000'. Should the&#xD;
      null hypothesis be rejected, 108 test subjects will be recruited for similar assignment to&#xD;
      each test altitude. This will be repeated until the altitude selection algorithm has been&#xD;
      completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.1. Age Distribution:52&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age Sedentary Proportion Sedentary (63 subjects) Exercising Proportion Exercising (45&#xD;
      subjects) Total # &lt; 30 11% 7 28% 13 20 30 - 39.9 17% 10 42% 19 29 40 - 49.9 25% 16 24% 11 27&#xD;
      50 - 59.9 25% 16 6% 2 18 60+ 22% 14 - - 14 Total 100% 63 100% 45 108&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.2. Gender Distribution for test subjects will be approximately 50% male and 50% female.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.3. Have flown on commercial flights during past 60 months, but not for 3 or more hours in&#xD;
      past 1 month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.4. Have not been above 4,000' in past 1 month.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.5. Medical History&#xD;
&#xD;
      Do not have a history of:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lung disease requiring medication or oxygen therapy at ground level Any of the following&#xD;
      conditions at AMA Class 3 or worse Chronic Obstructive Lung Disease Chronic&#xD;
      bronchitis/emphysema Asthma Restrictive Lung Diseases Any of the following cardiac conditions&#xD;
      at AMA Class 3 or worse Coronary Artery Disease Arrhythmia Congestive Heart Failure&#xD;
      Cerebrovascular disease Cerebrovascular accident (stroke) Lower Extremity Deep Vein&#xD;
      Thrombosis Diabetes mellitus, poorly controlled (change in medication doseage/ frequency in&#xD;
      past month) Seizure within past 6 months. Claustrophobia that would impair chamber&#xD;
      participation Musculoskeletal disorder that impairs self care and self locomotion. Current&#xD;
      anemia of any cause Sickle Cell Anemia Sickle Cell Trait Other conditions, which, in the&#xD;
      opinion of the Principal Investigator, might result in excessive risk upon exposure to a&#xD;
      hypobaric environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Shall not, at the time of the test:&#xD;
&#xD;
      have a contagious disease (including upper respiratory illness) be pregnant be within 4 weeks&#xD;
      of a major surgical procedure. have dental abscesses have been scuba diving within 24 hours&#xD;
      of test have donated blood within 24 hours of test be under the influence of drugs or alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
      Health status to be ascertained by questionnaire and interview before each chamber run.&#xD;
      Applicants who successfully complete the health questionnaire will undergo a phyical&#xD;
      examination by a qualified physician focusing on cardiovascular and pulmonary status before&#xD;
      final determination of eligibility will be made. Normal cardiovascular and pulmonary&#xD;
      examinations will be required for the applicant to be eligible for inclusion in the study.&#xD;
      Test subjects over 40 years of age who will be exercising at altitude will be required to&#xD;
      demonstrate their ability to exercise safely to 4.0 METS in a graded exercise tolerance test&#xD;
      to be performed before the day of the altitude chamber run.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A &quot;PreRun&quot; questionnaire will be administered the morning of the run before test subjects&#xD;
      enter the altitude chamber to determine if the test subjects have developed any disqualifying&#xD;
      conditions since undergoing the physician review. All PreRun questionnaires will be reviewed&#xD;
      by a Physician Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.6. Do not have special dietary needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.7. Can read and speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All questionnaires, routine and emergency instructions will be given in English. There are no&#xD;
      racial or ethnic exclusionary criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.8. Body Size: Body mass index less than 35 and Height less than 74&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The size of the commercial aircraft seats and the altitude chamber interior necessitate a&#xD;
      size limitation for the safety and comfort of participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7.6.9 Informed Consent: No applicant who has not voluntarily given informed consent to&#xD;
      participate will be allowed to participate in this study. Applicants will be given a draft&#xD;
      copy of the Informed Consent form to review when they are informed of the dates of&#xD;
      orientation sessions. The Informed Consent will be explained in detail during the&#xD;
      orientation, and all test subjects' questions concerning it and their participation in the&#xD;
      study will be explained. Only Physician and Scientific Researchers will obtain informed&#xD;
      consent from the candidates. All signed Informed Consent forms will be retained in accordance&#xD;
      with the Boeing Safety, Health, and Environmental Master Records Retention Schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8. STUDY EQUIPMENT AND PROTOCOLS&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.2 Protocols:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The detailed timeline of each run is given in Attachment 4. No test equipment will be&#xD;
      attached to the test subjects for the duration of the run. However, the detector of the pulse&#xD;
      oximeter will be intermittently clipped to each test subject's finger to measure blood&#xD;
      oxygenation. For each measurement, the detector will be attached for approximately 1 minute.&#xD;
      Throughout the test protocol from hour 2.5 till hour 14, the test subjects will be provided&#xD;
      with video entertainment and magazines, as they would have on a flight. Videos will be&#xD;
      stopped during survey times. The test subjects will be asked to bring with them those items&#xD;
      they normally take on a flight (books, work, etc.) and to wear clothing that they would wear&#xD;
      for a 20 hour flight.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At least one member of the team of investigators will be present in the altitude chamber at&#xD;
      all times during the test runs to conduct the testing and to monitor the condition of the&#xD;
      test subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Test subjects will be removed from the altitude chamber for the following reasons:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Test subject request&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Any of the following medical conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Loss of consciousness Chest pain that persists more than 5 minutes Shortness of breath&#xD;
           not relieved by reassurance Repeated vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Any other condition, which, in the judgment of the in-chamber observer or physician,&#xD;
           warrants removal for the safety of the test subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once a test subject leaves the chamber, he/she will not be allowed to return.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Altitude chamber runs will be scheduled to begin (Hour 0) at 9:00 am. Test subjects will&#xD;
      complete testing at approximately 6:30 am the following morning&#xD;
&#xD;
      The duration of the runs may be decreased if it is found that symptom prevalence and severity&#xD;
      plateau before 20 hours. This will be determined after all the sea level and 8,000' runs have&#xD;
      been completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.3 Research Methodology, Sampling and Data Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.3.1 Research Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the effects of moderate altitude exposure on comfort and well being, 108 test&#xD;
      subjects will be exposed to 8,000 foot-equivalent barometric pressure in an altitude chamber&#xD;
      for 20 hours and their responses to symptom survey questions will be compared to responses&#xD;
      from 100 test subjects exposed to ambient (ground) pressure for 20 hours in the same chamber.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will employ a Split-Split Plot Factorial design. The chamber runs are the&#xD;
      whole-plot units and the altitude (0', 8,000' and any intermediate altitudes) is the&#xD;
      whole-plot factor, a test subject is the split-plot unit with exercise as the split-plot&#xD;
      factor [Ex (exercise) vs Sed (sedentary)], and the repeated measurements on each test subject&#xD;
      represent the split-split unit with exposure time as the split-split plot factor. So under&#xD;
      this design the appropriate experimental unit for testing altitude differences is a chamber&#xD;
      run. The repeated measures in this study include the responses to the symptom items on the&#xD;
      questionnaires, which will be administered x times over the 20-hour time period, and the&#xD;
      measurements of PaO2, heart rate, etc., which will also be taken repeatedly over the time of&#xD;
      the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.3.2 Sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two hundred sixteen test subjects will serve in the study-approximately half will be female&#xD;
      and approximately half will be male. The age distribution breakdown is given in the table&#xD;
      below (note that for a given age range, approximately half of the test subjects will be male&#xD;
      and approximately half will be female). First, 216 test subjects will be selected that fit&#xD;
      the distribution given below. Then test subjects of a given gender within a given age range&#xD;
      will be randomly assigned to one of four conditions (0' Condition Ex; 0' Condition Sed;&#xD;
      8,000' Condition Ex; and 8,000' Condition Sed). See Attachment 8 for sample size&#xD;
      considerations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0' Condition 8,000' Condition Age # of Subj Ex M/F Sed M/F Ex M/F Sed M/F Ex M/F Sed M/F &lt; 30&#xD;
      40 13/13 7/7 6/7 4/3 7/6 3/4 30 - 39.9 58 19/19 10/10 10/9 5/5 9/10 5/5 40 - 49.9 54 11/11&#xD;
      16/16 5/6 8/8 6/5 8/8 50 - 59.9 36 2/2 16/16 1/1 8/8 1/1 8/8 60+ 28 - 14/14 - 7/7 - 7/7 Total&#xD;
      216 45/45 63/63 22/23 32/31 22/23 31/32&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.3.3 Data Collection and Confidentiality&#xD;
&#xD;
      Survey and telephone interview forms used for collection of test subject responses are shown&#xD;
      in Attachment 5. Data recording forms are shown in Attachment 6. The test subjects will be&#xD;
      identified on the survey forms by Test Subject Number alone. Data will be entered into an&#xD;
      electronic spread sheet using the Test Subject Number as identifier. To insure data&#xD;
      integrity, a spreadsheet linking Test Subject Number to name of test subject will be&#xD;
      available to the investigators. Spread sheets will reside on file servers protected by&#xD;
      password security access. When not in use, survey forms, telephone interview forms, and&#xD;
      laptops will be stored in locked cabinets. Paper records will be retained by The Boeing&#xD;
      Company and destroyed after 10 years. Electronic data will be stored in password protected&#xD;
      computers, or in similarly protected electronic format, indefinitely.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In preparation for data analysis, test subject responses and demographic information will be&#xD;
      merged using Test Subject Number, but names will not be included. Only grouped results will&#xD;
      be published. Nothing will be published in a form in which the test subject from which the&#xD;
      information arose can be identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8.3.4 Data Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      The symptom data will be analyzed for significant differences between the treatments by first&#xD;
      calculating AMS-R, AMS-C and AMS-D from the EQS questions. We will carry out the appropriate&#xD;
      Analysis of Variance (ANOVA) for the split-split plot factorial design to look at differences&#xD;
      due to altitude and main effects due to activity (Ex vs Sed) and interaction effects between&#xD;
      altitude and exercise. This ANOVA will also analyze the within test subject scores to&#xD;
      determine if symptom reporting changes over time. Second, the symptoms data will be recoded&#xD;
      to &quot;no symptom=0&quot; (0 response on the symptom scale) and &quot;symptom=1&quot; (a 1-6 response on the&#xD;
      symptom scale). These data will be analyzed for main effects and interaction effects between&#xD;
      altitude and exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The other dependent measures (SaO2, heart rate, etc.) will be analyzed using the appropriate&#xD;
      ANOVA for the split-split plot factorial design. These data will also be analyzed for main&#xD;
      effects (altitude and activity) and for changes over time, and for the altitude/activity&#xD;
      interaction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 2003</completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Single</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ESQ IV factor scores measured at 2 hour intervals</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen Saturation measured at 2 hour intervals</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment>500</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Mountain Sickness</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hypobaric hypoxia</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: age 21 - 75&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:Height greater than 6'2&quot;, BMI greater than 45. Specified acute or&#xD;
        chronic medical conditions -&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James M Muhm, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Boeing Company</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>May 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 15, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 15, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 17, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 16, 2006</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 16, 2006</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 17, 2006</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>hypoxia</keyword>
  <keyword>hypobaric</keyword>
  <keyword>altitude</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Altitude Sickness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

