<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00329511</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200-04</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00329511</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Comparison of Compliance Between Clonidine Patch and Methyldopa for the Treatment of Chronic Hypertension in Pregnancy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Comparison of Compliance Between Clonidine Patch and Methyldopa for the Treatment of Chronic Hypertension in Pregnancy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Afshan B. Hameed, M.D.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Irvine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      High blood pressure (BP) before pregnancy is called chronic hypertension (CHTN), and is&#xD;
      associated with an increased risk of development of pregnancy related high BP called&#xD;
      preeclampsia, preterm delivery, decreased growth of the fetus, fetal death, premature&#xD;
      separation of the placenta from the uterus resulting in damage to the fetus and cesarean&#xD;
      delivery. Longer duration and severity of CHTN in pregnancy leads to worse outcomes for the&#xD;
      mother and the fetus. Treatment of mild CHTN in pregnancy does not improve these outcomes,&#xD;
      and therefore, medications to lower BP are used for moderate to severe hypertension. To date&#xD;
      the literature on the medications used in pregnancy is extremely limited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methyldopa is used as a first choice medicine for CHTN in pregnancy. It acts on the central&#xD;
      nervous system (CNS) by relaxation of the blood vessels leading to a decrease in BP. It does&#xD;
      not decrease the blood flow to the uterus, placenta, or the fetus (4). Methyldopa is a weak&#xD;
      antihypertensive medicine given three or four times a day and frequently needs changes in the&#xD;
      dose or may require an additional medication to control BP. This may lead to a greater chance&#xD;
      of non compliance. Another option is Clonidine which is an effective antihypertensive&#xD;
      treatment and is available in many forms (oral, parenteral, and transdermal.) It acts on the&#xD;
      maternal CNS. Clonidine is not associated with teratogenic or neonatal side effects.&#xD;
      Transdermal clonidine (catapres-TTS®) is a preparation of clonidine hydrochloride that can be&#xD;
      released and absorbed transdermally over a 7-day period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will determine differences in compliance between the two antihypertensive regimens-&#xD;
      oral methyldopa and Catapres-TTS, comparisons of patient tolerability, compliance and&#xD;
      adequacy of BP control, as well as provide information on an alternate option for BP control.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of the Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this of open-label randomized clinical trial is to compare clonidine patch&#xD;
      (Catapres-TTS®) and orally administered methyldopa (Aldomet®) over a 4-week period for&#xD;
      compliance in pregnant women between 14 and 28 weeks of gestation. In addition, this study&#xD;
      will evaluate blood pressure (BP) control, patient tolerability, and development of side&#xD;
      effects to each medication. Patients will be alternately randomized to receive methyldopa&#xD;
      (standard of care) or clonidine patch.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clonidine is an effective antihypertensive agent with similar mechanism of action to&#xD;
      methyldopa. Transdermal clonidine may provide a better compliance profile, adequate BP&#xD;
      control and, therefore, may be used as an alternative to methyldopa for the treatment of CHTN&#xD;
      in pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome of the study is patient compliance. Compliance will be measured via patient&#xD;
      diary, promptness of keeping appointments, and pill/patch counts at each visit. Overall&#xD;
      compliance will be calculated over a 4 week study period by adding compliance points for each&#xD;
      visit as outlined in the data sheet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Change in mean arterial BP at weeks 1,2,3,4 in comparison to baseline BP at the initial&#xD;
           visit (It will be used in patients newly started on medications or in patients with&#xD;
           uncontrolled BP at baseline).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Side effects to each medication as reported by the patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background and Significance&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic hypertension (CHTN) affects 1-5% of pregnancies. It is defined as BP of 140/90 or&#xD;
      higher before the 20th week of gestation or beyond 12 weeks postpartum. CHTN is associated&#xD;
      with an increased risk of preeclampsia, preterm delivery, intrauterine growth restriction,&#xD;
      intrauterine fetal demise, placental abruption and cesarean delivery. Mild hypertension is&#xD;
      defined as BP &lt; 150/100 mm Hg and severe hypertension as BP &gt; 160/110 mm Hg. There is a&#xD;
      direct correlation of adverse perinatal outcomes with duration and severity of CHTN in&#xD;
      pregnancy. Treatment of mild CHTN in pregnancy does not improve perinatal outcomes, and&#xD;
      therefore, antihypertensive therapy is reserved for moderate to severe hypertension only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methyldopa is used as a first line therapy for CHTN in pregnancy. It is a central&#xD;
      alpha-adrenergic agonist that decreases peripheral sympathetic outflow and thus results in a&#xD;
      decrease in peripheral resistance and BP. It does not impact uteroplacental blood flow and&#xD;
      fetal hemodynamics. Methyldopa is a weak antihypertensive agent and often times there is a&#xD;
      need for increase in dose, frequency and/or addition of another medication to optimize BP&#xD;
      control with advancing gestational age. Side effects of methyldopa include sedation,&#xD;
      orthostatic hypotension, edema, weight gain, bradycardia, and dry mouth. Rarely, aggravation&#xD;
      of angina, congestive heart failure, pancreatitis, colitis, hyperprolactinemia, bone marrow&#xD;
      depression, hemolytic anemia, false positive anti-nuclear antibodies and rheumatoid factor&#xD;
      may be seen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of various classes of antihypertensive medications in pregnancy is limited due to&#xD;
      potential teratogenic effects. Angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors are contraindicated&#xD;
      in pregnancy. The use of beta-blockers and diuretics is controversial, and there is limited&#xD;
      data on calcium channel blockers in pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clonidine is an effective antihypertensive treatment and is available in oral, parenteral,&#xD;
      and transdermal dosage forms. Although oral and parenteral forms are commonly employed for&#xD;
      short-term use in hypertensive urgencies, data regarding its use in pregnancy are lacking. It&#xD;
      acts by stimulating α2-adrenergic receptors in the central nervous system (CNS), which&#xD;
      depresses peripheral sympathetic nervous system outflow, and thus lowering BP. Clonidine is&#xD;
      not associated with teratogenic effects in the fetus. Reproduction studies performed in&#xD;
      rabbits at doses up to 3 times the maximum recommended daily human dose (MRDHD) of clonidine&#xD;
      hydrochloride have revealed no evidence of teratogenic or embryotoxic potential. The&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics of clonidine in pregnancy has been studied. Clonidine crossed placenta and&#xD;
      fetal concentration is 0.89 of the maternal level. No neonatal side effects have been&#xD;
      reported. Clonidine is metabolized by the liver and is excreted unchanged in the urine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therapeutic levels of orally administered drugs are affected by the transit time through&#xD;
      small intestines and the presence of food and liquid in the gastrointestinal tract.&#xD;
      Transdermal administration of drugs by passes the first-pass metabolism through the liver,&#xD;
      requires smaller dose to achieve therapeutic effects, and promotes patient compliance. In&#xD;
      addition, the drug is absorbed through the skin at a constant rate eliminating peak and&#xD;
      troughs associated with oral administration. This may result in steadier BP control with&#xD;
      transdermal clonidine administration. This may be of benefit in pregnancy as the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal transit time is significantly prolonged due to progesterone effects and&#xD;
      nausea vomiting in the first trimester may limit the use of orally administered drugs. In&#xD;
      addition, one would expect improved patient compliance be avoiding repeated dosing such as&#xD;
      four times a day schedule for methyldopa.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Transdermal clonidine (Catapres-TTS®) is a preparation of clonidine hydrochloride that can be&#xD;
      released and absorbed transdermally over a 7-day period. Its side effect profile is similar&#xD;
      to methyldopa including tiredness, lethargy, drowsiness, constipation and dry mouth.&#xD;
      Orthostatic hypotension occurs in 3% patients with oral administration and has not been&#xD;
      reported with the transdermal form. Skin reactions including redness, itching, and darkening&#xD;
      of the skin may occur with clonidine patches. Rarely, angioedema, atrioventricular block,&#xD;
      chest pain, congestive heart failure, hepatitis, thrombocytopenia, or urinary retention may&#xD;
      occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study of hypertension in non-pregnant individuals from United Kingdom showed that only 40%&#xD;
      of patients who were started on a new antihypertensive drug were compliant six months later.&#xD;
      There are no data available on compliance with antihypertensive medications in pregnancy,&#xD;
      although our anecdotal experience is of improved compliance with medications in pregnancy&#xD;
      compared to a non-pregnant state.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our study will determine differences in compliance between the two antihypertensive drugs,&#xD;
      and will provide additional comparisons of patient tolerability and adequacy of BP control.&#xD;
      This may be of particular value in pregnant women who are unable to tolerate oral feeds e.g.&#xD;
      those with hyperemesis gravidarum, or in immediate postoperative period. In addition, it will&#xD;
      provide information on an alternate option for BP control, which has not been described in&#xD;
      obstetrical literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. National High Blood Pressure Educational Program Working Group. Report on High Blood&#xD;
           Pressure in Pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol 1990;163:1691-1712.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Report of the National High Blood Pressure Education Program Working Group on High Blood&#xD;
           Pressure in Pregnancy. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2000;183:S1-S22.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Chronic Hypertension in Pregnancy. ACOG Practice Bulletin No. 29. American College of&#xD;
           Obstetricians and Gynecologists. Obstet Gynecol 2001;98:177-185.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Montan S, Anandakumar C, Arulkumaran S, Ingemarsson I, Ratnam SS. Effects of Methyldopa&#xD;
           on Uteroplacental and Fetal Hemodynamics in Pregnancy Induced Hypertension. Am J Obstet&#xD;
           Gynecol 1993;168:152-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Horrath JS, Phippard A, Korda A, Hendersen-Sart DJ, Child A, Tiller DJ. Clonidine&#xD;
           Hydrochloride - A Safe and Effective Antihypertensive in Pregnancy. Obstet Gynecol&#xD;
           1985;66:634-8.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Turnbull AC, Ahmad S. Catapress in the Treatment of Hypertension in Pregnancy, A&#xD;
           Preliminary Study. In Hypertension. Symposium of the Royal College of Surgeons, London&#xD;
           1970:237-45&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Hartikainen-Sorri AL, Heikkinen JE, Koivisto M. Pharmacokinetics of Clonidine During&#xD;
           Pregnancy and Nursing. Obstet Gynecol 1987;69:598-600.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Ala-Kokko TI, Pienimaki P, Lampela E, Hollmen AI, Pelkonen O, Vahakangas K. Transfer of&#xD;
           Clonidine and Dexmedetrmidine Across the Isolated Perfused Human Placenta. Acta&#xD;
           Anesthesiol Scand 1997;41(2):313-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Jones JK, Gorkin L, Lian JF, Staffa JA, Fletcher AP. Discontinuation of and Changes in&#xD;
           Treatment after start of new courses of Antihypertensive Drugs: A Study of a United&#xD;
           Kingdom Population. BMJ 1995;311:293-5&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Feasibility of study. PI termination&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>September 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>methyldopa</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>clonidine patch</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>methyldopa vs. clonidine</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparison of compliance</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>clonidine patch</intervention_name>
    <description>methyldopa 250 - 750 mg qid clonidine patch 0.1 - 0.4 mg q week</description>
    <arm_group_label>A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>aldomet</other_name>
    <other_name>catapress tts</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Intrauterine pregnancy between 14 - 28 weeks of gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Chronic hypertension requiring antihypertensive therapy (BP &lt; 180/110)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects who consent to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No evidence of fetal compromise (i.e. intrauterine growth restriction)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Evidence or suspicion of preeclampsia&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known renal dysfunction (creatinine &gt; 1 mg/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known hepatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known cerebrovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Allergy to clonidine patch&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Afshan B Hameed, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, Irvine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Long Beach Memorial Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Long Beach</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90806</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 22, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 22, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 24, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 26, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 26, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 30, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Irvine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Afshan B. Hameed, M.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>hypertension</keyword>
  <keyword>compliance</keyword>
  <keyword>clonidine patch</keyword>
  <keyword>methyldopa</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension, Pregnancy-Induced</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Clonidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Methyldopa</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

