<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00119184</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-25/01/02-HMO-CTIL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00119184</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Spinal Analgesia Versus No Analgesia: Study for External Cephalic Version</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective Randomized Study to Examine the Success Rate of External Cephalic Version for Breech Presentation at Term Presentation: Spinal Analgesia Versus No Analgesia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hadassah Medical Organization</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hadassah Medical Organization</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to examine whether spinal anesthesia affects the chances of&#xD;
      successful external cephalic version (ECV) of a breech presenting fetus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two study groups will be included; one will receive spinal anesthesia, the other will not.&#xD;
      The non-spinal group will be permitted to cross over if ECV procedure is painful.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main outcome is success of ECV.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The rate of breech presentations in the general population of parturients has remained&#xD;
      unchanged at 3%. However, the recent finding that the fetus has an increased morbidity during&#xD;
      a vaginal delivery when compared with Cesarean section [1] has driven obstetricians towards&#xD;
      the decision that all breech presentations will be delivered surgically. The morbidity of the&#xD;
      mother with a breech presentation is not increased with a vaginal delivery; in fact the&#xD;
      maternal morbidity associated with surgery is higher than after a vaginal delivery [2,3].&#xD;
      Subsequent pregnancies are automatically deemed high risk due to the presence of a uterine&#xD;
      scar [4].&#xD;
&#xD;
      In an attempt to reduce the need for surgery with a breech presentation, the only option&#xD;
      available in the current climate, where a vaginal delivery is out of the question, is to&#xD;
      attempt to convert the fetal presentation from a breech to a vertex (head) presentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This technique may result in the premature onset of labor, which would require emergent&#xD;
      surgery, and there is also a risk of placental abruption [5]. Following external cephalic&#xD;
      version (ECV), the fetus may spontaneously return to the breech position. The success rates&#xD;
      vary from 30% in nulliparous women, to 67% in multiparous women [6].&#xD;
&#xD;
      In an attempt to improve the success rates of ECV, authors have previously utilized regional&#xD;
      anesthesia techniques [7-11]. Regional analgesia relaxes the stomach wall, and provides pain&#xD;
      relief during the ECV procedure. The use of regional analgesia has claimed to increase the&#xD;
      success rate of ECV to up to 80% [7]. However, other studies found no differences in success&#xD;
      rates between the group which received regional analgesia and the group that did not [12].&#xD;
      All of these studies looked at women who have reached at least 36 weeks gestation. Despite&#xD;
      the well-recognized differences in success rates between nulliparous and multiparous women,&#xD;
      none of the studies that have examined regional analgesia with ECV have controlled for this&#xD;
      factor in their studies. Thus the success rates, and any increase in success rates that is&#xD;
      seen, may purely be a function of the number of multiparous women enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will compare ECV separately in both a nulliparous and multiparous population, at&#xD;
      term, and compare the success rates when spinal anesthesia is employed, versus no anesthesia.&#xD;
      Success is defined as the conversion of a breech to vertex presentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is prospective and randomized. Both nulliparous and multiparous women will be&#xD;
      enrolled in the study, however each group will be randomized separately either to receive, or&#xD;
      not receive, neuraxial (spinal) analgesia. Approximately 50 nulliparous and 50 multiparous&#xD;
      women will be enrolled in each of the two groups. Randomization will be decided according to&#xD;
      the final number of the patient's identity number (odd numbers will receive spinal analgesia,&#xD;
      and even numbers will not receive analgesia). Written informed consent will be obtained prior&#xD;
      to inclusion in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All women will receive 20 mg nifedipine orally 30 minutes before the procedure according to&#xD;
      hospital protocol. They will have continuous fetal heart rate monitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After randomization, the spinal analgesia group (S) will receive 1000 cc Ringer's Lactate&#xD;
      solution. Additional monitoring will include ECG, non-invasive blood pressure and pulse&#xD;
      oximetry. In the sitting position, spinal anesthesia will be performed using a pencil-point&#xD;
      needle. 7.5 mg plain bupivacaine (Astra) will be injected intrathecally. The patient will be&#xD;
      reclined in a left lateral tilt, and the table will be adjusted in order to encourage the&#xD;
      spreading of the anesthetic drug to the T6 level. Once anesthesia is attained, the ECV&#xD;
      procedure will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The group assigned to receive no analgesia (N) will receive 1000 cc Ringer's Lactate solution&#xD;
      prior to the ECV procedure. These women will be monitored in the same way as group S. ECV&#xD;
      will be performed as usual. Women who are at an advanced stage of pregnancy, or have some&#xD;
      other obstetric indication for delivery on the day of the ECV, will be offered their spinal&#xD;
      analgesia with the addition of an epidural catheter (CSE-combined spinal epidural technique).&#xD;
      This technique is part of regular daily anesthesia practise, and allows for the&#xD;
      administration of additional analgesia after the effect of the spinal anesthesia has passed.&#xD;
      This would be sufficient either for labor or for Cesarean section analgesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2 obstetricians, at least one of whom has experience with the procedure, will perform the&#xD;
      ECV, with the aid of ultrasound surveillance. The ECV procedure will be halted if any of the&#xD;
      following occurs: fetal bradycardia, placental abruption, and failure of ECV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women from group N who are unable to tolerate the procedure due to discomfort will be&#xD;
      provided with regional analgesia, as described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results will be analyzed on an intention to treat basis. Demographic data including age,&#xD;
      parity, previous breech delivery, fetal size at 32 week ultrasound scan, and estimated amount&#xD;
      of amniotic fluid will be collected and analyzed by ANOVA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data regarding success of ECV and complications will be analyzed using student t test and Chi&#xD;
      square. Significance will be considered as p &lt; 0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Success of the anesthesia-assisted ECV technique will be defined as a significant increase in&#xD;
      the success rate of ECV, without a significant increase in the complication rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      References:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Hannah ME, Hannah WJ, Hewson SA. Planned caesarean section versus planned vaginal birth&#xD;
           for breech presentation at term: a randomized multicentre trial Term Breech&#xD;
           Collaborative Group. Lancet 2000 Oct; 356 (9239): 1368-9.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Sanchez-Ramos L, Wells TL, Adair CD. Route of breech delivery and maternal and neonatal&#xD;
           outcomes. Int J Gynecol Obstet 2001 Apr;73(1):7-14.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Jackson N, Paterson-Brown S. Physical Sequelae of caesarean section. Best Pract Res Clin&#xD;
           Obstet Gynecol 2001 Feb; 15 (1):49-61.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Mozurkewitch EL, Hutton EK. Elective repeat cesarean section versus trial of labor: a&#xD;
           metanalysis of the literature from 1989-1999. Am J Obstet Gynecol 2000 Nov;183 (5):&#xD;
           1187-97.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Kasule J, Chimbria TH, Brown IM. Controlled trial of external cephalic version. Br J&#xD;
           Obstet Gynaecol 1985;92:14-8.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Ezra Y, Elram T, Plotkin V, Elchalal U. Significance of success rate of external&#xD;
           cephalic versions and vaginal breech deliveries in counseling women with breech&#xD;
           presentation at term. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol 2000 May;90 (1):63-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Birnbach DJ, Matut J, Stein DJ et al. The effect of intrathecal analgesia on the success&#xD;
           of external cephalic version. Anesth Analg 2001 Aug; 93(2):410-3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Mancuso K, Yancey MK, Murphy JA et al. Epidural analgesia for cephalic version: a&#xD;
           randomized trial. Obstet Gynecol 2000 may;95(5):648-51.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Neiger R, Hennessy MD, Patel M. Reattempting failed external cephalic version under&#xD;
           epidural anesthesia. Am J Obstet Gynecol 1998 Nov;179(5):1136-9.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Schorr SJ, Speights SE, Ross EL et al. A randomized trial of epidural anesthesia to&#xD;
           improve external cephalic version success. Am J Obstet Gynecol 1997 Nov;177(5):1133-7.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Carlan SJ, Dent JM, Huckaby et al. The effect of epidural anesthesia on the safety and&#xD;
           success of external cephalic version at term. Anesth Analg 1994 Sept;79(3):525-8.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Dugoff L, Stamm CA, Jones OW 3rd et al. The effect of spinal anesthesia on the success&#xD;
           rate of external cephalic version: a randomized trial. Obstet Gynecol 1999&#xD;
           Mar;93(3):345-9.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Multiparas study terminated due to poor recruitment. Randomization revealed only after decision&#xD;
    recorded on clinicaltrials.gov&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>October 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2006</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Conversion of a breech to a vertex presentation</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications associated with ECV: Premature rupture of membranes, Contractions, Placental abruption, Fetal distress, Pain score during procedure (VAS Scale 0 = no pain, 10 = severe pain).</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications associated with analgesia: Severe maternal hypotension (&gt;20 reduction in systolic BP), Fetal distress (prior to performance of ECV), Post Dural Puncture Headache, Failure of analgesia.</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inability to perform procedure due to maternal distress or discomfort.</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mode of delivery and date from the ECV.</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Breech Presentation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>External cephalic version with spinal anesthesia</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>External cephalic version with spinal anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>External cephalic version without spinal anesthesia</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>External cephalic version without spinal anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>External cephalic version</intervention_name>
    <description>7.5 mg bupivacaine intrathecally</description>
    <arm_group_label>External cephalic version with spinal anesthesia</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>External cephalic version without spinal anesthesia</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>spinal anesthesia</intervention_name>
    <description>spinal anesthesia</description>
    <arm_group_label>External cephalic version with spinal anesthesia</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA I-II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  37 + weeks gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No previous attempt at ECV in this pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No fetal abnormality&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No previous uterine surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any contraindication for vaginal delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contra-indications to regional analgesia: uncorrected hypovolemia, coagulopathy&#xD;
             (including anti-coagulants but not low-dose [100mg] aspirin), infection or&#xD;
             inflammation of the skin overlying the lumbar area, raised intra-cranial pressure,&#xD;
             hypersensitivity to amide local anesthetic agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient refusal for regional analgesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of meningitis, neuropathy, or severe back pain with neurological&#xD;
             radiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor communication (no Hebrew or English spoken, deafness, blindness, serious&#xD;
             intellectual impairment or psychiatric disorder)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Morbid obesity&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carolyn F Weiniger, MB ChB</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dept Anesthesiology, Hadassah Hebrew University Medical School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah Hebrew University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <zip>12000</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2008</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 3, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 13, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 26, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 26, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 28, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Dr Carolyn Weiniger</name_title>
    <organization>Hadassah HMO</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>breech</keyword>
  <keyword>external cephalic version</keyword>
  <keyword>spinal</keyword>
  <keyword>success</keyword>
  <keyword>anesthesia,spinal</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breech Presentation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

