<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00113412</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SP01A-105-04</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00113412</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of an Oral Entry Inhibitor, SP01A, in Treatment-Experienced HIV-Infected Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multi-Center, Double-Blind, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Study Of Orally Administered SP01A As Monotherapy Treatment Of HIV-Infected Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Samaritan Pharmaceuticals, Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Samaritan Pharmaceuticals, Inc</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      One measurement of an HIV infected person's risk of progressing to AIDS is the number of&#xD;
      viral particles of HIV in their blood (called a &quot;viral load&quot;). In a previous phase I/II&#xD;
      study, SP01A was observed to significantly lower the amount of HIV in blood, improve quality&#xD;
      of life (how well subject's felt), have a favorable safety profile (minimal side effects),&#xD;
      and be well tolerated. Moreover, in in vitro testing SP01A: (1) demonstrated comparable or&#xD;
      greater efficacy than currently approved anti-HIV drugs in preventing HIV virus replication;&#xD;
      (2) was observed to have minimal toxic effect on human cells; and (3) demonstrated&#xD;
      significant efficacy in preventing virus replication of HIV virus strains that resist&#xD;
      currently approved anti-HIV treatments. Based on these results, SP01A demonstrates promise as&#xD;
      a new and novel anti-HIV treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this study is to further look at the dose response, efficacy, and safety of SP01A&#xD;
      as monotherapy, given as a capsule to be swallowed, in the treatment of HIV-infected&#xD;
      subjects. The investigators want to see if SP01A will lower the amount of HIV in blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be assigned by chance to 1 of 4 groups. Neither the subject nor the study&#xD;
      doctor or nurse will know which dose of the study drug the subject is taking or if the&#xD;
      subject is receiving the placebo (a capsule that looks like the study drug but does not&#xD;
      contain any active ingredient).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the 10-day study, the subject will be offered testing of their virus for&#xD;
      resistance to approved drugs (genotype) and transferred to their physician for continued&#xD;
      treatment with FDA-approved antiretroviral therapies. If the subject experiences a side&#xD;
      effect, which continues past the end of the study, they will be further monitored until the&#xD;
      side effect goes away.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-center, double-blind, randomized, placebo controlled Phase II study of orally&#xD;
      administered SP01A as monotherapy treatment in HIV-infected patients with evidence of&#xD;
      resistance to currently available antiretroviral therapy. This monotherapy study focuses on&#xD;
      HIV-infected subjects who have previously failed antiretroviral regimens (treatment failures;&#xD;
      defined as individuals with evidence of their viral load going up despite taking their&#xD;
      anti-HIV drugs precisely as prescribed).&#xD;
&#xD;
      HIV-positive subjects will be evaluated during the pre-study period. Following a 4-week&#xD;
      washout period (to ensure that any previous anti-HIV drug no longer remains in their system),&#xD;
      all study groups will initiate the 10-day monotherapy study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the conclusion of the 10-day monotherapy study, subjects will have the option of having&#xD;
      testing to determine the best anti-HIV treatment combination for their further treatment.&#xD;
      Further treatment, if indicated, will be limited to FDA-approved anti-HIV treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this study is to assess the dose-response, efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      orally administered SP01A as monotherapy treatment (study drug alone) of HIV-infected&#xD;
      subjects with evidence of resistance to currently available anti-HIV drug therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary analysis is the reduction in viral load (log10) within each SP01A study arm as&#xD;
      well as within the placebo arm as measured from the first day of drug administration (DAY-1&#xD;
      (Baseline)) to the last day of study drug administration (DAY-11 (Study-End)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary analysis is the reduction in viral load (log10) across SP01A active arms&#xD;
      measured from DAY-1 (Baseline) to DAY-11 (Study-End).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators may also test the HIV in each patient's blood to determine if one or more&#xD;
      HIV strains exists that are resistant to currently approved anti-HIV drugs. This testing will&#xD;
      be conducted at DAY-1 and Day-11. Additionally, the investigators may test to determine&#xD;
      whether the virus develops resistance to the study drug on DAY-11.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety will be assessed at each visit by laboratory evaluations, physical examination and/or&#xD;
      questioning for side effects. In the event of side effects, dosing of study drug may be&#xD;
      stopped according to provisions outlined in the protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>May 2005</start_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary objective of this study is to assess the dose-response, efficacy, and safety of orally administered SP01A as monotherapy treatment in HIV-infected patients with evidence of resistance to currently available antiretroviral therapy.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment>32</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SP01A</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible for inclusion into this study, patients must fulfill the following criteria&#xD;
        prior to the first day of study drug (i.e. Study Day-1) unless otherwise noted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be capable of giving informed consent. The principal investigator or&#xD;
             study nurse will be responsible for obtaining written informed consent from potential&#xD;
             patients prior to conducting any testing for the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2. Patient is HIV-positive and has treatment-experienced virologic failure or&#xD;
             documented resistance. Treatment-experienced virologic failure is defined as patients&#xD;
             meeting the following criteria; (1) previous experience with antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
             from at least two of the approved antiretroviral classes (i.e. treatment with a&#xD;
             nucleoside reverse transcriptase inhibitor, and/or non-nucleoside reverse&#xD;
             transcriptase inhibitor, and/or protease inhibitor) for three to six months; (2)&#xD;
             increasing HIV RNA after treatment had previously lowered viral load to low or&#xD;
             undetectable levels; (3) increasing viremia (HIV RNA &gt; 5,000 copies/mL) in at least&#xD;
             two viral load tests confirming their failing regimen. A patient does not need to&#xD;
             currently be on therapy. A patient that is currently on a stable antiretroviral&#xD;
             regimen that is successfully suppressing or maintaining viremia at low detectable&#xD;
             levels (HIV RNA &lt; 5,000 copies/mL) is not eligible for entry into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has been off all anti-viral medications, including any unapproved or&#xD;
             experimental treatment for HIV and antiretrovirals, for at least 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             Study Day-1 (baseline). The patient may initiate this 4 week period after screening,&#xD;
             if, in the judgment of the principal investigator, the patient qualifies for the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is at least 18 years of age and not older than 60 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is capable of adhering to the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a CD4+ count &gt;50 cells/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a viral load of &gt; 5000 copies/ml.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a Karnofsky score greater than or equal to 60.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients that are of childbearing potential: (1) have a negative urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test at screening, and agree to use a condom and another form of&#xD;
             contraception from the start of the study; or (2) are incapable of becoming pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients are ineligible to participate in the study if ANY of the following criteria are&#xD;
        met.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known or suspected allergy to procaine hydrochloride.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients using sulfonamides (including Septra/Bactrim). Sulfonamides should not be&#xD;
             used while on SP01A, because procaine will inactivate it. If a patient must be treated&#xD;
             with Septra/Bactrim, that patient will be removed from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with glaucoma using anti-cholinesterase inhibitors (Humorsol [demecarium&#xD;
             bromide] echothiophate iodide, Floropryl [isoflurophate], Isopto-Eserine&#xD;
             [physostigmine salicylate]). Anti-cholinesterase inhibitors should not be used while&#xD;
             on SP01A, since anticholinesterases inhibit the breakdown of procaine hydrochloride.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with SGOT baseline value &gt;3 times upper limit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with SGPT baseline value &gt;3 times upper limit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with creatinine &gt;2.0 mg/ dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with absolute neutrophil count &lt;1,000 cells/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with platelets baseline value &lt;75,000 cells/µl.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that currently have any active opportunistic infection. Prophylaxis for&#xD;
             Mycobacterium avium intracellulare (MAI), cytomegalovirus (CMV), Pneumocystis carinii&#xD;
             pneumonia (PCP), or herpes is permitted (excluding treatment with Sulfonamides).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females that are pregnant or breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing age who cannot either use dual contraception or&#xD;
             abstain from sexual intercourse during the clinical study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with less than 6 months life expectancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active hepatitis (viral or drug induced).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cancer, except peripheral (dermal) Kaposi's sarcoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that currently have an active alcohol or substance abuse problem.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any medical, psychological, psychiatric or substance use problem that,&#xD;
             in the opinion of the principal investigator, will interfere with the patient's&#xD;
             ability to complete the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A patient that is currently on a stable antiretroviral regimen that is successfully&#xD;
             suppressing or maintaining viremia at low detectable levels (HIV RNA &lt; 5,000&#xD;
             copies/ml) is not eligible for entry into the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erasto Saldi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Samaritan Pharmaceuticals, Inc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Therafirst Medical Centers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BioCollections Worldwide, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33137</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Orlando Immunology Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orlando</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32803</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Infectious Disease Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33614</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Anderson Medical Group</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15206</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tarant County Infectious Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Worth</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>76104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Health Science Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77009</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.samaritanpharma.com</url>
    <description>Samaritan Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xu J, Lecanu L, Han Z, Yao Z, Greeson J, Papadopoulos V. Inhibition of adrenal cortical steroid formation by procaine is mediated by reduction of the cAMP-induced 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl-coenzyme A reductase messenger ribonucleic acid levels. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2003 Dec;307(3):1148-57. Epub 2003 Oct 14.</citation>
    <PMID>14560037</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 7, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 8, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2006</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2006</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 22, 2006</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment Experienced</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

