<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04734379</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WP-0512-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04734379</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rho Kinase (ROCK) Inhibitor in Tauopathies - 1</brief_title>
  <acronym>ROCKIT-1</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2a Open-Label Preliminary Safety, Tolerability, and Biomarker Study of Oral Fasudil in Patients With the 4-Repeat Tauopathies of Progressive Supranuclear Palsy-Richardson Syndrome or Corticobasal Syndrome.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Woolsey Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Woolsey Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Phase 2a Open-Label Preliminary Safety, Tolerability, and Biomarker Study of Oral Fasudil&#xD;
      in Patients with the 4-Repeat Tauopathies of Progressive Supranuclear Palsy-Richardson&#xD;
      Syndrome or Corticobasal Syndrome&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After consent, participants will undergo screening evaluations, which may occur over the&#xD;
      course of up to 6 weeks. Subjects who meet inclusion/exclusion criteria will be enrolled into&#xD;
      the study and complete baseline evaluations. Dosing with study drug will begin on Day 1 and&#xD;
      continue for 48 weeks. Participants will return to the clinic at Week 1 (7 ± 2 days after the&#xD;
      first study drug administration) and at Weeks 12, 24, 36, and 48 for study evaluations, and&#xD;
      at Week 52 for post-treatment follow-up evaluations. Plasma biomarker collection will occur&#xD;
      at baseline, and Weeks 12, 24, 36, and 48. Cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) Biomarker collection&#xD;
      will occur at screening, Week 24 and Week 48. Brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) will&#xD;
      occur at screening, and Weeks 24 and 48. Safety labs will be collected at each study visit as&#xD;
      well as during Week 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse events (AEs) will be assessed at all visits and subjects will be contacted one day&#xD;
      after the start of treatment (that is, one day after Visit 1), and monthly thereafter&#xD;
      including at each visit. Subject will also be contacted one day after Visit 6/last day of&#xD;
      dosing with study drug for subjects who discontinue early.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects/caregivers will be queried for study drug compliance one day after the start of&#xD;
      treatment (that is, one day after Visit 1), and monthly thereafter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open label, single arm</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of adverse events [AEs] and serious adverse events [SAEs] as assessed by clinically significant abnormal physical examination findings; changes in vital signs; 12-lead electrocardiogram [ECG]; magnetic resonance imaging [MRI]; and hematology, blood chemistry, liver function, and urine tests.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phosphorylated tau</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with changes in concentrations of cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) and plasma phosphorylated tau</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarkers of neurodegeneration</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with changes in biomarkers of neurodegeneration, including neurofilament light chain (NfL), and total tau fragment levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Imaging biomarkers of neurodegeneration</measure>
    <time_frame>48 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with changes in imaging biomarkers of neurodegeneration, including changes in brain volume (whole brain, ventricles, hippocampus, frontal operculum, pre-central gyri, midbrain, pons and superior cerebellar peduncle) and white matter tract integrity (aslant tract, superior longitudinal fasciculus, and superior cerebellar peduncle) as determined by T1-weighted volumetric magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), diffusion tensor imaging (DTI)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Progressive Supranuclear Palsy</condition>
  <condition>Corticobasal Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral fasudil 180 mg/day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fasudil</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral fasudil 180 mg/day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Between 35 and 80 years of age (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to walk at least 10 steps with minimal assistance (stabilization of one arm or&#xD;
             use of cane/walker).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. MRI at Screening is consistent with the underlying neurodegenerative disease of the&#xD;
             respective diagnostic cohort (i.e. PSP-RS or CBS), with no large strokes or severe&#xD;
             white matter disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Mini-Mental State Exam (MMSE) at Screening is between 20 and 30 (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. For CBS: Amyloid beta (Aβ) positron emission tomography (PET) scan (florbetapir or&#xD;
             equivalent) at Screening is not consistent with underlying Alzheimer's disease (AD).&#xD;
             Previous Aβ PET scan negativity (assessed by a certified neuroradiologist) or previous&#xD;
             AD CSF biomarker (Aβ/tau level, P-tau181 or Aβ1-40 / Aβ1-42) or plasma AD biomarker&#xD;
             (P-tau181 or P-tau217) negativity may be used instead of performing an Aβ PET scan at&#xD;
             Screening at the Principal Investigator's (PI's) discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The following medications are allowed, but must be stable for 2 months prior to&#xD;
             Baseline:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. FDA-approved AD medications&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. FDA-approved Parkinson's Disease (PD) medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Other prescription medications are allowed as long as the dose is stable for 30 days&#xD;
             prior to Baseline. (Note Exclusion Criteria 17 and 18.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Has a reliable study partner who agrees to accompany the participant to visits, and&#xD;
             spends at least 5 hours per week with the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Signed and dated written informed consent obtained from the participant/legally&#xD;
             authorized representative (LAR) and the participant's study partner in accordance with&#xD;
             local Institutional Review Board (IRB) regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Women of childbearing potential (WCBP) must agree to abstain from sex or use an&#xD;
             adequate method of contraception for the duration of the screening period, the study&#xD;
             drug treatment period, and for 28 days after the last dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Males must agree to abstain from sex with WCBP or use an adequate method of&#xD;
             contraception for the duration of the study drug treatment period and for 75 days&#xD;
             after.&#xD;
&#xD;
             For PSP-RS Only&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Meets 2017 consensus criteria for possible or probable progressive supranuclear&#xD;
             palsy-Richardson syndrome (PSP-RS).&#xD;
&#xD;
             For CBS Only&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Meets 2013 consensus criteria for possible or probable corticobasal degeneration&#xD;
             (CBD), CBS subtype.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Meets criteria for probable AD established by the National Institute on Aging and the&#xD;
             Alzheimer's Association (NIA-AA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any other medical condition other than PSP-RS or CBS that could account for cognitive&#xD;
             or motor deficits (e.g., active seizure disorder, stroke, vascular dementia, substance&#xD;
             abuse or alcoholism).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of a prominent and sustained response to levodopa therapy in the opinion of&#xD;
             the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of significant cardiovascular, hematologic, renal, or hepatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Suicidal ideation per the Columbia-Suicide Severity Rating Scale (C-SSRS) that in the&#xD;
             opinion of the PI would pose a safety risk or interfere with the appropriate&#xD;
             interpretation of study data&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of major psychiatric illness or untreated depression that in the opinion of&#xD;
             the PI would pose a safety risk or interfere with the appropriate interpretation of&#xD;
             study data.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Neutrophil count &lt;1,500/mm3, platelets &lt;100,000/mm3, total bilirubin ≥1.5 x Upper&#xD;
             Limit of Normal (ULN), alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≥3 x ULN, aspartate&#xD;
             aminotransferase (AST) ≥3 x ULN, or International Normalized Ratio (INR) &gt;1.2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Serum creatinine &gt;1.3 mg/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Evidence of any clinically significant findings on screening or baseline evaluations&#xD;
             which, in the opinion of the PI would pose a safety risk or interfere with appropriate&#xD;
             interpretation of study data.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Current or recent history (within four weeks prior to Screening) of a clinically&#xD;
             significant bacterial, fungal, or mycobacterial infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Current clinically significant viral infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Major surgery within four weeks prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Any contraindication for MRI or unable to tolerate MRI scan at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Any contraindication to or unable to tolerate lumbar puncture at Screening, including&#xD;
             use of anticoagulant medications such as warfarin. Daily administration of aspirin up&#xD;
             to 81mg is not a contraindication, as long as the dose is stable for 30 days prior to&#xD;
             Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Participants who, in the opinion of the PI, are unable or unlikely to comply with the&#xD;
             dosing schedule or study evaluations.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Treatment with another investigational drug within 30 days or 5 half-lives of drug&#xD;
             before Baseline, whichever is longer. Treatment with investigational drugs other than&#xD;
             fasudil while on study will not be allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Treatment with systemic corticosteroids within 30 days or 5 half-lives of drug before&#xD;
             Baseline, whichever is longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. On more than one of the following drug classes: long-acting nitrates, beta-blockers,&#xD;
             or calcium channel blockers.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Known hypersensitivity to the inactive ingredients in the study drug (fasudil).&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Known to be pregnant or lactating; or positive pregnancy test at Screening or Baseline&#xD;
             (Day 1) for WCBP.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Cancer within 5 years of Screening, except for basal cell carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. History of serum or plasma progranulin level less than one standard deviation below&#xD;
             the normal participant mean for the laboratory performing the assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. History or evidence at Screening of known disease-associated mutations in GRN, TBK1,&#xD;
             C9ORF72, TARBP, CHMPB2, or VCP genes (FTLD causative gene mutations not associated&#xD;
             with underlying tau pathology).&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Blood pressure &lt; 90/60.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Evidence of orthostatic hypotension.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter Ljubenkov, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UCSF Weill Institute for Neurosciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Irina Gorodetskaya</last_name>
    <phone>415-476-2941</phone>
    <email>Irina.Gorodetskaya@ucsf.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mary Koestler, RN</last_name>
    <phone>415-476-0661</phone>
    <email>Mary.Koestler@ucsf.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Weill Institute for Neurosciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94158</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Peter Ljubenkov, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Peter Ljubenkov, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Supranuclear Palsy, Progressive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tauopathies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fasudil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

