<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733027</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IC 2018-06</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733027</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>First-in-human Phase I to Evaluate PEP-010 as Single Agent and in Combination With Paclitaxel (CleverPeptide)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Dose Escalation, First-in-human Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety, Pharmacokinetics and Preliminary Antitumor Activity of PEP-010, Administered as Single Agent and in Combination With Paclitaxel in Patients With Metastatic Solid Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut Curie</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut Curie</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, non-controlled, multicenter, dose escalation, first-in-human phase I&#xD;
      clinical trial with an expansion phase designed to assess the safety, tolerability, PK and PD&#xD;
      parameters, and preliminary antitumor activity of intravenous dosing of PEP-010 as single&#xD;
      agent and in combination with paclitaxel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PEP-010 will be administered as single agent in patients with solid cancers who are not&#xD;
      amenable to standard treatment, or in combination in patients who are eligible for the&#xD;
      paclitaxel therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PEP-010 will be administered on days 1, 2 and 3 every week. Treatment will be administered&#xD;
      until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, death or withdrawal of consent, whichever&#xD;
      occurs first. Each cycle will be of 21 days duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The initial starting dose of PEP-010, DL1 is selected based on pre-clinical data at 0.15&#xD;
      mg/kg. The other doses per injection from DL2 to DL7 are 0.3, 0.6; 1.2; 2.5; 5 and 10 mg/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For patients in Arm B, PEP-010 will be combined with Paclitaxel, at a dose of 80 mg/m²,&#xD;
      weekly until disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. Paclitaxel will be administered&#xD;
      according to local guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective for Dose escalation cohorts is to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD)&#xD;
      and the recommended phase 2 dose (RP2D) of PEP-010 when administered as single agent&#xD;
      (MTD1/RP2D1), and in combination with paclitaxel (MTD2/RP2D2) by recording the dose-limiting&#xD;
      toxicities (DLTs).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective for Expansion cohorts is to confirm the RP2Ds of PEP-010 as a single agent&#xD;
      and/or in combination in patients with metastatic and/or recurrent cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the safety and tolerability of PEP-010 when administered as single agent,&#xD;
           and in combination with paclitaxel.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the pharmacokinetics (PK) of PEP-010 as single agent, and in combination with&#xD;
           paclitaxel in Dose escalation cohorts.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the pharmacodynamic (PD) effects of PEP-010 as single agent, and in&#xD;
           combination with paclitaxel.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the preliminary antitumor activity of PEP-010 alone and in combination with&#xD;
           paclitaxel, using Objective Response Rate (ORR), Progression-Free Survival (PFS)&#xD;
           according to RECIST1.1, duration of response, and Overall Survival (OS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the immunogenicity of PEP-010 as single agent, and in combination with&#xD;
           paclitaxel in Dose escalation cohorts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The phase Ia dose escalation then expansion phase Ib</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of occurrence of dose-limiting toxicities (DLT) within cycle 1 (21 days) after initiation of the study treatment for both parts.</measure>
    <time_frame>21 days after study treatment initiation</time_frame>
    <description>The DLT is defined as any clinically significant non-hematological toxicity ≥ grade 3 and any hematological toxicity ≥ grade 4 of treatment-related adverse event</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">56</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Solid Tumor Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: PEP010 as single agent</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In arm A, the dose escalation phase will use accelerated titration design (ATD) for the first 4 dose levels (0.15, 0.3, 0.6, 1.2 mg/kg), followed by 3+3 design</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: PEP010 in combination with paclitaxel.</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In arm B, the dose escalation phase will begin with DL4 (1.2 mg/kg) and will follow a 3+3 design</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dose escalation, first-in-human phase I clinical trial with an Expansion phase</intervention_name>
    <description>PEP-010 will be administered on days 1, 2 and 3 every week, as a 3-hour intravenous infusion. Treatment will be administered until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity, death or withdrawal of consent, whichever occurs first. Each cycle will be of 21 days duration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: PEP010 as single agent</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: PEP010 in combination with paclitaxel.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Part I and II, Arms A and B:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Arm A: Patients must have histologically confirmed diagnosis of recurrent and/or&#xD;
             metastatic solid tumors, who are not amenable to standard therapy, with exceptions as&#xD;
             defined in the non-inclusion criteria,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Arm B: Patients must have histologically confirmed diagnosis of recurrent and/or&#xD;
             metastatic solid tumors. Patients must be eligible for a treatment with paclitaxel as&#xD;
             single agent. Patients who are eligible for standard of care paclitaxel-based&#xD;
             combination therapy should not be included in the trial, unless they have been&#xD;
             previously exposed to that specific combination therapy. Specifically :&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with ovarian cancer must have received prior therapy with paclitaxel as&#xD;
                  part of standard of care in combination with carboplatin.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with triple negative breast cancer are eligible for the trial since&#xD;
                  paclitaxel as single agent is standard of care in this disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age ≥ 18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) of 0 or 1,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must have measurable disease (as per RECIST version 1.1),&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient ability to comply with the collection of tumor biopsies, and tumors must be&#xD;
             accessible for biopsy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate bone marrow function as defined by: Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) of ≥ 1.5&#xD;
             x 109/L, platelet count of ≥ 100 x 109/L, and hemoglobin of ≥ 9 g/dL),&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate liver function, as determined by a serum total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 Upper Limit of&#xD;
             Normal (ULN), AST and ALT ≤ 3 x ULN (≤ 5 x ULN if liver metastases),&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate renal function, as determined by a serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN,&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Provision of signed written informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient ability to comply with protocol requirements,&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. If the patient is female:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient must be postmenopausal, surgically sterile, or they must agree to use a&#xD;
                  physical barrier method of contraception in addition to either an intrauterine&#xD;
                  device or hormonal contraception until at least 6 months after termination of&#xD;
                  study drug, or must refrain from heterosexual activity during this same period.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within the&#xD;
                  seven days prior to the first study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
             If the patient is male: patient must abstain from heterosexual activity or must agree&#xD;
             to use an acceptable method of contraception (e.g. condom) during the study for at&#xD;
             least 6 months after termination of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients covered by a health insurance system,&#xD;
&#xD;
             Specific Part II:&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Triple negative breast cancer and/or ovary cancer for the two first expansion cohorts&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Whatever lines of treatment with a previous treatment of taxane family&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Arm B: Allergy or hypersensitivity to components of the paclitaxel formulation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Allergy or hypersensitivity to PEP-010 formulation (Trehalose, Tween 20)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with known or suspected Central Nervous System (CNS) metastases including&#xD;
             leptomenigeal metastasis (except patient with radiographically stable, asymptomatic&#xD;
             previously irradiated lesion provided patient is ≥ 4 weeks beyond completing cranial&#xD;
             irradiation and ≥ 3 weeks of corticosteroids therapy),&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Evidence of significant, uncontrolled concomitant diseases, which could affect&#xD;
             compliance with the protocol or interpretation of results, including significant&#xD;
             cardiovascular disease (such as New York Heart Association Class III or IV cardiac&#xD;
             disease, myocardial infarction within the last 6 months, unstable arrhythmias, or&#xD;
             unstable angina), or pulmonary disease (including obstructive pulmonary disease and&#xD;
             history of symptomatic bronchospasm),&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Concomitant cancer in the past 3 years except prostate cancer controlled by hormone&#xD;
             therapy, cutaneous cancers (except melanoma) and in situ carcinoma,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Prior chemotherapy, radiotherapy (other than short cycle of palliative radiotherapy),&#xD;
             immunotherapy within 21 days of first receipt of study drug,&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Prior investigational agent within 30 days of first PEP-010 administration,&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Hormone therapy within 14 days of first receipt of study drug, with exception of&#xD;
             Gonadotropin-Releasing Hormone (GnRH) or Luteinizing-Hormone-Releasing Hormone (LHRH)&#xD;
             agonists used for advanced prostate cancer, if indicated,&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Prior relevant toxicities from chemotherapy or radiotherapy which have not regressed&#xD;
             to grade ≤1 severity except alopecia (NCI-CTCAE version 5.0),&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with acute infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any other uncontrolled diseases, metabolic dysfunction, physical examination finding,&#xD;
             or clinical laboratory finding or any other medical condition that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the investigator, contraindicates the use of an investigational drug, or will impose&#xD;
             excessive risk to the patient,&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients with known HIV, HBV and HCV infections,&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient with a positive screening test for Sars-Cov-2&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Pregnant or lactating women,&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients with altered mental status or psychiatric disorder that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the investigator, would preclude a valid patient informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Person deprived of liberty or under guardianship.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christophe LE TOURNEAU, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institut Curie</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anne-Claire COYNE, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00 33 1 56 24 32 40</phone>
    <email>drci.promotion@curie.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Anne-Claire COYNE</last_name>
    <phone>00 33 1 56 24 59 44</phone>
    <email>drci.promotion@curie.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CLCC F.Baclesse Caen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Caen</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elodie COQUAN, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elodie COQUAN, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Curie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75005</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christophe Le Tourneau, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christophe LE TOURNEAU, PR</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gustave Roussy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sophie POSTEL-VINAY, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sophie POSTEL-VINAY, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>1.Ezzalfani M. et al. The role of the expansion cohort in phase I trials in oncology: guidelines of the phase I HUB. Bull Cancer. 2015 Jan;102(1):73-82. doi:10.1016/j.bulcan. 2014.10.001. Epub 2015 Jan 2. Review. French. 2.M3(R2) guideline : Nonclinical Safety Studies for the Conduct of Human Clinical Trials and Marketing Authorization for Pharmaceuticals 3.ICH S9 - Nonclinical Evaluation for Anticancer Pharmaceuticals EMEA/CHMP/ICH/646107/2008 4.Masini et al. Histamin-releasing properties of polysorbate 80 in vitro and in vivo: correlation 1254 with its hypotensive action in the dog. Agents Actions 1985 Sep; 16(6):470-7. 5.Guideline on repeated dose toxicity - CPMP/SWP/1042/99 Rev 1 6.Storer B.E. Design and Analysis of Phase I Clinical Trials. Biometrics, Vol. 45, No. 3 (Sep., 1989), pp. 925-937. 7.Seshan V.E. et al. Clinical Trial Design and Data Analysis Functions, Package clinfun, version 1.0.15 (Apr 2018)</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

