<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04738708</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>002.1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04738708</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telegenetics or In-Person Genetic Counselling</brief_title>
  <official_title>Telegenetics or In-Person Genetic Counselling: A Comparison of Clinical Outcomes and Cost</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Centre, Singapore</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Centre, Singapore</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to compare clinical outcomes (informed choice and genetic counselling&#xD;
      outcomes) and cost (provider and patient time, travel, and telehealth platform) between&#xD;
      telegenetics and in-person genetic counselling.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will clarify if telegenetics is a feasible and non-inferior alternative to&#xD;
      in-person cancer genetic counselling. It aims to recruit 250 prospective patients attending&#xD;
      genetic counselling for Hereditary Breast and Ovarian Cancer (HBOC) and Lynch Syndrome in&#xD;
      Clinical Genetic Services (CGS) at National Cancer Centre Singapore (NCCS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomised 1:1 to telegenetics or in-person genetic counselling where 125&#xD;
      patients will be seen using video conference while another 125 will be seen face-to-face. The&#xD;
      randomisation will be stratified by suspected hereditary condition (HBOC/ Lynch) and age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon completion of the genetic consultation appointments, patients will be completing a&#xD;
      series of questions evaluating cognitive and psychosocial outcomes through an internet-facing&#xD;
      questionnaire.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Genomics Outcome Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcomes will be compared with a 6 item Genomics Outcome Scale (GOS) across five domains (decisional control, cognitive control, behavioral control, emotional regulation and hope) which are rated on a 5-point Likert scale ranging from &quot;strongly agree&quot; to &quot;strongly disagree&quot;. Scores are summed to provide an overall &quot;empowerment&quot; where higher scores equal higher levels of empowerment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adapted Multidimensional Measure of Informed Choice (MMIC) for Hereditary Breast and Ovarian Cancer (HBOC) and Lynch</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Participant's knowledge and attitude of HBOC and Lynch syndrome will be compared with a multi-dimensional measure of informed choice (MMIC) which composed of 11 items for knowledge of HBOC or 12 items for knowledge of Lynch syndrome and 4 items for attitudes. Items will be summed with a score or rated on a 7-pointed Likert scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Genetic Counselling Satisfaction Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Genetic counselling satisfaction is measured with a 6 item Genetic Counselling Satisfaction Scale. Items will be rated on a 5-point Likert scale and summed. Higher scores indicating higher satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Telehealth Patient Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Telehealth satisfaction is measured with a 7 item Telehealth Patient Survey. Items will be rated on a 5-point Likert scale and summed. Higher scores indicating higher satisfaction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Genetic Counselling</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Telemedicine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telemedicine</intervention_name>
    <description>Referring to the interactions between remote healthcare professionals and patient/ caregivers for the purposes of direct clinical care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Telemedicine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Routine in-person counselling</intervention_name>
    <description>Face-to-face genetic counselling.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 21 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients referred to CGS at NCCS or NBOC or Lynch syndrome pre-test genetic&#xD;
             counselling.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read and understand the English Language.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to consent and agree to be randomized to either telegenetics or in-person genetic&#xD;
             counselling.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under the age of 21 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who require genetic results urgently.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive difficulty/ impairment or current psychiatric or physical illness (visual/&#xD;
             hearing/ neurological) which impairs sound judgement and accurate reporting of medical&#xD;
             history over video consultation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ryan Tan</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Centre, Singapore</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ryan Tan</last_name>
    <phone>+65 6436 8000</phone>
    <email>ryan.shea.tan.y.c@singhealth.com.sg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Centre Singapore</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169610</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee AKF, Cho RHW, Lau EHL, Cheng HK, Wong EWY, Ku PKM, Chan JYK, Yeung ZWC. Mitigation of head and neck cancer service disruption during COVID-19 in Hong Kong through telehealth and multi-institutional collaboration. Head Neck. 2020 Jul;42(7):1454-1459. doi: 10.1002/hed.26226. Epub 2020 May 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32357277</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lonergan PE, Washington Iii SL, Branagan L, Gleason N, Pruthi RS, Carroll PR, Odisho AY. Rapid Utilization of Telehealth in a Comprehensive Cancer Center as a Response to COVID-19: Cross-Sectional Analysis. J Med Internet Res. 2020 Jul 6;22(7):e19322. doi: 10.2196/19322.</citation>
    <PMID>32568721</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pramesh CS, Badwe RA. Cancer Management in India during Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2020 May 14;382(20):e61. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2011595. Epub 2020 Apr 28.</citation>
    <PMID>32343498</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van de Haar J, Hoes LR, Coles CE, Seamon K, Fröhling S, Jäger D, Valenza F, de Braud F, De Petris L, Bergh J, Ernberg I, Besse B, Barlesi F, Garralda E, Piris-Giménez A, Baumann M, Apolone G, Soria JC, Tabernero J, Caldas C, Voest EE. Caring for patients with cancer in the COVID-19 era. Nat Med. 2020 May;26(5):665-671. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0874-8. Epub 2020 Apr 16. Review. Erratum in: Nat Med. 2020 Jul;26(7):1146.</citation>
    <PMID>32405058</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong ZW, Cross HL. Telehealth in cancer care during the COVID-19 pandemic. Med J Aust. 2020 Sep;213(5):237-237.e1. doi: 10.5694/mja2.50740. Epub 2020 Aug 16.</citation>
    <PMID>32803783</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dickinson R, Hall S, Sinclair JE, Bond C, Murchie P. Using technology to deliver cancer follow-up: a systematic review. BMC Cancer. 2014 May 3;14:311. doi: 10.1186/1471-2407-14-311. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24885758</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Finnane A, Dallest K, Janda M, Soyer HP. Teledermatology for the Diagnosis and Management of Skin Cancer: A Systematic Review. JAMA Dermatol. 2017 Mar 1;153(3):319-327. doi: 10.1001/jamadermatol.2016.4361. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27926766</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kubendran S, Sivamurthy S, Schaefer GB. A novel approach in pediatric telegenetic services: geneticist, pediatrician and genetic counselor team. Genet Med. 2017 Nov;19(11):1260-1267. doi: 10.1038/gim.2017.45. Epub 2017 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>28471436</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agha Z, Schapira RM, Laud PW, McNutt G, Roter DL. Patient satisfaction with physician-patient communication during telemedicine. Telemed J E Health. 2009 Nov;15(9):830-9. doi: 10.1089/tmj.2009.0030.</citation>
    <PMID>19919189</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hennemann-Krause L, Lopes AJ, Araújo JA, Petersen EM, Nunes RA. The assessment of telemedicine to support outpatient palliative care in advanced cancer. Palliat Support Care. 2015 Aug;13(4):1025-30. doi: 10.1017/S147895151400100X. Epub 2014 Aug 27.</citation>
    <PMID>25159308</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sabesan S, Larkins S, Evans R, Varma S, Andrews A, Beuttner P, Brennan S, Young M. Telemedicine for rural cancer care in North Queensland: bringing cancer care home. Aust J Rural Health. 2012 Oct;20(5):259-64. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-1584.2012.01299.x.</citation>
    <PMID>22998200</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buchanan AH, Datta SK, Skinner CS, Hollowell GP, Beresford HF, Freeland T, Rogers B, Boling J, Marcom PK, Adams MB. Randomized Trial of Telegenetics vs. In-Person Cancer Genetic Counseling: Cost, Patient Satisfaction and Attendance. J Genet Couns. 2015 Dec;24(6):961-70. doi: 10.1007/s10897-015-9836-6. Epub 2015 Apr 3.</citation>
    <PMID>25833335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schwartz MD, Valdimarsdottir HB, Peshkin BN, Mandelblatt J, Nusbaum R, Huang AT, Chang Y, Graves K, Isaacs C, Wood M, McKinnon W, Garber J, McCormick S, Kinney AY, Luta G, Kelleher S, Leventhal KG, Vegella P, Tong A, King L. Randomized noninferiority trial of telephone versus in-person genetic counseling for hereditary breast and ovarian cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2014 Mar 1;32(7):618-26. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2013.51.3226. Epub 2014 Jan 21.</citation>
    <PMID>24449235</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thaker DA, Monypenny R, Olver I, Sabesan S. Cost savings from a telemedicine model of care in northern Queensland, Australia. Med J Aust. 2013 Sep 16;199(6):414-7.</citation>
    <PMID>24033216</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marteau TM, Dormandy E, Michie S. A measure of informed choice. Health Expect. 2001 Jun;4(2):99-108.</citation>
    <PMID>11359540</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vadaparampil ST, Quinn GP, Small BJ, McIntyre J, Loi CA, Closser Z, Gwede CK. A pilot study of hereditary breast and ovarian knowledge among a multiethnic group of Hispanic women with a personal or family history of cancer. Genet Test Mol Biomarkers. 2010 Feb;14(1):99-106. doi: 10.1089/gtmb.2009.0088.</citation>
    <PMID>19929403</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cohn J, Blazey W, Tegay D, Harper B, Koehler S, Laurent B, Chan V, Jung MK, Krishnamachari B. Physician Risk Assessment Knowledge Regarding BRCA Genetics Testing. J Cancer Educ. 2015 Sep;30(3):573-9. doi: 10.1007/s13187-014-0724-9.</citation>
    <PMID>25234477</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chan V, Blazey W, Tegay D, Harper B, Koehler S, Laurent B, Lipka S, Cohn J, Jung MK, Krishnamachari B. Impact of academic affiliation and training on knowledge of hereditary colorectal cancer. Public Health Genomics. 2014;17(2):76-83. doi: 10.1159/000356938. Epub 2014 Jan 22.</citation>
    <PMID>24458016</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bannon SA, Mork M, Vilar E, Peterson SK, Lu K, Lynch PM, Rodriguez-Bigas MA, You YN. Patient-reported disease knowledge and educational needs in Lynch syndrome: findings of an interactive multidisciplinary patient conference. Hered Cancer Clin Pract. 2014 Feb 5;12(1):1. doi: 10.1186/1897-4287-12-1.</citation>
    <PMID>24499499</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McAllister M, Wood AM, Dunn G, Shiloh S, Todd C. The Genetic Counseling Outcome Scale: a new patient-reported outcome measure for clinical genetics services. Clin Genet. 2011 May;79(5):413-24. doi: 10.1111/j.1399-0004.2011.01636.x. Epub 2011 Feb 14. Erratum in: Clin Genet. 2011 Jul;80(1):99.</citation>
    <PMID>21255005</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yuen J, Lee SY, Courtney E, Lim J, Soh H, Li ST, Chen Y, McAllister M, Fenwick EK, Ngeow J. Evaluating empowerment in genetic counseling using patient-reported outcomes. Clin Genet. 2020 Feb;97(2):246-256. doi: 10.1111/cge.13646. Epub 2019 Oct 23.</citation>
    <PMID>31571202</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grant PE, Pampaka M, Payne K, Clarke A, McAllister M. Developing a short-form of the Genetic Counselling Outcome Scale: The Genomics Outcome Scale. Eur J Med Genet. 2019 May;62(5):324-334. doi: 10.1016/j.ejmg.2018.11.015. Epub 2018 Nov 26.</citation>
    <PMID>30496830</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DeMarco TA, Peshkin BN, Mars BD, Tercyak KP. Patient satisfaction with cancer genetic counseling: a psychometric analysis of the Genetic Counseling Satisfaction Scale. J Genet Couns. 2004 Aug;13(4):293-304.</citation>
    <PMID>19736695</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thomas C, McAllister M. Establishing the minimum clinically important difference for the Genetic Counseling Outcome Scale (GCOS-24). J Genet Couns. 2019 Oct;28(5):1003-1010. doi: 10.1002/jgc4.1152. Epub 2019 Jul 30.</citation>
    <PMID>31361378</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Voils CI, Venne VL, Weidenbacher H, Sperber N, Datta S. Comparison of Telephone and Televideo Modes for Delivery of Genetic Counseling: a Randomized Trial. J Genet Couns. 2018 Apr;27(2):339-348. doi: 10.1007/s10897-017-0189-1. Epub 2017 Dec 15.</citation>
    <PMID>29243007</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zilliacus EM, Meiser B, Lobb EA, Kelly PJ, Barlow-Stewart K, Kirk JA, Spigelman AD, Warwick LJ, Tucker KM. Are videoconferenced consultations as effective as face-to-face consultations for hereditary breast and ovarian cancer genetic counseling? Genet Med. 2011 Nov;13(11):933-41. doi: 10.1097/GIM.0b013e3182217a19.</citation>
    <PMID>21799430</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

