<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04732806</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NML-2020-001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1R44MH124574-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04732806</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Mightier Healthcare System</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Mightier Healthcare System: Introducing a Game-based Pediatric Mental Health Intervention Into Payor-sponsored Care to Evaluate Financial and Clinical Outcomes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Neuromotion Labs</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Magellan Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Neuromotion Labs</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Access to effective pediatric mental health treatment is a major public health concern in the&#xD;
      United States as paucity of pediatric providers leading to long wait times, financial burden,&#xD;
      and stigma pose significant barriers to treatment. Digital mental health promises to remedy&#xD;
      many chronic problems faced in providing timely and accessible mental health interventions to&#xD;
      children. With that in mind, the investigators and Neuromotion Inc. created Mightier, an&#xD;
      app-based heart rate biofeedback videogame platform designed to teach and facilitate practice&#xD;
      of emotional regulation skills. The technology behind Mightier is backed by three trials&#xD;
      showing clinical efficacy and since commercial launch 75% of families who have engaged with&#xD;
      the product report improvement. However, Neuromotion's core mission remains increasing access&#xD;
      to care, and the direct-to-consumer distribution of digital health also faces access&#xD;
      challenges. The investigators propose that access to effective digital mental health&#xD;
      interventions can be increased by meeting families where they already know to seek care: the&#xD;
      traditional healthcare system. The investigators have partnered with a nationwide behavioral&#xD;
      health insurance provider to pilot the integration of Mightier with traditional healthcare.&#xD;
      Families will be recruited via direct outreach from their behavioral health insurance&#xD;
      provider or via healthcare provider referral. Participating children will be randomized into&#xD;
      Mightier or treatment as usual control groups for 6 months. Behavioral healthcare utilization&#xD;
      will be observed for 12 months. Through this work the investigators will demonstrate the&#xD;
      value of Mightier to various stakeholders via decreased long-term healthcare utilization,&#xD;
      confirm that Mightier use results in decreased symptoms of emotional dysregulation,&#xD;
      irritability, and parent stress, and explore relationships among Mightier use, healthcare&#xD;
      utilization, and symptoms. Ultimately this work will pave the way forward for large scale&#xD;
      integration of digital healthcare and more traditional healthcare avenues while&#xD;
      simultaneously increasing Mightier's ability to reach children in need.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavioral healthcare utilization cost</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Dollars spent on behavioral healthcare over the study period. Provided by the behavioral healthcare payor partner.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Modified Overt Aggression Scale (MOAS) from baseline to 3 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The MOAS is a 5-point parent rated scale that rates the severity of four types of aggression: verbal, against property, against self (auto-aggression), and physical towards others. Scores range from 0-100 with lower scores representing less aggression (better outcome).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Disruptive Behavior Disorder Rating Scale (DBDRS) - Oppositional/Defiant Factor Score from baseline to 3 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The DBDRS is a 45-item scale that evaluates symptoms of Oppositional Defiant Disorder (ODD), Conduct Disorder (CD), and Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) from the parent's perspective. Scores range from 0-135 with lower scores representing fewer behaviors associated with the above disorders (better outcome). This secondary outcome will include the Oppositional/Defiant Factor Score consisting of items 3, 13, 15, 17, 24, 26, 28, and 39.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Affective Reactivity Index - Parent (ARI-P) from baseline to 3 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The ARI is a 7-item scale that consists of 6 symptom items and 1 impairment item. The scale was designed to determine irritable mood rather than behavioral consequences such as hostility and acts of aggression. Scores range from 0 - 12 with lower scores representing less irritability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Parent Stress Index - Short Form (PSI-SF) from baseline to 3 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The PSI-SF is a 36 item parent report scale that evaluates the extent and source of parent stress in the form of three subscales: Parental Distress, Parent-Child Dysfunctional Interaction, and Difficult Child. Total scores range from 36-180 with lower scores representing less parent stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Global Impression - Improvement, Irritability/Anger (CGI-I Irritability/Anger)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The CGI-I scale requires the clinician to rate total improvement whether or not, in the raters judgment, it is due to treatment. The clinician compares the patient's condition at baseline to the time of rating on a scale ranging from 1 (very much improved) to 7 (very much worse)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Global Impression - Improvement, Aggression (CGI-I Aggression)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The CGI-I scale requires the clinician to rate total improvement whether or not, in the raters judgment, it is due to treatment. The clinician compares the patient's condition at baseline to the time of rating on a scale ranging from 1 (very much improved) to 7 (very much worse)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Global Impression - Improvement, Disruptive/Oppositional Behavior (CGI-I Disruptive/Oppositional Behavior)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The CGI-I scale requires the clinician to rate total improvement whether or not, in the raters judgment, it is due to treatment. The clinician compares the patient's condition at baseline to the time of rating on a scale ranging from 1 (very much improved) to 7 (very much worse)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Parent Confidence and Resources from baseline to 3 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Two 5 item questions regarding parent confidence in their ability to manage their child's behaviors and adequacy of resources to manage their child's behaviors</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in NIH-Emotion Toolbox from baseline to 3 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The NIH toolbox for emotion was developed to create a standardized, comprehensive, and concise battery of tests that can recognize the full spectrum of emotional experiences and their impacts on health and wellbeing. The NIH Toolbox for emotion includes 4 subdomains: negative affect, psychological well-being, stress and self-efficacy, and social relationships. For the age range of 8-12, self-report and proxy measures are available. Given that we expect a wide range of cognitive, developmental, and metacognitive abilities, proxy report measures will be used.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Customer Satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated in the Mightier group only. Customer satisfaction will be rated using a single, parent/guardian response item. Response options will be extremely dissatisfied, somewhat dissatisfied, neither satisfied not dissatisfied, somewhat satisfied, or extremely satisfied.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Net Promoter Score</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated in the Mightier group only. Net Promotor Score represents the industry standard for evaluating customer willingness to recommend a product. The rating consists of a single parent/guardian report item with responses options ranging from 0 (not at all likely) to 10 (extremely likely). When scores are aggregated, Net Promoter Score is expressed as the percentage of customers who rated their likelihood to recommend the product as 9 or 10 minus the percentage of customers rating this at 6 or below.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Heart Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1hz intervals when playing game for 6 months</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Disruptive Behavior Disorder Rating Scale (DBDRS) - Total Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>The DBDRS is a 45-item scale that evaluates symptoms of Oppositional Defiant Disorder (ODD), Conduct Disorder (CD), and Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) from the parent's perspective. Scores range from 0-135 with lower scores representing fewer behaviors associated with the above disorders (better outcome).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Emotional Dysregulation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Six months of ad lib Mightier play in home</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mightier video games</intervention_name>
    <description>Biofeedback video game play in home</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 8-12&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Magellan Healthcare member&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MOAS score of greater than or equal to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of ADHD, ODD, CD, DMDD, IED, or ASD by MINI-KID&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WiFi at home (for Mightier tablet connection)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IQ &lt; 70 (by medical record or clinician judgment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extremely limited verbal capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Change in medication or medication dosage in the past month or planned change in&#xD;
             medication or medication dosage in the next month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of suicide attempt and current depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical limitations that preclude the use of Mightier&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sensory sensitivities that would preclude wearing an arm (or leg) heart rate monitor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of psychosis, mania, alcohol use disorder, substance use disorder, or PTSD by&#xD;
             MINI-Kid&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing or within the month prior to baseline visit placement in foster care or&#xD;
             residential facility&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jason Kahn, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>888-978-7495</phone>
    <email>jason@mightier.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alyssa Peechatka, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>888-978-7495</phone>
    <email>alyssa@mightier.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neuromotion Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jason Kahn, PhD</last_name>
      <email>jason@mightier.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alyssa Peechatka, PhD</last_name>
      <email>alyssa@mightier.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

