<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04734704</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHUBX 2020/41</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04734704</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Defining the Role of the Skin Microbiome in Immune-related Adverse Events</brief_title>
  <acronym>SKINBIOTA</acronym>
  <official_title>Defining the Role of the Skin Microbiome in Vitiligo and Immune-related Adverse Events in Advanced Melanoma Patients Treated With Anti-PD1</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Bordeaux</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre National de la Recherche Scientifique, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Bordeaux</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The skin microbiome has been implicated in several cutaneous autoimmune pathologies such as&#xD;
      psoriasis and atopic dermatitis. However, its role in vitiligo and vitiligo lesions occuring&#xD;
      in patients receiving anti-PD-1 for metastatic melanoma&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Melanoma is the most dangerous skin cancer accounting for the highest skin cancer deaths. The&#xD;
      prognosis for metastatic melanoma has improved considerably in recent years thanks to&#xD;
      advances in the field of immunotherapy. The development of molecules blocking certain&#xD;
      immunological &quot;checkpoints&quot; (checkpoints exerted by the CTLA-4 (Cytotoxic T lymphocytes&#xD;
      Associated protein 4) and PD-1 (Programmed cell Death protein 1) has made it possible to&#xD;
      obtain a significant improvement of the overall survival (OS) of patients treated for&#xD;
      metastatic melanoma. Ipilimumab, an antibody blocking CTLA-4, is the first immunotherapy&#xD;
      marketed, demonstrating for the first time a therapeutic response, however in a small number&#xD;
      of patients (10 to 15%) and with significant toxicity (25% of grade 3-4). Subsequently, a&#xD;
      second generation of more effective checkpoint blockers (30 to 40% good response) and less&#xD;
      toxic, anti-PD-1 antibodies (pembrolizumab and nivolumab), quickly obtained a marketing&#xD;
      authorization in the first line treatment of metastatic melanoma treatment and recently in an&#xD;
      adjuvant situation after lymph node dissection in order to limit the risk of recurrence.&#xD;
      However, despite these advances, a certain number of patients do not respond to treatment and&#xD;
      it remains difficult to predict this therapeutic response. Furthermore, patients treated with&#xD;
      ICI often experience cutaneous immune-related adverse events manifesting as skin rash,&#xD;
      dermatitis, epidermal necrolysis, and in some cases as vitiligo like depigmentation of the&#xD;
      skin, testifying to the development of a specific immunogenicity towards the melanocytes,&#xD;
      cells causing melanoma, and responsible for a discoloration of the skin. Several studies have&#xD;
      reported that a modification of certain bacteria in the digestive microbiota was predictive&#xD;
      of the antitumor response to immunotherapy, while others were predictive of the appearance of&#xD;
      significant autoimmune ICI-related toxicities (colitis). Several phase 1 studies have&#xD;
      evaluated the impact of taking probiotics or fecal transplants on the tumor response of&#xD;
      patients receiving immunotherapy for cancer (NCT 03819296; NCT03817125; NCT03643289). Thus by&#xD;
      these new concepts, it would be interesting to assess the composition of the skin microbiota&#xD;
      in patients treated with anti-PD-1 immunotherapy for the management of metastatic melanoma&#xD;
      and developing during their follow-up vitiligo; predictive side effect of improved survival.&#xD;
      These data will be compared to those obtained from patients with common vitiligo. This will&#xD;
      be examined in patients skin swabs sampled at lesional and non-lesional sites. Functionally,&#xD;
      we will characterize the microbial pathways using shotgun sequencing of microbial genomes and&#xD;
      meta-transcriptomics (RNA sequencing of microbial communities of the skin).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, Monocentric (CHU de Bordeaux, Department of dermatology ), with 4 groups :&#xD;
vitiligo patients&#xD;
Metastatic melanoma patients receiving anti-PD-1 but without cutaneous irAEs&#xD;
Metastatic melanoma patients receiving anti-PD-1 who developed vitiligo lesions&#xD;
metastatic melanoma patients who developed vitiligo under anti-PD-1, who discontinued the treatment.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine skin microbiota by sequencing with vitiligo in advanced melanoma patients under immune-checkpoint inhibitors (ICI) immunotherapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>The composition of the skin microbiota will be characterized on skin swabs using shotgun sequencing of microbial genomes and meta-transcriptomics (RNA sequencing of microbial communities of the skin).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">175</enrollment>
  <condition>Vitiligo</condition>
  <condition>Skin Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>vitiligo patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adult patients diagnosed with Vitiligo according to usual criteria</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>metastatic melanoma patients under anti-PD-1 who did not develop cutaneous irAEs</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>metastatic melanoma patients under anti-PD-1 who did not develop Cutaneous Immune-Related Adverse Events (cutaneous irAEs).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Metastatic melanoma patients under anti-PD-1 who developed vitiligo lesions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients with metastatic melanoma, under anti-PD-1 who developed vitiligo lesions</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>metastatic melanoma patients with vitiligo lesions under anti-PD-1 who discontinued</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Metastatic melanoma who developed vitiligo lesions under anti-PD-1 who discontinued the treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>skin swabs at lesional and non-lesional sites</intervention_name>
    <description>It will be examined in patients skin swabs sampled at lesional and non-lesional sites</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metastatic melanoma patients under anti-PD-1 who developed vitiligo lesions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>metastatic melanoma patients with vitiligo lesions under anti-PD-1 who discontinued</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>vitiligo patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>skin swabs on skin</intervention_name>
    <description>It will be examined in patients skin swabs sampled on skin</description>
    <arm_group_label>metastatic melanoma patients under anti-PD-1 who did not develop cutaneous irAEs</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients diagnosed with Vitiligo according to usual criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients with metastatic melanoma, under anti-PD-1 who developed vitiligo&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients with metastatic melanoma who did not develop Immune related adverse&#xD;
             events under anti-PD-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients with metastatic melanoma who developed vitiligo under anti-PD-1 and&#xD;
             discontinued the treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Free, informed by the participant and the investigator (at the latest on the day of&#xD;
             inclusion and before any examination required by the research).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No treatment for vitiligo in the past 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under legal protection or unable to express their consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not affiliated to a health insurance system.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients deprived of liberty by judiciary or administrative decision or hospitalized&#xD;
             without consent or admitted in a sanitary or social institution for another reason&#xD;
             than research.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Julien SENESCHAL, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Bordeaux</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julien SENESCHAL, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+335 57 82 25 00</phone>
    <email>julien.seneschal@chu-bordeaux.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maya SALEH, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+335 57 57 11 24</phone>
    <email>maya.saleh@u-bordeaux.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Service de Dermatologie - Hôpital Saint-André</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux</city>
        <zip>33075</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>checkpoint inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>vitiligo</keyword>
  <keyword>skin microbiota</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic melanoma.</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitiligo</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

