<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04734665</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4-2021-0076</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04734665</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Niraparib and Bevacizumab Maintenance Therapy in Platinum-sensitive Recurrent Ovarian Cancer Patients Previously Treated With a PARP Inhibitor</brief_title>
  <acronym>NIRVANA-R</acronym>
  <official_title>A Single-arm Phase II Study of Niraparib and Bevacizumab Maintenance Therapy in Platinum-sensitive Recurrent Ovarian Cancer Patients Previously Treated With a PARP Inhibitor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yonsei University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yonsei University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is phase II, open label, clinical trial to determine the efficacy of Niraparib&#xD;
      re-treatment with Bevacizumab of assessment progression-free survival(6 months PFS rate) with&#xD;
      platinum-sensitive recurrent ovarian cancer patients previously treated with a PARP&#xD;
      inhibitor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase II, open-label, non-randomized, multi-center study assessing the efficacy and&#xD;
      safety of Niraparib re-treatment with Bevacizumab of assessment progression-free survival(6&#xD;
      months PFS rate) with platinum-sensitive recurrent ovarian cancer patients previously treated&#xD;
      with a PARP inhibitor The study will assess the effectiveness of progression-free survival(6&#xD;
      months PFS rate) as determined by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) v1.1.&#xD;
      The subject will be treated to until disease progression as below:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Niraparib 200mg or 300mg (once daily[QD])*&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bevacizumab 15mg/kg every 3 weeks (Q3W)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The recommended starting dosage of niraparib is 200mg QD. For patients who weigh&#xD;
                ≥77 kg and have baseline platelet count ≥150,000/μL, the recommended starting&#xD;
                dosage is 300 mg QD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>progression-free survival(6 months PFS rate)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the clinical effectiveness of the study treatment assessed using progression free survival(6months) according to RECIST v1.1 criteria (Investigator determined)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to tumour progression (TTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first subsequent treatment(or death)</measure>
    <time_frame>The date of first documented first subsequent treatment or date of death, assessed up to 36months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to second subsequent treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>The date of first documented second subsequent treatment assessed up to 36months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Platinum-sensitive Recurrent Ovarian Cancer Patients Previously Treated With a PARP Inhibitor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Platinum-sensitive recurrent ovarian cancer patients previously treated with a PARP inhibitor, Non-mucinous</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Niraparib-Bevacizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Niraparib 200mg or 300mg (once daily[QD]) Bevacizumab 15mg/kg every 3 weeks (Q3W)&#xD;
*The recommended starting dosage of niraparib is 200mg QD. For patients who weigh ≥77 kg and have baseline platelet count ≥150,000/μL, the recommended starting dosage is 300 mg QD.</description>
    <arm_group_label>experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant has histologically confirmed diagnosis of high-grade predominantly serous,&#xD;
             endometrioid, carcinosarcoma, mixed mullerian with high-grade serous component, clear&#xD;
             cell, or low-grade serous OC, primary peritoneal cancer, or fallopian tube cancer will&#xD;
             be enrolled in this study (only up to 4 patients with clear cell carcinoma will be&#xD;
             included and mucinous carcinoma will not be included).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant has received at least 2 previous courses of platinum-containing therapy,&#xD;
             and has disease that was considered platinum sensitive following the penultimate (next&#xD;
             to last) platinum course (more than 12 months' period between penultimate platinum&#xD;
             regimen and progression of disease) Note: The last platinum regimen does not&#xD;
             necessarily have to immediately follow the next to last (penultimate) platinum&#xD;
             regimen. For example, if a patient received a non-platinum regimen between the&#xD;
             penultimate platinum regimen and last platinum regimen, they could be eligible, so&#xD;
             long as they meet all entry criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant has responded to last the platinum regimen (complete or partial response),&#xD;
             remains in response and is enrolled on study within 8 weeks of completion of the last&#xD;
             platinum regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant had prior treatment with PARP inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participant is able to provide a newly obtained core or excisional biopsy of a tumor&#xD;
             lesion for prospective testing of BRCA 1/2 and PD-L1 status prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female participants who are at least 20 years of age on the day of signing informed&#xD;
             consent with&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participant has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0&#xD;
             or 1, as assessed within 10 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Female participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. A female participant is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant (see Appendix&#xD;
             2), not breastfeeding, and at least one of the following conditions applies:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Not a woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP) as defined in Appendix 2 OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. A WOCBP who agrees to follow the contraceptive guidance in Appendix 2 during the&#xD;
                  treatment period and for at least 120 days following the last dose of niraparib&#xD;
                  and at least 210 days following the last dose of chemotherapy or bevacizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Informed Consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The participant (or legally acceptable representative if applicable) provides written&#xD;
             informed consent for the trial. The participant may also provide consent for future&#xD;
             biomedical research; however, the participant may participate in the main study&#xD;
             without participating in future biomedical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participant has adequate organ function as defined in the following contents; all&#xD;
             screening laboratory tests should be performed within 10 days prior to the start of&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1500/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥100 000/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL or ≥5.6 mmol/La&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine OR Measured or calculated creatinine clearance(GFR can also be used in&#xD;
                  place of creatinine or CrCl) ≤1.5 × ULN OR ≥30 mL/min for participant with&#xD;
                  creatinine levels &gt;1.5 × institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤1.5 ×ULN OR direct bilirubin ≤ULN for participants with total&#xD;
                  bilirubin levels &gt;1.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) ≤2.5 × ULN (≤5 × ULN for participants with liver&#xD;
                  metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  International normalized ratio (INR) OR prothrombin time (PT), Activated partial&#xD;
                  thromboplastin time (aPTT) ≤1.5 × ULN unless participant is receiving&#xD;
                  anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or aPTT is within therapeutic range of&#xD;
                  intended use of anticoagulants&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant has mucinous, germ cell, or borderline tumor of the ovary.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant has a history of non-infectious pneumonitis that required treatment with&#xD;
             steroids or currently has pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant either has myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS)/ acute myeloid leukemia (AML) or&#xD;
             has features suggestive of MDS/AML.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participant has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or has required&#xD;
             active treatment within the past 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Participants with basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of&#xD;
             the skin, or carcinoma in situ (e.g. breast carcinoma, cervical cancer in situ,&#xD;
             endometrial carinoma) that have undergone potentially curative therapy are not&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Participants with synchronous primary endometrial cancer or a past history of&#xD;
             primary endometrial cancer that met the following conditions are not excluded: Stage&#xD;
             not greater than IA: no more than superficial myometrial invasion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Drainage of ascites during last 2 cycles of last chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Palliative radiotherapy within 1 week encompassing &gt;20% of the bone marrow.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Persistent &gt; grade 2 toxicity from prior cancer therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Symptomatic uncontrolled brain or leptomeningeal metastases. A scan to confirm the&#xD;
             absence of brain metastases is not required. Patients with spinal cord compression may&#xD;
             be considered if they have received definitive treatment for this and evidence of&#xD;
             clinically stable disease for 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known hypersensitivity to the components of niraparib.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Major surgery within 3 weeks of starting the study or patient has not recovered from&#xD;
             any effects of any major surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients considered a poor medical risk due to a serious, uncontrolled medical&#xD;
             disorder, non-malignant systemic disease or active, uncontrolled infection. Examples&#xD;
             include, but are not limited to, uncontrolled ventricular arrhythmia, recent (within 3&#xD;
             months) myocardial infarction, uncontrolled major seizure disorder, unstable spinal&#xD;
             cord compression, superior vena cava syndrome, or any psychiatric disorder that&#xD;
             prohibits obtaining informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or lab abnormality that might&#xD;
             confound the results of the study, interfere with the patient's participation for the&#xD;
             full duration of the study treatment, or is not in the best interest of the patient to&#xD;
             participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Immunocompromised patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients with known active hepatic disease (i.e. , Hepatitis B or C).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Female</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jung Yun Lee</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Severance Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jung Yun Lee</last_name>
    <phone>82-2-2228-2237</phone>
    <email>jungyunlee@yuhs.ac</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yonsei University College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>03722</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jung Yun Lee</last_name>
      <phone>82-2-2228-2237</phone>
      <email>jungyunlee@yuhs.ac</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ovarian cancer, Platinum-sensitive, PARP inhibitor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Niraparib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>(Describe the IPD sharing plan, including what IPD are to be shared with other researchers.)</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

