<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733560</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FHREB2020-143</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733560</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Preoperative Analgesia by Infiltration of the Pudendal Nerve Prior to Sacrospinous Ligament Suspension</brief_title>
  <acronym>PAINS</acronym>
  <official_title>Preoperative Analgesia by Infiltration of the Pudendal Nerve Prior to Sacrospinous Ligament Suspension: The PAIN-S Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fraser Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fraser Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pelvic organ prolapse is a common problem. It affects about half of women and causes&#xD;
      uncomfortable bulge sensations (similar to sitting on a ball), urine and stool problems,&#xD;
      difficulty with sexual activity and embarrassment. Almost one of every five women undergoes&#xD;
      surgery to treat prolapse.Typically, vaginal surgery is done while patients are asleep and&#xD;
      local anesthetic- freezing medication- is injected where incisions are made to minimize the&#xD;
      pain from surgery when waking up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pudendal blocks are nerve blocks where local anesthetic is used to freeze a nerve that&#xD;
      supplies sensation to the vulva and vaginal area. It is traditionally used to help with pain&#xD;
      for women giving birth, but hasn't been studied well in women undergoing vaginal surgery for&#xD;
      prolapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators believe that by using a small amount of freezing to provide a pudendal&#xD;
      block at the time of surgery, on top of the freezing typically provided, that there will be&#xD;
      minimized pain after surgery and improve the recovery process. Based on previous studies&#xD;
      using pudendal blocks for different vulvar and vaginal procedures, the investigators believe&#xD;
      this to be a safe and potentially beneficial practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators are planning to conduct a randomized controlled trial of 50 women. 25 will&#xD;
      receive pudendal nerve blocks at the time of surgery, and 25 will receive placebo&#xD;
      injections.The investigators will monitor their pain scores, satisfaction, use of pain&#xD;
      medications and return to activities in order to determine if our intervention has caused a&#xD;
      significant improvement in recovery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization and Blinding:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women will be randomized to receive either Bupivacaine 0.25% or Normal Saline pudendal&#xD;
      injections based on the label within a sealed envelope randomly selected on the day of their&#xD;
      surgery. Fifty labels will be created with twenty-five labels each of &quot;Bupivacaine 20ml&quot; or&#xD;
      &quot;Normal Saline 20ml&quot; written on them. These will be placed in blank, identical envelopes and&#xD;
      sealed and shuffled prior to the start of the study. Upon selection, the sealed envelope will&#xD;
      be given to the circulating nurse who will draw up the selected solution and label it&#xD;
      &quot;pudendal block&quot;. The circulating nurse will be directed to not disclose the contents of the&#xD;
      envelope or syringe to the participant or to any other member of the team. They will then&#xD;
      re-seal the envelope with tape, place a patient label on it and return it to the surgical&#xD;
      team post procedure to be returned to a locked file cabinet within the surgical office at the&#xD;
      end of the day, to be kept securely with medical records. Group allocation envelopes will be&#xD;
      opened after the collection of all outcome data is complete to allow for data analysis. In&#xD;
      order to avoid local anesthetic toxicity, any calculations for other anesthetic agents&#xD;
      utilized for the surgical procedure or anesthetic will assume that 20 ml of 0.25% Bupivacaine&#xD;
      was administered. In the event that an emergent adverse complication is identified which may&#xD;
      be attributable to the administered agent, the treatment allocation can be unblinded if this&#xD;
      is deemed clinically necessary by the investigator or other treating physician. In the event&#xD;
      this is required, the patient will be withdrawn from the study and excluded from the final&#xD;
      analysis, but such case(s) will be described in the final study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The circulating nurse already draws up local anesthetic and normal saline as a routine part&#xD;
      of this procedure for use in other ways, and so the investigators do not anticipate that&#xD;
      their participation in this study will be a large burden of work. The investigators estimate&#xD;
      that it will add no more than 2 minutes to their preparation time for the surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pudendal Block administration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Pudendal block will be administered by the Surgeon or Surgical Fellow after the&#xD;
      administration of anesthetic and preparation for surgery but before the first surgical&#xD;
      incision. It will be administered with standard transvaginal technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standardization of the Anesthesia, Pre-op and postoperative pain management:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-operative, postoperative and intra-operative care will be standardized according to&#xD;
      guidelines that meet criteria for current standard of care as outlined in the appendix. These&#xD;
      pages will be printed on the chart to identify the patient as a participant in the study and&#xD;
      also to remind the surgical and anesthetic team of the guidelines of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standardization of postoperative pain management after discharge:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will receive the same instructions for management of postoperative pain. They&#xD;
      will receive instructions to use acetaminophen (Tylenol) regularly as well as Ibuprofen&#xD;
      (Advil) regularly as long as they have no contraindications or allergies to these&#xD;
      medications. They will be given a standardized prescription for tramadol to use in addition&#xD;
      to these medications for management of breakthrough pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study and Follow up Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will have no additional visits attributed to their participation in this study.&#xD;
      Instead they will receive electronic (email or text) surveys and telephone reminders over a&#xD;
      period of 2 weeks after their operation. The first survey will take less than 1 minute to&#xD;
      complete, the second will take less than 5 minutes to complete, and the final survey less&#xD;
      than 10 minutes to complete.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized control trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Patients are surgeons are blinded to the contents of the injections (either local anesthetic or saline). Allocations will be revealed after all data is collected at the time of data analysis.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative Pain Score</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at post-operative day 0</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a Visual Analog scale (1-10)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative Pain Score</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at post-operative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a Visual Analog scale (1-10)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative Pain Score</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at post-operative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a Visual Analog scale (1-10)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Readiness for discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at post-operative day 0 prior to discharge</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a 5 point Likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at postoperative day 0</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a 5 point Likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a 5 point Likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>measured on a 5 point Likert scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Recovery Index</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at postoperative day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Validated tool by Wong et al. Involving measures of return to activities of daily living</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Recovery Index</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Validated tool by Wong et al. Involving measures of return to activities of daily living</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative Analgesic use</measure>
    <time_frame>measured at postoperative day 14</time_frame>
    <description>pill count</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Pelvic Organ Prolapse</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pudendal nerve block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 women will receive pudendal nerve blocks of 0.25% Bupivicaine 10ml administered vaginally prior to making any surgical incisions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 women will receive sham pudendal nerve blocks using normal saline. These will also be administed vaginally prior to making any surgical incisions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pudendal nerve block</intervention_name>
    <description>Vaginally administered pudendal nerve block of 10ml 0.25% Bupivacaine prior to making any surgical incisions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pudendal nerve block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham Pudendal nerve block</intervention_name>
    <description>Vaginally administered pudendal nerve block of 10ml Normal Saline prior to making any surgical incisions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacaine Injectable Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Used for pudendal nerve block in the intervention arm</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pudendal nerve block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with prolapse and planning to undergo vaginal day surgery as treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be undergoing a sacrospinous ligament fixation as part of their procedure. Those&#xD;
             undergoing a concurrent anterior and/or posterior vaginal repair, or mid-urethral&#xD;
             sling will also be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read and write in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to complete email surveys for the first 2 weeks after surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with an allergy to local anesthetic (freezing injections)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who prefer to have surgery under spinal anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with planned concurrent vulvar, laparoscopic or abdominal surgery, or any&#xD;
             planned concurrent vaginal surgery other than those in the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with a pre-existing chronic pain disorder requiring the regular use of opioid&#xD;
             analgesics (more than twice weekly)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with a history of substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those with a history of bleeding disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who would prefer not to participate in the study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If unable to receive emails in order to fill out the surveys.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in any other research study involving drugs or devices&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sophia Badowski, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6138889851</phone>
    <email>slenson@qmed.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Darren Lazare, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6047279000</phone>
    <email>darren.Lazare@fraserhealth.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City Centre Obstetrics and Gynecology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Surrey</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V3V 0C6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sophia Badowski</last_name>
      <phone>6138889851</phone>
      <email>slenson@qmed.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Fraser Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sophia Badowski</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prolapse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pelvic Organ Prolapse</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

