<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04732299</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>XJTU1AF-CRF-2020-014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04732299</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Staging and Prognosis of Deep Venous Thrombosis of Lower Extremities</brief_title>
  <official_title>Staging Diagnosis and Prognosis of Lower Extremity Deep Venous Thrombosis Based on Magnetic Resonance Imaging: a Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>First Affiliated Hospital Xi'an Jiaotong University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>First Affiliated Hospital Xi'an Jiaotong University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Deep venous thrombosis (DVT) is a venous reflux disorder caused by abnormal coagulation of&#xD;
      blood in the deep vein, which usually occurs in the lower extremities. After thrombosis,&#xD;
      venous valve function is often destroyed, causing lower limb swelling, ulcers and other&#xD;
      congestive diseases, affecting the quality of life of patients; thrombus shedding is also&#xD;
      easy to cause pulmonary embolism, serious cases can lead to sudden death. Therefore, the&#xD;
      accurate diagnosis and curative effect evaluation of DVT are of great significance to the&#xD;
      prognosis of patients. At present, the treatment of DVT includes systematic thrombolysis and&#xD;
      catheter contact thrombolysis, among which oral drug thrombolysis has certain advantages in&#xD;
      clinical application. However, in the process of thrombosis, the composition of thrombus is&#xD;
      different in different periods, thus, defining the staging of thrombus plays an important&#xD;
      role in the decision-making of drug treatment. In view of the high resolution of magnetic&#xD;
      resonance imaging of soft tissue, thrombus can be directly imaged. Therefore, this project&#xD;
      will take the staging diagnosis of deep venous thrombosis as the starting point. Through the&#xD;
      development of magnetic resonance imaging, this paper tries to solve the problem of&#xD;
      evaluating the therapeutic effect of deep venous thrombosis in clinic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Deep venous thrombosis (DVT) is a venous reflux disorder caused by abnormal blood coagulation&#xD;
      in the deep vein, which usually occurs in the lower extremities. DVT is common in patients&#xD;
      with limb immobilization (such as after major orthopedic surgery), severe trauma, tumor, coma&#xD;
      or long-term bedridden patients. After thrombosis, venous valve function is often destroyed,&#xD;
      causing lower limb swelling, ulcers and other congestive diseases, affecting the quality of&#xD;
      life of patients; thrombus shedding is also easy to cause pulmonary embolism, serious cases&#xD;
      can lead to sudden death.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the process of thrombosis, the components of thrombus are different in different stages.&#xD;
      in the acute stage of thrombosis, the consumption of blood fibroses is less, mainly in the&#xD;
      thrombolytic therapy of activating plasminogen; in the subacute and chronic phase of&#xD;
      thrombosis, the consumption of fibrinolytic enzyme is more, anticoagulant therapy is needed&#xD;
      to prolong the clotting time. Therefore, defining the staging of thrombus is the key to make&#xD;
      a reasonable treatment plan and improve the therapeutic effect of DVT. The guidelines&#xD;
      recommend that for patients with moderate or high likelihood of DVT, if two consecutive&#xD;
      ultrasound examinations are negative, further X-ray venography, CT venography or magnetic&#xD;
      resonance venous thrombosis direct imaging are recommended. Among them, magnetic resonance&#xD;
      thrombus direct imaging depends on the content of methemoglobin in the body and will not&#xD;
      produce radiation to the human body. it can not only accurately judge the thrombus in the&#xD;
      pelvic and inferior vena cava, but also show the details of the changes in the vein wall or&#xD;
      lumen. Therefore, magnetic resonance thrombus direct imaging has a certain potential in the&#xD;
      differential diagnosis of acute, subacute and old thrombus. In this study, we will use&#xD;
      magnetic resonance thrombus direct imaging to stage and judge the efficacy of drug treatment,&#xD;
      in order to provide help for clinic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombus-muscle signal-to-noise ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>The interval between two MRI examinations per patient is 3 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative analysis of thrombus was performed by magnetic resonance thrombography for the first time, and the curative effect was evaluated again 3 months after clinical treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Venous Thrombosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acute thrombus group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Within 14 days after onset</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subacute thrombus group</arm_group_label>
    <description>During 15-30 days after onset</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Chronic thrombosis group</arm_group_label>
    <description>More than 15-30 days after onset</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MRI examination</intervention_name>
    <description>Magnetic resonance thrombography is used to determine the location of thrombus, quantify the thrombus and determine its stage.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acute thrombus group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Chronic thrombosis group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Subacute thrombus group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The people included in this study are patients suspected of deep venous thrombosis of lower&#xD;
        extremities for the first time and should be older than 18 years old.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected deep venous thrombosis of lower extremities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No treatment related to deep venous thrombosis of lower extremities&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication of magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of deep venous thrombosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergy to magnetic resonance contrast agents&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zhe Liu, Mr.</last_name>
    <phone>0086-13259756822</phone>
    <email>imagingliuzhe@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dronkers CE, Srámek A, Huisman MV, Klok FA. Accurate diagnosis of iliac vein thrombosis in pregnancy with magnetic resonance direct thrombus imaging (MRDTI). BMJ Case Rep. 2016 Dec 13;2016. pii: bcr2016218091. doi: 10.1136/bcr-2016-218091.</citation>
    <PMID>27965311</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karande GY, Hedgire SS, Sanchez Y, Baliyan V, Mishra V, Ganguli S, Prabhakar AM. Advanced imaging in acute and chronic deep vein thrombosis. Cardiovasc Diagn Ther. 2016 Dec;6(6):493-507. doi: 10.21037/cdt.2016.12.06. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28123971</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mendichovszky IA, Priest AN, Bowden DJ, Hunter S, Joubert I, Hilborne S, Graves MJ, Baglin T, Lomas DJ. Combined MR direct thrombus imaging and non-contrast magnetic resonance venography reveal the evolution of deep vein thrombosis: a feasibility study. Eur Radiol. 2017 Jun;27(6):2326-2332. doi: 10.1007/s00330-016-4555-4. Epub 2016 Aug 30.</citation>
    <PMID>27578046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xie G, Chen H, He X, Liang J, Deng W, He Z, Ye Y, Yang Q, Bi X, Liu X, Li D, Fan Z. Black-blood thrombus imaging (BTI): a contrast-free cardiovascular magnetic resonance approach for the diagnosis of non-acute deep vein thrombosis. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2017 Jan 18;19(1):4. doi: 10.1186/s12968-016-0320-8.</citation>
    <PMID>28095878</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen H, He X, Xie G, Liang J, Ye Y, Deng W, He Z, Liu D, Li D, Liu X, Fan Z. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance black-blood thrombus imaging for the diagnosis of acute deep vein thrombosis at 1.5 Tesla. J Cardiovasc Magn Reson. 2018 Jun 25;20(1):42. doi: 10.1186/s12968-018-0459-6.</citation>
    <PMID>29936910</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhuang G, Tang C, He X, Liang J, He Z, Ye Y, Deng W, Liu D, Chen H. DANTE-SPACE: a new technical tool for DVT on 1.5T MRI. Int J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2019 Dec;35(12):2231-2237. doi: 10.1007/s10554-019-01675-w. Epub 2019 Aug 24.</citation>
    <PMID>31446527</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MRI, Venous Thrombosis, Staging, Prognosis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

