<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04736394</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>YHCT-NIT-R2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04736394</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 3 Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of APL-1202 as a Single-agent Oral Treatment Versus Intravesical Instillation of Epirubicin Hydrochloride in naïve Intermediate-risk NMIBC Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>ASCERTAIN</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multi-center, Randomized, Open-label, Parallel-controlled Phase 3 Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Clinical Safety and Efficacy of APL-1202 as a Single-agent Oral Treatment Versus Intravesical Instillation of Epirubicin Hydrochloride in naïve Intermediate-risk Non-muscle Invasive Bladder Cancer (NMIBC) Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jiangsu Yahong Meditech Co., Ltd aka Asieris</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jiangsu Yahong Meditech Co., Ltd aka Asieris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A multi-center, randomized, open-label, parallel-controlled Phase Ⅲ clinical trial to&#xD;
      evaluate the clinical safety and efficacy of APL-1202 as a single-agent oral treatment versus&#xD;
      intravesical instillation of Epirubicin hydrochloride in naïve intermediate-risk non-muscle&#xD;
      invasive bladder cancer (NMIBC) patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A multi-center, randomized, open-label, placebo controlled Phase Ⅲ trial. The subjects must&#xD;
      be histopathologically diagnosed, naïve intermediate-risk NMIBC patient. The screening period&#xD;
      is 6 weeks prior to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial including 2 stages:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • First stages: The subjects are randomly assigned to receive APL-1202 single-agent oral&#xD;
      treatment or intravesical instillation of Epirubicin hydrochloride at a ratio of 1:1. At this&#xD;
      stage, an interim analysis will be performed after the first 100 subjects enrolled completing&#xD;
      the 6-month visit (completing the second cystoscopy), and the Independent Data Monitoring&#xD;
      Committee (IDMC) conducted a preliminary evaluation of the safety. If approved by the IDMC&#xD;
      after the safety evaluation, the trial will proceed to the second stage. Before the result of&#xD;
      the interim analysis are obtained, subjects receiving APL-1202 will continue to be given&#xD;
      continuous administration if they have completed the 6-month visit (V4). After the interim&#xD;
      analysis, if the safety of continuous administration is as expected, subjects receiving&#xD;
      APL-1202 will continue to do the same, otherwise it will be adjusted to the administration of&#xD;
      APL-1202 at every 3-month interval which is proven to be safe and tolerable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Second stage: After the interim analysis of the first stage, the subjects of the second&#xD;
      stage will be enrolled, and the subjects were randomly assigned to receive APL-1202&#xD;
      single-agent oral treatment or intravesical instillation of Epirubicin hydrochloride at a&#xD;
      ratio of 1:1. For treatment, according to the results of the interim analysis, if the safety&#xD;
      of continuous administration reaches the expected level, subjects receiving APL-1202 will&#xD;
      continue to do the same, otherwise it will be adjusted to the administration of APL-1202 at&#xD;
      every 3-month interval which is proven to be safe and tolerable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this trial, the APL-1202 dosing regimen will continue until subjects exit the trial early&#xD;
      for any reason, complete 24 months' treatment or the trial is terminated early.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cystoscopy will be performed every 3 months in the enrolled subjects. If there is no&#xD;
      recurrence in the enrolled subject during the treatment period (2 years after enrollment),&#xD;
      cystoscopy will be performed every 6 months during the follow-up period until recurrence or&#xD;
      the end of the clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety assessment will be performed every 3 months during the treatment period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Event-free survival (EFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Event-free survival (EFS) based on the assessment of pathological report from the Independent Pathology Review Committee (IPRC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Event-free survival (EFS) based on the assessment of pathological report from each site</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Event-free survival (EFS) based on the assessment of pathological report from each site</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival (OS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence-free rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Recurrence-free rate at 12,18, and 24 months after enrollment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free rate at 12,18, and 24 months after enrollment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical benefit rates</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical benefit rates at 12,18, 24 months after enrollment (clinical benefits are defined as the pathological improvement of the recurrence, no high-risk recurrence, progression-free recurrence, no radical therapy and no death)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC)-Quality of Life Questionnaire-Core 30 (QLQ-C30) Global Health Status/Quality of Life Total Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC-QLQ-C30 is a 30-item questionnaire developed to assess the quality of life of cancer patients. Participant responses to the questions &quot;How would you rate your overall health during the past week?&quot; and &quot;How would you rate your overall quality of life during the past week?&quot; are scored on a 7-point scale (1=Very Poor to 7=Excellent). Using linear transformation, raw scores are standardized, so that scores range from 0 to 100. A higher score indicates a better overall outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in EORTC-QLQ-Non-muscle Invasive Bladder Cancer Module 24 (NMIBC24) Total Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC-QLQ-NMIBC24 is a 24-item questionnaire developed to supplement the EORTC QLQ-C30 in high-risk NMIBC patients. Each item is scored out of 4 total points (1=Not at All to 4=Very Much). All responses are transformed from 0 to 100, with a high score indicating more symptoms or problems. The change from baseline in EORTC-QLQ-NMIBC24 total score will be presented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cystectomy-free survival (CFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 48 months</time_frame>
    <description>Cystectomy-free survival (CFS)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-muscle Invasive Bladder Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Epirubicin hydrochloride group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>intravesical instillation of Epirubicin hydrochloride</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>APL-1202 group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>receive APL-1202 single-agent oral treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>APL-1202</intervention_name>
    <description>APL-1202 single-agent oral treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>APL-1202 group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Epirubicin Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Epirubicin hydrochloride</description>
    <arm_group_label>Epirubicin hydrochloride group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All patients must meet all the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be informed of the investigational nature of this study and must provide written&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years, male or female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-muscle invasive transitional cell carcinoma of the bladder is histologically&#xD;
             confirmed by Independent Pathology Review Committee (IPRC). Diagnosis and&#xD;
             classification of intermediate-risk NMIBC is according to 2014 CUA Guideline of&#xD;
             Diagnosis and Treatment of Urological Diseases in China:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Low-risk: Primary, solitary, TaGl (PUNLMP, low-grade urothelial carcinoma), &lt;3cm, no CIS.&#xD;
        (Note: the above conditions must be met at the same time as a low-risk NMIBC)&#xD;
        Intermediate-risk: All tumours not defined in the two adjacent categories (between the&#xD;
        category of low and high risk) High-risk: Any of the following: ① T1 tumour; ②G3(high-grade&#xD;
        urothelial carcinoma) tumour;③carcinoma in situ (CIS); ④ Multiple, recurrent and large (&gt; 3&#xD;
        cm) TaG1G2(low-grade urothelial carcinoma) tumours (all features must be present)&#xD;
&#xD;
        • No visible tumor after transurethral resection of bladder tumor (TURBT) on tumor lesion.&#xD;
        Some requirements about Re-TURBT are as follows: It is recommended to conduct the secondary&#xD;
        TURBT under following situations: incomplete first TURBT; no muscle tissue found in the&#xD;
        first TURBT specimen, except Ta G1 (low grade) tumor and CIS only.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The secondary TURBT is recommended 2-6 weeks, but better at 4 weeks, after the first TURBT.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For subjects undergoing secondary TURBT, they will be enrolled after the second TURBT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who never received intravesical instillation (including BCG or intravesical&#xD;
             chemotherapy) prior to enrollment, except single, immediate, post-operative&#xD;
             intravesical chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide pathological tissue specimen for assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG PS ≤ 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients, who have not received blood transfusion or colony-stimulating factor&#xD;
             treatment within 14 days before the examination, must have normal organ and marrow&#xD;
             function within 42 days of study entry (according to normal range in clinical site).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Absolute neutrophil count &gt;1.5×109/L Platelets &gt; 100 ×109/L Hemoglobin &gt; 9.0 g/dL Alkaline&#xD;
        phosphatase &lt; 2.5 ULN GFR (Cockcroft-Gault formula calculated) ≥ 50 mL/min Total bilirubin,&#xD;
        alanine aminotransferase or aspartate aminotransferase&lt; 1.5 ULN INR &lt;1.5, except for&#xD;
        subjects receiving anticoagulation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female should be either surgically sterilized or menopause or agree to use effective&#xD;
             contraceptive measures during treatment. Women of reproductive age must have a&#xD;
             negative result of pregnancy test during the screening period (pregnancy test will be&#xD;
             not required if one of the following situations exists: the subject has undergone&#xD;
             sterilization such as hysterectomy and/or bilateral oophorectomy, has no menstruation&#xD;
             for 12 months and been diagnosed as menopause based on factors such as age). However,&#xD;
             pregnancy tests are required for patients with bilateral fallopian tube ligation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male subjects should be either surgically sterilized or agreed to use effective&#xD;
             contraceptive measures. From signing the informed consent, subjects must take&#xD;
             continuous measures until 3 months after the end of the treatment of trial. The&#xD;
             definition of effective contraceptive measures will be based on the principal&#xD;
             investigator(PI) or appointed delegate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected life expectancy is more than 48 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The presence of any of the following will exclude a patient from study enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low-risk: Primary, solitary, TaGl (PUNLMP, low-grade urothelial carcinoma), &lt;3cm, no&#xD;
             CIS. (PS: the above conditions must be met at the same time as a low-risk NMIBC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High-risk: Any of the following: ① T1 tumour; ②G3(high-grade urothelial carcinoma)&#xD;
             tumour;③carcinoma in situ (CIS); ④ Multiple, recurrent and large (&gt; 3 cm)&#xD;
             TaG1G2(low-grade urothelial carcinoma) tumours (all features must be present)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tumors of T2 stage or more serious&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The histological types are mainly non-urothelial carcinomas such as squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma and adenocarcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urothelial carcinoma outside the bladder (renal pelvis, ureter or urethra)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received intravesical therapy in last TURBT/cystoscopy prior to treatment period, but&#xD;
             not including immediate intravesical therapy once (the subjects who received the&#xD;
             immediate intravesical therapy need to be recorded in e-CRF)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received surgery (not includes TURBT/cystoscopy), radiation therapy, or systemic&#xD;
             therapy within 6 weeks before enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignancies within 2 years with exception of currently treated basal cell, squamous&#xD;
             cell carcinoma of the skin, or carcinoma &quot;in-situ' of the cervix&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade 3 (according to the NCI CTCAE 5.0) hemorrhage in any part of body within 6 weeks&#xD;
             before starting the treatment of trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following within 6 months prior to study drug administration: myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, severe/unstable angina, coronary/peripheral artery bypass graft,&#xD;
             symptomatic congestive heart failure, cerebrovascular accident or transient ischemic&#xD;
             attack, or pulmonary embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension that cannot be controlled by medications (systolic blood pressure≥140&#xD;
             mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure≥90mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled active infections before starting the treatment of trial, such as acute&#xD;
             pneumonia, active hepatitis B, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dysphagia or known drug absorption disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anuria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One week prior to enrollment, having gross hematuria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active duodenal ulcers, ulcerative colitis and other gastrointestinal diseases or&#xD;
             other conditions that the investigator may determine to cause gastrointestinal&#xD;
             bleeding or perforation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The risk of participation or administration may increase, judged by investigator, or&#xD;
             other severe acute or chronic medical conditions may interfere with the interpretation&#xD;
             and judgment of results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  or optic nerve disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects have optic nerve disorders and cataracts, or other related medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding. Female patients with reproductive potential have a&#xD;
             positive pregnancy test prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychological or mental abnormality, subjects are estimated to have insufficient&#xD;
             adherence to this clinical study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Four weeks prior to enrollment, participate in other clinical trials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who had previously received anthracycline for systemic chemotherapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epirubicin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

