<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04737525</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIS1418</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04737525</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Connective Tissue Graft Versus a Porcine-derived Membrane (Mucoderm) After Immediate Placement</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Influence of a Connective Tissue Graft Versus a Porcine-derived Membrane (Mucoderm) on the Aesthetic Outcome After Immediate Placement and Loading of a Tapered Dental Implant in the Anterior Maxilla. A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vilniaus Implantologijos Centro (VIC) Klinika</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Straumann Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vilniaus Implantologijos Centro (VIC) Klinika</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Esthetic outcome of immediate implant placement in fresh extraction sockets remains one of&#xD;
      the biggest challenges in implant dentistry. Recently a method to preserve the peri-implant&#xD;
      tissues was introduced using provisional restoration, allogenic bone and soft tissue&#xD;
      thickening. However, the evidence that this immediate provisialisation with soft tissue&#xD;
      grafting using different grafting materials results in constantly high Pink Esthetic scores,&#xD;
      especially compared to the delayed loading approach is still lacking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this clinical trial is to assess the esthetic outcome of immediate temporization&#xD;
      of immediately placed and loaded tapered implants in fresh extraction sockets with bone and&#xD;
      soft tissue augmentation, using either a connective tissue graft (CTG) or a porcine-derived&#xD;
      membrane (Mucoderm) in maxillary anterior sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are to investigate the influence of immediate loading on the success&#xD;
      rate of tapered implants and crestal bone levels.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 10, 2031</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Aesthetic evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline, 1 year, 5 and 10 years after prosthetic delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Pink esthetic score (PES) according to Fürhauser et al. 2005 Seven variables will be evaluated: mesial papilla, distal papilla, soft-tissue level, soft-tissue contour, alveolar process deficiency, soft-tissue color and texture. Using a 0-1-2 scoring system, 0 being the lowest, 2 being the highest value, the maximum achievable PES is 14. For the PES assessment, frontal photographs will be taken using a digital camera with a flash strobe mounted on a tripod (Canon 350d, 3456×2304 pixel resolution). PES will be assessed at baseline (Final Prosthesis), 3- and 12-month visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recession of gingiva (REC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline, 1 year, 5 and 10 years after prosthetic delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Position of the gingival/mucosal margin - recorded with a periodontal probe from the incisal edge to the margin at the zenith.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Immediate Implants</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Immediate implant placement and temporization of tapered implants after tooth extraction with buccal augmentation using allogenic bone and porcine-derived membrane.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Immediate implant placement and temporization of tapered implants after tooth extraction with buccal augmentation using allogenic bone and connective tissue grafting (CTG).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dental implant placement, bone and soft tissue augmentation on buccal site</intervention_name>
    <description>Atraumatic extraction&#xD;
Palatinal positioning of tapered implant (BLX) 3.75mm diameter&#xD;
3-4 mm below vestibular gingival line or 1 mm below bone crest&#xD;
Implant placement&#xD;
Allogenic bone packing of the &quot;jumping distance&quot; and soft tissue grafting&#xD;
Connective tissue graft (CTG) or porcine-derived membrane&#xD;
Provisional restoration out of occlusion and mandibular movements&#xD;
X-ray</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Test group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males and females of at least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 1 implant per patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject must have voluntarily signed the informed consent before any study related&#xD;
             action, are willing and able to attend scheduled follow-up visits, and agree that the&#xD;
             pseudonymized data will be collected and analyzed&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Anterior single teeth (canines and incisors) in both jaws&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Class I extraction socket (intact buccal wall) or Class II (1/3 of buccal wall)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. No recession of gingival contour of tooth to be extracted&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No periodontal bone loss of neighboring anterior teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No implants in neighboring teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Atraumatic extraction of the tooth with intact socket walls remaining&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Deep bite (severe II class)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Heavy smokers (more than 10 cigarettes/day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Systemic disease (diabetes, osteoporosis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Primary stability after implant placement not achieved&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VIC clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vilnius</city>
        <zip>10205</zip>
        <country>Lithuania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Lithuania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Soft tissue grafting</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

