<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04737694</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-07HC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04737694</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ketone Supplements and Substrate Oxidation and Physical Performance</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of Ketone Ester Supplementation on Substrate Oxidation and Physical Performance</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this randomized crossover study is to examine the influence of consuming a&#xD;
      ketone ester plus carbohydrate (KE+CHO) supplement on substrate oxidation and physical&#xD;
      performance in 15 healthy adults. Following a 48-hr muscle glycogen normalization period,&#xD;
      volunteers will consume either an isocaloric KE+CHO (KE: 573 mg KE/kg body mass, CHO: 110 g)&#xD;
      or isocaloric CHO drink and complete 90-min of metabolically-matched, load carriage (~30%&#xD;
      body mass) steady-state aerobic (~60 ± 5 % of VO2peak) exercise on a treadmill. Glucose&#xD;
      tracers will be used to assess glucose turnover, and contribution to exogenous and plasma&#xD;
      glucose oxidation. Serial blood draws will be collected during each trial to assess endocrine&#xD;
      and circulating substrate responses. After steady-state exercise volunteers will complete a&#xD;
      time to exhaustion (TTE) physical performance tests at 85% VO2peak on a treadmill. Volunteers&#xD;
      will then be provided with food for the remainder of the day. Following a 10-hr overnight&#xD;
      fast, volunteers will return to the laboratory and consume the same supplement (KE+CHO or&#xD;
      CHO) as they did the previous day. Volunteers will then perform a 4-mile load carriage time&#xD;
      trial on a treadmill. Following a minimum 7-day washout period, volunteers will return to the&#xD;
      laboratory to complete the second arm of the study. The primary risks associated with this&#xD;
      study include those associated with exercise, blood draws, and gastrointestinal discomfort&#xD;
      from the KE+CHO supplement.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Following an overnight (10 hour) fast, two catheters will be placed into the lower arm (one&#xD;
      in each arm). One arm will be used for infusion of 6,6-[2H2] glucose tracer and the other&#xD;
      will be used for blood sampling under resting and exercise conditions. Following an initial&#xD;
      blood sample collection to determine background enrichments, a primed, continuous infusion of&#xD;
      6,6-[2H2] glucose will begin (prime, 82.2 µmol∙kg-1; continuous rate, 0.78 µmol∙kg-1∙min-1,&#xD;
      Figure 1). The 6,6-[2H2] glucose will be infused for 100 min under resting fasted conditions&#xD;
      to ensure isotopic steady-state is achieved prior to initiating exercise. Volunteers will&#xD;
      consume either an isocaloric KE+CHO (KE: 573 mg KE/kg body mass, CHO: 110 g) or CHO drink&#xD;
      prior to and during 90-min of metabolically-matched (~60 ± 5 % of VO2peak), steady-state load&#xD;
      carriage (~30% body mass) exercise. Drinks will be enriched with U-13C-glucose (Cambridge&#xD;
      Isotope Laboratory, Andover, MA, USA) to increase the isotopic enrichment well above natural&#xD;
      levels and optimize the measurement of exogenous carbohydrate oxidation. During exercise&#xD;
      V̇O2, V̇CO2, and HR will be measured at approximately 0, 20, 45, 60, 75, and 85 min.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the 90-min steady-state treadmill exercise, participants will complete a TTE&#xD;
      performance test. For volunteer safety TTE performance tests will be conducted without the&#xD;
      additional weight from the load carriage exercise. Volunteers will be given time to stretch&#xD;
      and warm-up on the treadmill before the TTE performance test beings. Volunteers will then run&#xD;
      on the treadmill at a fixed speed and grade that elicits 85% of their VO2peak. The TTE&#xD;
      performance test will be determined as the time of volitional exhaustion. Following&#xD;
      completion of the test, a self-selected cool-down will occur. Volunteers will complete a&#xD;
      minimum of two practice exercise sessions to ensure they are familiar with the performance&#xD;
      test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following day volunteers will return to the laboratory after an overnight fast. After&#xD;
      consuming the study drink (KE+CHO or CHO) participants will complete a self-paced 4-mile load&#xD;
      carriage (~30% body mass) time trial on a treadmill to assess aerobic performance. Time trial&#xD;
      performance will be assessed as the total amount of time taken to complete 4 miles. The&#xD;
      treadmill will be set at a constant 1% grade for the entire test. Following a warm-up period,&#xD;
      volunteers will blindly modulate treadmill speed in order to complete the distance as quickly&#xD;
      as possible. The only feedback given will be distance covered at half mile increments. At&#xD;
      half mile increments volunteers' rate of perceived exertion will be determined using the Borg&#xD;
      Scale. Heart rate will be monitored throughout the time trial. Heart rate will be recorded at&#xD;
      half mile increments. No motivation will be provided during the time trial. Participants may&#xD;
      consume water ad libitum during the time trial. Following completion of the test, a&#xD;
      self-selected cool-down will occur. Volunteers will complete a minimum of two practice&#xD;
      exercise sessions to ensure they are familiar with the performance test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double blinded randomized crossover design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double blinded</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to exhaustion</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the effect of ketone esters plus carbohydrate (KE + CHO) supplementation on physical performance as determine by time to exhaustion at 85% VO2max on a treadmill compared to CHO alone</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time trial</measure>
    <time_frame>120 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the effect of ketone esters plus carbohydrate (KE + CHO) supplementation on physical performance as determine by a self paced 4 mile time trial on a treadmill compared to CHO alone</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Substrate oxidatoin</measure>
    <time_frame>90 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the effect of KE + CHO supplementation on changes in substrate oxidation during moderate-intensity load carriage exercise compared to CHO alone.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Ketosis</condition>
  <condition>Glucose Metabolism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ketone + Carbohydrate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>573 mg/ kg body weight ketone ester + 110 g glucose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Carbohydrate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Isocaloric amount of glucose to match ketone + carbohydrate</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketone ester</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral ketone ester + glucose supplement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ketone + Carbohydrate</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Glucose</intervention_name>
    <description>Glucose supplement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carbohydrate</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women aged 18 - 39 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) &lt; 30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Routinely participate in aerobic and/or resistance exercise at least 2 days per week&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refrain from the use of caffeine, alcohol, dietary supplements, and nicotine while&#xD;
             consuming study diets&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Supervisor approval to participate for active duty military and federal civilian&#xD;
             employees working within the US Army Natick Soldier Systems Center&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metabolic or cardiovascular abnormalities, gastrointestinal disorders (i.e., kidney&#xD;
             disease, diabetes, cardiovascular disease, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disease or medication (i.e., diabetes medications, statins, corticosteroids, etc) that&#xD;
             affects macronutrient utilization and/or the ability to participate in strenuous&#xD;
             exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergies or intolerance to foods (including but not limited to lactose&#xD;
             intolerance/milk allergy) to be utilized in the study or vegetarian practices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present condition of alcoholism, anabolic steroids, or other substance abuse issues&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Musculoskeletal injuries that compromise the ability to exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to avoid non-study exercise and foods during each of the 3 day testing&#xD;
             periods&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood donation within 8 weeks of beginning the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lee M Margolis, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>United States Army Research Institute of Environmental Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>USARIEM</name>
      <address>
        <city>Natick</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>01760</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

