<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04735783</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TS_Placebo_2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04735783</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Placebo Breakfast Consumption, Appetite and Food Intake</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of the Perception of Breakfast Consumption on Appetite and Energy Intake in Healthy Males</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nottingham Trent University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Loughborough University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nottingham Trent University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study was to examine the effects of a very low-energy, viscous placebo&#xD;
      breakfast meal on subjective appetite sensations during the morning, and food intake at&#xD;
      lunch, compared to a typical whole-food breakfast meal and a water-only control. Participants&#xD;
      will not be told that the placebo breakfast contains nearly no energy until the end of the&#xD;
      study. The breakfasts will be provided in a randomised order, with a period of at least four&#xD;
      days separating the trials. Blood samples will be taken before and after the breakfast is&#xD;
      eaten to see how appetite-regulating proteins and blood sugars respond during the morning.&#xD;
      Appetite questionnaires will also be completed throughout the morning, and a pasta-based&#xD;
      lunch meal will be provided so that voluntary food intake can be measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Obesity is a risk factor for several chronic diseases, including type-2 diabetes, heart&#xD;
      disease and some forms of cancer. There is clear evidence demonstrating that weight gain&#xD;
      occurs progressively over the lifespan, highlighting that preventative action should be taken&#xD;
      by young, lean individuals, who may yet develop overweight or obesity later in life. A&#xD;
      positive energy imbalance, in which energy intake exceeds energy expenditure for a sustained&#xD;
      duration, is known to be the underlying systematic cause of obesity. Therefore, reducing&#xD;
      daily energy intake is a seemingly simple solution to the this problem. However, compensatory&#xD;
      alterations in appetite regulation which stimulate an increase in energy intake often impede&#xD;
      the long-term success of such interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Extending the overnight fasting period, thereby restricting the time available for food&#xD;
      intake, has emerged as an effective dietary strategy for reducing daily energy intake and may&#xD;
      assist with weight management. Laboratory studies have shown that skipping breakfast&#xD;
      typically results in increased appetite during the morning, and an increase in energy intake&#xD;
      at lunch. Therefore, the long-term success of skipping breakfast may be reduced by elevated&#xD;
      appetite sensations. A recent study which aimed to assess the effects of a very-low energy,&#xD;
      placebo breakfast on resistance exercise performance noted that appetite was suppressed after&#xD;
      consuming the placebo, despite its lack of energy content. Whether this suppression of&#xD;
      appetite following placebo breakfast consumption results in a reduced energy intake at lunch,&#xD;
      is currently unknown. Therefore, the investigators are interested to examine the subjective&#xD;
      and hormonal appetite responses to placebo breakfast consumption, compared with these&#xD;
      responses to an overt breakfast consumption trial an overt breakfast skipping trial, and&#xD;
      whether these changes result in any differences in voluntary energy intake at lunch.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present study is a randomised, controlled, crossover study in which fourteen healthy,&#xD;
      habitual breakfast-consuming (self-reported) males will consume a very low-energy, viscous&#xD;
      placebo breakfast, a typically consumed, whole-food breakfast, and a water-only control. At&#xD;
      least four days will separate trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will firstly complete a pre-screening session in which anthropometric data will&#xD;
      be collected. This will be used to determine the energy content of the typical whole-food&#xD;
      breakfast.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 11, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 11, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study design is a randomised, controlled, crossover design in which participants undertake three dietary conditions in a randomised order with at least a four day period in between trials.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Due to the obvious differences between the three breakfasts meals (viscous, jelly-like placebo breakfast, typical whole-food breakfast, water-only control), participants will be aware that the three trials are different. However, they will not be told that the placebo breakfast contains nearly no energy, and therefore, are blinded to this aspect of the study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Voluntary energy intake (Kilocalories) at a laboratory-based test lunch meal</measure>
    <time_frame>195 minutes post-breakfast provision.</time_frame>
    <description>A laboratory-based meal consisting of pasta, tomato sauce and olive oil will be provided to participants in excess of expected consumption. Participants will be permitted 20 minutes to eat as much or as little as they desire, until 'comfortably full and satisfied'.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual Analogue Scale for Subjective Ratings of Appetite</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 10 minutes, 30 minutes, 60 minutes, 120 minutes, 195 minutes, 215 minutes, 275 minutes post-breakfast provision.</time_frame>
    <description>Time-course of subjective ratings of hunger between breakfast provision and one hour after consuming lunch, measured using an appetite visual analogue scale. The scale is divided into subscales of different appetite perceptions including: hunger, fullness, desire to eat and prospective food consumption. Each subscale is rated on a 100mm scale (i.e. from 0 - 100), with a rating of 100 fully supporting the perception and a rating of 0 fully opposing the perception.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acylated ghrelin</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 60 minutes, 180 minutes post-breakfast provision.</time_frame>
    <description>Time-course of acylated ghrelin plasma concentrations across experimental trials.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peptide tyrosine-tyrosine (PYY)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 60 minutes, 180 minutes post-breakfast provision.</time_frame>
    <description>Time-course of PYY plasma concentrations across experimental trials.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood glucose concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 30 minutes, 60 minutes, 90 minutes, 120 minutes, 180 minutes post-breakfast provision.</time_frame>
    <description>Time-course of blood glucose concentrations across experimental trials.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Very low-energy, viscous placebo breakfast</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will consumed a viscous breakfast meal from a standard bowl with a standard spoon. The volume of the meal will be 5 mL/kg body mass, consisting of 15% (0.75 mL/kg body mass) low-energy flavoured squash, with the remainder made up of tap water. To thicken the solution and increase the perception of energy intake, 0.1 g/kg xanthan gum (a soluble fibre often used as a low-energy thickening agent) will be added and the mixture will be blended thoroughly. An additional 3 mL/kg tap water will be consumed as a drink alongside the meal in this trial.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Typical, whole-food breakfast</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will consume a standardised meal consisting of puffed rice cereal, semi-skimmed milk, white bread, seedless strawberry jam, and apple juice. This meal will provide 20% of estimated energy requirements, determined by multiplying estimated resting metabolic rate by a physical activity level of 1.6. A measured volume of tap water will be consumed alongside this meal, in order to match total water content of the typical whole-food breakfast to the very low-energy, viscous placebo breakfast.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Water-only control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will consume 8 mL/kg body mass of plain tap water to match the total water content of the typical whole-food breakfast and the very low-energy, viscous placebo breakfast.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo breakfast</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will consume a very low-energy, placebo breakfast meal, but will be unaware of its near complete absence of energy until the end of the study.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Very low-energy, viscous placebo breakfast</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Typical whole-food breakfast</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will consume a typical whole-food breakfast meal, equating to 20% of estimated energy requirements.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Typical, whole-food breakfast</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Water-only control</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will consume a volume of plain water to match the water content of the very low-energy placebo breakfast and the typical whole-food breakfast.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Water-only control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-smoker.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Habitually consuming breakfast at least 3 days per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have maintained a stable weight for 6 months (self-reported).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No known history of gastric, digestive, cardiovascular or renal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Food allergies, dislike or intolerance of study foods or drinks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently on a weight management program or have irregular eating patterns (i.e.&#xD;
             extended fasting periods &gt;8h other than overnight - self reported).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medication that may affect hormone concentrations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excessive alcohol consumption (&gt;4 units/day).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intensive training schedule (&gt;10 hours/week).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Loughborough University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Loughborough</city>
        <zip>LE11 3TU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nottingham Trent University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nottingham</city>
        <zip>NG11 8NS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Naharudin MN, Adams J, Richardson H, Thomson T, Oxinou C, Marshall C, Clayton DJ, Mears SA, Yusof A, Hulston CJ, James LJ. Viscous placebo and carbohydrate breakfasts similarly decrease appetite and increase resistance exercise performance compared with a control breakfast in trained males. Br J Nutr. 2020 Mar 16:1-9. doi: 10.1017/S0007114520001002. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32174286</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mears SA, Dickinson K, Bergin-Taylor K, Dee R, Kay J, James LJ. Perception of Breakfast Ingestion Enhances High-Intensity Cycling Performance. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018 Apr 1;13(4):504-509. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0318. Epub 2018 May 14.</citation>
    <PMID>28952831</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chowdhury EA, Richardson JD, Tsintzas K, Thompson D, Betts JA. Effect of extended morning fasting upon ad libitum lunch intake and associated metabolic and hormonal responses in obese adults. Int J Obes (Lond). 2016 Feb;40(2):305-11. doi: 10.1038/ijo.2015.154. Epub 2015 Aug 17.</citation>
    <PMID>26278005</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chowdhury EA, Richardson JD, Tsintzas K, Thompson D, Betts JA. Carbohydrate-rich breakfast attenuates glycaemic, insulinaemic and ghrelin response to ad libitum lunch relative to morning fasting in lean adults. Br J Nutr. 2015 Jul 14;114(1):98-107. doi: 10.1017/S0007114515001506. Epub 2015 May 25.</citation>
    <PMID>26004166</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clayton DJ, Barutcu A, Machin C, Stensel DJ, James LJ. Effect of Breakfast Omission on Energy Intake and Evening Exercise Performance. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2015 Dec;47(12):2645-52. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0000000000000702.</citation>
    <PMID>25970668</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Betts JA, Chowdhury EA, Gonzalez JT, Richardson JD, Tsintzas K, Thompson D. Is breakfast the most important meal of the day? Proc Nutr Soc. 2016 Nov;75(4):464-474. Epub 2016 Jun 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27292940</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clayton DJ, James LJ. The effect of breakfast on appetite regulation, energy balance and exercise performance. Proc Nutr Soc. 2016 Aug;75(3):319-27. doi: 10.1017/S0029665115004243. Epub 2015 Dec 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26653842</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Astbury NM, Taylor MA, Macdonald IA. Breakfast consumption affects appetite, energy intake, and the metabolic and endocrine responses to foods consumed later in the day in male habitual breakfast eaters. J Nutr. 2011 Jul;141(7):1381-9. doi: 10.3945/jn.110.128645. Epub 2011 May 11.</citation>
    <PMID>21562233</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Levitsky DA, Pacanowski CR. Effect of skipping breakfast on subsequent energy intake. Physiol Behav. 2013 Jul 2;119:9-16. doi: 10.1016/j.physbeh.2013.05.006. Epub 2013 May 11.</citation>
    <PMID>23672851</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Betts JA, Richardson JD, Chowdhury EA, Holman GD, Tsintzas K, Thompson D. The causal role of breakfast in energy balance and health: a randomized controlled trial in lean adults. Am J Clin Nutr. 2014 Aug;100(2):539-47. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.114.083402. Epub 2014 Jun 4.</citation>
    <PMID>24898233</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Nottingham Trent University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tommy Slater</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breakfast skipping</keyword>
  <keyword>Energy intake</keyword>
  <keyword>Energy balance</keyword>
  <keyword>Appetite hormones</keyword>
  <keyword>Placebo feeding</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

