<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733274</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18.081.01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733274</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patient and Healthcare Professional Views on Genetic/Genomic Information and Testing</brief_title>
  <official_title>Patient and Healthcare Professional Views on Genetic/Genomic Information and Testing</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Boston College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Boston College</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Technologic advances (i.e. next generation sequencing technologies and novel bioinformatics&#xD;
      approaches) have been drivers of scientific discovery and have deepened our understanding of&#xD;
      the genetics and genomics of health and disease. In parallel, the falling cost of sequencing&#xD;
      has led to screening moving from specialty clinics into the primary care setting. However,&#xD;
      our ability to help patients and families understand these technologies and related genetic&#xD;
      health literacy issues lag behind. These factors pose a number of questions and challenges&#xD;
      for clinicians including: how can we best present complex genetic/genomic information to&#xD;
      patients to ensure that patients understand the information and can make informed decisions?&#xD;
      What are the specific information and support needs of patients and families to be able to&#xD;
      make decisions that are in line with their values? In collaboration with investigators from&#xD;
      the Harvard Reproductive Endocrine Sciences Center at the Massachusetts General Hospital,&#xD;
      this project broadly aims to examine patient understanding and factors affecting decisions&#xD;
      surrounding genetic testing. Using the paradigm of a rare genetic disorder (isolated&#xD;
      gonadotropin releasing hormone [GnRH] deficiency - hypogonadotropic hypogonadism/Kallmann&#xD;
      syndrome [HH/KS]) we will examine the views and perspectives of patients and healthcare&#xD;
      professionals alike regarding genetic/genomic information and testing with the intention of&#xD;
      identifying patient-centered responses to these unmet needs and challenges.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The focus of this study is to better understand perspectives on genetic testing. The study&#xD;
      will collect and analyze both quantitative and qualitative data form healthcare professionals&#xD;
      as well as patients. Findings will be used to inform more person-centered approaches to&#xD;
      genetic testing that will support high-quality decisions that are informed and aligned with&#xD;
      patient values and preferences. To achieve this, the study has three specific aims.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1. Evaluate the understandability and acceptability of education materials (including&#xD;
      information on genetic testing) co-created with patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient education materials will be created drawing on healthcare professionals expertise&#xD;
      (i.e. content experts) and patients (i.e. lived experience). Quality of materials will be&#xD;
      quantitatively measured using the gold standard Patient Education Materials Assessment Tool&#xD;
      (PEMAT).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2. Identify the central elements for a patient decision aid using expert clinician&#xD;
      opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthcare professionals who are content experts in the field will be surveyed to determine&#xD;
      key information for a proposed genetic testing decision aid. Quantitative findings will guide&#xD;
      the content of a patient decision aid for genetic testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3. Explore patient needs for information and support related to genetic testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative focus groups with patients will be conducted and analyzed using thematic&#xD;
      analysis. Findings will inform the development of a patient decision aid for genetic testing&#xD;
      that is responsive to the aspects which matter most to patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 22, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the understandability and acceptability of education materials (including information on genetic testing) cocreated with patients</measure>
    <time_frame>1-hour post-test</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Education Materials Assessment Tool (PEMAT): higher scores indicate materials that are more readily understood and actionable by patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Aim 2. Identify the central elements for a patient decision aid using expert clinician opinion</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>survey with Likert-type scale questions: higher scores indicate a perceived higher priority for respective items/topic matter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Aim 3. Explore patient needs for information and support related to genetic testing</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative focus group findings (thematic analysis) - open ended questions will probe the nature of experiences with genetic testing as well as perceived promoters and barriers to testing and sharing results with potentially at-risk blood relatives</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aim 3. Explore patient needs for information and support related to genetic testing</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>similarities/differences in face-to-face vs. virtual focus groups - emergent themes form face-to-face and virtual focus groups will be compared to identify similarities/differences in the type and quantity of elicited codes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypogonadism, Hypogonadotropic</condition>
  <condition>Kallmann Syndrome</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patietns diagnosed with either normosmic hypogonadotropic hypogonadism (HH) or Kallmann&#xD;
        syndrome (KS)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. self-identified as having been diagnosed with either normosmic hypogonadotropic&#xD;
             hypogonadism (HH) or Kallmann syndrome (KS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. between the ages of 18-70 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. primary language is English/capable of responding to a written questionnaire in&#xD;
             English&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. has lived in the United states for 5 years or longer&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. checking the opt-in electronic consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. other diagnosis of hypogonadism i.e. Klinefelter syndrome, or adult-onset&#xD;
             hypogonadotropic hypogonadism&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. outside the stated age range&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrew A Dwyer, FNP-BC, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Boston College</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrew A Dwyer, FNP-BC, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>617-522-1711</phone>
    <email>andrew.dwyer@bc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrew A Dwyer, FNP-BC, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>617-552-1711</phone>
      <email>andrew.dwyer@bc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Boston College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chestnut Hill</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02467</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrew A Dwyer, FNP-BC, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>617-552-1711</phone>
      <email>andrew.dwyer@bc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Boston College</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andrew Dwyer</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kallmann Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypogonadism</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

