<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04735380</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P-2020-1159</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04735380</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Agreements Between Transcutaneous and Arterial Monitoring of Oxygen and Carbon Dioxide After Non-cardiac Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Agreements Between Transcutaneous and Arterial Monitoring of Oxygen and Carbon Dioxide After Non-cardiac Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary aim of the study is to describe the association between changes in TcO2 and TcCO2&#xD;
      and interventions such as blood transfusion, fluid therapy, respiratory support, use of&#xD;
      vasopressors, analgesics, and adverse events during PACU admission. The secondary aim is to&#xD;
      describe the agreement between TcPO2 and TcPCO2 and PaO2 and PaCO2 in patients after&#xD;
      non-cardiac surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study method The data collection will start 1st of February 2021 and will be finished by 30th&#xD;
      of April 2021. Patients will be set up with TCM equipment and an Empatica at the PACU. They&#xD;
      will be observed for 2 hours. If an intervention is started before 2 hours and not completed,&#xD;
      recordings will continue until 5 minutes after the intervention is completed for a maximum of&#xD;
      1 hour (3 hours maximal observation). The sensor will be placed on the patient's&#xD;
      antebrachium. Patients will be set up with TCM equipment as soon as possible after arrival at&#xD;
      PACU. Every clinical procedure entailing changes in circulatory and/or respiratory support or&#xD;
      medication (appendix 1) will be observed and noted in a timetable (ap-pendix 2). Perfusion&#xD;
      index (PI) and a full DASAIM score (Danish Association of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care&#xD;
      Medicine) will be noted every 15 minutes. Every ABG analysis of PaO2, PaCO2 and lactate&#xD;
      conducted during the observational period will be noted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age, sex, BMI (Body Mass Index), ASA-score (American Society of Anesthesiologists physical&#xD;
      sta-tus classification), comorbidity (Charlson Comorbidity Index - CCI), baseline laboratory&#xD;
      data (hemo-globin and creatinine) and name of surgical procedure will be obtained for each&#xD;
      patient. REDCap (Research Electronic Data Capture) will be used as a data management system&#xD;
      for the project. The study is a part of the Wireless Assessment of Respiratory and&#xD;
      circulatory Distress (WARD) project.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study materials All patients will be monitored with a TCM-5 Flex monitor connected to a&#xD;
      Sensor 84 (Radiometer Medical Aps, Brønshøj, Denmark). The sensor consists of a&#xD;
      Stow-Severinghaus-type TcPCO2 electrode combined with a Clark-type TcPO2 electrode, with&#xD;
      values per second for TcPO2, TcPCO2 in kPa and heat effect measured in units of mW. The&#xD;
      sensor temperature will automatically be heated to 43.5℃ and calibrated. The sensor membrane&#xD;
      will be changed every 28th day. There will be a 20-minute stabilization period from patient&#xD;
      setup to valid data capturing. The use of sensors and monitors will be according to the&#xD;
      manufacturer's instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As a supplement, patients will be wearing an Empatica, as a measurement for the activity of&#xD;
      the autonomic nervous system. The Empatica tracks activity, heartrate, blood volume pulse,&#xD;
      skin temper-ature and skin conductance. The Empatica E4 consist of a PPG sensor and an EDA&#xD;
      sensor. Data from the E4 will be processed in further studies and is not a part of the&#xD;
      statistical analysis in this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics The primary analysis is changes in TCM readings, and the association between&#xD;
      clinical procedures, tested using paired statistics comparing both average (mean) TcPO2 and&#xD;
      TcPCO2 during 5 minutes before an intervention versus 5 minutes after an intervention.&#xD;
      Depending on the data distribution, either t-test or Wilcoxon test will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary analysis includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Changes in TCM and association with specific intervention including grouping into&#xD;
           circulatory and respiratory groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Agreement between TcPO2 and PaO2, TcPCO2 and PaCO2. Agreement between the two&#xD;
           tech-niques will be assessed using Bland-Altmann analysis including description of mean&#xD;
           differ-ence and limits of agreement(17). In case of left-skewed data, log transformation&#xD;
           will be ap-plied. A four-quadrant plot will be constructed to assess trending ability&#xD;
           and a concordance rate will be calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tertiary analysis includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An ANCOVA (analyses of co-variance) of the primary and secondary outcomes, with the&#xD;
           following predefined variables: age, sex, BMI, ASA-score, and comorbidity, baseline&#xD;
           labora-tory data (hemoglobin and creatinine).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Agreement between perfusion-index and TCM. Agreement between the two techniques will be&#xD;
           assessed using Bland-Altmann analysis including description of mean difference and&#xD;
           limits of agreement. In case of left-skewed data, log transformation will be applied. A&#xD;
           four-quadrant plot will be constructed to assess trending ability and a concordance rate&#xD;
           will be calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All results will be stated with their 95% confidence interval (CI). The significance level&#xD;
      will be 5%, meaning p-values under 0.05 will be acknowledged as statistically significant.&#xD;
      All analyses will be performed using Python 3.7 and the software program PyCharm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>TCM changes</measure>
    <time_frame>31-08-21</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is changes in TCM recordings before and after clinical interventions and/or acute severe adverse events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ABG and TCM</measure>
    <time_frame>31-08-21</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary outcome is changes in arterial blood gasses before and after clinical interventions and/or acute severe adverse events if recorded in the PACU.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Post Anesthesia Care Optimaization</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TCM-5 Flex monitor connected to a Sensor 84 (Radiometer Medical Aps, Brønshøj, Denmark)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients undergo 2-3 hrs of observation while wearing the device.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will be patients undergoing major abdominal, urological, vascular, or&#xD;
        orthope-dic surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A scheduled stay at PACU for at least 3 postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;18 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sandra Amalie Thy</last_name>
    <phone>+4526991622</phone>
    <email>sandra.amalie.thy@regionh.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rigshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sandra A Thy, Medical student</last_name>
      <phone>+4526991622</phone>
      <email>sandra.amalie.thy@regionh.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Denmark</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Eske Kvanner Aasvang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

