<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04730843</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ES102-1001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04730843</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of ES102 (OX40 Agonist) in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Multicenter, Dose-escalation and Cohort Expansion Phase 1 Clinical Study of ES102 Administered as a Single Agent in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Elpiscience Biopharma, Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Elpiscience Biopharma, Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety, tolerance, Dose-Limiting Toxicity (DLT),&#xD;
      Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and/or Recommended Phase 2 Dose (RP2D) of ES102 (OX40 Agonist)&#xD;
      administered as a single agent in patients with advanced solid tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) and/or Recommended Phase 2 Dose (RP2D) of of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The MTD and/or RP2D of ES102 will be determined.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events and serious adverse events of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The safety profile of ES102 will be assessed by the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE), version 5.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the serum concentration time curve (AUC) of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the serum concentration time curve (AUC) of ES102 will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed serum concentration (Cmax) of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum observed serum concentration (Cmax) of ES102 will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Trough observed serum concentration (Ctrough) of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3years</time_frame>
    <description>Trough observed serum concentration (Ctrough) of ES102 will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Cmax (Tmax) of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3years</time_frame>
    <description>Time to Cmax (Tmax) of ES102 will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3years</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of anti-drug antibodies (ADA) against ES102 will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-tumor activity of ES102</measure>
    <time_frame>2-3years</time_frame>
    <description>Tumor response will be determined by the revised Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors version 1.1 (RECISTv1.1).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <condition>Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A dose escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ES102 will be escalated in patients with advanced solid tumors.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part B expansion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with advanced non-small cell lung cancer, advanced esophageal squamous cell carcinoma, other advanced solid tumors (such as nasopharyngeal carcinoma, cervical cancer, gastrointestinal tumors, other reproductive system tumors, etc.) will be treated with ES102 at the RP2D.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ES102</intervention_name>
    <description>ES102 is administered via intravenous injection once every 21 days, every 21 days as a treatment cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part A dose escalation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part B expansion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Males or females aged ≥18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Part A: Subjects with pathological or cytological diagnosed advanced solid tumor,&#xD;
             whose disease has progressed despite standard therapies, or for whom no further&#xD;
             standard therapy exists, or who is unsuitable for available standard therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Part B: Subjects with NSCLC, ESCC, NPC, GI or Cervical cancers, with advanced disease,&#xD;
             which has progressed despite all standard therapies or for whom no standard therapy&#xD;
             exists, or who is unsuitable for available standard therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
             All subjects with NSCLC have documentation of absence of tumor activating EGFR&#xD;
             mutation and absence of ALK and ROS1 gene rearrangements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. PD-L1 by IHC result mandatory but any score allowed .&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At least one measurable lesion is required (RECIST v1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate hematologic, coagulation, hepatic and renal function as defined per protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group performance status (ECOG PS) of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Estimated life expectancy, in the judgment of the investigator, of at least 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Male and female subjects of childbearing potential and their spouses must be willing&#xD;
             to use feasible contraceptive methods considered effective by the investigator, from&#xD;
             the time of signing informed consent and for the duration of study participation&#xD;
             through 3 months, following the last dose of study drug. Postmenopausal women are&#xD;
             considered to have no fertility potential only if menostasis lasts for at least 12&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Prior exposure to OX40 agonists.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known allergies to CHO-produced antibodies, which in the opinion of the Investigator&#xD;
             suggests an increased potential for an adverse hypersensitivity to ES102.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Receipt of any anticancer investigational product or any approved anticancer drug(s)&#xD;
             or biological product(s) within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study drug with&#xD;
             certain exceptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with other malignancies within 2 years before screening shall be excluded in&#xD;
             Part B. Some exceptions as defined per protocol apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Hematologic malignancies (e.g., ALL, AML, MDS, CLL, CML, NHL, Hodgkin's lymphoma and&#xD;
             multiple myeloma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known or active primary central nervous system (CNS) tumors, leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
             and CNS metastases. Exception: subjects with previously treated, asymptomatic, and&#xD;
             clinically stable CNS metastases may be allowed study entry if certain criteria apply&#xD;
             in Part B.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Grade ≥ 3 immune-related adverse events (irAEs) or irAE that lead to discontinuation&#xD;
             of prior immunotherapy. Some exceptions as defined per protocol apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Active autoimmune disease or documented history of autoimmune disease that required&#xD;
             systemic steroids or other immunosuppressive medications. Certain exceptions as&#xD;
             defined in protocol apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Treatment with systemic immunosuppressive medications within 4 weeks prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of study drug. Certain exceptions as defined in protocol apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection&#xD;
             for Part A. Exceptions as defined in protocol for Part B will apply.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Active interstitial lung disease (ILD) or pneumonitis or a history of ILD or&#xD;
             pneumonitis requiring treatment with steroids or other immunosuppressive medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Clinically significant cardiac condition, including myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             uncontrolled angina, cerebrovascular accident, or other acute uncontrolled heart&#xD;
             disease &lt; 6 months; left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 50%; New York Heart&#xD;
             Association (NYHA) Class III or IV congestive heart failure; or uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Active, hemodynamically significant pulmonary embolism within 3 months prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to enrollment on this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Systemic anti-infectious drug treatments within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Prior organ allograft transplantations or allogeneic peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC)&#xD;
             or bone marrow (BM) transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Pregnant or nursing females.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any known, documented, or suspected history of substance abuse that would preclude&#xD;
             subject from participation, unless clinically justified (i.e., will not interfere with&#xD;
             study participation and/or will not compromise trial objectives) per judgment of the&#xD;
             Investigator and with approval of the Medical Monitor or Study Director.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. The subject is inappropriate to participate in this study for other reasons in the&#xD;
             judgment of the Investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ning Chen</last_name>
    <phone>86 15021415086</phone>
    <email>clinical-operation@elpiscience.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jilin Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changchun</city>
        <state>Jilin</state>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ning Zhang</last_name>
      <phone>86 0431-80596067</phone>
      <email>JPCHIRB@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ES102</keyword>
  <keyword>solid tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>phase 1</keyword>
  <keyword>OX40</keyword>
  <keyword>INBRX-106</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

