<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733183</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PH-L19TNFSARC-03/18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733183</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of L19TNF in Previously Treated Patients With Advanced Stage or Metastatic Soft-tissue Sarcoma</brief_title>
  <acronym>FLASH</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized Study to Investigate the Efficacy and Safety of the Tumor-targeting Human Antibody-cytokine Fusion Protein L19TNF in Previously Treated Patients With Advanced Stage or Metastatic Soft-tissue Sarcoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Philogen S.p.A.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Philogen S.p.A.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Open label, randomized, controlled phase II study preceded by a safety run-in part in&#xD;
      subjects with advanced or metastatic soft-tissue sarcoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Open label, randomized, controlled phase II study preceded by a safety run-in part in&#xD;
      subjects with advanced or metastatic soft-tissue sarcoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Safety Run-in Part: Six (6) patients will be treated with 1000 mg/m2 dacarbazine (DTIC)&#xD;
           on Day 1 every 3 weeks plus 13 µg/kg L19TNF on Days 1, 3 and 5 every 3 weeks to test for&#xD;
           safety of the combination. Should unacceptable toxicities occur in ≥ 2 patients during&#xD;
           an observation period from Day 1 to Day 21 (first cycle), enrollment will be stopped at&#xD;
           this dose level and 6 patients will be treated sequentially with DTIC at 850 mg/m2 on&#xD;
           Day 1 every 3 weeks plus 13 µg/kg L19TNF on Days 1, 3 and 5 every 3 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Tumor Activity Evaluation Part&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 86 patients will be enrolled and parallel assigned in a 1:1 fashion to one of&#xD;
      two different arms, as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Arm 1: Patients will receive DTIC on Day 1 every 3 weeks plus L19TNF on Days 1, 3 and 5&#xD;
           every 3 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Arm 2: Patients will receive DTIC on Day 1 every 3 weeks. During the conduct of the&#xD;
           study, detailed safety parameters will be routinely reviewed by the DSMB.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Safety Run in: Six (6) Patients will be treated with 1000 or 850 mg/m2 dacarbazine (DTIC) on Day 1 every three weeks plus 13 µg/kg L19TNF on Days 1, 3 and 5 every three weeks to test for safety of the combination as evaluated by an independent Data Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB).&#xD;
Tumor Activity Evaluation Part Arm 1: Patients will receive DTIC on Day 1 and L19TNF on Days 1, 3 and 5 every 3 weeks.&#xD;
Arm 2: Patients will receive DTIC on Day 1 every 3 weeks.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The PFS rate will be assessed at 3 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS) in according to RECIST v.1.1. The duration is defined beginning from randomization to progression or death from any cause.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The PFS rate will be assessed at 6 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS) in according to RECIST v.1.1. The duration is defined beginning from randomization to progression or death from any cause.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The PFS rate will be assessed at 9 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS) in according to RECIST v.1.1. The duration is defined beginning from randomization to progression or death from any cause.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The PFS rate will be assessed at 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS) in according to RECIST v.1.1. The duration is defined beginning from randomization to progression or death from any cause.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The OS will be calculated at 12, 18, 24 and 36 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival (OS) will be assessed for all randomized patients. The duration is defined beginning from randomization to death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>The ORR rate will be assessed at 3, 6, 9, 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Objective response rate (ORR, consisting of CR plus PR; only the non-irradiated lesions are measured) according to RECIST v.1.1 between arms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>The ORR rate will be assessed at 3, 6, 9, 12 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Objective Response Rate (ORR, consisting of iCR plus iPR; only the non-irradiated lesions are measured) according to iRECIST in Arm1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: From week 1 up to week 52</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with adverse events (AEs) assessed on CTCAE v.4.03</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HAFA assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>At day 1 of week 1 and week 2; at day 1 from week 4 up to week 18; at week 22 (EoT)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of the formation of human anti-fusion protein antibodies (HAFA) against L19TNF.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">98</enrollment>
  <condition>Soft Tissue Sarcoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm1: DTIC + L19TNF</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive Dacarbazine (DTIC) on Day 1 and L19TNF on Days 1, 3 and 5 every 21 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2: DTIC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive Dacarbazine (DTIC) on Day 1 every 21-day cycle .</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dacarbazine</intervention_name>
    <description>Dacarbazine (DTIC), 1000 mg/m2 or 850 mg/m2 on Day 1 of every 21-day cycle (based on results and DSMB evaluation in the safety run-in part of the study)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2: DTIC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm1: DTIC + L19TNF</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>DTIC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>onfekafusp alfa</intervention_name>
    <description>L19TNF, 13 μg/kg, on Day 1, 3, and 5 of every 21-day cycle for a maximum of 6 induction cycles. Patients experiencing apparent or real benefit with minimal or acceptable toxicity from the first 6 cycles of treatment, can receive, at investigator's discretion, maintenance treatment of 13 μg/kg, on Day 1 every 21-day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm1: DTIC + L19TNF</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>L19TNF</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female, 18 to 80 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Histologically or cytologically confirmed advanced unresectable or metastatic soft&#xD;
             tissue sarcoma (STS), Grade 2 - 3 according to the FNLCC grading system. Participants&#xD;
             with bone sarcomas including Ewing sarcoma, Kaposi's sarcoma and gastrointestinal&#xD;
             stromal tumors (GIST) will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects who received at least two prior systemic therapies (e.g., anthracyclines,&#xD;
             taxanes, ifosfamide, gemcitabine, trabectedin, pazopanib, eribulin) for advanced or&#xD;
             metastatic disease including at least one prior therapy based on anthracyclines as&#xD;
             monotherapy or in combination. Neoadjuvant and adjuvant therapies can be considered as&#xD;
             a prior line of treatment if the time to recurrence from completion of treatment was ≤&#xD;
             12 months. Previous therapy with anthracyclines is not compulsory in situations of&#xD;
             contraindications to this class of drugs. All previous therapies must have completed ≥&#xD;
             3 weeks (21 days) prior to study treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Evidence of disease progression after prior line of therapy for advanced or metastatic&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must have at least one unidimensionally measurable lesion by computed&#xD;
             tomography as defined by RECIST criteria v.1.1. If only one lesion is present at&#xD;
             screening this lesion should not have been irradiated during previous treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Life expectancy of at least 3 months in the judgment of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ECOG ≤ 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Documented negative test for HIV-HBV-HCV. For HBV serology: the determination of&#xD;
             HBsAg, anti-HBsAg-Ab and anti-HBcAg-Ab is required. In patients with serology&#xD;
             documenting previous exposure to HBV (i.e., anti-HBs Ab with no history of vaccination&#xD;
             and/or anti-HBc Ab), negative serum HBV-DNA is required. For HCV: HCV-RNA or HCV&#xD;
             antibody test. Subjects with a positive test for HCV antibody but no detection of&#xD;
             HCV-RNA indicating no current infection are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Female patients: negative serum pregnancy test at screening for women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential (WOCBP)*. WOCBP must agree to use, from the screening to six months&#xD;
             following the last study drug administration, highly effective contraception methods,&#xD;
             as defined by the &quot;Recommendations for contraception and pregnancy testing in clinical&#xD;
             trials&quot; issued by the Head of Medicine Agencies' Clinical Trial Facilitation Group&#xD;
             (www.hma.eu/ctfg.html) and which include, for instance, progesterone-only or combined&#xD;
             (estrogen- and progesterone-containing) hormonal contraception associated with&#xD;
             inhibition of ovulation, intrauterine devices, intrauterine hormone-releasing systems,&#xD;
             bilateral tubal occlusion, vasectomized partner or sexual abstinence. Male patients:&#xD;
             Male subjects able to father children must agree to use two acceptable methods of&#xD;
             contraception throughout the study (e.g. condom with spermicidal gel). Double-barrier&#xD;
             contraception is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that&#xD;
             the subject has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Willingness and ability to comply with the scheduled visits, treatment plan,&#xD;
             laboratory tests and other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of childbearing potential are defined as females who have experienced&#xD;
                  menarche, are not postmenopausal (12 months with no menses without an alternative&#xD;
                  medical cause) and are not permanently sterilized (e.g., tubal occlusion,&#xD;
                  hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy or bilateral salpingectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Anti-cancer treatment with radiation therapy (with the exception of radiation of&#xD;
             single lesions for palliative reasons, e.g. pain management which then are not taken&#xD;
             as indicator lesions for iRECIST response), chemotherapy, targeted therapies,&#xD;
             immunotherapy, hormones or other antitumor therapies within 3 weeks prior to study&#xD;
             treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects who participated in an investigational drug or device study within 3 weeks&#xD;
             prior to study treatment start.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous treatment with TNF or L19TNF or DTIC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known history of allergy to intravenously administered human&#xD;
             proteins/peptides/antibodies and any other constituent of the product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1.5 x 109/L, platelets &lt; 100 x 109/L and hemoglobin&#xD;
             (Hb) &lt; 9.0 g/dl, with the exception of values lower than these due to cytologically or&#xD;
             histologically proven marrow metastasis, which will not constitute exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Chronically impaired renal function as expressed by creatinine clearance &lt; 60 mL/min&#xD;
             or serum creatinine &gt; 1.5 ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Inadequate liver function (ALT or AST ≥ 3 x ULN or ALP or GGT ≥ 2.5 x ULN, or total&#xD;
             bilirubin ≥ 1.5 x ULN). For patients with metastatic lesions in the liver ALT, AST,&#xD;
             GGT or ALP ≥ 5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any severe concomitant condition which in the opinion of investigators makes it&#xD;
             undesirable for the patient to participate in the study or which could jeopardize&#xD;
             compliance with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History within the last year of cerebrovascular disease and/or acute or subacute&#xD;
             coronary syndromes including myocardial infarction, unstable or severe stable angina&#xD;
             pectoris.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Heart insufficiency (&gt; Grade II, New York Heart Association (NYHA) criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Clinically significant cardiac arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Abnormalities observed during baseline ECG and echocardiogram investigations that are&#xD;
             considered as clinically significant by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Uncontrolled hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Ischemic peripheral vascular disease (Grade IIb-IV according to Leriche-Fontaine&#xD;
             classification).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Severe diabetic retinopathy such as severe non-proliferative retinopathy and&#xD;
             proliferative retinopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Major trauma including major surgery (such as abdominal/cardiac/thoracic surgery)&#xD;
             within 4 weeks of administration of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Pregnancy or breast-feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Requirement of chronic administration of corticosteroids or other immunosuppressant&#xD;
             drugs. Limited use of corticosteroids to treat or prevent acute hypersensitivity&#xD;
             reactions is not considered an exclusion criterion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Presence of active and uncontrolled infections or other severe concurrent disease,&#xD;
             which, in the opinion of the investigator, would place the patient at undue risk or&#xD;
             interfere with the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Known active or latent tuberculosis (TB).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Concurrent malignancies other than soft-tissue sarcoma, unless the patient has been&#xD;
             disease-free for at least 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Serious, non-healing wound, ulcer or bone fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Allergy to study medication or excipients in study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Concurrent therapy with anticoagulants at full therapeutic dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Concurrent use of other anti-cancer treatments or agents other than study medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Teresa Hemmerle, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+390577017816</phone>
    <email>regulatory@philogen.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Serena Bettarini, Pharmacist</last_name>
    <phone>+39057717816</phone>
    <email>regulatory@philogen.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Münster University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Münster</city>
        <zip>48149</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christoph Schliemann, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+49 251 8346239</phone>
      <email>Christoph.Schliemann@ukmuenster.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dacarbazine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

