<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04732065</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200814</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-00046</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04732065</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ONC206 for Treatment of Newly Diagnosed, or Recurrent Diffuse Midline Gliomas, and Other Recurrent Malignant Brain Tumors (PNOC 023)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Open Label Phase 1 and Target Validation Study of ONC206 in Children and Young Adults With Newly Diagnosed or Recurrent Diffuse Midline Glioma (DMG), and Other Recurrent Primary Malignant Brain Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sabine Mueller, MD, PhD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chimerix</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mithil Prasad Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Storm the Heavens Fund</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The ChadTough Defeat DIPG Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Francisco</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial studies the effects and best dose of ONC206 alone or in combination with&#xD;
      radiation therapy in treating patients with diffuse midline gliomas that is newly diagnosed&#xD;
      or has come back (recurrent) or other recurrent primary malignant brain tumors. ONC206 is a&#xD;
      recently discovered compound that may stop cancer cells from growing. This drug has been&#xD;
      shown in laboratory experiments to kill brain tumor cells by causing a so called &quot;stress&#xD;
      response&quot; in tumor cells. This stress response causes cancer cells to die, but without&#xD;
      affecting normal cells. ONC206 alone or in combination with radiation therapy may be&#xD;
      effective in treating newly diagnosed or recurrent diffuse midline gliomas and other&#xD;
      recurrent primary malignant brain tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the safety and tolerability of DRD2 antagonist/ClpP agonist ONC206 (ONC206).&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of ONC206 as single agent in children and&#xD;
      young adults with diffuse midline glioma (DMG) who completed at least one line of prior&#xD;
      therapy that included focal radiation therapy. (Arm A).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To determine the MTD of ONC206 in combination with focal radiation therapy in newly&#xD;
      diagnosed children and young adults with DMG. (Arm B).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To determine the MTD of ONC206 in combination with re-irradiation in children and young&#xD;
      adults with first progression of DMG. (Arm C).&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. To determine the MTD of ONC206 in children and young adults with recurrent primary&#xD;
      malignant brain tumors including participants with recurrent DMGs if they are not eligible&#xD;
      for the other arms. (Arm D).&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. To assess the concentration of ONC206 in tumor tissue from children and young adults with&#xD;
      DMG and compare to plasma drug levels pre-surgery. (Target validation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      VII. To assess the concentration of ONC206 in tumor tissue in children and young adults with&#xD;
      recurrent primary malignant brain tumors and compare to plasma drug levels pre-surgery.&#xD;
      (Target validation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To describe the pharmacokinetics associated with ONC206 without radiation therapy. (Arms A&#xD;
      and D).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Determine changes in cranial nerve scoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Determine clinical responses within the confines of a phase 1/expansion study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Evaluate correlation of amount of serum and cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) circulating tumor&#xD;
      DNA (ctDNA) with clinical outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Evaluate association of clinical outcomes with anatomic location of tumor, H3K27 mutation&#xD;
      status and other partner mutations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. Pharmacodynamic (PD) effects in tumor tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VI. Assess the overall response rate to ONC206 in patients with prior ONC201 exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VII. Assess pharmacodynamics (PD) of ONC206 and perform exploratory pharmacokinetic (PK)-PD&#xD;
      analyses to investigate and identify the relationship between drug exposure and clinical&#xD;
      endpoints for both safety and efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VIII. To assess Health Related Quality of Life (HRQOL) outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      VIIII. To assess patient and/or proxy satisfaction with study participation via&#xD;
      patient-reported outcome (PRO) measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of ONC206. Patients are assigned to 1 of 4 arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARMS A and D: Patients receive ONC206 orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1, 8, 15, 22.&#xD;
      Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 12 months in the absence of disease progression or&#xD;
      unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARMS B and C: Patients undergo standard of care radiation therapy daily 5 days a week and&#xD;
      receive ONC206 as in Arm A.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days and then every 3&#xD;
      months for up to 5 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants with dose-limiting toxicities (DLT)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>A DLT is defined as a treatment-related adverse event (AE) or abnormal laboratory value that occurs in the first cycle of treatment (Cycle 1 for Arm A and D; Cycle 0 for Arm B and C), meets criteria for DLT as outlined below and is assessed as unrelated to disease, disease progression, inter-current illness, or concomitant medications, and is judged by the investigator to be related to ONC206 as graded by National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>The Bayesian optimal interval (BOIN) design will be used to find the MTD within each arm. MTD is selected based on isotonic regression and this computation is implemented by the shiny app &quot;BOIN&quot; available at http://www.trialdesign.org. Specifically, select as the MTD the dose for which the isotonic estimate of the toxicity rate is closest to the target toxicity rate. If there are ties, select the higher dose level when the isotonic estimate is lower than the target toxicity rate and select the lower dose level when the isotonic estimate is greater than or equal to the target toxicity rate.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean maximum concentration (Cmax) of ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (pre-dose, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8 and 24 hours post-dose), pre-dose on Day 8, pre-dose on Day 15 of Cycle 1, pre-dose on Day 1 of Cycle 2, 4, 6, etc. (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Concentration-time data will be summarized by N, Mean, Standard Deviation, Median, Min, Max and 95% Confidence Interval</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean corresponding time (Tmax) of ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (pre-dose, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8 and 24 hours post-dose), pre-dose on Day 8, pre-dose on Day 15 of Cycle 1, pre-dose on Day 1 of Cycle 2, 4, 6, etc. (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>PK parameters will be estimated using standard population PK methodologies and non-linear mixed effect modeling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the curve (AUC) of ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (pre-dose, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8 and 24 hours post-dose), pre-dose on Day 8, pre-dose on Day 15 of Cycle 1, pre-dose on Day 1 of Cycle 2, 4, 6, etc. (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>PK parameters will be estimated using standard population PK methodologies and non-linear mixed effect modeling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination half-life (t1/2) of ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (pre-dose, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8 and 24 hours post-dose), pre-dose on Day 8, pre-dose on Day 15 of Cycle 1, pre-dose on Day 1 of Cycle 2, 4, 6, etc. (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>PK parameters will be estimated using standard population PK methodologies and non-linear mixed effect modeling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Total body clearance (CL) for ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (pre-dose, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8 and 24 hours post-dose), pre-dose on Day 8, pre-dose on Day 15 of Cycle 1, pre-dose on Day 1 of Cycle 2, 4, 6, etc. (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>PK parameters will be estimated using standard population PK methodologies and non-linear mixed effect modeling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean Volume of Distribution (Vd) for ONC206</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 (pre-dose, 0.5, 1, 2, 4, 8 and 24 hours post-dose), pre-dose on Day 8, pre-dose on Day 15 of Cycle 1, pre-dose on Day 1 of Cycle 2, 4, 6, etc. (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
    <description>PK parameters will be estimated using standard population PK methodologies and non-linear mixed effect modeling</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">256</enrollment>
  <condition>Diffuse Midline Glioma (DMG)</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Brain Tumors</condition>
  <condition>Glioblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Ependymoma</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Malignant Brain Neoplasm</condition>
  <condition>Spinal Cord Glioma</condition>
  <condition>WHO Grade III Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: ONC206 for participants with diffuse midline gliomas + prior therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive ONC206 PO QD on days 1, 8, 15, 22. Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: ONC206 + radiation therapy for newly diagnosed participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo standard of care radiation therapy daily 5 days a week and receive ONC206 PO QD on days 1, 8, 15, 22. Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C: ONC206 + radiation therapy, DMGs with evidence of first progression but previously untreated</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergo standard of care radiation therapy daily 5 days a week and receive ONC206 PO QD on days 1, 8, 15, 22. Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D: ONC206 Therapy, Primary malignant brain tumors with progression</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive ONC206 PO QD on days 1, 8, 15, 22. Cycles repeat every 28 days for up to 12 months in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ONC206</intervention_name>
    <description>Given orally (PO)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm A: ONC206 for participants with diffuse midline gliomas + prior therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: ONC206 + radiation therapy for newly diagnosed participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C: ONC206 + radiation therapy, DMGs with evidence of first progression but previously untreated</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm D: ONC206 Therapy, Primary malignant brain tumors with progression</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>antagonist of dopamine receptor D2 (DRD2) /human mitochondrial caseinolytic protease P (ClpP)ClpP Agonist</other_name>
    <other_name>DRD2 antagonist/ClpP agonist</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care Radiation Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Undergo RT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm B: ONC206 + radiation therapy for newly diagnosed participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm C: ONC206 + radiation therapy, DMGs with evidence of first progression but previously untreated</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Radiation Therapy (RT)</other_name>
    <other_name>Cancer Radiotherapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM A: Children and young adults with DMG (2-21 years of age) who completed at least&#xD;
             one line of prior therapy. Prior treatment must have included focal radiation therapy&#xD;
             and patients must be within 4-14 weeks from completion of radiation therapy and have&#xD;
             no evidence of disease progression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM A: Tumor tissue confirmation of DMG is mandatory and pathology must be consistent&#xD;
             with a DMG including DMG H3K27M mutant and World Health Organization (WHO) grade III&#xD;
             and IV H3 wildtype gliomas. WHO grade II diffuse astrocytomas or other low grade&#xD;
             gliomas without H3K27M mutation are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM A: Participants must have recovered from all acute side effects of prior therapy.&#xD;
             From the projected start of scheduled study treatment, the following time periods must&#xD;
             have elapsed: 5 half-lives from any investigational agent, 4 weeks from cytotoxic&#xD;
             therapy (except 23 days for temozolomide and 6 weeks from nitrosoureas), 4 weeks from&#xD;
             antibodies and must be at least 7 days since the completion of therapy with a biologic&#xD;
             or small molecule agent. For any biologic or small molecule agent with known adverse&#xD;
             events that can occur beyond 7 days after administration, the period prior to&#xD;
             enrollment must be beyond the time during which adverse events are known to occur&#xD;
             (these should be discussed with the study team)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM B: Newly diagnosed children and young adults (2-21 years of age) with a diagnosis&#xD;
             of DMG are eligible, including spinal cord DMGs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM B: Tumor tissue confirmation of DMG is mandatory and pathology must be consistent&#xD;
             with a DMG including DMG H3K27M mutant and WHO grade III and IV H3 wildtype gliomas.&#xD;
             WHO grade II diffuse astrocytomas or other low grade gliomas without H3K27M mutation&#xD;
             are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM C: Children and young adults with DMGs (2-21 years of age) who have evidence of&#xD;
             first progression but have not been treated for this progression and are recommended&#xD;
             to get reirradiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM C: Patients must have undergone prior focal radiation therapy as part of their&#xD;
             initial therapy and should be at least 6 months from prior radiation therapy. If&#xD;
             timing is less than 6 months from prior focal radiation, these patients need to be&#xD;
             discussed with the study chair(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM C: Tumor tissue confirmation of DMG is mandatory and pathology must be consistent&#xD;
             with a DMG including DMG H3K27M mutant and WHO grade III and IV H3 wildtype gliomas.&#xD;
             WHO grade II diffuse astrocytomas or other low grade gliomas without H3K27M mutation&#xD;
             are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM C: Participants must have recovered from all acute side effects of prior therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM C: From the projected start of scheduled study treatment, the following time&#xD;
             periods must have elapsed: 5 half-lives from any investigational agent, 4 weeks from&#xD;
             cytotoxic therapy (except 23 days for temozolomide and 6 weeks from nitrosoureas), 4&#xD;
             weeks from antibodies and must be at least 7 days since the completion of therapy with&#xD;
             a biologic or small molecule agent. For any biologic or small molecule agent with&#xD;
             known adverse events that can occur beyond 7 days after administration, the period&#xD;
             prior to enrollment must be beyond the time during which adverse events are known to&#xD;
             occur (these should be discussed with the study team)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM D: Children and young adults with recurrent primary malignant brain tumors (2 - 21&#xD;
             years of age) who have evidence of progression but have not been treated for this&#xD;
             progression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM D: Tumor tissue confirmation is mandatory and pathology must be consistent with&#xD;
             recurrent primary malignant brain tumor (diagnosis of recurrent ependymoma is allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM D: Participants must have recovered from all acute side effects of prior therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM D: From the projected start of scheduled study treatment, the following time&#xD;
             periods must have elapsed: 5 half-lives from any investigational agent, 4 weeks from&#xD;
             cytotoxic therapy (except 23 days for temozolomide and 6 weeks from nitrosoureas), 4&#xD;
             weeks from antibodies and must be at least 7 days since the completion of therapy with&#xD;
             a biologic or small molecule agent. For any biologic or small molecule agent with&#xD;
             known adverse events that can occur beyond 7 days after administration, the period&#xD;
             prior to enrollment must be beyond the time during which adverse events are known to&#xD;
             occur (these should be discussed with the study team)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ARM D: Participants who are receiving dexamethasone must be on a stable or decreasing&#xD;
             dose for at least 3 days prior to baseline magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TARGET VALIDATION: Newly diagnosed children and adults (2 years of age and above) with&#xD;
             imaging consistent with a DMG are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TARGET VALIDATION: Children and young adults with recurrent primary malignant brain&#xD;
             tumors, including recurrent DMG, (2 years of age and above) who have evidence of&#xD;
             progression but have not been treated for this progression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TARGET VALIDATION: Participants must undergo tumor tissue collection as part of their&#xD;
             standard of care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are receiving steroids must be on a stable or decreasing dose for at&#xD;
             least 3 days prior to baseline MRI scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripheral absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= neutrophil 1.0 g/l&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 100 x 10^9/L (transfusion independent, defined as not receiving&#xD;
             platelet transfusions for at least 7 days prior to enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &gt;= 90&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73 m^2 or a serum creatinine based on age/gender equal upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin (sum of conjugated + unconjugated) =&lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) for&#xD;
             age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase (SGPT) (alanine aminotransferase (ALT)) =&lt; 2 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with seizure disorder may be enrolled if seizure disorder is well controlled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effects of ONC206 on the developing human fetus is unknown. For this reason,&#xD;
             females of child-bearing potential and males must agree to use adequate contraception.&#xD;
             Adequate methods include: hormonal or barrier method of birth control; or abstinence&#xD;
             prior to study entry and for the duration of study participation. Should a woman&#xD;
             become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating&#xD;
             in this study, she should inform her treating physician immediately. Males treated or&#xD;
             enrolled on this protocol must also agree to use adequate contraception prior to the&#xD;
             study and for the duration of study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky &gt;= 50 for participants &gt; 16 years of age and Lansky &gt;= 50 for participants&#xD;
             =&lt; 16 years of age. Participants who are unable to walk because of paralysis, but who&#xD;
             are up in a wheelchair, will be considered ambulatory for the purpose of assessing the&#xD;
             performance score&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be willing to provide archival formalin-fixed embedded (FFPE) and frozen&#xD;
             tissue specimens for biomarker studies, if available&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A legal parent/guardian or participant must be able to understand, and willing to&#xD;
             sign, a written informed consent and assent document, as appropriate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are currently receiving another investigational drug are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are currently receiving other anti-cancer agents are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a known disorder that affects their immune system, such as human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or hepatitis B or C, or an auto-immune disorder requiring&#xD;
             systemic cytotoxic or immunosuppressive therapy are not eligible. Note: Participants&#xD;
             that are currently using inhaled, intranasal, ocular, topical or other non-oral or&#xD;
             non-intravenous (IV) steroids are not necessarily excluded from the study but need to&#xD;
             be discussed with the study chair&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with uncontrolled infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants of childbearing potential must not be pregnant or breast-feeding.&#xD;
             Female participants of childbearing potential must have a negative serum or urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test prior to the start of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active illicit drug use or diagnosis of alcoholism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to ONC206&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to follow the procedures of the study, e.g. due to language problems,&#xD;
             psychological disorders, dementia, etc. of the participant or family&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participants with illnesses that may affect absorption of ONC206&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participants on strong inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A4, 2D6, 1A2, 2C9 and 2C19 at&#xD;
             least 14 days prior and throughout the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sabine Mueller, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kelly Hitchner</last_name>
    <phone>(415) 502-1600</phone>
    <email>Kelly.Hitchner@ucsf.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Francisco</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kelly Hitchner</last_name>
      <phone>415-502-1600</phone>
      <email>Kelly.Hitchner@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <email>PNOC023@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sabine Mueller, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Francisco</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sabine Mueller, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>H3 K27M-Mutant</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain Tumors</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ependymoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dopamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data after de-identification.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

