<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04733404</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DragonFly-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04733404</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Effectiveness Study of Dragonfly System for Functional Mitral Regurgitation</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Multicenter, Objective Performance Criteria Study to Evaluate the Safety and Effectiveness of Dragonfly Transcatheter Mitral Valve Repair System for the Treatment of Functional Mitral Regurgitation (FMR) Subjects.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hangzhou Valgen Medtech Co., Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hangzhou Valgen Medtech Co., Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To confirm the effectiveness and safety of the Dragonfly transcatheter mitral valve repair&#xD;
      system for the treatment of chronic moderate to severe (3+) or severe (4+) functional mitral&#xD;
      regurgitation (FMR) who remained clinically symptomatic after guideline-directed medical&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective, multicenter, objective performance criteria design. Patients are&#xD;
      chronic moderate to severe (3+) or severe (4+) functional mitral regurgitation (FMR) who&#xD;
      remained clinically symptomatic after guideline-directed medical treatment. After signing an&#xD;
      informed consent form, subjects are enrolled and treated with the DragonFly Transcatheter&#xD;
      Mitral Valve Repair System. All subjects receive clinical follow-up immediately after&#xD;
      procedure, before discharge, 30 days after procedure, 6 months after procedure, and 12 months&#xD;
      after procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is defined as a composite measure include all-cause mortality and&#xD;
      recurrent heart failure hospitalization at 12 months after procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary outcomes include acute procedural success, acute device success, mitral&#xD;
      regurgitation degree (MR≤2+), recurrent heart failure hospitalization, NYHA class I or II at&#xD;
      30 days, 6 months, and 12 months, and the improvement in 6 minutes walk test distance, left&#xD;
      ventricular end-diastolic volume, quality of life change as assessed by the Kansas City&#xD;
      Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire (KCCQ) score from baseline at 12 months after procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The safety endpoints include major adverse events (MAEs) at 30 days and 12 months after&#xD;
      procedure, and all-cause mortality, cardiac mortality at 30 days, 6 months, and 12 months&#xD;
      after procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the safety and effectiveness of the Valgen Medtech DragonFly Transcatheter Mitral&#xD;
      Valve Repair System in the treatment of patients with chronic moderate to severe (3+) or&#xD;
      severe (4+) functional mitral regurgitation (FMR) who remained clinically symptomatic after&#xD;
      guideline-directed medical treatment, and to evaluate the product performance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with composite measures- All-cause death and recurrent HF hospitalizations.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>A composite of all-cause death or recurrent heart failure (HF) hospitalizations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mitral regurgitation severity</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6 months, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of patients with mitral regurgitation of 2+ or less.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrent heart failure (HF) hospitalizations</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6 months, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with incidence of re-hospitalizations for heart failure after Dragonfly implantation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>NYHA Class</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6 months, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with New York Heart Association (NYHA) Function Class I or II.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 6 minutes walk test distance</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in 6 Minute Walk Test distance at 12 months over baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement in quality of life (QoL) at 12 months over baseline, as measured by the Kansas City Cardiomyopathy Questionnaire (KCCQ).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Left Ventricular End Diastolic Volume (LVEDV)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Left Ventricular End Diastolic Volume (LVEDV) as determined by the core echocardiography laboratory from a transthoracic echocardiogram (TTE).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute procedural success</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after procedure, Discharge: The day after the patient's exit from the cardiac catheterization laboratory</time_frame>
    <description>Successful in Dragonfly implantation, and residual MR of 2+ or less at discharge. An echocardiography echocardiogram at 30 days can be accepted if the discharge image was not available or hard to interpret. A death before discharge or a re-operation of mitral valve prior to 30 days is defined as acute procedure failure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute device success</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after procedure</time_frame>
    <description>One or more Dragonfly devices are successfully delivered and released, edge-to-edge leaflet repair confirmed by echocardiogram, and successfully withdrawal of the delivery catheter.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of major adverse events (MAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>MAE is defined as a combined clinical endpoint of death, stroke, myocardial infarction, renal failure, and nonelective cardiovascular surgery for device or procedure-related adverse events occurring after transseptal catheterization.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6 months, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of all-cause death includes cardiac death, non-cardiac death, and death from unknown causes.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6 months, and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of cardiac death</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Mitral Regurgitation Functional</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dragonfly Mitral Valve Repair System</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The experimental group is allocated to use a novel mitral valve repair system for edge-to-edge repair manufactured by Hangzhou Valgen Medtech Co., Ltd.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dragonfly Transcatheter Mitral Valve Repair System</intervention_name>
    <description>To conduct edge-to-edge repair with Dragonfly System under the guidance of transesophageal echocardiography.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dragonfly Mitral Valve Repair System</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 yrs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Symptomatic functional mitral regurgitation (FMR) (≥3+) due to ischemic or&#xD;
             non-ischemic cardiomyopathy Note 1: Functional MR requires the presence of overall or&#xD;
             localized LV wall motion abnormalities that are considered to be the primary cause of&#xD;
             MR. Despite the eligibility, subjects may not enroll if leaflet prolapse or other&#xD;
             evidence of degenerative MR is present.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note 2: An Eligible transthoracic echocardiography must be obtained at least 30 days&#xD;
             after the subject has been stabilized on optimal therapy with Guideline Directed&#xD;
             Medical Therapy (GDMT), and after meeting two of the following conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. GDMT dose increase of no greater than 100% or decrease of no greater than 50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Coronary revascularization and/or implantation of a cardiac resynchronization&#xD;
                  therapy device (CRT or CRT-D) or reprogramming of the implanted CRT or CRT-D&#xD;
                  resulting in an increase in biventricular pacing (from &lt;92% to ≥92%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects have been adequately treated according to applicable criteria, including&#xD;
             treatment for coronary artery disease, left ventricular dysfunction, mitral&#xD;
             regurgitation, and heart failure (e.g., with cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT or&#xD;
             CRT-D), coronary revascularization, and/or have received stable GDMT, as defined in&#xD;
             (Appendix IV: Definition of GDMT), confirmed by the local heart team.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. NYHA functional class II to IVa.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥ 20% and ≤50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Left ventricular end-systolic dimension (LVESD) ≤ 70 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Anatomically suitable for transcatheter mitral valve repair by edge-to-edge technique&#xD;
             and can be treated by the DragonflyTM device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Elevated BNP &gt;150 pg/ml or corrected NT-proBNP ≥600 pg/ml or heart failure&#xD;
             hospitalization within the past 12 months ('corrected' refers to a 4% reduction in the&#xD;
             BNP or NT-proBNP cutoff for every increase of 1 kg/m2 in BMI above a reference BMI of&#xD;
             20 kg/m2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Transseptal catheterization and femoral vein access is determined to be feasible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The subject or subject's legal representative has been informed of the nature of the&#xD;
             trial, willing to accept the experimental tests, and has provided written informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Echocardiographic evidence of intracardiac mass, thrombus, or vegetation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The presence of other severe heart valve disease requiring surgical intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior mitral valve leaflet surgery or transcatheter mitral valve intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, restrictive cardiomyopathy, constrictive pericarditis,&#xD;
             infiltrative cardiomyopathy (e.g., amyloidosis, hemochromatosis, sarcoidosis, etc.),&#xD;
             or any other structural heart disease causing heart failure other than dilated&#xD;
             cardiomyopathy of either ischemic or non-ischemic etiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Moderate to severe right heart dysfunction or an estimated pulmonary artery systolic&#xD;
             pressure (PASP) &gt; 70 mmHg assessed by echocardiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of acute myocardial infarction in the prior 4 weeks or untreated clinically&#xD;
             significant coronary artery disease requiring revascularization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any percutaneous cardiac intervention within the 30 days, or any cardiac surgery&#xD;
             within the 6 months prior to randomization, or any implant of any Cardiac&#xD;
             Resynchronization Therapy (CRT) or Cardiac Resynchronization Therapy with&#xD;
             cardioverter-defibrillator (CRT-D) or Implantable Cardioverter Defibrillator (ICD)&#xD;
             within the last 30days prior to subject registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. In the judgment of the investigator, the subject's femoral vein is unable to&#xD;
             accommodate a 25F catheter or has an ipsilateral deep venous thrombosis; or the&#xD;
             anatomy is not accessible for transseptal puncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects in whom transesophageal echocardiography (TEE) or general anesthesia is&#xD;
             contraindicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. End-stage heart failure (ACC/AHA stage D), or prior orthotopic heart transplantation,&#xD;
             or on the waiting list for heart transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Active endocarditis, or active rheumatic heart disease, or leaflets degenerated from&#xD;
             either endocarditis or rheumatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Severe Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) (requiring continuous home oxygen&#xD;
             therapy or long-term application of steroid hormone medication).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Cerebrovascular accident within 30 days prior to randomization or symptomatic severe&#xD;
             carotid stenosis (&gt; 70% by ultrasound), or carotid artery stenting within 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Evidence of acute peptic ulcer or gastrointestinal hemorrhage in the prior 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Hemorrhagic or coagulopathic disorders, contraindications to antithrombotic&#xD;
             medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Modified Rankin Scale ≥4.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. The subjects suffer from diseases that may lead to difficulty in evaluating treatment&#xD;
             (e.g., cancer, severe metabolic disease, psychosis, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Pregnant or breastfeeding women, or women who plan to become pregnant within the next&#xD;
             12 months. Note: Women of childbearing age should take a pregnancy test with a&#xD;
             negative result within 14 days prior to registration and use scientifically safe&#xD;
             contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Hemodynamic instability defined as systolic pressure &lt; 90 mmHg without afterload&#xD;
             reduction, cardiogenic shock, or the need for inotropic support or an intra-aortic&#xD;
             balloon pump.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Active infections requiring antibiotic therapy (in the case of temporary illness,&#xD;
             antibiotics must be discontinued for at least 14 days before the subject can be&#xD;
             enrolled).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Currently participating in an investigational drug or another device study that has&#xD;
             not completed its primary endpoints or would clinically interfere with the endpoint of&#xD;
             this study. Note: Trials requiring extended follow-up for products that were&#xD;
             investigational, but have since become commercially available, are not considered&#xD;
             investigational trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. In the judgment of the investigator, subjects may not complete the trial according to&#xD;
             poor compliance or in other circumstances when the investigator determines that the&#xD;
             subject is unfit to participate in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jianan Wang, MD, PH.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jing Dai</last_name>
    <phone>+8617710418660</phone>
    <email>jing.dai@valgenmed.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shuangjie Li</last_name>
    <phone>+8617756106609</phone>
    <email>shuangjie.li@valgenmed.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Second Affiliated Hospital Zhejiang University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <state>Zhejiang</state>
        <zip>310000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mitral Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

