<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03556930</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU 042018-088</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03556930</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Simulated Radiotherapy Treatment Assisted With Pediatric Radiation Oncology With Movie Induced Sedation Effect Technique</brief_title>
  <official_title>Simulated Radiotherapy Treatment Assisted With Pediatric Radiation Oncology With Movie Induced Sedation Effect (PROMISE) Technique</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pediatric patient will watch age-proper movie during radiation treatment. The motion of&#xD;
      pedi-patient will continually be monitored by an AlignRT system (VisionRT LTD, UK).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For most pediatric cancer patients under 7 years of age, current standard radiotherapy&#xD;
      practice involves the use of anesthesia or sedation at each fraction to ensure that the&#xD;
      patient remains still during the treatment. A child may receive up to 30 episodes of&#xD;
      anesthesia in succession. This also means that, for the 6-week duration of radiotherapy, a&#xD;
      child may never fully return to his/her baseline activity. More importantly, the excessive&#xD;
      use of anesthesia introduces many risks and side effects that, combined with chemotherapy,&#xD;
      and cancer itself, can greatly reduce the overall treatment experience for the children and&#xD;
      their families&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the two years, the investigators have been actively developing technologies to facilitate&#xD;
      a novel pediatric radiotherapy, which called Pediatric Radiation Oncology with Movie Induced&#xD;
      Sedation Effect (PROMISE). The main idea of PROMISE is that pediatric patient will watch&#xD;
      age-proper movie during radiation treatment. The motion of pediatric patient will continually&#xD;
      be monitored by an AlignRT system (VisionRT LTD, UK). Both movie and radiation beam will be&#xD;
      paused if the motion of pediatric patient is beyond positioning accuracy threshold. Movie and&#xD;
      beam will be resumed if pediatric patient is positioning with in tolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the investigators will use the developed PROMISE software and hardware&#xD;
      platform to evaluate the feasibility of non-sedated radiotherapy treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator will use radio to mimic radiation beam delivery and gantry motion to mimic&#xD;
      radiation device rotation. Pediatric patient will watch an age-appropriate movie of his/her&#xD;
      choice. AlignRT (VisionRT LTD, UK) imaging system will be used to monitor the motion of the&#xD;
      patient. If the motion exceeds any pre-defined positioning thresholds the sound mimic&#xD;
      treatment beam noise will be held off and the movie will be paused.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the patient reverts to treatment position within a pre-defined temporal threshold (1&#xD;
      minute), the simulated treatment will be resumed with a continuing movie.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the patient cannot revert to the treatment position within a pre-defined time threshold/or&#xD;
      the movement is beyond any pre-defined re-alignment threshold value the radiation beam and&#xD;
      the movie will be turned off, the patient will be readjusted and the treatment will resume.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In any study case, the simulated PROMISE treatment will be ceased if therapists have to&#xD;
      re-position the patient more than three times.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The simulated PROMISE treatment will be repeated in three times in three different days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Project was never initiated.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 27, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Device Feasibility</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate the feasibility of applying PROMISE for pediatric radiotherapy by analyzing overall treatment time</measure>
    <time_frame>in three different days</time_frame>
    <description>Analyze overall treatment time including time for hardware and software setup</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine overall PROMISE radiotherapy treatment efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>in three different days</time_frame>
    <description>- Analyze PROMISE workflow based on record time:&#xD;
Times of beam/movie pauses. Times the child reverts back to the treatment position.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To quantify PROMISE radiotherapy treatment dose deviation</measure>
    <time_frame>in three different days</time_frame>
    <description>- Analyze the dose deviation from original treatment plan.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Childhood Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Movie Induced Sedation Effect</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pediatric Radiation Oncology with Movie Induced Sedation Effect monitored by an AlignRT system (VisionRT LTD, UK).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AlignRT system (VisionRT LTD, UK)</intervention_name>
    <description>Pediatric patient will watch age-proper movie during radiation treatment. The motion of pediatric patient will continually be monitored by an AlignRT system (VisionRT LTD, UK). Both movie and radiation beam will be paused if the motion of pediatric patient is beyond positioning accuracy threshold. Movie and beam will be resumed if pediatric patient is positioning with in tolerance.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Movie Induced Sedation Effect</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients Age: ≥4 and ≤10&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients and his/her legal guardian must be willing and capable to provide informed consent&#xD;
        to participate in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must be compliant to all required pretreatment evaluations:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Informed Consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Medical Diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Demographics&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Review subject eligibility criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Physical exam including vital signs, height and weight Vital signs (temperature,&#xD;
             pulse, respirations, blood pressure) will be collected before simulation treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Simulated PROMISE treatment screening Patient will be asked for lying on treatment&#xD;
             couch for 30 seconds with PROMISE movie on. If patient stay still for 30 seconds, s/he&#xD;
             is eligible for the simulated PROMISE treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients aren't compliant to all required pretreatment evaluations&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Steve Jiang, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 1, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 14, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Non-sedated radiotherapy treatment</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

