<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01094951</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P30MH085943-03</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>P30MH085943-03</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30MH085943</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01094951</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Engaging Depressed Low-Income Seniors in Mental Health Services</brief_title>
  <acronym>ENGAGE</acronym>
  <official_title>Engaging Depressed Low-Income Seniors in Mental Health Services</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This two-stage research study will&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. train caseworkers in three participating New York City Neighborhood Houses to screen&#xD;
           their clients for depression, and&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. examine the usefulness of training these caseworkers in an intervention that targets&#xD;
           barriers seniors face in receiving mental health services. In this intervention, called&#xD;
           ENGAGE, Case Workers will: 1. identify and address seniors' barriers to receiving mental&#xD;
           health services; 2. include the seniors' preferences in deciding which treatment options&#xD;
           to choose; and 3. help seniors connect with affordable mental health services of their&#xD;
           choice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this research study, study investigators are partnering with United Neighborhood Houses of&#xD;
      New York, the umbrella membership organization of the 34 New York City Neighborhood Houses.&#xD;
      Due to the limited scope of this feasibility study, we have selected three Houses to serve as&#xD;
      recruitment sites. These three house approximate the gender and racial characteristics of the&#xD;
      larger group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Stage 1, investigators will work with the three Houses in implementing systematic&#xD;
      research assessments to identify level of psychopathology, referral patterns, and connections&#xD;
      to mental health evaluation among their depressed senior clients. Investigators will train&#xD;
      caseworkers to screen their clients for depression and will also instruct caseworkers to&#xD;
      refer any senior scoring endorsing depressive symptoms to their partnering community-based&#xD;
      mental health or medical clinic. Data on successful connections to mental health evaluation&#xD;
      will serve as the comparison to that achieved by Stage 2, the ENGAGE intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Stage 2 study investigators will train all caseworkers from each Neighborhood House to&#xD;
      use the ENGAGE intervention. For eligible depressed seniors, the caseworker will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. provide psychoeducation that addresses client-specific barriers to evaluation and care&#xD;
           (e.g., stigma, transportation);&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. use shared decision-making strategies to engage seniors and arrive at a decision about&#xD;
           where and from whom to receive an evaluation and possible care; and&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. provide connections to preferred mental health services. Mental health service options&#xD;
           will include referral to the senior's primary care physician or local community mental&#xD;
           health clinic for further evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In two subsequent sessions 2 and 4 weeks later, the caseworker will assess success in&#xD;
      receiving a mental health evaluation, and in initiating treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the senior has not yet pursued an evaluation, the caseworker will continue to address&#xD;
           his/her individual barriers and will re-engage in shared decision-making if necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the senior did receive an evaluation that confirms a depressive diagnosis, but&#xD;
           remains undecided about treatment, the case worker will empower and help the senior to&#xD;
           select an appropriate treatment of his/her choice and will encourage ongoing engagement&#xD;
           in this treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If an evaluation revealed the absence of a depressive disorder and no treatment&#xD;
           recommendations, the caseworker will re-assess to ensure that depression did not emerge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of ENGAGE intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Baseline, 4, 8, and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Examine the feasibility of training case workers in 3 Neighborhood Houses in ENGAGE - an intervention that identifies and addresses attitudinal and concrete barriers to pursuing evaluation and care; incorporates shared decision making in service and treatment options; and facilitates connection to affordable mental health services.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Increase in referrals for mental health evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Baseline, 4, 8, and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Conduct a preliminary study to evaluate whether ENGAGE can increase the number of seniors (with symptoms of depression on a screen) who follow through with a referral for mental health evaluation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ENGAGE</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>In stage 1, study investigators will train Neighborhood House caseworkers to screen their clients for depressive symptoms.&#xD;
In stage 2, study investigators will train Neighborhood House caseworkers to use the ENGAGE intervention in referring their clients to mental health services</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ENGAGE</intervention_name>
    <description>During Stage 2, investigators will train Neighborhood House caseworkers to 1. provide psychoeducation that addresses client-specific barriers to evaluation and care; 2. use shared decision-making strategies to engage seniors and arrive at a decision about where and from whom to receive an evaluation and possible care; and 3. provide connections to preferred community-based mental health services.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ENGAGE</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 60 years and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive screen for major depression (PHQ-9 greater than 10): We chose standard PHQ-9&#xD;
             screening to correspond to routine procedures within each House that identify seniors&#xD;
             in need of evaluation for treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capacity to provide written consent for both research assessment and treatment. This&#xD;
             criterion is necessary because subjects must be able to participate meaningfully in&#xD;
             the interventions offered by the study and the assessment procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Working knowledge of English. Fluency in English sufficient for comprehending&#xD;
             questionnaires of the study and/or for understanding the case worker. English does not&#xD;
             have to be the subject's first language.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  MMSE score &lt; 24 or clinical diagnosis of dementia. Dementia, or cognitive impairment&#xD;
             at this level may limit the senior's ability to participate in the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychotic or manic symptoms or alcohol or substance dependence. These symptoms and&#xD;
             disorders will be determined by the SCID assessment and require alternative&#xD;
             interventions than those offered by the study. We focus in this project on seniors&#xD;
             with depressive symptoms given existing Neighborhood House procedures for standard&#xD;
             depression screening, and given difficulties in training case worker staff on&#xD;
             screening for other psychiatric disorders. If this project is successful, we may then&#xD;
             expand our efforts to target other disorders such as psychotic, manic, and alcohol and&#xD;
             substance abuse and dependence disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antidepressant medication or psychotherapy in the 4 weeks prior to baseline&#xD;
             evaluation. The intervention is focused on linking depressed seniors who are in need&#xD;
             of mental health services rather than those currently receiving treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute or severe medical illness: i.e., delirium, metastatic cancer, decompensated&#xD;
             cardiac, liver or kidney failure, major surgery, stroke or myocardial infarction&#xD;
             during the three months prior to entry; or drugs often causing depression, e.g.,&#xD;
             steroids, reserpine, alpha-methyl-dopa, tamoxifen, vincristine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antisocial personality by DSM-IV: This disorder will possibly interfere with adherence&#xD;
             to research procedures and treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Patrick J. Raue, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>George S. Alexopoulos, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 26, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 29, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 6, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 6, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

