<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01129076</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999910104</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-HG-N104</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01129076</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Perceptions of Thalassemia Major in Singapore: An Exploratory Study of Stigma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Perceptions of Thalassemia Major in Singapore: An Exploratory Study of Stigma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Thalassemia major (TM) is a chronic disorder that affects a person s ability to produce&#xD;
           hemoglobin, resulting in anemia. Hemoglobin is a component of red blood cells that&#xD;
           carries oxygen and nutrients to cells in the body. As a result, individuals require&#xD;
           life-long blood transfusions and extensive medical management. Studies have shown that&#xD;
           because of its demanding nature, TM might negatively affect an individual s quality of&#xD;
           life, sense of self, and social integration, but little is known about affected&#xD;
           individuals overall experiences with and perceptions of TM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  TM is caused by a genetic change in the thalassemia gene. The disease is passed to&#xD;
           children by parents who carry one copy of the altered thalassemia gene. The parents are&#xD;
           called carriers of the condition and have a 25 percent chance of having a child with TM.&#xD;
           It is possible to screen for carriers of TM and use this information for pregnancy&#xD;
           planning and management.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  TM is common among people from South and South East Asia and is an important public&#xD;
           health concern in Singapore. More research is needed to explore the lives of people with&#xD;
           TM, and the societal perceptions that exist in Singapore about TM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To describe the familial, social, and professional experiences of individuals with TM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To investigate the social messages being given out about TM in Singapore and the sources&#xD;
           of those messages.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore the impact of these experiences, perceptions, and social messages on&#xD;
           individuals who have TM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To explore how the experiences and perceptions of individuals who have TM affect their&#xD;
           life, sense of self, social integration, and compliance with medical treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Residents of Singapore who are 14 years of age or older, can speak English, and&#xD;
           currently have TM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parents of individuals with TM who are 14 years of age or older. Parents must be 21&#xD;
           years of age or older, be able to speak English, and have had caregiving&#xD;
           responsibilities for their child at some point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All participants will have a one-time semi-structured interview, followed by a&#xD;
           questionnaire to obtain demographic information.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Interviews will be conducted in Singapore and are expected to last for 30 to 90 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals with TM will be asked about their own perceptions of TM; familial, social,&#xD;
           and professional experiences involving TM; and their perceptions of others views and of&#xD;
           social messages related to TM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parents of individuals with TM will be asked about their experiences in caring for a&#xD;
           child with TM, talking to their child about TM, telling people about their child s TM,&#xD;
           and interacting with health care providers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Thalassemia major (TM) is a chronic, inherited hematological disorder that can require&#xD;
      life-long medical care. As a result of the chronic and demanding nature of the condition,&#xD;
      studies have shown that TM might negatively affect an individual s quality of life, sense of&#xD;
      self, social integration, and compliance with medical treatment. Yet, little is known about&#xD;
      affected individuals overall experiences with and perceptions of TM. In this study, the&#xD;
      concept of stigma will be used to explore and understand these experiences and perceptions in&#xD;
      the population of individuals with TM in Singapore. This study will involve qualitative&#xD;
      interviews with TM patients and parents of TM patients. Interviews will focus on individuals&#xD;
      family, social and professional experiences with TM; the social messages that exist in&#xD;
      Singapore about TM and their sources; individuals perceptions of how others view TM;&#xD;
      individuals own perceptions of TM; and the impact of these various experiences, messages and&#xD;
      perceptions on the individual with TM. Interviews will be conducted with approximately 20-30&#xD;
      individuals with TM, and 10-20 parents of individuals with TM. Interviews will be transcribed&#xD;
      and subjected to thematic analysis to identify common themes. The results of this study will&#xD;
      further our understanding of the psychosocial burden of TM and the potential role of stigma&#xD;
      in this population, which may ultimately inform the care for individuals with TM. The study s&#xD;
      setting will also provide insights into the impact of the Singaporean sociocultural context&#xD;
      on the psychosocial elements of living with a genetic condition, which might eventually help&#xD;
      to inform the development of appropriate psychosocial support services and genetic counseling&#xD;
      services in the region.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 23, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date>January 7, 2016</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Thalassemia Major</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who currently have TM and receive at least 8 blood transfusions in a year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents of Singapore&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents of individuals with TM will be eligible for participation if they are age 21&#xD;
             years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents must be residents of Singapore&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents must speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For a parent to participate in the study, it will not be required that his or her&#xD;
             child also participate in the study or vice versa.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children under age 14 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaking individuals&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Barbara B Biesecker</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Singapore General Hospital Outram Rd.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>169608</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>KK Women's &amp;amp; Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ismail A, Campbell MJ, Ibrahim HM, Jones GL. Health Related Quality of Life in Malaysian children with thalassaemia. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2006 Jul 2;4:39.</citation>
    <PMID>16813662</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hoedemaekers R, ten Have H. Geneticization: the Cyprus paradigm. J Med Philos. 1998 Jun;23(3):274-87.</citation>
    <PMID>9736189</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Major B, O'Brien LT. The social psychology of stigma. Annu Rev Psychol. 2005;56:393-421. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15709941</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 7, 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 21, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 21, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 24, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 14, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 14, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 17, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Thalassemia Major</keyword>
  <keyword>Stigma</keyword>
  <keyword>Singapore</keyword>
  <keyword>Qualitative</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thalassemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>beta-Thalassemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

