<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00280982</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MEC-2005-269</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>PMR-MM05-001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00280982</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dendritic Cell-based Immunotherapy in Mesothelioma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Vaccination With Autologous Dendritic Cells Pulsed With Tumor Lysate for Treatment of Patients With Malignant Pleural Mesothelioma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Erasmus Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Erasmus Medical Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Exploiting the immunostimulatory capacities of dendritic cells holds great promise for cancer&#xD;
      immunotherapy. A mouse model for malignant mesothelioma allowed us to prove that autologous&#xD;
      dendritic cells presenting tumor antigens were very effective by (partly) inhibiting tumor&#xD;
      growth. This study will test the feasibility and safety of a clinical trial using autologous&#xD;
      DC as a therapeutic adjuvant for the treatment of malignant pleural mesothelioma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For this phase I study, patients with end-stage malignant mesothelioma and who are deemed to&#xD;
      be fit enough to be treated with chemotherapy will be asked to participate in this study.&#xD;
      Patients will first be treated with 4 courses of chemotherapy (standard&#xD;
      treatment[Alimta/cisplatin]). After this chemotherapy a leukapherese is performed of which&#xD;
      the monocytes are used for differentiation to dendritic cells. The procedure to grow these&#xD;
      dendritic cells in vitro (culture) and pulse them with tumor lysate is performed in a&#xD;
      cleanroom environment. Several quality control tests will be performed before the dendritic&#xD;
      cells are ready for re-injection. Three doses of properly pulsed autologous dendritic cells&#xD;
      are then re-injected every two weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using the proper procedure in mesothelioma patients, minor side effects are expected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ten (10) patients will be treated by this procedure to define the safety and toxicity of&#xD;
      immunization and to observe (anti-tumor) immune responses.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>safety</measure>
    <time_frame>april 2008</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>april 2008</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Pleural Mesothelioma</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>tumor lysate-loaded autologous dendritic cells</intervention_name>
    <description>50x10e6 cells per vaccination, 3 times, 2 weeks interval</description>
    <other_name>DC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinically and histological or cytological confirmed newly diagnosed&#xD;
             mesothelioma, that can be measured in two dimensions by a radiologic imaging study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be at least 18 years old and must be able to give written informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be ambulatory (Karnofsky scale &gt; 70, or WHO-ECOG performance status 0,1,&#xD;
             or 2) and in stable medical condition. The expected survival must be at least 4&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have normal organ function and adequate bone marrow reserve: absolute&#xD;
             neutrophil count &gt; 1.5*109/l, platelet count &gt; 100*109/l, and Hb &gt; 6.0 mmol/l.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive delayed type hypersensitivity skin test (induration &gt; 2mm after 48hrs)&#xD;
             against at least one positive control antigen of MULTITEST CMI (Pasteur merieux).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable disease or response after chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of sufficient tumor material of the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to return to the Erasmus MC for adequate follow-up as required by this&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conditions that make the patient unfit for chemotherapy or progressive disease after 4&#xD;
             cycles of chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pleurodesis at the affected side before the pleural fluid is obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical or psychological impediment to probable compliance with the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on steroid (or other immunosuppressive agents) are excluded on the basis of&#xD;
             potential immune suppression. Patients must have had 6 weeks of discontinuation and&#xD;
             must stop of any such treatment during the time of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior malignancy is allowed except for adequately treated basal cell or squamous&#xD;
             cell skin cancer, superficial or in-situ cancer of the bladder or other cancer for&#xD;
             which the patient has been disease-free for five years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious concomitant disease, no active infections. Patients with a history of&#xD;
             autoimmune disease or organ allografts, or with active acute or chronic infection,&#xD;
             including HIV and viral hepatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with serious intercurrent chronic or acute illness such as pulmonary (asthma&#xD;
             or COPD) or cardiac (NYHA class III or IV) or hepatic disease or other illness&#xD;
             considered by the study coordinators to constitute an unwarranted high risk for&#xD;
             investigational DC treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a known allergy to shell fish (contains KLH).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with inadequate peripheral vein access to perform leukapheresis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant participation in another clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An organic brain syndrome or other significant psychiatric abnormality which would&#xD;
             comprise the ability to give informed consent, and preclude participation in the full&#xD;
             protocol and follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of assurance of compliance with the protocol. Lack of availability for&#xD;
             follow-up assessment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joachim G Aerts, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Erasmus Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Pulmonary Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <state>Zuid-Holland</state>
        <zip>3015 GE</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hegmans JP, Hemmes A, Aerts JG, Hoogsteden HC, Lambrecht BN. Immunotherapy of murine malignant mesothelioma using tumor lysate-pulsed dendritic cells. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2005 May 15;171(10):1168-77. Epub 2005 Mar 11.</citation>
    <PMID>15764728</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 20, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 20, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 24, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 16, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Erasmus MC</name_title>
    <organization>Pulmonary Medicine</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>dendritic cells, immunotherapy, vaccination, mesothelioma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mesothelioma, Malignant</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

