<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00283348</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Cell 500</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00283348</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>New Strategies for Non-invasive Detection of Chronic Allograft Nephropathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>New Strategies for Non-invasive Detection of Chronic Allograft Nephropathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Virginia Commonwealth University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hoffmann-La Roche</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Virginia Commonwealth University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to help researchers find out more about a condition called&#xD;
      &quot;Chronic Allograft Nephropathy&quot; (CAN). CAN is a complication that sometimes occurs after&#xD;
      kidney transplantation and affects the function of the transplanted kidney. It is hoped that&#xD;
      by studying blood, urine, and tissue samples of kidney transplant patients, new ways of&#xD;
      diagnosing and treating CAN may be found.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We hypothesize that patients with CAN will manifest different patterns of gene expression&#xD;
      profiling (compared with non-CAN controls), detectable in peripheral blood mononuclear cells&#xD;
      (PBMCs) and urine cells. By studying differences that exist in peripheral blood or in the&#xD;
      graft and its local environment (urine samples), informative biomarkers may be discovered to&#xD;
      improve treatment programs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 1: To investigate the genes involved in the molecular mechanism that characterize CAN in&#xD;
      kidney transplant recipients, we will study gene expression in kidney biopsy samples from&#xD;
      patients with CAN. For comparison analysis, we will study gene expression profiling in normal&#xD;
      kidney biopsies (Control Group 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 2: To determine whether there is a role for assessing peripheral blood mononuclear cell&#xD;
      (PBMC) and urine cell gene expression patterns as a means of measuring the immunologic and&#xD;
      clinical status of kidney transplant recipients, we will compare gene expression profiles&#xD;
      among PBMC, urine and biopsy samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 3: To establish the clinical utility of the set of markers resulting from AIMS 1 and 2 in&#xD;
      the diagnostic of CAN, we will use &quot;real time&quot;(RT)-PCR in PBMC and urine samples employing a&#xD;
      limited panel of markers in an independent group of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 4: To study the role of the pre-established panel of molecular markers in the early&#xD;
      detection of CAN in patients receiving mycophenolate mofetil (MMF) as immunosuppressive&#xD;
      treatment, we will study urine and PBMC samples from patients more than 12 months&#xD;
      post-transplantation, with normal creatinine, and proteinuria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background and Significance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic allograft nephropathy (CAN) is a devastating complication of kidney transplantation&#xD;
      that is responsible for a significant proportion of graft loss (1-5). Although currently&#xD;
      available immunosuppressive therapy is increasingly effective against acute rejection of a&#xD;
      transplanted organ, chronic rejection (CR) remains difficult to treat. Nevertheless, a&#xD;
      relevant proportion of patients with CR of a kidney transplant maintain satisfactory organ&#xD;
      function for a long time. CAN is characterized by a progressive decline in kidney function,&#xD;
      which is not attributable to a specific cause (6-8). CAN is a poorly known complex process&#xD;
      resulting from as yet undefined etiology with both immune and non-immune components (8).&#xD;
      Alloantigen-dependent causes of CAN include acute rejection episodes, particularly multiple,&#xD;
      late, or vascular acute rejection episodes (9-13). With the use of a new immunosuppressive&#xD;
      regimen, the frequency of acute rejection episodes has become reduced, which may possibly&#xD;
      have an influence on future development of CAN. However, donor antigen-independent factors&#xD;
      also play a role in the occurrence and progression of CAN. This includes donor-related&#xD;
      factors such as donor age and number of mismatch, which have an impact on late graft outcome&#xD;
      (13). Donation-related circumstances, such as prolonged cold ischemia time, are associated&#xD;
      with delayed graft function and related to poor late renal transplant results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recipient related factors may also act as co-factors contributing to an accelerated&#xD;
      deterioration of the functional units in the kidney, including vascular, of renal arteries&#xD;
      and a subsequent relative hypoxia of the kidney, frequently leading to interstitial fibrosis.&#xD;
      Interestingly, many of the pathways involved in chronic injury and fibrosis are regulated&#xD;
      very early in the course of the injury, when the downstream effects of these alterations are&#xD;
      still not evident by pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The histopathologic features of CAN can be characterized by proliferative changes of the&#xD;
      vascular wall, in which smooth muscle cells and parenchymal cells proliferate, leading to a&#xD;
      narrowing of renal arteries, which may contribute to a relative hypoxia of the tissue.&#xD;
      Subsequently, fibroblasts will contribute to fibrotic scarring in the vascular wall. CAN is&#xD;
      also characterized by the occurrence of fibrosis in the interstitial tissue along with&#xD;
      tubular atrophy (14). The glomeruli are also often affected by various degrees of&#xD;
      glomerulosclerosis. An inflammatory infiltrate is frequently found and consists of invading&#xD;
      lymphocytes and monocytes-macrophages into virtually all affected compartments of the kidney.&#xD;
      The inflammatory infiltrate observed in CAN can be induced by both antigen-dependent and&#xD;
      antigen-independent factors. These histopathologic changes can be graded according to the&#xD;
      Banff system (14), which gives a score of the degree of CAN. These histopathologic changes&#xD;
      act in concert, contributing to a gradual progression of renal allograft dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fundamental studies in solid organ transplantation have characterized specific functional&#xD;
      roles for individual genes in the immunological cascade leading to organ rejection.&#xD;
      Nevertheless, significant redundancy in the immune system is suggested by clinical&#xD;
      variability in acute rejection outcomes, in the progression of chronic rejection, and by the&#xD;
      potential to acquire graft tolerance. Underlying all of these complex systems are concordant&#xD;
      expression and co-regulation of multiple genes in known and novel molecular pathways.&#xD;
      Ascertaining their individual functions in adapting the effector response is now possible&#xD;
      with gene expression profiling using microarrays. Although cDNA microarrays (large numbers of&#xD;
      genes represented by complementary DNAs or oligonucleotides immobilized onto microscope&#xD;
      slides or silicon chips) were successfully used to profile gene expression in cancer&#xD;
      (15,16,17,18,19), their impact in transplantation research has so far been relatively modest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      I suggest that the highlighted section be deleted, or at least placed in parentheses. It&#xD;
      makes the sentence very difficult to understand, though I know it is meant to clarify.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is accumulating evidence that non-invasive immune monitoring may be useful in the early&#xD;
      period after renal transplant (20,21), particularly with regard to predicting the presence of&#xD;
      acute rejection. It is less clear whether chronic allograft nephropathy (CAN) is also&#xD;
      associated with consistent changes in peripheral blood or urine cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover, current methods of diagnosing allograft dysfunction are inadequate for detecting&#xD;
      the significant organ damage that occurs prior to the establishment of clinical&#xD;
      manifestations. The development of assays or novel technologies that will allow detection of&#xD;
      allograft dysfunction/rejection, monitor responses to therapy, and predict long-term outcomes&#xD;
      is vital for the success of transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this project we propose to establish the molecular markers that characterize CAN using&#xD;
      gene expression profiling in kidney biopsies of patients with CAN and to relate these&#xD;
      findings with the profiles in PBMC and urine samples from the same patients. In addition, we&#xD;
      will establish and validate (in a independent group of patients) the clinical utility of a&#xD;
      limited set of molecular markers, resulting of the microarray analysis, using RT-PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      V. Statistical Analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Security Plan Kidney tissue, PBMC and urine from kidney transplant patients with or&#xD;
      without CAN will be studied. A Secure Data Base containing all the demographic information&#xD;
      for the patients will be kept at the Virginia Commonwealth University, but patient&#xD;
      identifiers will be removed and a study number assigned to each patient. The tissues required&#xD;
      will include kidney biopsies only from patients with CAN.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Human Subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. Description and Research Materials Kidney tissues will be obtained with informed consent&#xD;
      from patients with clinical suspicion of CAN (at least 15 patients). Tissue samples (needle&#xD;
      biopsies) will be snap-frozen in liquid nitrogen within 5 minutes after excision and shipped&#xD;
      under appropriate conditions, on dry ice, to maintain specimen integrity. All samples will be&#xD;
      submitted for pathological evaluation, and a pathology report and clinical summary will be&#xD;
      sent with the samples in all cases in a manner insuring patient confidentiality by removing&#xD;
      patient identifiers and labeling with the assigned patient number.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peripheral blood and urine samples (1-2 tbs) will be obtained from patients at the biopsy&#xD;
      time. Kidney biopsies will be obtained with informed consent from normal kidneys at&#xD;
      transplantation (needle biopsy from donor kidney, N=10).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peripheral blood and urine samples will be collected monthly during 1 year with informed&#xD;
      consent from kidney transplant patients with diagnostic of CAN confirmed by biopsy. As&#xD;
      Control Group, stable long-term transplant patients (more than 12 months post-TX) with&#xD;
      creatinine levels &lt;1.6 mg/dL, and proteinuria less than 500mg/24hs, will be studied. (You may&#xD;
      want to give an estimated number of patients to be included in the Control Group) All&#xD;
      practices dealing with human subjects will be performed according to the ethical guidelines&#xD;
      of the Institutional Review Board for the Protection of Human Subjects of the Virginia&#xD;
      Commonwealth University.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment Plan Patients seen at VCU Hume-Lee Transplant Clinic who qualify according to the&#xD;
      inclusion/exclusion criteria will be asked to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. Potential Risks When blood is drawn there is a risk of bruising, bleeding, swelling or&#xD;
      infection at the site where the blood is drawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Kidney biopsies can be painful where the needle enters the body, and a bruise can form.&#xD;
      Bleeding can occur where the needle is inserted in to the kidney. Blood can appear in the&#xD;
      urine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every effort will be made to maintain confidentiality. All identifying information will be&#xD;
      kept in a secure data bank with access limited to research personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      C. Risk Reduction The tissue being obtained upon tissue biopsy is part of the sample that&#xD;
      would be obtained for diagnostic purposes and not specifically for this protocol. The blood&#xD;
      samples will be obtained at the same time as venous access is already in place. A urine&#xD;
      sample will be collected prior to the biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All staff members handling tissue, PBMC and urine samples have been trained and are qualified&#xD;
      to safely handle HCV infected tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      D. Risk/Benefit Because this is not a treatment study, there are no specific risks to the&#xD;
      study subjects. CAN will be diagnosed and treated in the same way, whether or not they&#xD;
      participate in the study. There is no guarantee that patients will benefit from participation&#xD;
      in this study. The knowledge gained may be invaluable in the future particularly for&#xD;
      diagnosing of CAN.&#xD;
&#xD;
      D. Compensation Plan Subjects will not be compensated for their participation in this study.&#xD;
      E. Consent Issues Patients who meet study requirements will be consented.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">121</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Rejection</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood, Urine&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients Diagnosis of Chronic Allograft Nephropathy at VCUHS Clinic&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received primary kidney transplant Diagnosis of Chronic Allograft Nephropathy Stable&#xD;
             immunosuppression for one month prior to entry&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious comorbidity Pregnancy Retransplantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel G Maluf, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Virginia Commonwealth University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Valeria Mas, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Virginia Commonwealth University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VCU Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Richmond</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23298</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 25, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 25, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 27, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 16, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 16, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 20, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Renal Transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunosuppression</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Rejection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

