<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00288977</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2001P001702</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00288977</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Islet Transplantation in Type 1 Diabetic Recipients of Kidney Transplants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Islet Transplantation in Type 1 Diabetic Recipients of Renal Allografts, Using the Edmonton Protocol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Joslin Diabetes Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study hypothesis is that we can reproduce results of islet transplantation in type one&#xD;
      diabetics in patients with a kidney transplant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This trial is designed to replicate the protocol currently being tested by the Immune&#xD;
      Tolerance Network (ITN) in a population of patients that have been previously transplanted&#xD;
      (recipients of functioning renal allografts) and are therefore immunosuppressed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data will be generated using substantially identical techniques for islet preparation, re&#xD;
      transplantation with additional islets to meet the minimum islet cell mass, and an identical&#xD;
      steroid-free post-transplant regimen utilizing sirolimus, low dose tacrolimus, and&#xD;
      daclizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.1. Primary and secondary endpoints and additional measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study efficacy endpoints and additional measures are described in the following subsections.&#xD;
      Measures relating to the islet preparation quality (Section 3.1.3) and other variables&#xD;
      relating to key cellular and genetic markers (Section 3.1.4) followed during the study are&#xD;
      not considered clinical outcome variables. Details describing requirements for efficacy&#xD;
      testing are found in Section 6.1. Safety measures are described in Section 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.1.1. Primary endpoint&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint for this study is independence from insulin injections with adequate&#xD;
      control of blood glucose in subjects with Type 1 diabetes at one year post final transplant.&#xD;
      Subjects will be considered as a success when at the one year assessment they are not using&#xD;
      insulin, they have a HbA1c &lt;6.5% and they achieve fasting glucose levels not exceeding 7.8&#xD;
      mmol/L (140 mg/dL) more than three times in a week (using the morning fasting glucose level),&#xD;
      and not exceeding two hour post-prandial (using any post meal glucose level) values of 10&#xD;
      mmol/L (180 mg/dL) more than four times in a week. A subject will still be considered a&#xD;
      success if an intercurrent illness or other event (e.g., high tacrolimus level) causes a&#xD;
      participant to require insulin use for a period not exceeding a total of 14 days, and&#xD;
      assessment after this event demonstrates insulin independence and adequate glucose control as&#xD;
      defined above. This assessment must be completed no later than two weeks after the scheduled&#xD;
      one year assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.1.2. Secondary parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary parameters that support the primary goal of the investigation will be assessed at&#xD;
      generally the same intervals as the primary endpoint, with some taken more or less frequently&#xD;
      as indicated in detail in Sections 5.2 and 6.1. Additional clinical measurements are also&#xD;
      taken during the study that are not considered endpoints for formal analyses, but are to be&#xD;
      carefully followed as a part of the study. The schedule for these additional elements is&#xD;
      listed in Sections 5.2, 6.2 and 7.2. The secondary variables include the following measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Basal C-peptide levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. HbA1C levels&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Glucose tolerance&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. C-peptide response to arginine&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. MAGE improvement&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Mixed Meal Test&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Durability of insulin independence and adequate blood glucose control&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.1.3. Islet quality endpoints&#xD;
&#xD;
      Islet cell preparations for each transplant will be assessed using the following elements:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Islet yield per isolation used for clinical transplantation, expressed as i) total islet&#xD;
           equivalents and ii) islet equivalents per kg recipient body weight.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Islet viability, as assessed by a fluorescent dye inclusion/exclusion assay to assess&#xD;
           metabolic activity and membrane integrity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. In vitro islet responsiveness to glucose challenge, as measured by 2-hour static&#xD;
           incubation following 12-24 hour culture at 37º C in CMRL 1066 (10% FCS, 25 mmol HEPES).&#xD;
           A stimulation index, a ratio of insulin secretion during high glucose over insulin&#xD;
           secretion during low basal secretion is calculated as an index of islet function.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Islet cell immunohistochemical composition and purity assessment, (as determined by JDRF&#xD;
           Center for Islet Transplantation at Harvard Medical School - Islet Morphology Core&#xD;
           Laboratory)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Evidence of no microbial contamination, as documented by a negative Gram stain of the&#xD;
           islet preparation immediately pre-transplant, and by negative microbial cultures&#xD;
           reported after at least 5 days incubation for aerobes, anaerobes, fungi.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Evidence of a low endotoxin content of the final islet preparation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.1.4. Cellular and genetic markers&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples will be collected before and after transplant for immunologic studies to be processed&#xD;
      in the laboratories of Dr. Terry Strom at the Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center and Dr.&#xD;
      Mohamed Sayegh at the Brigham and Women's Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Alteration in autoimmune markers for GAD65, ICA512, and mIAA, comparing blood samples&#xD;
           drawn pre-transplant and 3, 6, 9, 12, 24 and 36 months after final transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Changes in autoantibody and other immune markers comparing blood samples drawn&#xD;
           pre-transplant and 3, 6, 12, 24, and 36 months after final transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Samples will also be taken for future laboratory and genetic studies comparing blood&#xD;
           samples drawn pre-transplant and usually 3, 6, and 12 months after final transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2. Description of trial design and schematic diagram of procedures and stages&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because this is an open-label, single-arm study, a schematic diagram of the design is omitted&#xD;
      for simplicity. For a general description of the trial design, please refer to Section 2. A&#xD;
      tabular listing of visit schedules and tests is found in Appendix 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.3. Measures to minimize bias&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is an open-label feasibility study with definitive clinical endpoints of insulin&#xD;
      independence, blood glucose and C peptide production as measures of procedural success. As&#xD;
      donor islets become available the appropriate ABO compatible blood types will be matched to&#xD;
      eligible participants. Clinical investigators are not masked to treatment assignment or&#xD;
      follow up assessment information for this pilot study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4. Description of trial treatments and dosage regimen &amp; labeling&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each islet cell transplantation procedure under this protocol is derived from an individual&#xD;
      donor pancreas, processed for immediate transplantation. All containers and components are&#xD;
      appropriately labeled during preparation. Each final islet preparation released for use is&#xD;
      labeled to indicate its identity and date of preparation. Records regarding donor identity&#xD;
      will be kept in a coded manner for quality control purposes and will be kept absolutely&#xD;
      confidential in accordance with standard procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4.1. Islet Infusion(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A target total of &gt; 10,000 IE/kg recipient body weight will be infused via a percutaneous&#xD;
      transhepatic catheter inserted into the portal vein (see Section 1.4.2). This will in all&#xD;
      likelihood require more than one islet infusion to achieve this goal. The first infusion must&#xD;
      contain at least 5,000 IE/kg recipient body weight. In the event that a subject does not&#xD;
      achieve insulin-independence with normoglycemia after two fresh islet infusions, a third&#xD;
      transplant may be considered as described in Section 5.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4.2. Immunosuppressive Therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
      Beginning with the initial transplant, a immunosuppressive regimen will be administered to&#xD;
      all subjects. Subjects will receive initial doses of daclizumab, sirolimus, and low dose&#xD;
      tacrolimus according to the following schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4.2.1. Daclizumab regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
      Daclizumab will be administered at a dose of 1 mg/kg peripheral IV given immediately&#xD;
      pre-transplant, and at 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks after transplant, for a total of 5 doses (over 8&#xD;
      weeks). If a subsequent islet infusion is required beyond this induction period, then a&#xD;
      further 5 dose course of daclizumab will be given according to the same schedule. If the&#xD;
      second (or third) transplant occurs and no daclizumab was given in the preceding 7 days, then&#xD;
      the dosing regimen will begin at the time of transplant. If daclizumab has been administered&#xD;
      within the past 7 days, then the dose at transplant is omitted, and the first dose given 2&#xD;
      weeks post transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4.2.2. Sirolimus regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients enrolled in this trial will already be on Sirolimus therapy. If needed, the dose&#xD;
      will be increased to 0.1 mg/kg/day PO and adjusted to the target range of 12-15 ng/ml for the&#xD;
      3 months following the most recent islet infusion. After three months following last&#xD;
      transplant, the target whole blood level will be lowered to 7-10ng/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4.2.3. Tacrolimus regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients enrolled in this trial will already be on Tacrolimus therapy. As soon as trough&#xD;
      levels are available, the dose will be adjusted to the target range of 3-6 ng/ml throughout&#xD;
      the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2000</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>independence from insulin injections with adequate control of blood glucose in subjects with Type 1 diabetes at one year post final transplant</measure>
    <time_frame>one year post final islet cell transplant</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">8</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Kidney Transplantation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>islet cell transplant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Islet Infusion</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>islet cell transplant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Enrolling subjects must have Type 1 diabetes mellitus for more than 5 years, complicated by&#xD;
        renal failure requiring a kidney transplant. The complicating situations are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Reduced awareness of hypoglycemia,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Metabolic lability/instability,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Despite efforts at optimal glucose control, progressive secondary complications of&#xD;
             diabetes as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
        i) Retinopathy- ii) Nephropathy- or&#xD;
&#xD;
        iii) Neuropathy-&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Severe co-existing cardiac disease, characterized by any one of these conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  recent myocardial infarction (within past 6 months), or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  angiographic evidence of non-correctable coronary artery disease, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  evidence of ischemia on functional cardiac exam (•&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Active alcohol or substance abuse-includes cigarette smoking (&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Failure to fulfill major work, school, or home responsibilities;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Drinking in situations that are physically dangerous, such as while driving a car&#xD;
                  or operating machinery;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Recurring alcohol-related legal problems, such as being arrested for driving&#xD;
                  under the influence of alcohol or for physically hurting someone while drunk;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Continued drinking despite having ongoing relationship problems that are caused&#xD;
                  or worsened by the effects of alcohol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Psychiatric disorder making the subject not a suitable candidate for transplantation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of non-adherence to prescribed regimens&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active infection including hepatitis C, hepatitis B, HIV, or TB (or under treatment&#xD;
             for suspected TB)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any history of malignancy except squamous or basal skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. BMI &gt; 26 kg/m2 or body weight &gt; 70 kg for females and &gt; 75kg for males at the&#xD;
             screening visit. (An allowance for weight gain of up to +2 kg body weight is permitted&#xD;
             between the screening visit and actual transplant. No transplant can be given to a&#xD;
             female subject weighing &gt; 72 kg or a male subject weighing &gt; 77kg on the day of&#xD;
             transplant. See Section 5.1 for minimum islet equivalent infusion requirements per&#xD;
             recipient body weight.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. C-peptide response to arginine stimulation (5 gm I.V.) (any C-peptide ≥ 0.3 ng/mL at&#xD;
             2, 3, 4, 5, 7 and 10 min post infusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Inability to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Age less than 18 or greater than 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Serum creatinine &gt; 1.8 mg/dL, In addition, there must be no change in serum creatinine&#xD;
             of &gt; 0.4 mg/dl in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Baseline Hb &lt; 10.5 gm/dL in women, or &lt; 13 gm/dL in men&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Baseline LFT's outside of normal range with the exception of Gilberts Syndrome. n.&#xD;
             Presence of gallstones (subjects may be eligible two weeks after a laparoscopic&#xD;
             cholecystectomy ).&#xD;
&#xD;
        o. Hemangioma in liver on baseline ultrasound exam&#xD;
&#xD;
        p. Untreated proliferative retinopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
        q. Positive pregnancy test, intent for future pregnancy or male subjects' intent to&#xD;
        procreate, failure to follow effective contraceptive measures, or presently breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
        r. Evidence of sensitization as determined by a general PRA with reactivity &gt; 20%. t.&#xD;
        Insulin requirement &gt; 0.7 IU/kg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
        s. HbA1C &gt; 12%&#xD;
&#xD;
        t. Inability to complete all scheduled visits during screening and post-transplant&#xD;
        follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        u. Hyperlipidemia (fasting LDL cholesterol &gt; 130 mg/dL, treated or untreated; and/or&#xD;
        fasting triglycerides &gt; 200 mg/dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
        v. Under treatment for a medical condition requiring chronic use of steroids at a dose &gt;&#xD;
        prednisone 5 mg/day w. Use of coumadin or other anticoagulant therapy (except aspirin) or&#xD;
        subject with PT INR &gt; 1.5 x. Addison's disease.y. EBV- negative subjects (use EBNA test for&#xD;
        screening) to reduce potential risk of EBV infection for previously unexposed recipient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martha Pavlakis, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Joslin Diabetes Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 7, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 9, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 14, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 14, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Martha Pavlakis</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Islet Transplantation</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

