<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03787394</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NL67908.081.18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03787394</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sensory and Hedonic Effects of FAAA-conjugates Added to Food Products</brief_title>
  <official_title>Sensory and Hedonic Effects of FAAA-conjugates Added to Food Products</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wageningen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wageningen University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rationale: According to preliminary observations provided by the research and development&#xD;
      department (R&amp;D) of Givaudan, addition of specific fatty acid-amino acid (FAAA)-conjugates to&#xD;
      a wide range of food products resulted in an enhancement of several sensory and hedonic&#xD;
      effects. Such effects could be attributed to the so-called kokumi sensation, a taste concept&#xD;
      that has been described as a &quot;taste enhancer&quot; that magnifies and lengthens all the other five&#xD;
      basic tastes. The exact mechanisms of the kokumi sensation are as of yet unclear. Perception&#xD;
      of the kokumi sensation depends on the context of other taste compounds and integration into&#xD;
      food matrices. A systematic investigation is necessary to objectively evaluate whether the&#xD;
      addition of specific FAAA-conjugates results in the enhancement of sensory and hedonic&#xD;
      effects. Furthermore, we want to assess the dependency of these effects on the food matrix.&#xD;
      To do so, a combination of discrimination, descriptive and hedonic testing will be carried&#xD;
      out.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: The primary objectives are: to determine if there is a perceivable difference&#xD;
      between plain and FAAA-enriched versions of selected food products and describe sensory&#xD;
      and/or hedonic differences between them; to assess the dependency of FAAA-conjugates on the&#xD;
      food matrix.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design: A two-step, randomised controlled intervention study will be carried out. Study&#xD;
      population: 40 healthy, adult (18-55 years) males and females (BMI 18 - 27 kg/m2) from&#xD;
      Wageningen and surroundings will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention (if applicable): FAAA-conjugates: in step one, FAAA-conjugates will be&#xD;
      integrated into food products; in step two, FAAA-conjugates will both be administered&#xD;
      separately (using a tasteless mouthwash) and integrated into food products.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main study parameters/endpoints: The primary outcome parameters are: proportion of correct&#xD;
      answers (discrimination testing); sensory evaluation score means (descriptive testing); and&#xD;
      hedonic evaluation score means (hedonic testing).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group&#xD;
      relatedness: The current study is non-therapeutic to subjects. Risks associated with&#xD;
      participation are negligible and compared to other studies, the burden can be considered low.&#xD;
      The FAAA-conjugates used in the intervention are declared &quot;generally recognised as safe&quot;&#xD;
      (GRAS) by the Flavour Extract Manufacturers Association (FEMA) and pose no known adverse&#xD;
      health effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      FAAA conjugates are compounds containing different long-chain fatty acids and simple amino&#xD;
      acids. They are involved in multiple signalling pathways playing a role in the regulation of&#xD;
      homeostatic and non-homeostatic eating behaviour (Jager &amp; Witkamp, 2014). FAAA-conjugates are&#xD;
      naturally occurring in various animal and plant food sources, yet their dietary relevance and&#xD;
      exact mechanism of action remains unclear. Notwithstanding, they have been related to&#xD;
      improved food sensations and hedonic effects (Jager &amp; Witkamp, 2014; Witkamp, 2018; Yoshida&#xD;
      et al., 2013). FAAA compounds have been declared GRAS by FEMA, which guarantees their safe&#xD;
      use in commercially available food products (Flavour Extract Manufacturers Association,&#xD;
      2018).&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to preliminary observations provided by the research and development department&#xD;
      (R&amp;D) of Givaudan, the addition of specific FAAA-conjugates to a range of food products&#xD;
      resulted in an enhancement of several sensory- and hedonic effects in product evaluation.&#xD;
      Panellists reported accentuated palatability; aftertaste masking; enhanced fat, sweet, salt&#xD;
      and umami perception; and mouthfeel improvement. However, the reproducibility of these&#xD;
      results is questionable, as substantial variation in the effects arose both within and&#xD;
      between a small sample of volunteers. It is unclear whether these effects are specific for&#xD;
      and dependent on integration of these conjugates in a certain food matrix, or if they have a&#xD;
      more general boosting effect, relevant for taste or flavour. Perhaps the boosting effect also&#xD;
      affects other sensory domains (e.g. vision).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aforementioned reported sensory/hedonic effects could be attributed to what has been&#xD;
      described in literature as the kokumi sensation, which is related to activation of&#xD;
      calcium-sensing receptors on the human tongue, albeit the exact mechanism remains to be&#xD;
      elucidated (Feng, Zhang, Zhuang, Zhou, &amp; Xu, 2016; Kuroda &amp; Miyamura, 2015; Ohsu et al.,&#xD;
      2010). Although Kokumi is associated with taste perception, it is most likely not a primary&#xD;
      taste, since its effects exist in the context of other taste compounds. On their own, kokumi&#xD;
      compounds elicit only very slight or no taste sensations but incorporated in a food matrix&#xD;
      they can enhance other taste sensations. The threshold concentration of kokumi compounds in a&#xD;
      plain water solution to induce a taste sensation is usually very high, while the threshold&#xD;
      concentration in food to enhance other taste sensations can be very low. (Dunkel, Koster, &amp;&#xD;
      Hofmann, 2007; Feng et al., 2016; Kuroda &amp; Miyamura, 2015).&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the basis of preliminary testing done by R&amp;D Givaudan, the study described in the current&#xD;
      protocol aims to systematically investigate the sensory and hedonic effects of&#xD;
      FAAA-conjugates. To do so, specific FAAA-conjugates will be integrated into two food products&#xD;
      (one sweet (chocolate milk) and one savoury (salad dressing), which will be sensorially and&#xD;
      hedonically evaluated. Furthermore, the dependency of FAAA-conjugates on the food matrix will&#xD;
      be studied by administering them separately from food products. An untrained panel will be&#xD;
      used, since consumers are not only capable of providing accurate and reliable information&#xD;
      about product sensory characteristics, but can also serve as a measure of potential&#xD;
      performance of the product in the marketplace (Ares &amp; Varela, 2017; Lawless &amp; Heymann, 2010).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If results are in line with the aforementioned preliminary observations, they can add to the&#xD;
      body of knowledge and underpin future studies investigating the kokumi sensation and the&#xD;
      mechanistic background of FAAA-conjugate effects. Moreover, food product reformulation with&#xD;
      the use of FAAA-conjugates could positively impact a wide range of consumers. Due to their&#xD;
      boosting sensory/hedonic effects, enriching foods with FAAA-conjugates has the potential to&#xD;
      reduce sugar, fat and salt content in a wide range of food products without compromising on&#xD;
      experienced flavour, thereby reducing sugar, fat and salt intake and their harmful effects.&#xD;
      More importantly, the elderly and seriously ill patients could benefit from the&#xD;
      palatability-enhancing effects ascribed to kokumi molecules, which could stimulate appetite&#xD;
      and help reverse weight loss (Witkamp, 2018).&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective(s):&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of the current study is to determine if there is an objective&#xD;
      perceivable difference between plain and FAAA-enriched versions of selected food products and&#xD;
      describe sensory and/or hedonic differences between them, using a combination of&#xD;
      discrimination testing, descriptive analyses and hedonic tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objective(s):&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objective is to assess the dependency of FAAA-conjugates on the food matrix, by&#xD;
      separating administration of compound and product and assessing how separation affects&#xD;
      sensory and hedonic evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 9, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A two-step, randomised controlled intervention study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>discrimination test</measure>
    <time_frame>90 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>percentage correctly identified FAAA-enriched samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>descriptive tests</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>ratings sensory attributes on VAS-scales</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>hedonic test</measure>
    <time_frame>45 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>ratings product liking on VAS-scales</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Sensory Testing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FAAA-enriched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>food products enriched with FAAA-conjugates</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Plain</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Food products without FAAA-conjugates</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>adding taste enhancer</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparing sensory profiles of food products either enriched with FAAA-conjugates or plain</description>
    <arm_group_label>FAAA-enriched</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Plain</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 18-55 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI: 18.0 - 27.0 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy (as judged by subject)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumer of products used in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proficient in spoken and written English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to meet any of the inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight loss or weight gain of 5 kg or more during the last 2 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular smoker (&gt; 1 cigarette per day);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Restrained eater, assessed by the DEBQ (score of &gt;2.37 for men and &gt;3.24 for women&#xD;
             (van Strien, Frijters, Bergers, &amp; Defares, 1986))&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating woman&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anosmia or ageusia (self-reported)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Food allergies or intolerances relevant for the food products used in the experiment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Student/employee of the WUR Sensory Science and Eating Behaviour department&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gerry Jager, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Wageningen University, Division of Human Nutrition</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Gerry Jager, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+31317485850</phone>
    <email>gerry.jager@wur.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>December 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 24, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 26, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 24, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 24, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 26, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>taste enhancers</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

