<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03788304</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>High flow nasal cannula</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03788304</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>High Flow Nasal Cannula Versus Non-invasive Ventilation in Prevention of Escalation to Invasive Mechanical Ventilation in Patients With Acute Hypoxemic Respiratory Failure</brief_title>
  <official_title>High Flow Nasal Cannula Versus Non-invasive Ventilation in Prevention of Escalation to Invasive Mechanical Ventilation in Patients With Acute Hypoxemic Respiratory Failure</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Oxygen therapy is first-line treatment in the management of acute respiratory failure (ARF).&#xD;
      Different oxygen devices have become available over recent decades, such as low-flow systems&#xD;
      (nasal cannula, simple facemask, non-rebreathing reservoir mask) and high-flow systems&#xD;
      (Venturi mask) . Since the 90's, non-invasive ventilation (NIV) has been largely used with&#xD;
      strong level of evidence in cardiogenic pulmonary edema and chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
      disease (COPD) exacerbation. NIV improves gas exchange and reduces inspiratory effort through&#xD;
      positive pressure. However, good tolerance to NIV is sometimes difficult to achieve due to&#xD;
      frequent leaks around the mask, possibly leading to patient-ventilator asynchrony and even to&#xD;
      intubation . High-flow nasal oxygen therapy (HFNO) is an innovative high-flow system that&#xD;
      allows for delivering up to 60 liters\ min of heated and fully humidified gas with a FIO2&#xD;
      ranging between 21% and 100% . It is a new method of respiratory support in adults that has&#xD;
      been used in neonatal ARF for some years. The reason this study is necessary is because, even&#xD;
      though NIV has been demonstrated to prevent endotracheal intubation (and its associated&#xD;
      complications) in a broad range of ARF patients, HFNC has been proposed to have the same&#xD;
      effect as NIV while being easier tolerated, more physiological , allowing patients to&#xD;
      continue to talk, eat and drink through mouth while on HFNC&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Oxygen therapy is the first-line treatment in management of acute respiratory failure (ARF).&#xD;
      Different oxygen delivery devices have become available over recent decades, either low-flow&#xD;
      systems (nasal cannula, simple facemask, non-rebreathing reservoir mask) or high-flow systems&#xD;
      (Venturi mask) . The choice of a specific device in management of ARF is based on the&#xD;
      severity of hypoxemia, the underlying mechanisms, the patient's breathing pattern and&#xD;
      tolerance .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Critically ill patients often require high-flow devices to meet their oxygen needs .&#xD;
      Tachypneic patients with ARF, have a peak inspiratory flow rate that is usually high and&#xD;
      often exceeds the oxygen flow delivered by the traditional oxygen devices . Using&#xD;
      conventional devices, oxygen flow is limited to no more than 15 L/min. Meanwhile, the&#xD;
      required inspiratory flow for patients with respiratory failure varies widely in a range from&#xD;
      30 to120 L/min. The difference between patient inspiratory flow and delivered flow is large&#xD;
      with conventional oxygen devices leading to patient discomfort . Moreover; high respiratory&#xD;
      rate can generate significant entrainment of room air in the mask and dilution of the&#xD;
      inspired oxygen with an insufficient oxygen concentration. The suboptimal humidification of&#xD;
      the inhaled oxygen provided by standard bubble humidifiers and the limited and unknown&#xD;
      inspiratory oxygen fraction (FIO2) delivery are additional drawbacks of these devices .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since the 90's, noninvasive ventilation (NIV) has been largely used with strong level of&#xD;
      evidence in cardiogenic pulmonary edema and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)&#xD;
      exacerbation. NIV improves gas exchange and reduces inspiratory effort through positive&#xD;
      pressure. However, good tolerance to NIV is sometimes difficult to achieve due to frequent&#xD;
      leaks around the mask, possibly leading to patient-ventilator asynchrony and even to&#xD;
      intubation. It may have other deleterious effects such as delayed intubation by masking signs&#xD;
      of respiratory distress, or barotrauma by the high tidal volume potentially generated under&#xD;
      positive pressure .&#xD;
&#xD;
      To ensure good results, an appropriate interface is more important than the ventilation mode&#xD;
      . Oronasal masks, nasal masks, and hoods are most commonly used for NIV. Oronasal masks are&#xD;
      usually tried first because they ensure the effects of NIV better than other interfaces.&#xD;
      Unfortunately, it is not comfortable, and many patients find it hard to tolerate. It is also&#xD;
      associated with a relatively high incidence of air leakage. Also, skin lesions at the nose&#xD;
      induced by long-term use of this device may result in frequent treatment interruptions and&#xD;
      discontinuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      High-flow nasal oxygen therapy (HFNO) is an innovative high-flow system that allows for&#xD;
      delivering up to 60 liters/ min of heated and fully humidified gas with a FIO2 ranging&#xD;
      between 21% and 100% [.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HFNO delivery systems: main technical characteristics: - The administration of HFNO&#xD;
           requires the following: high pressure sources of oxygen and air, an air-oxygen blender&#xD;
           or a high-flow 'Venturi' system (which permits delivery of an accurate FIO2 between 21%&#xD;
           and 100%), a humidifying and heating system for conditioning the gas to optimal&#xD;
           temperature (37 ºC) and humidity (44mg H2O/ liters), a sterile water reservoir, a&#xD;
           non-condensing circuitry, and an interface . The two most widely marketed HFNO systems&#xD;
           are the Precision Flow by Vapotherm and Optiflow by Fisher &amp; Pykel Healthcare Ltd.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physiological effects of HFNC: - Gas from an air/oxygen blender that can generate a&#xD;
           total flow of up to 60 L/min is heated and humidified with an active humidifier and&#xD;
           subsequently delivered through a heated circuit. High flow of adequately heated and&#xD;
           humidified gas is considered to have a number of physiological effects&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Washout of nasopharyngeal dead space: Washout of upper airway dead space from the&#xD;
                delivery of a large amount of oxygen can improve the efficiency of ventilation and&#xD;
                enhance oxygen delivery . HFNC is the only noninvasive respiratory support that&#xD;
                does not increase dead space. With an oxygen mask, especially at low flow, carbon&#xD;
                dioxide is rebreathed .&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Warming and humidification of secretions: Warming of inspired oxygen and heating it&#xD;
                to core temperature is more effective at high flow rates (typically &gt;40 L/minute)&#xD;
                than low flow rates. Thus, HFNC is better at heating and humidifying inspired&#xD;
                oxygen than conventional high-flow systems such as Venturi masks or nonrebreathers&#xD;
                (flow rate typically 10 to 15 L/minute) or low-flow systems (flow rates typically&#xD;
                &lt;10 L/minute) . Increased humidification results in increased water content in&#xD;
                mucous, which can facilitate secretion removal and may also decrease the work of&#xD;
                breathing and avoid airway desiccation and epithelial injury&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) effect: Several studies in adults have&#xD;
                shown that, similar to infants and neonates, HFNC increases nasopharyngeal airway&#xD;
                pressure that peaks at the end of expiration (ie, &quot;PEEP effect&quot;) . This &quot;PEEP&#xD;
                effect&quot; can potentially unload auto-PEEP, decrease work of breathing, and enhance&#xD;
                oxygenation in patients with alveolar filling diseases such as congestive heart&#xD;
                failure or acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). As flow increases,&#xD;
                nasopharyngeal pressure increases (ie, a dose effect) . The CPAP effect is greatest&#xD;
                with the mouth closed. In general, every increase of 10 L/minute of flow yields&#xD;
                approximately 0.7 cm H2O of airway pressure when the mouth is closed and 0.35 cm of&#xD;
                H2O when the mouth is open.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Small pliable nasal prongs: HFNC nasal prongs are generally soft and pliable.&#xD;
                Consequently, several studies have reported improved patient comfort with HFNC when&#xD;
                compared with conventional low-flow oxygen delivered through nasal cannula or&#xD;
                high-flow oxygen delivered through a face mask .&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. High flow rates: High flow rates result in minimal entrainment of room air when&#xD;
                HFNC is used; this results in more accurate delivery of oxygen. Patients in&#xD;
                respiratory distress generate high inspiratory flow rates that exceed flow rates of&#xD;
                standard oxygen equipment, resulting in entrainment of room air and a reduction in&#xD;
                the delivery of the set FIO2. The rate of flow in HFNC generally exceeds that of&#xD;
                the patient, entraining very little room air and resulting in an FIO2 that is more&#xD;
                reliably delivered . High flow rates have also been shown to result in an improved&#xD;
                breathing pattern by increasing tidal volume and decreasing respiratory rate .&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Reduction of work of breathing: The HFNO system may significantly reduce the energy&#xD;
                requirement (metabolic work) associated with gas conditioning. By providing high&#xD;
                gas flows, HFNO reduces the resistance of the upper airway and then decreases the&#xD;
                resistive breathing effort .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>patients with will be randomly enrolled to either non invasive group or HFNC group and improvement and patient satisfaction will be assessed</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Neither the participant , care provider , the investigator nor the outcome assessor will select patients in both groups , see results of other patients till the end of the study or informed by literature opinion in this intervention</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Endotracheal intubation rate.</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>needs escalation to invasive mechanical ventilation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In hospital mortality.</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>length of hospital stay</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>hospital coast</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>duration of ICU stay</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>icu occupancy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>duration of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>need ventilatory support</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>development of complications</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>due to devices</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Failure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non invasive ventilation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Respiratory assistance is provided by a NIV either Puritan Bennet 840 , Engström Carestation or Hamilton-G5 , will be used for conventional non-invasive ventilation via an oronasal mask. Settings will be adjusted based on the clinical assessment of the respiratory therapist . Initial setting includes: -&#xD;
Positive End Expiratory Pressure (PEEP): 5 cmH2O.&#xD;
Pressure support (PS): 12-20 cmH2O.&#xD;
FiO2 will be adjusted to achieve a SpO2 at least 95%</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High flow nasal cannula</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>High flow nasal cannula consists of an apparatus that allows adjustable FiO2 from 21 to 100% and delivers a modified gas flow up to 60 l/ min .&#xD;
will be set with: -&#xD;
Temperature at 37°C or 34°C&#xD;
Flow rate 30: 50 L/min.&#xD;
FiO2 will be adjusted to achieve a SpO2 at least 95%</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>non-invasive ventilation</intervention_name>
    <description>conventional NIV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non invasive ventilation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>high flow nasal cannula</intervention_name>
    <description>HFNC ventilation</description>
    <arm_group_label>High flow nasal cannula</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants admitted to the RICU with acute hypoxemic respiratory failure requiring&#xD;
             NIV support with the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. RR&gt; 25 breath/minute&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Use of accessory muscles of respiration, paradoxical breathing, thoracoabdominal&#xD;
                  asynchrony.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hypoxemia evidenced by PaO2 / FiO2 ratio &lt;300&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who have any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        I. Indication for emergency endotracheal intubation. II. HR &lt;50 beat\minute with decreased&#xD;
        level of consciousness III. Persistent hemodynamic instability with&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic blood pressure &lt;90 mmHg after infusing a bolus of crystalloid solution at a&#xD;
             dose of 30 ml / kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  life-threatening arrhythmia. IV. Undrained pneumothorax or Pneumothorax with&#xD;
             persistent air leak. V. Extensive facial trauma or burn VI. Refusal to participate.&#xD;
             VII. Usual long-term treatment with NIV for chronic disease VIII. Altered mental&#xD;
             status with decreased consciousness and/or evidence of inability to understand .&#xD;
&#xD;
        IX. Tracheotomy or other upper airway disorders X. Active upper gastrointestinal bleeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed F Adam, lecturer</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manal A El-Khawaga, lecturer</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Entsar H mohamed, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+201019968106</phone>
    <email>dr.entsar_hsanen@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gamal M Rabie, professor</last_name>
    <phone>+201155213224</phone>
    <email>Gamalagmy135@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut University hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>assiut University 71515</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Entsar H mohamed, master</last_name>
      <phone>01019968106</phone>
      <email>dr.entsar_hsanen@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Gamal M Rabie, MD</last_name>
      <phone>01155213224</phone>
      <email>Gamalagmy135@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>1-Renda, T., Corrado, A., Iskandar, G., et al. High-flow nasal oxygen therapy in intensive care and anaesthesia . British journal of anaesthesia 2018 , 120(1), 18-27 2-Kallstrom TJ. AARC clinical practice guideline: oxygen therapy for adults in the acute care facility: 2002 revision and update. Respir Care 2002; 47: 717-20. 3-O'Driscoll BR, Howard LS, Davison AG, on behalf of the British Thoracic Society. BTS guideline for emergency oxygen use in adult patients. Thorax 2008; 63: 1-68. 4-Sim MA, Dean P, Kinsella J, et al. Performance of oxygen delivery devices when the breathing pattern of respiratory failure is simulated. Anaesthesia 2008; 63: 938-40 5-Nishimura, M. High-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy in adults: physiological benefits, indication, clinical benefits, and adverse effects. Respiratory Care 2016, 61(4), 529-541.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 20, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 26, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 17, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 17, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Entsar Hsanen Mohamed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

