<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03781739</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB # 16-005813</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03781739</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>MANP in Hypertension and Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>MANP-HTN-MS</acronym>
  <official_title>A PHASE I, DOUBLE BLIND, PLACEBO-CONTROLLED STUDY EVALUATING THE CARDIOVASCULAR AND METABOLIC PROPERTIES OF MANP IN SUBJECTS WITH HYPERTENSION AND METABOLIC SYNDROME ACCORDING TO RS5068 GENOTYPES</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>American Heart Association</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mayo Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Evaluate the cardiovascular and metabolic properties of MANP in subjects with HTN and MS&#xD;
      according to rs5068 genotypes&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      6 Study Procedures 6.1 Day 0 - Visit 1 (screening visit) 6.2 At visit 1 informed consent will&#xD;
      be obtained (Table 1). Introduction and orientation to the study will take place. Medical&#xD;
      history will be collected. Physical exam will be performed and laboratory exams history will&#xD;
      be screened. Electrocardiogram will be recorded and screening laboratory tests will be&#xD;
      performed. Blood pressure and heart rate will be recorded. Subjects will be instructed about&#xD;
      the fluid intake allowed (2.5 liter/day) and the diet (moderate sodium intake: 3.0 gr/day) to&#xD;
      follow for the duration of the study from day 1 to day 7. Subjects will be instructed on&#xD;
      completing a 24-hour urine collection starting on day 4 at 4pm (see day 4 below).&#xD;
      Antihypertensive medications are required to be at a stable dose for 30 days preceding visit&#xD;
      1 on day 1. Throughout the duration of the study subjects will be maintained on their chronic&#xD;
      antihypertensive treatment except for day 6 in which MANP or placebo will be administered.&#xD;
      Subjects will be instructed to avoid strenuous physical activities and to abstain from&#xD;
      smoking and alcohol from day 1 until the completion of the study on day 7. Caffeine&#xD;
      consumption will be prohibited from 7.00 pm on day 5 until the dismissal from the CRTU on day&#xD;
      7. Day 1 Start of diet and fluid restriction compliance. (Interval of time between day 0 and&#xD;
      day 1 will depend upon the CRTU schedules 6.3 Day 4 On Day 4 at 4 pm the subjects will start&#xD;
      24-hour urine collection in order to establish adherence to the moderate sodium diet (Table&#xD;
      1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      6.4 Day 5 On day 5 at 4pm subjects will bring the 24-hour urine collection to the CRTU and&#xD;
      24-hour urine sodium will be measured. If the patient has been compliant with the sodium&#xD;
      diet, she/he will be admitted to the CRTU to continue the study and a physical exam will be&#xD;
      performed. At 7.00 pm subjects will start fasting and abstain from their usual hypoglycemic&#xD;
      therapy in consideration of the blood draws for metabolic parameters that will be performed&#xD;
      on day 6. Caffeine consumption is prohibited from 7:00 pm on day 5 until the dismissal from&#xD;
      the CRTU on day 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6.5 Day 6 - Visit 2 On day 6 at 8:00 am enrolled patients will receive a single injection of&#xD;
      MANP (2.5 μg/kg SQ) or placebo (0.9% saline solution) and will be under observation for the&#xD;
      24 hours following the MANP/placebo administration (Table 1). Blood pressure and heart rate&#xD;
      will be monitored continually and recorded before MANP/placebo injection and at several&#xD;
      intervals after MANP/placebo administration. Timed urine collection and blood samples to&#xD;
      evaluate neurohumoral, renal function and metabolic plasma parameters will be collected prior&#xD;
      to MANP /placebo injection and at different time points after MANP and placebo&#xD;
      administration. Subjects will eat their meal and take their usual hypoglycemic medications&#xD;
      after the last blood draw for metabolic parameters (4 hours after the MANP injection).&#xD;
      Subjects will be maintained on their chronic antihypertensive treatment except for day 6 in&#xD;
      which MANP will be administered. They will take their usual antihypertensive therapy 24 hours&#xD;
      after MANP injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6.6 Day 7 Once completed the 24 hour observation following MANP administration a physical&#xD;
      exam will be performed and the subjects will be dismissed from the CRTU&#xD;
&#xD;
      6.7 Day 14 (± 2 days) Laboratory tests will be performed and assessed. Subjects will be&#xD;
      contacted by phone to review laboratory tests results and assess the onset of any potential&#xD;
      side effect following the MANP/placebo administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6.8 Day 30 (-2 days, + 5 days) Blood collection for anti-MANP antibody testing will be&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 18, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 10, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 14, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>cardiovascular outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>systolic blood pressure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>second messenger</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>cGMP plasma levels</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>metabolic outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>glycerol and non-esterified fatty acids (NEFA) plasma levels</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>secondary cardiovascular outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>diastolic blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>secondary metabolic outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>adiponectin plasma levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MANP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>subjects receiving MANP (2.5 micrograms/kg, single subcutaneous injection)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>subjects receiving placebo (saline solution, single subcutaneous injection)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MANP</intervention_name>
    <description>single subcutaneous injection of MANP and monitoring of metabolic, cardiovascular and renal parameters</description>
    <arm_group_label>MANP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension defined as 140 mmHg ≤ systolic BP ≤ 180 mmHg or 90 mmHg ≤ diastolic BP ≤&#xD;
             100 mmHg despite anti-hypertensive medical therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metabolic Syndrome defined as the presence of any two of the following traits:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abdominal obesity, defined as a waist circumference in men ≥102 cm (40 in) and in&#xD;
             women ≥88 cm (35 in)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum triglycerides ≥150 mg/dL (1.7 mmol/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum HDL cholesterol &lt;40 mg/dL (1 mmol/L) in men and &lt;50 mg/dL (1.3 mmol/L) in women&#xD;
             or drug treatment for low HDL cholesterol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting plasma glucose ≥100 mg/dL (5.6 mmol/L) or drug treatment for elevated blood&#xD;
             glucose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between the ages of 18 and 75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of antihypertensive medications at a stable dose for 30 days preceding screening&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of statins or ezetimibe or combinations on stable dose for 60 days preceding&#xD;
             screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or allergy to MANP or its components, carperitide, other&#xD;
             natriuretic peptides, or related compounds;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with orthostatic hypotension at the screening visit, defined as a decrease in&#xD;
             systolic BP of &gt;20 mmHg or a decrease in diastolic BP of &gt;10 mmHg within three minutes&#xD;
             of standing when compared with blood pressure from the sitting position.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a systolic BP &gt;180 mmHg or a diastolic BP &gt;100 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of abnormal laboratory values at screening visit considered clinically&#xD;
             significant by the Investigator. Specifically they will be excluded if a) Serum sodium&#xD;
             of &lt; 135 mEq/dL or &gt; 145 mEq/dL; b) Serum potassium of &lt; 3.5 mEq/dL or &gt; 5.1 mEq/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects whose body weight has changed more than 3% in the last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having received any investigational drug or device within 30 days prior to entry into&#xD;
             the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history (within the last 2 years) of alcohol risky use (defined as more than 14&#xD;
             standard drinks per week on average or more than 4 drinks on any day for men under age&#xD;
             65 - defined as more than 7 standard drinks per week on average or more than 3 drinks&#xD;
             on any day for women and adults 65 years and older);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of illicit drug use, psychiatric illness that might impair the participation&#xD;
             to the study, physical dependence to any opioid, or any history of substance abuse or&#xD;
             addiction;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of difficulty with donating blood or donated blood or blood products within&#xD;
             45 days prior to enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant new illness in the 1 month before screening in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe allergies;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of coronary artery disease or cerebrovascular disease or syncope;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of epilepsy or other seizure disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of organ transplantation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignancy within 5 years of the screening visit (with the exception of basal cell and&#xD;
             squamous cell skin carcinoma);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant intrinsic renal disease, renal artery stenosis, or history of&#xD;
             fibromuscular dysplasia of the renal arteries;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumption of a phosphodiesterase-5 inhibitor (sildenafil, vardenafil, or tadalafil)&#xD;
             within 72 hours of receiving MANP.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Episodic or chronic use of nitrates (Isordil, nitroglycerine), MAO inhibitors,&#xD;
             antipsychotics, antiarrhythmics, psychostimulants, systemic corticosteroids,&#xD;
             cholestyramine and cholestipol reisins, fibrates, nicotinic acid, cyclosporin,&#xD;
             rifampin or other highly potent PgP inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any disease or condition (medical or surgical) which, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, might compromise the hematologic, cardiovascular, pulmonary, renal,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, hepatic, or central nervous system; or other conditions that may&#xD;
             interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism or excretion of study drug, or&#xD;
             would place the subject at increased risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who smoke or have any history of tobacco product use more recently than 6&#xD;
             months prior to the enrollment into the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul M McKie, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Foundation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mayo.edu/research/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Mayo Clinic Clinical Trials</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 18, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 20, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 13, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mayo Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Paul M. McKie, M.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

