<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03786328</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2013-18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03786328</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Outreach Collaborative Model for Early Identification and Treatment of Mental Disorder in Danish Workplaces</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Outreach Collaborative Model for Early Identification and Treatment of Mental Disorder in Danish Workplaces</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Helle Østermark Sørensen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Spar Nord Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aalborg University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Depression and anxiety are prevalent mental disorders among the working population with&#xD;
      potentially high personal and financial cost. The aim of the study is to test the&#xD;
      applicability of an outreach collaborative model for early identification and treatment of&#xD;
      clinical and sub-clinical mental disorders among Danish employees. applicability was examined&#xD;
      by I) investigating the fractions of identified and treated clinical and subclinical cases,&#xD;
      II) describing the distribution and characteristics of cases identified and III)&#xD;
      investigating the effect of allocated treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A longitudinal study design with four assessments over 16 months are applied. Six&#xD;
      medium-large companies will be included, both public and private cooperations. Self-reporting&#xD;
      questionnaires probing for psychopathology will be distributed to all employees in the six&#xD;
      consecutively enrolled companies at the four time points. Employees meeting the screening&#xD;
      criteria at T1 will be assessed diagnostically. Subjects diagnosed with a clinical mental&#xD;
      disorder will be allocated to outpatient psychiatric treatment, and subjects with subclinical&#xD;
      conditions will be allocated to preventive cognitive behavioural therapy. Follow-up is&#xD;
      conducted 6 and 12 months after initiation of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in the study is voluntary at all levels. Written informed consent will be&#xD;
      obtained from participant selected for diagnostic interview and treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Common mental disorders, like depression and anxiety are prevalent mental disorders among the&#xD;
      working population with prevalence's of approximately 3% respectively. These disorder induce&#xD;
      high personal and financial cost, due to increased number of sick days, impaired functioning&#xD;
      - socially and professionally, reduced job satisfaction and reduced quality of life and an&#xD;
      increased risk of loss of work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to clinical conditions, many employees are affected by symptoms of depression and&#xD;
      anxiety at a subclinical level which can be socially inhibiting for the individual as well as&#xD;
      negatively impacting job satisfaction, work productivity and attendance. Untreated and not&#xD;
      early identified, these subclinical cases can lead to actual mental disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both the general population and the working population, evidence has demonstrated a high&#xD;
      level of unmet need for mental health care and treatment. The unmet needs are partly&#xD;
      explained by diagnostic difficulties and inadequate treatment in general practice, and partly&#xD;
      by the fact that many individuals affected do not seek professional help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In light of the high costs and unmet need for treatment, prevention and early detection of&#xD;
      mental disorders among the working population ought to be a public health priority. Evidence&#xD;
      suggests that much could be gained by investing in preventive initiatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research studies within occupational mental health have mainly tested workplace-initiated&#xD;
      stress management programmes or other universal prevention programmes using work-related&#xD;
      outcome measures like sickness absence, work productivity and cost-effectiveness. Secondary&#xD;
      prevention and early intervention programmes targeting mental health problems directly by&#xD;
      using clinical standardized measures of depression or anxiety are limited, or suffer from&#xD;
      limitations such as weak control conditions, short-term follow-up and lack of diagnostic&#xD;
      assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When targeting workplace mental health problems, it is recommended to apply a collaborative&#xD;
      approach between workplaces and mental health specialists in order to minimize the risk of&#xD;
      misclassification and inadequate treatment .&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this study, the investigators therefore developed an outreach secondary prevention model&#xD;
      to be tested in collaboration between the psychiatric treatment system and workplaces in the&#xD;
      North Denmark Region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall aim of the study was to investigate the applicability of an outreach&#xD;
      collaborative model for early identification and treatment of clinical and sub-clinical cases&#xD;
      of mental disorder among a Danish working population. The investigation had the following&#xD;
      objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I) To investigate the applicability of the early identification model, measured as fractions&#xD;
      of identified clinical and subclinical cases, fraction of cases who accepted treatment and&#xD;
      fraction of cases who completed treatment II) To describe the distribution and characteristic&#xD;
      of clinical and subclinical cases identified by the early identification model III) To&#xD;
      investigate the effect of allocated treatment on symptomatology for clinical and subclinical&#xD;
      cases&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHOD:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design The study applies a longitudinal naturalistic design with four points of&#xD;
      assessment (T0-T3) during a period of 16 months for each participating company. The time from&#xD;
      T0 to T1 (4 months) constitutes a pre-treatment period and is incorporated in the design as a&#xD;
      control period for comparison. After the second assessment (T1), screening and diagnostic&#xD;
      assessment will be initiated. Identified cases will afterwards be allocated to treatment.&#xD;
      Follow-up assessments are conducted after 6 months (T2) and 12 months (T3) for all employees.&#xD;
      The assessments uses self-reporting questionnaires probing for psychopathology. All&#xD;
      questionnaires are mailed to the employees' private postal addresses at the four points of&#xD;
      assessment (T0-T3) followed by a reminder after two weeks in case of no response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants In order to demonstrate the model's applicability in a representative sample,&#xD;
      the investigators will enrol six medium-large companies with a minimum of 100 employees each.&#xD;
      Companies with more than 300 employees will not be addressed due to the limitations of the&#xD;
      available treatment capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measures The questionnaires used the Symptom Check List 90 Revised (SCL90-R) [30] as basis&#xD;
      for identification of clinical and subclinical cases of mental disorders and follow-up to&#xD;
      treatment. Questionnaires also collected data on demography, different work-related&#xD;
      characteristics and job-satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following screening criteria for identification of clinical and subclinical cases of&#xD;
      mental disorder is used:&#xD;
&#xD;
      i) Global Severity Index score &gt; 0.63 or ii) values of &gt; 0.63 in two or more subscales or&#xD;
      iii) values of &gt; 0.63 in the Depression subscale&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedure Participants meeting the screening criteria at the second assessment (T1) will be&#xD;
      invited to a diagnostic assessment in order to determine the presence of a mental disorder.&#xD;
      The diagnostic interviews will be conducted by medical doctors at Aalborg Psychiatric&#xD;
      Hospital, all trained and experienced user of the diagnostic instruments utilized. The&#xD;
      presence of a mental disorder will initially be determined by use of Present State&#xD;
      Examination (PSE). Participants assessed with a state of anxiety or depression will&#xD;
      afterwards be rated on the Hamilton Depression Scale (HAM-D) and/or Hamilton Anxiety Scale&#xD;
      (HAM-A) to assess the severity of the condition. Depending on the outcome of the diagnostic&#xD;
      interview, participants will be offered two different courses of treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment course I: Psychiatric treatment for clinical cases Individuals diagnosed with a&#xD;
      mental disorder according to the PSE, and with HAM-D score ≥ 18 or HAM-A score ≥ 20, will be&#xD;
      referred to psychiatric treatment in an outpatient specialized clinic for affective disorders&#xD;
      at Aalborg Psychiatric Hospital. The treatment will follow standard treatment procedures for&#xD;
      psychiatric outpatients with diagnoses of depression and anxiety. Treatment is performed by&#xD;
      trained clinicians (psychiatrists, psychologists and nurses) employed at the Clinic for&#xD;
      Affective Disorders. The course of treatment includes medical consultations as well as&#xD;
      psychotherapeutic sessions and treatment will continue until remission is achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment course II: Preventive treatment for subclinical cases Individuals assessed with&#xD;
      subclinical conditions of depression or anxiety, defined as a HAM-D score of 13-17 or a HAM-A&#xD;
      score of 15-19, are offered preventive treatment. This course of treatment consists of eight&#xD;
      sessions of cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) conducted by clinical psychologists at Aalborg&#xD;
      Psychiatric Hospital. During the sessions, the therapeutic focus is on stress-reduction and&#xD;
      resilience.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis The primary analysis are carried out by counting the number of clinical&#xD;
      and subclinical cases identified from the early identification procedure. Secondly, the&#xD;
      investigators will perform a descriptive analysis with the study population allocated into&#xD;
      four groups: clinical cases, subclinical cases, untreated cases and healthy subjects. Groups&#xD;
      will be compared at baseline (T1) on demography, work-related characteristics and the three&#xD;
      outcome measures Global Severity Index, Depression and Anxiety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To analyze the effect of both treatments, the investigators will use mixed effects linear&#xD;
      regression using random intercept and with participants nested inside the companies. A&#xD;
      p-value &lt; 0.05 was considered statistically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics Information about the study are initially provided to the workplace management and the&#xD;
      health and safety representatives and subsequently to all employees at joint open meetings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is emphasized that the study is voluntary at all levels. Written participant information&#xD;
      will accompany all questionnaires. The return of the questionnaires will be considered as&#xD;
      acceptance of participation in the questionnaire part. Written informed consent will be&#xD;
      obtained from all participants involved in diagnostic interview and treatment. The employees&#xD;
      are guaranteed complete anonymity in relation to their workplace and company management. The&#xD;
      study are approved by the Danish Data Protection Agency (j. 2008-58-0028). The study was&#xD;
      presented to the Danish Scientific Ethics Committee (N-20070016), but the need for approval&#xD;
      was waived due to the nature of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Severity of Psychopathological symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at baseline and 6 and 12 month follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The change in severity of psychopathological symptoms are measured with the Symptom Checklist 90, revised (SCL-90-R) that is a psychiatric self-report inventory with high reliability and validity to measure overall psychological distress and to detect changes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">73</enrollment>
  <condition>Depression, Anxiety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Clinical cases of Mental Disorder</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The group of individuals identified with a clinical mental disorder on the basis of the diagnostic interviews This group will be assigned to Standard Psychiatric Treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subclinical cases of Mental Disorder</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The group of individuals identified with a sub-clinical mental condition on the basis of the diagnostic interviews This group will be assigned to Preventive Psychological Treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard Psychiatric Treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard psychiatric treatment is offered individuals identified with a clinical mental disorder. Treatment will follow golden standard treatment in the psychiatric clinic, meaning a combination of therapy and psychopharmacological treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Clinical cases of Mental Disorder</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Preventive Psychological Treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Preventive Psychological Treatment is offered individuals identified with a sub-clinical mental condition. Treatment consists of 8 sessions of cognitive-behavioural therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subclinical cases of Mental Disorder</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals for the diagnostic interview and treatment are selected on the basis of their&#xD;
        response to the SCL-90-R questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hence, individuals are included in diagnostic interview, if scores on the SCL90-R inventory&#xD;
        one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Global Severity Index score &gt; 0.63 or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  values of &gt; 0.63 in two or more subscales or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  values of &gt; 0.63 in the Depression subscale&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals not meeting the above screening criteria will not participate in&#xD;
             diagnostic interview and treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>December 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 18, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 20, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 26, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 20, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 20, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 26, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Aalborg Psychiatric Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Helle Østermark Sørensen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MHSc, Research Nurse</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Early detection and treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

