<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03788291</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ULYM18086</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03788291</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acalabrutinib and High Frequency Low Dose Subcutaneous Rituximab in Patients With Previously Untreated Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia / Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Acalabrutinib and High Frequency Low Dose Subcutaneous Rituximab in Patients With Previously Untreated CLL/SLL</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Rochester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Rochester</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main purpose of this research study is to find out if the combination of acalabrutinib&#xD;
      and high frequency low dose subcutaneous rituximab is safe and effective in patients who have&#xD;
      previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite an array of available therapies, CLL remains an incurable disease. Furthermore, the&#xD;
      presence of certain cytogenetic abnormalities and high-risk mutational features predicts for&#xD;
      a reduced response to treatment, and as a result, a shorter period of progression-free&#xD;
      survival. The development of a well-tolerated more effective, easily administered and limited&#xD;
      duration therapy would be a major contribution to the management of CLL and other B cell&#xD;
      malignancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acalabrutinib is an imidazopyrazine analogue and a potent inhibitor of BTK in vitro and in&#xD;
      vivo. Acalabrutinib shows improved selectivity for BTK compared with ibrutinib. Functional&#xD;
      inhibition of non-target cells (eg, T cells, NK cells, platelets) was not observed for&#xD;
      acalabrutinib at clinically relevant concentrations. Rituximab is a chimeric monoclonal&#xD;
      antibody targeting CD20 FDA approved for the treatment of CLL/SLL using intravenous or&#xD;
      subcutaneous formulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antibody dependent cellular phagocytosis may be optimized using high frequency subcutaneous&#xD;
      administration of anti-CD20 monoclonal antibodies. Unlike ibrutinib, acalabrutinib does not&#xD;
      cause significant in vitro inhibition of rituximab induced antibody dependent cellular&#xD;
      phagocytosis in vitro. The investigator thus proposes that acalabrutinib would be an ideal&#xD;
      partner drug with high frequency low dose SQ rituximab in the treatment of CLL and that the&#xD;
      combination will increase the efficacy of therapy for CLL patients by decreasing the time to&#xD;
      achievement of complete response and allowing for shorter and less toxic therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 25, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with a complete response rate (CR) at 1 year of therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To satisfy criteria for a CR, all of the following criteria must be met:&#xD;
No evidence of new disease&#xD;
ALC in peripheral blood of &lt;4 x 109/L&#xD;
Regression of all target nodal masses to normal size ≤1.5 cm in the LD&#xD;
Normal spleen and liver size&#xD;
Regression to normal of all nodal non-target disease and disappearance of all detectable non-nodal, non-target disease&#xD;
Morphologically negative bone marrow defined as &lt;30% of nucleated cells being lymphoid cells and no lymphoid nodules in a bone marrow sample (the presence of benign reactive nodules is still compatible with a CR)&#xD;
Absence of constitutional symptoms&#xD;
Peripheral blood counts meeting all of the following criteria:&#xD;
ANC &gt;1.5 x 109/L without need for exogenous growth factors (e.g., G-CSF)&#xD;
Platelet count ≥100 x 109/L without need for exogenous growth factors&#xD;
Hemoglobin ≥110 g/L (11.0 g/dL) without red blood cell transfusions or need for exogenous growth factors (e.g., erythropoietin)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with minimal residual disease in peripheral blood and bone</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>6-color flow cytometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL)</condition>
  <condition>Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma (SLL)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acalabrutinib and Rituximab treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rituximab: administered 2 times weekly for 6 cycles. Initial dose day 1: 50 mg IV, Then 50 mg SQ thereafter.&#xD;
Acalabrutinib: 100 mg po BID starting on day 8 of cycle 1.&#xD;
Patients who have attained a complete response who are also MRD negative at cycle 12 will undergo a BM biopsy to confirm CR and MRD negatively. If confirmed, the patient will stop therapy and be followed until disease progression.&#xD;
Patients not in a MRD negative CR, will continue acalabrutinib.&#xD;
Repeat response assessments (CTs, MRD testing in blood) will be performed at 24 cycles of therapy for those continuing on acalabrutinib. If both negative the patient will undergo a BM biopsy to confirm CR and MRD negativity. If confirmed, the patient will stop therapy and be followed until disease progression. In the absence of a CR or if MRD +, acalabrutinib may be continued until disease progression, unacceptable toxicity or physician/patient discretion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acalabrutinib</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg by mouth twice a day starting on day 8 of cycle 1</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acalabrutinib and Rituximab treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered 2 times weekly for 6 cycles. Initial dose day 1: 50 mg IV, then 50 mg SQ thereafter.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acalabrutinib and Rituximab treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosis of B-cell CLL or SLL, with diagnosis established according to IWCLL criteria&#xD;
             and documented within medical records. Patients must not have received previous&#xD;
             therapy for CLL/SLL&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. CLL/SLL that warrants treatment consistent with accepted IWCLL criteria for initiation&#xD;
             of therapy. Any one of the following conditions constitutes CLL/SLL that warrants&#xD;
             treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Evidence of progressive marrow failure as manifested by the onset or worsening of&#xD;
                  anemia and/or thrombocytopenia, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Massive (i.e., lower edge of spleen ≥6 cm below the left costal margin),&#xD;
                  progressive, or symptomatic splenomegaly, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Massive (i.e., ≥10 cm in the longest diameter), progressive, or symptomatic&#xD;
                  lymphadenopathy, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Progressive lymphocytosis in the absence of infection, with an increase in blood&#xD;
                  absolute lymphocyte count (ALC) ≥50% over a 2-month period or lymphocyte doubling&#xD;
                  time of &lt;6 months (as long as initial ALC was ≥30,000/L), or&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Autoimmune anemia and/or thrombocytopenia that is poorly responsive to&#xD;
                  corticosteroids or other standard therapy, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Constitutional symptoms, defined as any one or more of the following&#xD;
                  disease-related symptoms or signs occurring in the absence of evidence of&#xD;
                  infection:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Unintentional weight loss of ≥10% within the previous 6 months, or&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. Significant fatigue (≥Grade 2), or&#xD;
&#xD;
             iii. Fevers &gt;100.5°F or 38.0°C for ≥2 weeks, or&#xD;
&#xD;
             iv. Drenching night sweats for &gt;1 month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Adequate organ system function, defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 0.5x109/L and platelet count ≥ 30x109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Total bilirubin ≤2.5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) unless due to&#xD;
                  Gilbert's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤2.5 x ULN if&#xD;
                  no liver involvement or ≤5 x the ULN if known liver involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Calculated creatinine clearance &gt;30 mL/min (as calculated by the Cockcroft-Gault&#xD;
                  formula)&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patients with PT/INR or aPTT ≤2xULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG performance status ≤ 2 unless related to CLL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Male or female ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ability to swallow and retain oral medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP) who are sexually active must use highly&#xD;
             effective methods of contraception during treatment and for 2 days after the last dose&#xD;
             of acalabrutinib and for 12 months following last dose of rituximab. (see Appendix 3&#xD;
             for examples)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Willingness and ability to comply with study and follow-up procedures, and give&#xD;
             written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients receiving cancer therapy (i.e., chemotherapy, radiation therapy,&#xD;
             immunotherapy, biologic therapy, hormonal therapy, surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Systemic corticosteroid therapy started prior to study entry is allowed as&#xD;
             clinically warranted. Topical or inhaled corticosteroids are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Serologic status reflecting active hepatitis B or C infection. Patients who are&#xD;
             hepatitis B core antibody (anti-HBc) positive and who are surface antigen negative&#xD;
             will need to have a negative polymerase chain reaction (PCR). Those who are hepatitis&#xD;
             B surface antigen (HbsAg) positive or hepatitis B PCR positive will be excluded.&#xD;
             Subjects who are hepatitis C antibody positive will need to have a negative PCR&#xD;
             result. Those who are hepatitis C PCR positive will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known history of HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known histological transformation from CLL to an aggressive lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Evidence of ongoing systemic bacterial, fungal or viral infection, except localized&#xD;
             fungal infections of skin or nails. NOTE: Patients may be receiving prophylactic&#xD;
             antiviral or antibacterial therapies at investigator discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Live virus vaccines within 4 weeks prior to C1D1 or during rituximab therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of anaphylaxis (excluding infusion related reactions) in association with&#xD;
             previous anti-CD20 administration or acalabrutinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions or other conditions that could&#xD;
             affect their participation in the study such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Symptomatic, or history of documented congestive heart failure (NY Heart&#xD;
                  Association functional classification III-IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia (Patients with controlled atrial&#xD;
                  fibrillation/flutter are eligible)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Myocardial infarction within 3 months of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Angina not well-controlled by medication&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Poorly controlled or clinically significant atherosclerotic vascular disease&#xD;
                  including cerebrovascular accident (CVA), transient ischemic attack (TIA),&#xD;
                  angioplasty, cardiac/vascular stenting within 3 months of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Active bleeding or history of bleeding diathesis (eg, hemophilia or von&#xD;
                  Willebrand disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Any history of intracranial bleed or stroke within 6 months of first dose of&#xD;
                  study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Patients with suspected or confirmed PML&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Patients with malabsorption syndrome or gastrointestinal disease that limits&#xD;
                  absorption of oral medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Malignancy within 2 years of study enrollment except for adequately treated basal,&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma or non-melanomatous skin cancer, carcinoma in situ of the&#xD;
             cervix, superficial bladder cancer not treated with intravesical chemotherapy or BCG&#xD;
             within 6 months, localized prostate cancer and PSA &lt;1.0 mg/dL on 2 consecutive&#xD;
             measurements at least 3 months apart with the most recent one being within 4 weeks of&#xD;
             study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with active uncontrolled autoimmune hemolytic anemia or ITP.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Inability to discontinue use of strong CYP3A inhibitors. Patients taking moderate&#xD;
             CYP3A inhibitors or strong CYP3A inducers are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Requires or receiving anticoagulation with warfarin or equivalent vitamin K&#xD;
             antagonists (eg, phenprocoumon) within 7 days of first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Requires treatment with proton pump inhibitors (eg, omeprazole, esomeprazole,&#xD;
             lansoprazole, dexlansoprazole, rabeprazole, or pantoprazole) at study entry. Subjects&#xD;
             receiving proton pump inhibitors who switch to H2-receptor antagonists or antacids are&#xD;
             eligible for enrollment to this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul Barr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Rochester</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robin Boerman</last_name>
    <phone>585-273-1507</phone>
    <email>Robin_Boerman@URMC.Rochester.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14642</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrew Bui</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 24, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Rochester</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Paul Barr</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of the Clinical Trials Office for Wilmot Cancer Institute</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia (CLL)</keyword>
  <keyword>Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma (SLL)</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase II</keyword>
  <keyword>Acalabrutinib</keyword>
  <keyword>Rituximab</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acalabrutinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

