<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02961322</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9657</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02961322</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Medico-economic Study of the Lobo-isthmectomy Assisted Robot</brief_title>
  <acronym>LIRA</acronym>
  <official_title>Medico-economic Study of the Lobo-isthmectomy Assisted Robot</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Montpellier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Montpellier</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a study of health economics longitudinal cohort on the evaluation of direct medical&#xD;
      cost of a surgical technique based on the use of an innovative device (the da Vinci® surgical&#xD;
      robot Si) and its comprehensive care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Over 50,000 thyroidectomies are performed each year in France. The externally surgery&#xD;
      produces satisfactory results, but it nevertheless remains a risk of complications in the&#xD;
      order of 10 to 20%. Moreover, the patients operated by traditional externally have a&#xD;
      basi-cervical visible scar which is a major concern for many of them. The team of Montpellier&#xD;
      University Hospital is a pioneer in the use of the technique of endoscopic thyroidectomy&#xD;
      under robotic assistance that saves totally cervical scarring for patients, but also decrease&#xD;
      the rate of complications. This technique based on the use of the da Vinci robotic system if&#xD;
      justified, depending on the manufacturer and the scientific literature, with its minimally&#xD;
      invasive character, an amplitude of greater movement than the hand of man, and movements&#xD;
      called intuitive that reduce tremors instruments during the operation (Patel 2008). In France&#xD;
      and in Europe, there is a growing demand from patients and surgeons to access the surgical&#xD;
      technique. An assessment of the real and specific cost of this technique and its overall&#xD;
      management is essential in order to assess the financial impact of the introduction of this&#xD;
      surgery for our hospitals, or no data is available on this in Literature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this study is to describe the direct medical cost of the treatment of&#xD;
      thyroid Lobo-Isthmectomy Robot-Assisted (LIRA) with a follow-up 12 months. The secondary&#xD;
      objectives of this research are to determine the rate of laryngeal paralysis, the rate of&#xD;
      complications specific to access axillary robot, the size of the incision made for surgery,&#xD;
      the number of channel conversion transaxillary assisted robot traditional externally, to&#xD;
      assess the satisfaction of each patient over his scar, pain over time, the evolution of&#xD;
      potential disorders sensitivity of anterior chest wall, the vocal functional suites and&#xD;
      quality of life self-administered questionnaire (Voice handicap Index VHI 10 and Short Forme&#xD;
      SF-36), and finally to compare the cost of care by the robot with the average cost of a&#xD;
      conventional surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>January 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>direct medical cost</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Lobo-isthmectomy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lobo isthmectomy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>lobo-isthmectomy assisted robot</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>lobo isthmectomy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient candidate for thyroid lobectomy or lobo-isthmectomy for benign nodular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  normal laryngeal mobility (clinical evaluation by an ENT (Ear-Nose-Throat) Doctor)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  breast cancer absence being supported&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No suspected thyroid cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nodules size &lt;6cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirm Benin character nodules by fine needle biopsy made within 6 months prior to&#xD;
             patient inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient available for post-operative follow-up of 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient participating or having participated in another interventional study in the&#xD;
             previous 3 months or exclusion period determined by a previous study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under guardianship or trusteeship or under judicial protection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to give informed patient information&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women, breastfeeding or parturient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications (or incompatible combination therapy) for a necessary treatment in&#xD;
             this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication to general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergencies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast Cancer being supported&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  treatment or surgical sentinel node of the planned breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  thyroid nodule ranked in the ultrasound TIRADS 5 (Thyroid image reporting and data&#xD;
             system)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fine needle aspiration biopsy with BETHESDA score result 5 and 6&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plunging Nodule&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Cesar CARTIER, MD</last_name>
    <phone>467 336 897</phone>
    <phone_ext>33</phone_ext>
    <email>c-cartier@chu-montpellier.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 8, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 8, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 10, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 10, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

