<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02965222</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WY710628</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02965222</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study Select Top-grade Embryo by Time-lapse Imaging</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study Select Top-grade Embryo by Time-lapse Imaging</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shanghai First Maternity and Infant Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shanghai First Maternity and Infant Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To establish embryo time-difference kinetics scoring model for embryo selection before embryo&#xD;
      transfer. It is especially suitable for selective single embryo transfer, advanced infertile&#xD;
      women, and patients with repeated transplant failure. It can effectively improve clinical&#xD;
      pregnancy rate, improve embryo implantation rate and Rate of return home. Reduce the risk of&#xD;
      multiple pregnancies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. BACKGROUND:&#xD;
&#xD;
           At present, embryo selection in embryonic laboratories at various reproductive centers&#xD;
           continues to follow conventional morphological assessments based on the time period&#xD;
           provided by the 2016 Expert Consensus Guidelines for Laboratory Operations (revised from&#xD;
           the Istanbul consensus) (discussion board), after insemination of the 1th-6th day&#xD;
           (except the 4th day) to observe the specific time points of embryonic morphology, static&#xD;
           observation, score, select the embryo. This method of observation of embryonic&#xD;
           development is not comprehensive enough, and the lack of quantifiable recognized&#xD;
           indicators .&#xD;
&#xD;
           EmbryoScope Time-lapse culture system is the latest development of human assisted&#xD;
           reproductive embryo from fertilization to blastocyst development. The time-lapse imaging&#xD;
           system (TLI) is used to record the embryonic development process from fertilization to&#xD;
           blastocyst formation. The timing of change plays a key role in the developmental&#xD;
           potential of the embryo, such as the time of emergence and disappearance of pronucleus,&#xD;
           the time of early cleavage, cleavage pattern and so on. At present, the latest 2016&#xD;
           Laboratory Operation Expert Consensus Guide (discussion board) provides a grading&#xD;
           standard that does not objectively reflect specific information on morphological&#xD;
           changes, such as cleavage patterns, the specific time of morphological changes, and so&#xD;
           on for embryonic development and post- Determine the fate of embryos play a vital role.&#xD;
           Due to the clinical diagnosis and treatment of the center of the standard, laboratory&#xD;
           culture system, and the difference between the laboratory standard operation&#xD;
           procedure,and embryonic development speed differences. Therefore, it is desirable to use&#xD;
           the EmbryoScope Time-lapse culture system to find out the best timing of morphological&#xD;
           changes of embryos in accordance with the laboratory culture system on the basis of the&#xD;
           expert consensus time period. To establish an evaluation model of embryo morphology&#xD;
           kinetics suitable for our laboratory. Embryology time-of-flight monitoring Morphological&#xD;
           kinetics evaluation model is suitable for patients with in vitro fertilization/&#xD;
           intracytoplasmic sperm injection , especially for infertile women in assisted&#xD;
           reproduction, women with repeated transplantation failure, women with fertility&#xD;
           disorders requiring egg activation, Single embryo transfer of patients, effectively&#xD;
           avoid multiple pregnancy, reduce the risk of multiple pregnancy. Selection of embryos&#xD;
           with developmental potential for transplantation, improve embryo quality, improve the&#xD;
           accuracy of embryo selection, contribute to successful pregnancy. But also can alleviate&#xD;
           this part of the patient's mental stress, but also contribute to successful pregnancy.&#xD;
           At the same time, for laboratory embryologists to provide more data reference, more&#xD;
           human embryonic development information.&#xD;
&#xD;
           At present, several large-scale centers are undergoing their own embryo laboratory&#xD;
           kinetics of the scoring model. Shanshan Wang et al suggested that the cleavage pattern&#xD;
           of embryos and time parameters combined to establish a new embryo screening model for&#xD;
           single embryo transfer embryo, to obtain an ideal pregnancy outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
           EmbryoScope Time-lapse culture system and embryo selection, compared to the traditional&#xD;
           culture system and the static morphology of the embryo selection, EmbryoScope Timelapse&#xD;
           selection of transplanted embryos, the clinical pregnancy rate [3], EmbryoScope&#xD;
           Time-lapse culture system, Significantly improved. The literature of N. Basile and P.&#xD;
           Vime [4] suggests that blastocyst culture [10] plus the choice of embryo morphology&#xD;
           kinetics may be the best treatment for improving clinical outcomes. Studies have been&#xD;
           reported , time difference imaging system does not interfere with embryonic culture&#xD;
           conditions in the case of interval 20 min, 5 min or 1 min to shoot images, and continued&#xD;
           to the first 3 days or 5 days. In addition, the TLI image acquisition system can exclude&#xD;
           some of the abnormal cleaved embryos that are considered to have &quot;normal&quot; developmental&#xD;
           potential in static assessment. A number of studies have shown that the TLI culture&#xD;
           system combined with the morphological scoring method to select the embryos obtained&#xD;
           after transplantation compared with the purely morphological method of the choice of&#xD;
           static embryos can be more satisfactory to patients with pregnancy outcomes .&#xD;
&#xD;
           In this study, we compared the clinical outcomes of patients with two different culture&#xD;
           routes, analyzed the advantages of TLI combined with morphological scoring methods, and&#xD;
           established the model of embryonic time difference morphology kinetics in our&#xD;
           laboratory. The aim of this study was to prospectively select embryos for selective&#xD;
           single embryo transfer, advanced infertility women and patients with repeated graft&#xD;
           failure to improve the clinical pregnancy rate and reduce the occurrence of multiple&#xD;
           births.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Trial design:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Samples were selected according to the inclusion criteria, and groups A and B were&#xD;
           grouped according to the random number table, with 40-50 patients in each group. The&#xD;
           random number table is attached. In order to avoid the withdrawal of patients or other&#xD;
           reasons not suitable for inclusion in the trial, the researchers increased the sample&#xD;
           size, the random number table increased to 150. A group of patients with oocytes&#xD;
           injecting human chorionic gonadotrophin (HCG) 38-40 hours intracytoplasmic sperm&#xD;
           injection (ICSI), and then into the ordinary three-gas incubator, conventional&#xD;
           fertilization 4hours ,the demolition of eggs into the ordinary three-chamber, after&#xD;
           insemination .The embryos were evaluated and selected by the current morphological&#xD;
           scoring method. The oocytes of Group B were taken ICSI after infecting HCG 38-40 hours .&#xD;
           And then be placed in the Time-Lapse. The ovaries were placed in the Time-Lapse after&#xD;
           4Hhours fertilization, and the embryos were evaluated by time-lapse imaging (TLI). The&#xD;
           cleavage pattern and time parameters for marker embryo development were recorded daily&#xD;
           after insemination. (1) The rate of high-quality embryos (cleavage and blastocyst&#xD;
           stage), clinical pregnancy rate and embryo implantation rate in group A and group B; (2)&#xD;
           The cleavage pattern and time parameters of embryo in group B were analyzed&#xD;
           retrospectively, And the quality of blastocysts were analyzed. Logistic regression&#xD;
           analysis was used to establish the criteria of embryo selection.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (Age&gt; 38 years), patients with recurrent graft failure (number of cycles ≥ 3), the&#xD;
           development of embryos in this part of the patients were observed by TLI.Results: (1)&#xD;
           Embryonic development , Select high-quality embryos for transplantation, observation of&#xD;
           pregnancy outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Statistical methods: The data were expressed as mean ± standard deviation (x ± s) or&#xD;
           rate (%), and the data were analyzed by Statistical Package for the Social Sciences 23.0&#xD;
           software. The quartile method was used to classify the time parameters, and the&#xD;
           advantage period of each parameter was calculated with the outcome of pregnancy and high&#xD;
           quality blastocyst formation. Logistic regression analysis of clinical variables&#xD;
           (cleavage patterns and time parameters) and the relationship between high-quality&#xD;
           blastocysts, the rate of each group were compared using χ 2 test, P &lt;0.05 for the&#xD;
           difference was statistically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Quality control and quality assurance Patients will managed by the listed investigators&#xD;
           who have adequate experience in managing assisted reproduction treatments.A Trial&#xD;
           steering committee will be formed which will oversee the conduct of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Data Handing and record keeping All data will be stored for three years. A desighnted&#xD;
           research nurse will be responsible for data management including data coding,monitoring&#xD;
           and verification.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>December 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>live birth rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>numer of live birth per transfer cycle</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>implantation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Top-grade Embryo</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After injecting HCG 38- 40 hours , the patient's oocytes will be taken with ICSI , then placed in the Time-Lapse. The oocytes will be IVF after 4 hours and will be stripped surrounding cumulus cell ,then will be placed in the Time-Lapse.The third day the top-grade embryo will be selected by time-lapse imaging (TLI) . The cleavage pattern and time parameters for marker embryo development were recorded daily after insemination.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The development of the embryos at time-lapse was recorded directly and was not disturbed by temperature changes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>the time-lapse videography</intervention_name>
    <description>The all oocytes will be placed in the Time-Lapes .The third day the top-grade embryo will be selected by time-lapse imaging (TLI) .</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. women under 38 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ≤2th cycle&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. transplantation cycle&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. women with abnormal oocytes in the past(≥30%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. women with other systemic diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. women with abnormal uterine cavity shown on hysterosalpingogram or saline infusion&#xD;
             sonogram&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>38 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yu Wang, Master</last_name>
    <phone>86-20261423</phone>
    <phone_ext>2014</phone_ext>
    <email>wangyutea7121@sina.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Xiao Ming Teng, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>86-20261156</phone>
    <phone_ext>2014</phone_ext>
    <email>tengxiaoming@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shanghai first Maternity and Infant health hospital, Tong Ji University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <zip>201204</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Basile N, Vime P, Florensa M, Aparicio Ruiz B, García Velasco JA, Remohí J, Meseguer M. The use of morphokinetics as a predictor of implantation: a multicentric study to define and validate an algorithm for embryo selection. Hum Reprod. 2015 Feb;30(2):276-83. doi: 10.1093/humrep/deu331. Epub 2014 Dec 19.</citation>
    <PMID>25527613</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rubio I, Galán A, Larreategui Z, Ayerdi F, Bellver J, Herrero J, Meseguer M. Clinical validation of embryo culture and selection by morphokinetic analysis: a randomized, controlled trial of the EmbryoScope. Fertil Steril. 2014 Nov;102(5):1287-1294.e5. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2014.07.738. Epub 2014 Sep 11.</citation>
    <PMID>25217875</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Payne D, Flaherty SP, Barry MF, Matthews CD. Preliminary observations on polar body extrusion and pronuclear formation in human oocytes using time-lapse video cinematography. Hum Reprod. 1997 Mar;12(3):532-41.</citation>
    <PMID>9130755</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 9, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 11, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 16, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 16, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>blastocyst</keyword>
  <keyword>pregnancy rate</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

