<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02212431</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3/001/14</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-000284-40</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02212431</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>First Study of Oral Cysteamine in Cystic Fibrosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label Investigation of the Tolerability and Pharmacokinetics of Oral Cysteamine in Adults With Cystic Fibrosis.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Aberdeen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cystic Fibrosis Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>NHS Grampian</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Huddersfield</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Aberdeen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The morbidity and mortality associated with Cystic Fibrosis (CF) are the result of chronic&#xD;
      suppurative lung disease. The aggressive use of antibiotics is one of the mainstays of&#xD;
      treatment in CF, however, the problems of multiple drug resistance and adverse reactions are&#xD;
      major clinical issues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cysteamine is a licensed drug used in the treatment of cystinosis. In vitro work suggests&#xD;
      that cysteamine has properties of potential benefit in CF. Cysteamine is a potent mucolytic,&#xD;
      it disrupts biofilms, it is antimicrobial, and synergises with other antibiotic agents. CF is&#xD;
      characterised by malabsorption and it is not known whether cysteamine is absorbed in CF,&#xD;
      furthermore it is not known if cysteamine enters the bronchial secretions. It is not possible&#xD;
      to assume that the pharmacokinetics of cysteamine in patients with CF are the same as those&#xD;
      reported for cystinosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: to characterise the pharmacokinetic profile of cysteamine in people with CF, to&#xD;
      ascertain whether cysteamine enters the bronchial secretions and the tolerability of&#xD;
      cysteamine by patients with CF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: a single centre, single group open label investigation of the tolerability and&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics of oral cysteamine (Cystagon) when administered to patients with Cystic&#xD;
      Fibrosis at the dose licensed for use in cystinosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting: adult CF clinic, Aberdeen Royal Infirmary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Target population: 12 patients aged ≥18years with CF associated lung disease who are&#xD;
      clinically stable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: Oral cysteamine (Cystagon) will be increased from 450mg od to 450mg qds over&#xD;
      three weeks, they will remain on 450mg qds for two weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment: face to face health outcome assessments will be carried out for all participants&#xD;
      at recruitment/baseline, 1, 2, 3, and 5 and 6 weeks. Serial blood cysteamine levels will be&#xD;
      measured in the first 24 hours after the first dose. Sputum cysteamine will be quantified&#xD;
      after two weeks of full dose cysteamine 450mg qds. Disease specific health status (CFQ-R)&#xD;
      will be assessed at baseline and after two weeks of full dose. At each assessment, lung&#xD;
      function (FEV1, FVC), adverse reactions and serious adverse events will be ascertained. Blood&#xD;
      samples will be taken for measurement of haematological and biochemical parameters. Sputum&#xD;
      samples at each assessment will be analysed for microbial load and spinnbarkeit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cystic Fibrosis (CF) is the commonest fatal inherited disease in Caucasian populations of&#xD;
      European origin. The morbidity and mortality associated with CF are the result of chronic&#xD;
      suppurative lung disease. The lungs of people with CF are chronically infected with bacteria&#xD;
      that cause chronic infection and acute periods of worsening infection known as exacerbations.&#xD;
      Many of the bacteria that infect patients with CF are intrinsically resistant to many&#xD;
      antibiotics and bacterial antibiotic resistance is increasing, in addition many of the&#xD;
      pathogenic bacteria grow in biofilms that contributes to antibiotic resistance. The&#xD;
      aggressive use of antibiotics to suppress chronic infection and to treat acute exacerbations&#xD;
      is one of the mainstays of treatment in CF that has contributed to the increased survival of&#xD;
      CF patients. However, the problems of multiple drug resistance and adverse reactions are&#xD;
      major clinical issues. This has led to calls for research into new antibiotics and new&#xD;
      antibiotic strategies to target the biofilm and to increase the effectiveness of currently&#xD;
      available antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cysteamine is a licensed drug used in the treatment of cystinosis for more than 20 years.&#xD;
      Laboratory based work suggests that cysteamine may be a beneficial adjunct to conventional&#xD;
      antibiotic treatment in CF. Cysteamine is a potent mucolytic, it disrupts biofilms, it is&#xD;
      antimicrobial, and synergises with other antibiotic agents, broadening their spectrum of&#xD;
      activity, delivers a post-antimicrobial effect and reverses antibiotic resistance (even in&#xD;
      multi-drug resistant bacteria). Although the pharmacokinetic characteristics of cysteamine&#xD;
      are well established in people with cystinosis, there are no such data for cysteamine in CF.&#xD;
      CF is characterised by malabsorption and it is not known whether cysteamine is absorbed in&#xD;
      CF, furthermore it is not known if cysteamine enters the bronchial secretions. It is not&#xD;
      possible to assume that the pharmacokinetics of cysteamine in patients with CF are the same&#xD;
      as those reported for cystinosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Oral cysteamine will be absorbed into the vascular space and bronchial secretions&#xD;
      after administration to people with Cystic Fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: to characterise the pharmacokinetic profile of cysteamine in people with CF, to&#xD;
      ascertain whether cysteamine enters the bronchial secretions and the tolerability of&#xD;
      cysteamine by patients with CF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: a single centre, single group open label investigation of the tolerability and&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics of oral cysteamine (Cystagon) when administered to patients with Cystic&#xD;
      Fibrosis at the dose licensed for use in cystinosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting: adult CF clinic, Aberdeen Royal Infirmary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Target population: 12 patients aged ≥18years with CF associated lung disease who are&#xD;
      clinically stable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: as recommended for cystinosis, patients will be maintained on their normal CF&#xD;
      medication. Oral cysteamine (Cystagon) will be increased from 450mg od to 450mg qds over&#xD;
      three weeks, they will remain on 450mg qds for two weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment: face to face health outcome assessments will be carried out for all participants&#xD;
      at recruitment/baseline, 1, 2, 3, and 5 and 6 weeks. Serial blood cysteamine levels will be&#xD;
      measured in the first 24 hours after the first dose. Sputum cysteamine will be quantified&#xD;
      after two weeks of full dose cysteamine 450mg qds. Disease specific health status (CFQ-R)&#xD;
      will be assessed at baseline and after two weeks of full dose. At each assessment, lung&#xD;
      function (FEV1, FVC), adverse reactions and serious adverse events will be ascertained. Blood&#xD;
      samples will be taken for measurement of haematological and biochemical parameters that are&#xD;
      recognised, but rare side effects of cysteamine. Sputum samples at each assessment will be&#xD;
      analysed microbiologically (quantitative, antibiotic sensitivity and rheology) to assess&#xD;
      effects of cysteamine on sputum microbiology, sputum collected prior to first dosing will be&#xD;
      used to develop a laboratory based method to quantify cysteamine in sputum.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination rate constant [k]</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Blood cysteamine prior to the initial dose on day 1 and 0.5, 1, 1.5, 2, 2.5, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, and 24 hours post-dose</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of cysteamine in sputum at week 5</measure>
    <time_frame>3 hours after final dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in weight from baseline at week 5</measure>
    <time_frame>5 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Serious and Non-Serious Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in FEV1, FVC from baseline at week 5</measure>
    <time_frame>5 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in disease related health status from baseline at week 5 measured by CFQ-R</measure>
    <time_frame>5 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in haematological and biochemical indices from baseline at week 5</measure>
    <time_frame>5 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>change in sputum microbiology from baseline at week 5</measure>
    <time_frame>5 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Cystic Fibrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cysteamine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dosing will be in accordance with licensed use of cysteamine for cystinosis, i.e. 450mg qds.&#xD;
Dose will be escalated:&#xD;
450mg od for one week 450mg bd for one week 450mg tds for one week 450mg qds for two weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cysteamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose will be increased weekly from 450mg od to 450mg bd, to 450mg tds to 450mg qds, will remain on highest dose for 2 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cysteamine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cystagon 150mg capsules</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CF related suppurative lung disease who expectorate sputum,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically stable for &gt;4 weeks,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged ≥18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight &gt;50kg,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants of child bearing potential should be using a reliable form of&#xD;
             contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to the active substance, any form of cysteamine, or to any of the&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitivity to penicillamine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lung, liver transplant, on active transplant list.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women, current pregnancy or breast-feeding, or planned pregnancy during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other significant disease/disorder which, in the investigator's opinion, either&#xD;
             puts the patient at risk because of study participation or may influence the results&#xD;
             of the study or the patient's ability to participate in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Graham Devereux, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Aberdeen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aberdeen Royal Infirmary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aberdeen</city>
        <zip>AB25 2ZN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 7, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 8, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 5, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cystic Fibrosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Cysteamine</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cystic Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cysteamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

