<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04246671</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAEK-VAC-HerBy-001 Phase 1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04246671</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intravenous TAEK-VAC-HerBy Vaccine Alone and in Combination Treatment in HER2 Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1/2 Expansion Cohorts Trial of Intravenous Administration of TAEK-VAC-HerBy Vaccine Alone and in Combination With HER2- and PD-1/PD-L1 Antibodies in Patients With Advanced HER2-expressing Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bavarian Nordic</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bavarian Nordic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Phase 1/2 open label trial of intravenous administration of TAEK-VAC-HerBy vaccine in&#xD;
      patients with advanced HER2- expressing cancer. The study will be completed in 3 stages. In&#xD;
      Stage 1 patients will be enrolled and treated according to a 3+3 dose escalation scheme. Up&#xD;
      to 4 dose levels will be explored. Stage 2 will enroll patients with HER2- positive breast&#xD;
      and gastric cancer to administer the TAEK-VAC-HerBy vaccine in combination with HER2&#xD;
      antibodies. Stage 3 will enroll patients to evaluate the safety and tolerability of the&#xD;
      TAEK-VAC-HerBy vaccine in combination with HER2 antibodies and PD-1/PD-L1 antibody. Patients,&#xD;
      in all three stages, will receive TAEK-VAC-HerBy every three weeks, three administrations in&#xD;
      total.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients with Dose Limiting Toxicity (DLT)</measure>
    <time_frame>DLT evaluation period is 30 days after the last vaccine dose</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of patients with DLTs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Gastric Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Chordoma</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Merkel Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Small-cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^7 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total at the dose level 1x10^7 Inf.U.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^8 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total at the dose level 1x10^8 Inf.U.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^9 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total at the dose level 1x10^9 Inf.U.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^10 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total at the dose level 1x10^10 Inf.U.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (Trastuzumab + TVH)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered to patients who are on stable dose of Trastuzumab. TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (T-DM1 + TVH)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered to patients who are on stable dose of T-DM1. TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (Trastuzumab + Pertuzumab + TVH)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously to patients who are on stable dose of Trastuzumab and Pertuzumab. TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered every three weeks with three administrations in total.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (Her2 + TVH + PD1/PD-L1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total in combination with a HER2 antibody and a PD-1/PD-L1 Antibody.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TAEK-VAC-HerBy</intervention_name>
    <description>TAEK-VAC-HerBy will be administered intravenously every three weeks with three administrations in total at the dose indicated by the enrolled cohort. It may also be administered concurrently with a HER2 antibody or a checkpoint inhibitor depending on the trial stage.</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^10 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^7 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^8 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 1 (TVH 1x10^9 Inf.U)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (Her2 + TVH + PD1/PD-L1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (T-DM1 + TVH)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (Trastuzumab + Pertuzumab + TVH)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TAEK-VAC-HerBy Stage 2 - (Trastuzumab + TVH)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Men and women &gt; 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients must be able to understand and be willing to sign a written informed consent&#xD;
             document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willingness and ability to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan, laboratory&#xD;
             tests, and other trial procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must have a metastatic or recurrent locally advanced malignant tumor,&#xD;
             histologically documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must have completed or had disease progression on at least one prior line of&#xD;
             disease-appropriate therapy for locally advanced or metastatic disease, or not be&#xD;
             candidates for therapy of proven efficacy for their disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. ECOG performance status 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients must have normal organ and bone marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal function:&#xD;
&#xD;
             Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) OR creatinine clearance (CrCl) ≥&#xD;
             40 mL/min (if using the Cockcroft-Gault formula below): Female CrCl = [(140 - age in&#xD;
             years) x weight in kg x 0.85] / [72 x serum creatinine in mg/dL] Male CrCl = [(140 -&#xD;
             age in years) x weight in kg x 1.00] / [72 x serum creatinine in mg/dL] •Liver&#xD;
             function: Alanine Aminotransferase (ALT) and Aspartate Aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 3 x&#xD;
             the ULN. Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (in subjects with Gilbert's syndrome a total&#xD;
             bilirubin ≤ 3.0 x ULN), or &lt; 5 x ULN, if liver metastases are present.&#xD;
&#xD;
             •Hematological parameters (within one week of starting therapy):&#xD;
&#xD;
             •Hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
             •Platelet count ≥ 100,000/µL.&#xD;
&#xD;
             •Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1/µL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Normal left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Troponin I within normal limits.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. A maximum cumulative dose of prior doxorubicin ≤ 360 mg/m2 or epirubicin ≤ 720 mg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any prior chemotherapy, targeted therapy, immunotherapy and/or radiation must be&#xD;
             completed at least 4 weeks prior to the first planned dose of TVH vaccine, with the&#xD;
             following exceptions, assuming any toxicity related to these therapies is well&#xD;
             controlled or resolved and the patient has been on that therapy for at least 8 weeks&#xD;
             at the time of enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breast cancer - patients may remain on hormonal therapy if indicated (Estrogen&#xD;
                  Receptor/Progesterone Receptor positive [ER/PR+]).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients must have recovered (Grade 1 or baseline) from any clinically significant&#xD;
             toxicity associated with prior therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Women of child-bearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy&#xD;
             test within 24 hours prior to administration of TVH vaccine or HER2-targeting&#xD;
             antibodies. Both men and women must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or&#xD;
             barrier method of birth control; abstinence) through the trial treatment period and&#xD;
             for at least 3 months after the last vaccination therapy for TAEK-VAC-HerBy&#xD;
             monotherapy (Stage 1) and 7 months for combination treatment arms (Stage 2 and 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
             ADDITIONAL INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR STAGE 1 ONLY&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient population:&#xD;
&#xD;
             •Patients with metastatic cancer with a high probability of brachyury expression (such&#xD;
             as lung, breast, ovarian, prostate, colorectal, pancreatic, hepatocellular, Merkel&#xD;
             cell, small cell lung cancer or chordoma; other tumors may be included as data on the&#xD;
             level of brachyury in those tumors becomes available) and have progressed on at least&#xD;
             two lines of systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             •Patients with unresectable locally advanced and metastatic breast and&#xD;
             gastric/gastroesophageal junction cancer expressing HER2 at levels lower than the&#xD;
             threshold required for definition of HER-2 positivity by ASCO/CAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other unresectable locally advanced or metastatic cancers (such as ovarian,&#xD;
                  bladder, salivary gland, endometrial, pancreatic and non-small-cell lung cancer&#xD;
                  NSCLC, etc) with HER2 amplification by adjusted fold change detected by NGS, FISH&#xD;
                  detected HER2/CEP17 ≥2, or any level of HER2 detected by IHC are acceptable since&#xD;
                  no HER2 targeted therapy is FDA-approved for those indications. Patients that are&#xD;
                  enrolled with tumors having HER2 expression below the threshold required for&#xD;
                  definition of HER2 positivity by ASCO/CAP must have progressed on at least two&#xD;
                  lines of systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with breast and gastric HER2- positive tumors as per ASCO/CAP must have&#xD;
                  progressed after receipt of all therapies known to confer clinical benefit:&#xD;
                  oBreast: trastuzumab, pertuzumab, T-DM1. These patients may have also received&#xD;
                  tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKI) such as lapatinib or neratinib as well as&#xD;
                  different lines of chemotherapy. oGastric and gastroesophageal junction cancer:&#xD;
                  at the time of progression after trastuzumab in combination with chemotherapy as&#xD;
                  first line therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients must have measurable or evaluable disease. Measurable disease is defined by&#xD;
             RECIST 1.1. In the case of evaluable disease, patients should have cancer-related&#xD;
             symptoms to justify risk. Evaluable disease is defined as any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Elevated serum tumor marker known to be related to the patient's tumor burden.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clear radiographic or physical exam evidence of tumor which does not meet RECIST&#xD;
                  1.1 measurability criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        ADDITIONAL INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR STAGES 2 AND 3&#xD;
&#xD;
        14. Patients must have measurable disease by computed tomography (CT)/ magnetic resonance&#xD;
        imaging (MRI) per RECIST 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
        15. Patient population:&#xD;
&#xD;
        •Cohort 2 will include patients with HER2-positive tumors (breast, gastric).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohorts 3 and 4 will include only patients with metastatic HER2-positive breast&#xD;
             cancer: oCohort 3 will include patients with less than CR to T-DM1 treatment (SD, PR)&#xD;
             or patients at the first evidence of progression while on T-DM1 treatment and before&#xD;
             initiating an alternative systemic treatment oCohort 4 will include patients on&#xD;
             treatment with trastuzumab plus pertuzumab with less than CR (PR or SD) or as a window&#xD;
             of opportunity at the first evidence of progression and before initiating the next&#xD;
             line of standard treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 5 will include patients with treatment combination used for a cohort of Stage 2&#xD;
             which completed recruitment first (or a subgroup of 6 patients within the Cohort 2: 2a&#xD;
             (breast) or 2b (gastric). The cohort needs to satisfy criteria listed above.&#xD;
&#xD;
             16. HER2 status must be determined as defined by the most recent ASCO/CAP guidelines&#xD;
             for breast and gastric/gastroesophageal cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
             17. For Cohort 2, 3 and 4, patients must be on a stable dose of HER2 antibody(ies).&#xD;
             Patient is defined to be on a stable dose of HER2 antibody(ies) if they have completed&#xD;
             the chemotherapy component of regimens consisting on the combination of chemotherapy&#xD;
             with HER2-targeting antibodies and have continued with the antibody for a minimum of 2&#xD;
             months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        ADDITIONAL INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR STAGE 3&#xD;
&#xD;
        18. Availability of formalin fixed paraffin embedded (FFPE) tumor sample (consecutive 10 x&#xD;
        4µm sections, not older than 3 years) for PD-L1 expression determination. Result&#xD;
        availability is not mandatory for patient inclusion into the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        19. Patients must be immune check-point inhibitor treatment naïve.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Receipt of an investigational agent within 28 days of the first planned dose of TVH&#xD;
             vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Concurrent chemotherapy or radiotherapy or other immunotherapy not explicitly allowed&#xD;
             by inclusion criteria for that stage of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. During the Stage 2 and 3, patients with history of other malignancies within last 5&#xD;
             years with an estimated risk of recurrence higher than 50% are excluded. Examples of&#xD;
             low risk of recurrence malignancies are non-melanoma skin cancer, in situ cervical,&#xD;
             superficial bladder cancer, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Known metastatic disease to the central nervous system, unless previously treated and&#xD;
             responded with a minimum stable disease over 2 CT scans separated at least 4 weeks&#xD;
             from each other, and more than 6 weeks since the last dose of dexamethasone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of allergy or untoward reaction to prior vaccination with vaccinia virus,&#xD;
             aminoglycoside antibiotics, ciprofloxacin, or egg products.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active infection within 72 hours prior to vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Administration of antibiotics within 7 days prior to initial vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects should have no known evidence of being immunocompromised as listed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positivity, chronic hepatitis infection,&#xD;
                  including B and C&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active, known or suspected autoimmune disease. Subjects with vitiligo, type I&#xD;
                  diabetes mellitus, residual hypothyroidism due to autoimmune condition only&#xD;
                  requiring hormone replacement, and psoriasis not requiring systemic treatment are&#xD;
                  permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunosuppressive therapy, post-organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Chronic administration (defined as &gt; 5 consecutive days of &gt; 15 mg of prednisone (or&#xD;
             equivalent) per day) of systemic corticosteroids within 14 days of the first planned&#xD;
             dose of TAEK-VAC-HerBy vaccine. Use of inhaled steroids, nasal sprays, eye drops, and&#xD;
             topical creams is allowed. Steroids premedication for CT scans is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Vaccinations or planned vaccinations with a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the&#xD;
             trial vaccination or with an inactivated vaccine within 14 days prior to the trial&#xD;
             vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Clinically significant cardiomyopathy, coronary disease, congestive heart failure&#xD;
             (NYHA class III or IV) or reduced as per institutional standards LVEF, poorly&#xD;
             controlled hypertension (systolic &gt; 180 mm Hg or diastolic &gt; 100 mm Hg) or&#xD;
             cerebrovascular accident within 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known history of, or any evidence of active, non-infectious pneumonitis or primary&#xD;
             pulmonary fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Any other condition, which in the opinion of the Investigator, would indicate the&#xD;
             subject is a poor candidate for treatment with TVH vaccine or would interfere with the&#xD;
             evaluation of the trial endpoints.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mary (Nora) L Disis, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington Medicine Seattle</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tatiana Adams, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+49 172 840 04 36</phone>
    <email>info@bavarian-nordic.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic - Phoenix, Arizona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85259</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocancerclinicalstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mohamad Sonbol</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic - Jacksonville, Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocancerclinicalstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Saranya Chumsri</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aiana Cerezo, BS</last_name>
      <phone>813-745-6985</phone>
      <email>aiana.cerezo@moffitt.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ricardo Costa</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Georgia Cancer Center August University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Augusta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30912</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Latasha McKie</last_name>
      <phone>706-721-4249</phone>
      <email>LGOMILLIONMCKIE@augusta.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Priyanka Raval</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic - Rochester, Minnesota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocancerclinicalstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ciara O'Sullivan</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Providence Cancer Institute</last_name>
      <phone>503-215-2614</phone>
      <email>CanClinRsrchStudies@providence.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Page</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Washington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98195</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kris Kauno</last_name>
      <phone>206-543-3829</phone>
      <email>kkauno@uw.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mary (Nora) Disis</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 29, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brachyury</keyword>
  <keyword>HER2-expressing tumors</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Merkel Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chordoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

