<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04241965</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>325-201-00003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04241965</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Single-blind, Placebo-controlled, Outpatient Trial to Assess the Effects of Single Oral Tablet Dose of OPC-214870</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1b, Single-blind, Placebo-controlled, Adaptive Design, Outpatient Trial to Assess the Effects of Single Oral Tablet Doses of OPC-214870 on Photic-induced Paroxysmal Electroencephalogram Responses in Subjects Who Have Demonstrated Photoepileptiform Discharges on Electroencephalogram With or Without Seizures</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Otsuka Pharmaceutical Development &amp; Commercialization, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Otsuka Pharmaceutical Development &amp; Commercialization, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Despite availability of several antiepileptic drugs (AEDs), in one-third of patients,&#xD;
      epilepsy remains uncontrolled with AEDs. There is a need to develop new approaches to improve&#xD;
      the existing medications to relieve patients' epilepsy, and OPC-214870 is being studied for&#xD;
      this purpose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 18, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Standardized Photosensitivity Range (SPR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>OPC-214870 in comparison to placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Onset and duration of SPR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 days</time_frame>
    <description>OPC-214870 in comparison to placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose; up to 400 mg capsule; adaptive dosage determined by initial dosing from cohort 1.Potential for a matching placebo dose to be administered.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose; potential for a matching OPC-214870 dose to be administered.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OPC-214870</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet(s)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet(s)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female subjects between 18 and 64 years of age, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 40 kg/m^2, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a diagnosis and history of photoparoxysmal response on EEG.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be stable for 1 month prior to screening. Stable is defined as having no&#xD;
             change in concomitant therapy and no worsening in the opinion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects may be treatment-naïve to AEDs or currently treated with up to 3 AEDs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have a reproducible standardized photosensitivity range on EEG of at&#xD;
             least 3 points in at least 1 eye condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who agree to remain abstinent, or practice double-barrier forms of birth&#xD;
             control, from trial to screening through 90 days after the last dose of IMP, OR males&#xD;
             and females of non-childbearing potential who are documented as sterile (i.e. male&#xD;
             subjects who have undergone bilateral orchidectomy and female subjects who have&#xD;
             undergone bilateral oophorectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, or hysterectomy, or who&#xD;
             have been postmenopausal for at least 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of non-epileptic seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of status epilepticus in the past 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An active central nervous system (CNS) infection, demyelinating disease, degenerative&#xD;
             neurological disease, or any CNS disease deemed to be progressive during the course of&#xD;
             the trial that may confound the interpretation of the trial results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine drug screen for substance of abuse or upon check in to the trial site.&#xD;
             Benzodiazepines are excluded as a drug of abuse, but are allowed as rescue medication&#xD;
             or when part of subject's stable concomitant medication at enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of drug and/or alcohol abuse within 24 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumption of grapefruit, grapefruit juice, Seville oranges, or Seville orange juice&#xD;
             within 7 days prior to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consumption of more than 1 alcoholic drink within 24 hours prior to dosing. Food and&#xD;
             beverages containing methylxanthines (caffeinated coffee, caffeinated tea, caffeinated&#xD;
             soda, and chocolate) must remain stable throughout the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extreme physical activity within 24 hours before screening and visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are breast-feeding and/or who have a positive pregnancy test result prior&#xD;
             to receiving IMP&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject having taken an investigational drug within 30 days preceding screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of over-the-counter drugs, herbal medicines, or vitamin supplements within 14 days&#xD;
             or 5 half-lives, whichever is longer, prior to dosing and antibiotics within 30 days&#xD;
             prior to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who had neurosurgery in last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects on a ketogenic diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of significant sleep disorders, or any disorder or activity that causes sleep&#xD;
             deprivation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who work &quot;night shifts&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with uncontrolled sleep disorders; subjects should be on a stable dose of&#xD;
             sleep medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of, or current hepatitis or acquired immunodeficiency syndrome or carriers of&#xD;
             hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C antibodies (anti-HCV), and/or HIV&#xD;
             antibodies.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Otsuka Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>844-687-8522</phone>
    <email>OtsukaUS@druginfo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>For additional information regarding sites, contact 844-687-8522</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ormond Beach</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34174</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Anonymized Individual participant data (IPD) that underlie the results of this study will be shared with researchers to achieve aims pre-specified in a methodologically sound research proposal. Small studies with less than 25 participants are excluded from data sharing.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be available after marketing approval in global markets, or beginning 1-3 years following article publication. There is no end date to the availability of the data.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Otsuka will share data on an Otsuka-owned remotely accessible data sharing platform with Python and R analytical software. Research requests should be directed to clinicaltransparency@Otsuka-us.com</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://clinical-trials.otsuka.com</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

