<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03718767</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>190006</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>19-C-0006</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03718767</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nivolumab in Patients With IDH-Mutant Gliomas With and Without Hypermutator Phenotype</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial Evaluating Nivolumab In Patients With IDH-Mutant Gliomas With And Without Hypermutator Phenotype</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gliomas are the most common malignant brain tumors. Some have certain changes (mutations) in&#xD;
      the genes IDH1 or IDH2. If there are a high number of mutations in a tumor, it is called&#xD;
      hypermutator phenotype (HMP). The drug nivolumab helps the immune system fight cancer.&#xD;
      Researchers think it can be more effective in patients with IDH1 or IDH2 mutated gliomas with&#xD;
      HMP. They will test gliomas with and without HMP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To see if nivolumab stops tumor growth and prolongs the time that the tumor is controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults 18 years or older with IDH1 or IDH2 mutated gliomas&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heart, blood, and pregnancy tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Review of symptoms and activity levels&#xD;
&#xD;
      Brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI). Participants will lie in a cylinder that takes&#xD;
      pictures in a strong magnetic field.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tumor samples&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will get the study drug in 4-week cycles. They will get it through a small&#xD;
      plastic tube in a vein (IV) on days 1 and 15 of cycles 1-4. For cycles 5-16, they will get it&#xD;
      just on day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On days 1 and 15 of each cycle, participants will repeat some or all screening tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After cycle 16, participants will have 3 follow-up visits over 100 days. They will answer&#xD;
      health questions, have physical and neurological exams, and have blood tests. They may have a&#xD;
      brain MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants whose disease did not get worse but who finished the study drug within 1 year of&#xD;
      treatment may have imaging studies every 8 weeks for up to 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be called or emailed every 6 months with questions about their health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Glioma is the most common malignant brain tumor. Genes coding for isocitrate&#xD;
           dehydrogenases 1and 2 (IDH1 and IDH2), metabolic enzymes, are frequently mutated in&#xD;
           gliomas, particularly lower-grade gliomas (LGGs). IDH1/2 mutation causes a unique tumor&#xD;
           biology, including the accumulation of 2-hydroxyglutarate (2-HG), an oncometabolite,&#xD;
           which in turn causes genomic hypermethylation and tumorigenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  IDH-mutant LGGs undergo a slow but unremitting progression to higher grade&#xD;
           transformation (HT) and eventually become high grade gliomas (HGGs) with a significant&#xD;
           increase in the number of somatic mutations. A subset of patients with transformed HGGs&#xD;
           develop a hypermutator phenotype (HMP), possibly related, but not limited, to previous&#xD;
           treatment with alkylating agents and radiotherapy. The mechanisms of this clinical&#xD;
           phenomenon are not well understood, and no effective treatments are available for the&#xD;
           HMP HGGs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  High tumor mutation burden (TMB) is a characteristic finding in many of the transformed&#xD;
           tumors. Furthermore, this increased mutation burden, with commensurate increase in&#xD;
           neoantigen expression, may be correlated with a better response to immune checkpoint&#xD;
&#xD;
      inhibitor (ICPIs) treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nivolumab is a monoclonal antibody that binds to the PD1 receptor and blocks its&#xD;
           interaction with PD L1 and PD L2 and subsequently releasing PD 1 pathway mediated&#xD;
           inhibition of the immune response, including antitumor immune response.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The US Food and Drug Administration granted approval to nivolumab for the treatment of&#xD;
           unresectable or metastatic melanoma, advanced non-small cell lung cancer, renal cell&#xD;
           carcinoma, Hodgkin s lymphoma, recurrent or metastatic squamous cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
           head and neck, locally advanced or metastatic urothelial carcinoma, microsatellite&#xD;
           instability-high or mismatched repair deficient metastatic colorectal cancer and&#xD;
           hepatocellular carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The first randomized clinical trial in glioblastoma with nivolumab (CheckMate-143) was&#xD;
           completed in early 2017. Unfortunately, the study didn t meet its primary endpoint of&#xD;
           improved overall survival over bevacizumab monotherapy. The objective response rate&#xD;
           (ORR) was lower in nivolumab arm than bevacizumab arm. However, the response with&#xD;
           nivolumab was more durable. The safety profile of nivolumab was very consistent with&#xD;
           what has been observed in other tumor types.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVE:&lt;TAB&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
      -To determine the 6-month progression free survival rate in IDH-mutant gliomas patients with&#xD;
      and without HMP in responses to nivolumab treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ELIGIBILITY:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with glioma, confirmed by NCI Laboratory of Pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age greater than or equal to 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  KPS greater than or equal to 60%&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  IDH 1 or IDH 2 mutation confirmed by DNA sequencing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients must have TMB status performed at NIH&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Tumor tissue or slides should be available for molecular and immune profiling&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study is an open label phase II clinical trial of the immune checkpoint inhibitor,&#xD;
           nivolumab, in patients with HMP and NHMP IDH-mutant gliomas.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with HMP and NHMP will receive nivolumab at a standard dose of 240 mg&#xD;
           intravenously every 2 weeks for cycles 1-4, then doses of 480 mg every 4 weeks for&#xD;
           cycles 5-16. A maximum of 20 treatments will be given (16 cycles).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A maximum of 29 patients with IDH-mutant glioma with HMP (Cohort 1) and 46 patients with&#xD;
           NHMP (Cohort 2) will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A Simon's optimal two-stage design will be used to conduct the HMP arm and the NHMP arm&#xD;
           independently. For the HMP cohort, in stage I, a total number of 10 patients are&#xD;
           accrued. If 9 or more patients progress by 6 months, the cohort will be terminated&#xD;
           early; otherwise, additional 19 patients will be accrued in stage II, resulting in a&#xD;
           total sample size of 29. Among these 29 patients, if 6 or more patients are&#xD;
           progression-free at 6 months, we will claim that the treatment is promising for patients&#xD;
           with HMP IDH-mutant gliomas. For NHMP cohort, in stage I, a total number of 15 patients&#xD;
           are accrued. If 10 or more patients progress by 6 months, the cohort will be terminated&#xD;
           early; otherwise, additional 31 patients will be accrued in stage II, resulting in a&#xD;
           total sample size of 46. Among these 46 patients, if 19 or more patients are&#xD;
           progression-free at 6 months, we will claim that the treatment is patients with NHMP&#xD;
           IDH-mutant gliomas.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 27, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 27, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>6-month progression free survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients that do not have progressive disease after 6 months</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median amount of time subject survives after therapy and Proportion of patients that have progressive disease after 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months and death</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the 1-year progression free survival rate and overall survival in IDHmutant gliomas patients with and without HMP in response to nivolumab treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between neoantigen burden of tumor and proportion of subjects that survive after 6 and 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine whether the neoantigen burden in tumor prior to the treatment is correlated with treatment response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients that have improvement in quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Study Calendar -last collection of QOL questioner.</time_frame>
    <description>To longitudinally evaluate patient reported outcome measures using self-reported symptom severity and interference with daily activities using the MDASIBT.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">95</enrollment>
  <condition>Glioma</condition>
  <condition>Glioblastoma</condition>
  <condition>High Grage Glioma</condition>
  <condition>Low Grade Glioma</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1/Nivolumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nivolumab is given IV as flat dose of 240 mg for Cycles 1-4 and 480 mg for Cycles 5-16.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Nivolumab is given IV as flat dose of 240 mg for Cycles 1-4 and 480 mg for Cycles 5-16.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1/Nivolumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have recurrent glioma (histologically confirmed by NIH Laboratory of&#xD;
             Pathology) with IDH1 or IDH2 mutation (confirmed by DNA sequencing, FoundationOne is&#xD;
             preferable for confirmation of mutation, but not necessary).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have tumor specific mutational load (number of somatic mutations per&#xD;
             exome) performed at NIH. Must have either result of previous NIH testing or must&#xD;
             provide adequate tissue sample for testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The tumor tissue (e.g. block or 15 unstained slides) must be available for molecular&#xD;
             and immune profiling. Fresh or frozen tumor sample will be used if available, but not&#xD;
             mandatory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 18 years. Because no dosing or adverse event data are&#xD;
             currently available on the use of nivolumab in patients &lt;18 years of age, children are&#xD;
             excluded from this study, but will be eligible for future pediatric trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be able to tolerate an MRI study with intravenous gadolinium contrast.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky greater than or equal to 60%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count greater than or equal to 1,500/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet Count greater than or equal to 100,000/MCL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin greater than 9.0 g/dL (may be transfused to achieve this level)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  BUN less than or equal to 30 mg/dL and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine less than or equal to 1.7 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin (except patients with Gilbert s Syndrome, who are eligible for&#xD;
                  the study but exempt from the total bilirubin eligibility criterion) less than or&#xD;
                  equal to 2.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT and AST less than or equal to 2.5x institutional upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effects of nivolumab on the developing human fetus are unknown. For this reason,&#xD;
             women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception&#xD;
             (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for&#xD;
             the duration of study participation and up to 5 months (women) and 7 months (men)&#xD;
             after the last dose of the drug. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is&#xD;
             pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she should inform&#xD;
             her treating physician immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient must be able to understand and be willing to sign a written informed&#xD;
             consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have a history of receiving immune therapy, such as a vaccine therapy,&#xD;
             dendritic cell vaccine or intracavitary or convectional enhanced delivery of therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to nivolumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe hypersensitivity reaction to any monoclonal antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior invasive malignancy (except non-melanomatous skin cancer) unless disease free&#xD;
             for a minimum of 3 years prior to initiation of study therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active autoimmune disease or history of autoimmune disease that might&#xD;
             recur, which may affect vital organ function or require immune suppressive treatment&#xD;
             including systemic corticosteroids. These include but are not limited to patients with&#xD;
             a history of immune related neurologic disease, multiple sclerosis, autoimmune&#xD;
             (demyelinating) neuropathy, Guillain-Barre syndrome or CIDP, myasthenia gravis;&#xD;
             systemic autoimmune disease such as SLE, connective tissue diseases, scleroderma,&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease (IBD), Crohn s, ulcerative colitis, hepatitis; and patients&#xD;
             with a history of toxic epidermal necrolysis (TEN), Stevens-Johnson syndrome, or&#xD;
             phospholipid syndrome. Such diseases should be excluded because of the risk of&#xD;
             recurrence or exacerbation of disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Of note, patients with vitiligo, endocrine deficiencies including thyroiditis&#xD;
             managed with replacement hormones including physiologic corticosteroids are eligible.&#xD;
             Patients with rheumatoid arthritis and other arthropathies, Sj(SqrRoot)(Delta)gren s&#xD;
             syndrome and psoriasis controlled with topical medication and patients with positive&#xD;
             serology, such as antinuclear antibodies (ANA), anti-thyroid antibodies should be&#xD;
             evaluated for the presence of target organ involvement and potential need for systemic&#xD;
             treatment but should otherwise be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient must not be currently on a corticosteroid dose greater than physiologic&#xD;
             replacement dosing defined as 30 mg of cortisone per day or its equivalent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations (within timeframes identified in&#xD;
             the bullets below) that would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known HIV-positive or acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) based upon current&#xD;
             CDC definition; note, however, that HIV testing is not required for entry into this&#xD;
             protocol. The need to exclude patients with AIDS is based on the lack of information&#xD;
             regarding the safety of nivolumab in patients with active HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study because nivolumab s potential for&#xD;
             teratogenic or abortifacient effects is unknown. Because there is an unknown but&#xD;
             potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the&#xD;
             mother with nivolumab, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated&#xD;
             with nivolumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known active, chronic or history of hepatitis infection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jing Wu, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>NCI NOB Referral Group</last_name>
    <phone>(866) 251-9686</phone>
    <email>ncinobreferrals@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>888-624-1937</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2019-C-0006.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 31, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 24, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PD 1 Pathway</keyword>
  <keyword>High Tumor Mutational Load</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune Checkpoint</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

