<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03717337</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Faculty of dentistry 2018</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03717337</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Success Rate of Single Versus Two Visit Regenerative Treatment Protocol in Non Vital Mature Anterior Teeth</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Success Rate of Non Vital Mature Anterior Teeth With Periapical Lesion Following Single Versus Two Visit Regenerative Treatment Protocol A Randomized Clinical Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study evaluates success rate of non vital mature anterior teeth with periapical lesion&#xD;
      treated by regenerative endodontic protocol in single visit versus two visit technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are randomized into two groups where treatment will be done either in one visit&#xD;
      including access, disinfection, placing platelet rich plasma as scaffold and restoration or&#xD;
      two visit protocol involving access, disinfection and placing calcium hydroxide as intracanal&#xD;
      medicament in first visit followed by a second visit after 3 weeks involving reopening of the&#xD;
      tooth, removing intracanal medicament and placing platelet rich plasma as scaffold then&#xD;
      restoration. Success rate is defined as absence of subjective signs and symptoms along with&#xD;
      healing of periapical lesion&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Title: Evaluation of Success Rate of Non Vital Mature Anterior Teeth with Periapical Lesion&#xD;
      Following Single versus Two Visit Regenerative Treatment Protocol (A Randomized Clinical&#xD;
      Trial) Regenerative endodontics can be defined as biologically based procedures designed to&#xD;
      replace damaged structures, including dentin and root structures, as well as cells of the&#xD;
      pulp-dentin complex.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The majority of endodontic patients are adults, thus the application of the tissue&#xD;
      engineering concept to mature teeth could provide a biological treatment modality instead of&#xD;
      the conventional one. In fact, several advantages were reported about regenerative procedures&#xD;
      in well developed mature teeth. Reconstitution of the neurovascular system in root canals by&#xD;
      pulp regeneration will provide pulp tissues with an immune system, which will function as the&#xD;
      first line of defense against microbial challenge. Moreover, restoration of pulp dentine&#xD;
      complex will protect the tooth during loading and mastication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Different treatment protocols for pulp regeneration were reported in the literature regarding&#xD;
      irrigation (type, concentration and time), intracanal medication, pulpal space barrier,&#xD;
      incorporation and lack of scaffolds (blood clot, PRP,PRF, collagen) as well as recall visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale for conducting the research and choice of comparators:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multiple visits protocol has been the commonly used technique in regenerative endodontic&#xD;
      procedures. It involves the placement of intracanal medicaments between visits (calcium&#xD;
      hydroxide and triple antibiotic paste) which have many drawbacks such as difficulty in&#xD;
      removal, tooth discoloration, weakening of the root and tooth loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Completing revascularization in one visit has many advantages. First, it reduces the chance&#xD;
      of additional bacterial contamination of the space. Second, a single revascularization&#xD;
      protocol may overcome the problem of poor patient compliance and reduce the number of&#xD;
      appointments needed. Third, it can help to combat potential injury of the tooth and tooth&#xD;
      discoloration Unfortunately, up till the moment it is not clear which protocol is the most&#xD;
      effective. Thus randomized clinical trials are required to provide plausible answers to this&#xD;
      question In the present research the recent single visit regenerative treatment for necrotic&#xD;
      mature teeth will be compared to the conventionally used two visit one&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The design of this randomized clinical trial is a parallel group two arms trial with 1:1 allocation ratio</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>single</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Post operative pain: NRS</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>absence of pain reported by the patient by numerical rate scale, the 11-point numeric scale ranges from '0' representing one pain extreme (e.g. &quot;no pain&quot;) to '10' representing the other pain extreme (e.g. &quot;pain as bad as you can imagine&quot; or &quot;worst pain imaginable&quot;)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in swelling and/or sinus</measure>
    <time_frame>3,6,9,12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The presence of swelling or sinus will be reported by a binary question yes/no</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Periapical healing</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The existing periapical lesion will be measured by mm by CBCT before intiation of treatment and after one year</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antimicrobial effect</measure>
    <time_frame>before and after complete disinfection either in the same visit or after 3 weeks from the second visit</time_frame>
    <description>intracanal bacterial count by culture method</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Tooth giving respond to electrical pulp tester</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Discoloration</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6, 9 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Recording tooth shade before and after treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulp Necrosis</condition>
  <condition>Periapical Lesion</condition>
  <condition>Anterior Teeth</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single visit pulp regeneration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Regenerative endodontic procedure not involving placement of intracanal medicament will be done in single visit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Two visit pulp regeneration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Regenerative endodontic procedure involving placing intracanal medicament will be done in two visit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Single visit pulp regeneration</intervention_name>
    <description>Access cavity, disinfection, preparing and injecting platelet rich plasma, and restoring the tooth all done in one visit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single visit pulp regeneration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Two visit pulp regeneration</intervention_name>
    <description>first visit : access, disinfection and placing calcium hydroxide as intracanal medicament second visit: re opening of tooth, preparing and injecting platelet rich plasma and restoring the tooth.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Two visit pulp regeneration</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Single canal anterior tooth&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mature root&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non vital with radiographic evidence of periapical lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Periapical lesion of average size 2-5mm&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive patient compliance for participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with good oral hygiene&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Normal periodontal probing depth ≤ 3 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Compromised remaining tooth structure that need post and core build up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non restorable teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vital teeth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiographic evidence of external or internal root resorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Roots showing fracture or ankylosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medically compromised patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Greater than grade I mobility or periodontal probing depth greater than 3mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immature tooth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with pain, swelling or fistula tracts&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 24, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 24, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>lamiaa Mohamed Ragaei Lasheen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant lecturer of endodontics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Regeneration, mature teeth, regenerative procedures</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Pulp Necrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Necrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

