<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03718325</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HUM00147961</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03718325</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Burst Spinal Cord Stimulation (Burst-SCS) Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Characterization of Burst Spinal Cord Stimulation for Chronic Pain Management</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Michigan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Michigan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Recently a new form of spinal cord stimulation therapy called burst spinal cord stimulation&#xD;
      (Burst-SCS) is available to treat chronic pain. The goal of this study is to learn more about&#xD;
      how Burst-SCS works to reduce chronic pain. The study will examine chronic pain patients who&#xD;
      have been deemed candidates for Burst-SCS therapy, and who have already been selected to&#xD;
      receive a temporary externalized trial of Burst-SCS from their own doctors as part of their&#xD;
      standard clinical care for chronic pain management. During the study, participants will be&#xD;
      asked to complete a variety of evaluations at certain time points. In addition, there will be&#xD;
      a randomized, double blind, crossover phase, where the particular effects of Burst-SCS and&#xD;
      sham SCS will be evaluated. The device used to deliver Burst-SCS and sham SCS is the St. Jude&#xD;
      Medical Invisible Trial System.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 12, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>There will be two research teams. One team will be unblinded (e.g. clinical care provider/company representative, study coordinator) and will perform stimulator programming/adjustment, and the other team will be blinded (e.g. research personnel) and will perform clinical testing and collect study outcome measures.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Visual Analog Scale (VAS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-implant visit, up to approximately 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>VAS is a horizontal line 100 millimeters (mm) in length with the word &quot;no pain&quot; and &quot;worst possible pain&quot; with a score between 0 (no pain) to a score of 100 (worst possible pain). The participant marks on the line the point that they feel represents their perception of their current state. The score is determined by measuring in millimeters from the left hand with a total range of 0-100 millimeters. Higher VAS values represent more severe pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Short-Form McGill Pain Questionnaire (SFMPQ) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-implant visit, up to approximately 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>SFMPQ will be used to describe the quality of pain and has 15 descriptors (11 sensory and 4 affective). Each descriptor is scored by a 4-point intensity scale (0=none to 3=severe) (sensory range 0-45). Three pain scores are derived from the sum of the intensity rank values of the words chosen for sensory, affective and total descriptors. The SFMPQ also includes the Present Pain Intensity (PPI) index (for example (i.e.) the VAS) and an Evaluative Overall Intensity of Total Pain Experience.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in General Pain Disability Index (PDI) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-implant visit, up to approximately 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of pain will be described by using this 6-question survey regarding daily living activity. Range is 0 (0 points, completely able to function) to 10 (10 points, totally unable to function). The higher the number score the greater the disability (due to pain).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Brief Pain Inventory-Short Form (BPI-SF) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-implant visit, up to approximately 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Pain severity is measured and includes 9 questions with scores ranging from 0 to 10 with higher scores indicating more severe pain and greater interference with functioning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Michigan Body Map (MBM)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Pain spread will be collected by having the participants check all areas of their body as outlined on the body map where they have felt persistent or recurrent pain. If there is no pain, the No chronic pain box will be marked. MBM will be used to assess body areas where chronic pain is experienced, and quantify the degree of widespread body pain in the participant (i.e. pain centralization).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fibromyalgia Survey Questionnaire (FSQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Participant is to mark where they have had pain or tenderness on a map of their body (or mark no pain in areas). FSQ in combination with the MBM will be used to assess pain centralization.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain, Chronic</condition>
  <condition>Failed Back Surgery Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Burst-SCS/sham SCS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>First, participants will receive clinically-effective Burst-SCS per their standard of care. Study evaluations will be completed prior to and after stimulation. Then, participants will have their stimulation adjusted to receive sham (no) SCS. Study evaluations will be completed prior to and after this sham.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham SCS/Burst-SCS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>First, participants will receive sham (no) SCS. Study evaluations will be completed prior to and after this sham. Then, participants will have their stimulation adjusted to receive clinically-effective Burst-SCS per their standard of care. Study evaluations will be completed prior to and after stimulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Burst-SCS</intervention_name>
    <description>The treatment arm used in the study is clinically-effective burst spinal cord stimulation (Burst-SCS). The device used to deliver Burst-SCS is the St. Jude Medical Invisible Trial System.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Burst-SCS/sham SCS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sham SCS/Burst-SCS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham SCS</intervention_name>
    <description>The placebo control arm used in the study is sham spinal cord stimulation (sham SCS). The device used to deliver sham SCS is the St. Jude Medical Invisible Trial System.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Burst-SCS/sham SCS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sham SCS/Burst-SCS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men or women with chronic, intractable pain of the trunk and/or limbs, including&#xD;
             unilateral or bilateral pain associated with any of the following: failed back surgery&#xD;
             syndrome and intractable low back and leg pain, and for whom Burst-SCS has been&#xD;
             recommended as a treatment option&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Candidates who can speak, read, and understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are pregnant- as determined by verbal report or chart review&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with current, habitual, or previous use within the last 12 months of&#xD;
             artificial nails, nail enhancements, or nail extensions that cover any portion of&#xD;
             either thumbnail. Exceptions, including brief and/or occasional use, may be&#xD;
             permissible at the discretion of the principal investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are unable or unwilling to cooperate with clinical testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects having any impairment, activity or situation that, in the judgement of the&#xD;
             study coordinator or PI, would prevent satisfactory completion of the study protocol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Scott Lempka, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Michigan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 23, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 23, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 24, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Michigan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Scott Lempka</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Biomedical Engineering and Assistant Professor of Anesthesiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Burst-SCS</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Spinal cord stimulation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Failed Back Surgery Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

