<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03713528</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9140</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03713528</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Can Intraosseous Antibiotics Improve the Results of Irrigation &amp; Debridement and Prosthetic Retention for PJI?</brief_title>
  <official_title>Can Intraosseous Antibiotics Improve the Results of Irrigation &amp; Debridement and Prosthetic Retention for PJI?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>OrthoCarolina Research Institute, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>American Association of Hip and Knee Surgeons</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>OrthoCarolina Research Institute, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of Study: In order to improve upon the variable results seen in irrigation and&#xD;
      debridement for periprosthetic infection, we ask if the use of intraosseous regional&#xD;
      administration of antibiotics at the time of irrigation and debridement will improve the&#xD;
      modest success of standard irrigation and debridement. We will use the existing literature on&#xD;
      standard irrigation and debridement procedures to compare with the results of the irrigation&#xD;
      and debridement with the use of intraosseous antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impact Question:&#xD;
&#xD;
      How will this study benefit the patient? Currently when an I&amp;D fails, the patient needs to&#xD;
      undergo two more major procedures: 1) implant removal and 2) reimplantation of the&#xD;
      prosthesis. Any improvement in the results of a standard irrigation and debridement procedure&#xD;
      may decrease the number of patients having to go through further extensive procedures to cure&#xD;
      their infection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Type of Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a multicenter, single arm, retrospective/prospective clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment Group:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • The treatment group includes any patient with an acute perioperative infection, an acute&#xD;
      hematogenous, or a chronic infection with unresectable components and treated with&#xD;
      intraoperative intraosseous vancomycin during a one-stage debridement protocol. Additionally,&#xD;
      patients will be treated with at least 4 weeks of IV antibiotics under guidance of an&#xD;
      infectious disease specialist, and indefinite antibiotic chronic suppression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical and Antibiotic Administration Technique:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Initially, all patients will receive standard weight based cefazolin (1 gram for patients &lt;&#xD;
      80kg, 2 grams for patients between 80-120kg, and 3 grams for patients over 120kg)&#xD;
      preoperatively. Our protocol for MRSA positive patients is to use cefazolin and vancomycin&#xD;
      preoperatively. Because irrigation and debridement in patients with gram positive infections&#xD;
      are frequently done urgently before exact organism identification and sensitivities are&#xD;
      available it is important to cover the patient broadly with cefazolin and vancomycin&#xD;
      initially.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment group will receive post debridement intraosseous vancomycin as described below.&#xD;
      In total knee infections a pneumatic tourniquet must be used for the procedure. After&#xD;
      entering the knee joint the following process is followed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Fluid is collected in four syringes and placed into two sets of aerobic and anaerobic&#xD;
           adult blood culture bottles,&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Two synovial tissue cultures from different areas of the joint are obtained and sent for&#xD;
           culture,&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. If not enough fluid is obtained send an additional tissue culture,&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Remaining tissue is sent for final pathologic analysis at the end of the case.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After obtaining cultures radical synovial debridement is performed debriding the inner&#xD;
      surface of the entire knee capsule including the posterior capsule of the knee. Modular parts&#xD;
      will be removed, that is the polyethylene insert for knees.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Debridement and Irrigation Protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a complete synovectomy is performed along with extraction of modular parts any exposed&#xD;
      metallic parts will be scrubbed with a sterile brush soaked in dilute betadine. A 5-step&#xD;
      irrigation protocol will then be used for all surgeries:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Pulse lavage with 3 liters of normal saline (NS),&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Lavage with 100 cc's of 3% H202 and 100 cc's of sterile water, a 50/50 solution left in&#xD;
           wound for 2 minutes,&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Lavage 3 liters NS,&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Lavage with 1 liter of dilute, sterile Betadine (22.5 ml Betadine/liter NS) - left in&#xD;
           wound for 3 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Pulse lavage with 3 liters of NS&#xD;
&#xD;
      After debridement and irrigation the interventional group will receive intraosseous&#xD;
      vancomycin 500mg in 150ml of normal saline. This dose was selected based on the studies of&#xD;
      Young (10) and Clarke (11) who used this dose in two high risk groups (revision TKA and high&#xD;
      BMI patients) with no significant side effects or red man syndromes. This solution will be&#xD;
      prepared by the hospital pharmacy and administered via an EZ-IO intraosseous cannula. In&#xD;
      total knees the cannula will be placed in the proximal medial tibia using a starter drill&#xD;
      slightly smaller than the diameter of the cannula to ensure a press fit just distal to the&#xD;
      tibia implant in the vicinity of the pes anserine tendons. 75ccs of the vancomycin solution&#xD;
      will be injected as a bolus. Subsequent to this the remaining 75ccs will be placed in the&#xD;
      distal femur just proximal to the femoral component evenly split between the medial and&#xD;
      lateral femoral condyles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After irrigation and debridement the wound will be closed over a betadine soaked lap sponge&#xD;
      placed between the components. Contaminated drapes and instruments will be removed and the&#xD;
      patient will be re-prepped with new drapes. New instruments will be used to insert the new&#xD;
      modular parts. After opening the wound and prior to inserting new modular parts the wound&#xD;
      will be irrigated this time with the following regime:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Pulse lavage with 3 liters of normal saline (NS),&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Lavage with 100 cc's of 3% H202 and 100 cc's of sterile water, a 50/50 solution left in&#xD;
           wound for 2 minutes,&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Lavage 1 liters NS,&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Lavage with 1 liter of dilute, sterile Betadine (22.5 ml Betadine/liter NS) - left in&#xD;
           wound for 3 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Pulse lavage with 3 liters of NS&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the modular parts are reinserted the wound is closed with monofilament sutures over&#xD;
      drains.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-operative treatment will be managed by an infectious disease specialist with at least&#xD;
      four weeks of intravenous antibiotics followed by indefinite chronic suppression as&#xD;
      recommended by the Musculoskeletal Infection Society (Table 1). Baseline creatinine will be&#xD;
      obtained preoperatively and on postop days 1 and 2. Infectious disease consultants will&#xD;
      monitor peak and trough levels based on the specific antibiotic administered and they will&#xD;
      adjust dosage as indicated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 14, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>multicenter, single arm, retrospective/prospective clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence of Infection</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measured will be the recurrence of infection by the same organism or reinfection with a new organism as determined by the criteria using the International Consensus Meeting on PJI (1 year follow-up).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Joint Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The treatment group includes any patient with an acute perioperative periprosthetic infection, acute hematogenous infection, or unresectable infection with a gram positive organism sensitive to vancomycin and treated with intraoperative intraosseous vancomycin. Additionally, patients will be treated with at least 4 weeks of IV antibiotics under guidance of an infectious disease specialist, and indefinite antibiotic chronic suppression.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intraoperative Intraosseous Vancomycin</intervention_name>
    <description>After debridement and irrigation the interventional group will receive intraosseous vancomycin 500mg in 150ml of normal saline. This solution will be prepared by the hospital pharmacy and administered via an EZ-IO intraosseous cannula. 75ccs of the vancomycin solution will be injected as a bolus. Subsequent to this the remaining 75ccs will be placed in the distal femur just proximal to the femoral component evenly split between the medial and lateral femoral condyles in knees.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Vancomycin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria (to be completed at time of consent) I. Acute perioperative&#xD;
        periprosthetic infection in the first 90 days following primary surgery OR, II. Acute&#xD;
        hematogenous infection with symptoms less than four weeks OR, III. Any patient with a&#xD;
        chronic periprosthetic knee infection, or a prosthetic knee that is considered unresectable&#xD;
        due to the presence of extremely difficult to extract implants such as cones/sleeves/or&#xD;
        long cemented or cementless stems and indicated for an irrigation debridement procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        IV. Patients indicated for an irrigation debridement procedure of a knee periprosthetic&#xD;
        knee joint infection as defined by the inclusion criteria noted above with a gram positive&#xD;
        organism susceptible to vancomycin, defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A sinus communicating with the prosthesis, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Two positive cultures obtained from the prosthesis, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. 3 of 5 criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        i. Elevated ESR (&gt;30mm/hr) and CRP (&gt;10mg/L) ii. Elevated synovial leukocyte count (&gt;3000&#xD;
        cells/µL) or change of ++ on leukocyte esterase strip iii. Elevated synovial neutrophil&#xD;
        percentage (&gt;80%) iv. One positive culture v. Positive histological analysis of&#xD;
        periprosthetic tissue (&gt;5 neutrophils per high power field in 5 high power fields x400) We&#xD;
        understand that on occasion, irrigation &amp; debridement is performed emergently, therefore&#xD;
        enrollment may continue without all laboratory/cultures completed. All inclusion criteria&#xD;
        in this situation will be confirmed postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
        V. Any patient &gt;18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria I. Surgical wound that cannot be closed. II. Patients with an acute PJI&#xD;
        greater than 90 days following primary surgery (using standard implants).&#xD;
&#xD;
        III. Hematogenous infection with symptoms greater than four weeks IV. Know hypersensitivity&#xD;
        to Vancomycin V. Major Renal disease defined as creatinine &gt; 2.0 (See previous comments, No&#xD;
        Red Man syndrome in 2 subsequent studies on intraosseous vancomycin in revision TKA and&#xD;
        High BMI patients respectively (9). Additionally, systemic levels were 8 times lower with&#xD;
        intraosseous antibiotics than IV Vancomycin.) VI. Unable to use a tourniquet due to&#xD;
        vascular disease VII. Pregnant women VIII. Allergy to antibiotic&#xD;
&#xD;
        Screen Failure (following initial procedure):&#xD;
&#xD;
        IX. Culture negative infections whereby the infecting organism was not identified OR X.&#xD;
        Vancomycin-resistant organisms&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Fehring, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>OrthoCarolina Research Institute, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Atrium Mercy Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28207</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>OrthoCarolina Research Institute/OrthoCarolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28207</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Novant Health Charlotte Orthopedic Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28209</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hartman MB, Fehring TK, Jordan L, Norton HJ. Periprosthetic knee sepsis. The role of irrigation and debridement. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 1991 Dec;(273):113-8.</citation>
    <PMID>1959257</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bradbury T, Fehring TK, Taunton M, Hanssen A, Azzam K, Parvizi J, Odum SM. The fate of acute methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus periprosthetic knee infections treated by open debridement and retention of components. J Arthroplasty. 2009 Sep;24(6 Suppl):101-4. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2009.04.028. Epub 2009 Jun 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19553077</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fehring TK, Odum SM, Berend KR, Jiranek WA, Parvizi J, Bozic KJ, Della Valle CJ, Gioe TJ. Failure of irrigation and débridement for early postoperative periprosthetic infection. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2013 Jan;471(1):250-7. doi: 10.1007/s11999-012-2373-9.</citation>
    <PMID>22552768</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bryan AJ, Abdel MP, Sanders TL, Fitzgerald SF, Hanssen AD, Berry DJ. Irrigation and Debridement with Component Retention for Acute Infection After Hip Arthroplasty: Improved Results with Contemporary Management. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2017 Dec 6;99(23):2011-2018. doi: 10.2106/JBJS.16.01103.</citation>
    <PMID>29206791</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Urish KL, Bullock AG, Kreger AM, Shah NB, Jeong K, Rothenberger SD; Infected Implant Consortium. A Multicenter Study of Irrigation and Debridement in Total Knee Arthroplasty Periprosthetic Joint Infection: Treatment Failure Is High. J Arthroplasty. 2018 Apr;33(4):1154-1159. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2017.11.029. Epub 2017 Nov 21.</citation>
    <PMID>29221840</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Young SW, Zhang M, Freeman JT, Vince KG, Coleman B. Higher cefazolin concentrations with intraosseous regional prophylaxis in TKA. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2013 Jan;471(1):244-9. doi: 10.1007/s11999-012-2469-2.</citation>
    <PMID>22773397</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Young SW, Zhang M, Freeman JT, Mutu-Grigg J, Pavlou P, Moore GA. The Mark Coventry Award: Higher tissue concentrations of vancomycin with low-dose intraosseous regional versus systemic prophylaxis in TKA: a randomized trial. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2014 Jan;472(1):57-65. doi: 10.1007/s11999-013-3038-z.</citation>
    <PMID>23666589</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Young SW, Roberts T, Johnson S, Dalton JP, Coleman B, Wiles S. Regional Intraosseous Administration of Prophylactic Antibiotics is More Effective Than Systemic Administration in a Mouse Model of TKA. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2015 Nov;473(11):3573-84. doi: 10.1007/s11999-015-4464-x. Epub 2015 Jul 30.</citation>
    <PMID>26224291</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Young SW, Zhang M, Moore GA, Pitto RP, Clarke HD, Spangehl MJ. The John N. Insall Award: Higher Tissue Concentrations of Vancomycin Achieved With Intraosseous Regional Prophylaxis in Revision TKA: A Randomized Controlled Trial. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2018 Jan;476(1):66-74. doi: 10.1007/s11999.0000000000000013.</citation>
    <PMID>29529618</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chin SJ, Moore GA, Zhang M, Clarke HD, Spangehl MJ, Young SW. The AAHKS Clinical Research Award: Intraosseous Regional Prophylaxis Provides Higher Tissue Concentrations in High BMI Patients in Total Knee Arthroplasty: A Randomized Trial. J Arthroplasty. 2018 Jul;33(7S):S13-S18. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2018.03.013. Epub 2018 Mar 15.</citation>
    <PMID>29655497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lichstein P, Gehrke T, Lombardi A, Romano C, Stockley I, Babis G, Bialecki J, Bucsi L, Cai X, Cao L, de Beaubien B, Erhardt J, Goodman S, Jiranek W, Keogh P, Lewallen D, Manner P, Marczynski W, Mason JB, Mulhall K, Paprosky W, Patel P, Piccaluga F, Polkowski G, Pulido L, Stockley I, Suarez J, Thorey F, Tikhilov R, Velazquez JD, Winkler H. One-stage vs two-stage exchange. J Arthroplasty. 2014 Feb;29(2 Suppl):108-11. doi: 10.1016/j.arth.2013.09.048. Epub 2013 Oct 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24360339</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 18, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 18, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vancomycin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

