<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03717129</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00110315</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>IN-US-292-4089</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03717129</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Analysis of Crushed and Whole Tablet Genvoya</brief_title>
  <official_title>Analysis of Crushed and Whole Tablet Genvoya</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Gilead Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Step-wise, two sequential, single-dose, bioequivalence study in 12 healthy volunteers to&#xD;
      determine whether crushed Genvoya tablet is bioequivalent to whole Genvoya tablet. The first&#xD;
      study sequence will involve a directly observed single dose of the fixed dose formulation of&#xD;
      whole Genvoya tablet, with semi-intensive pharmacokinetic serum sampling at time points&#xD;
      following the dose. After a washout period of seven days, subjects will then receive a&#xD;
      directly observed single dose of a crushed tablet of Genvoya with subsequent semi-intensive&#xD;
      pharmacokinetic serum sampling.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Genvoya, a fixed-dose combination of the two Nucleoside Reverse Transcriptase Inhibitors&#xD;
      (NRTI) emtricitabine (FTC) 200mg and tenofovir alafenamide (TAF) 10mg, with the integrase&#xD;
      inhibitor elvitegravir (EVG) and the boosting agent cobicistat (COBI), is FDA approved for&#xD;
      the treatment of HIV-infected patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the availability of Genvoya allowing for a single tablet fixed-dose combination and&#xD;
      once-daily dosing, a substantial number of individuals living with HIV suffer from pill&#xD;
      aversion, dysphagia, odynophagia, or problems swallowing oral regimens, all of which can&#xD;
      contribute to non-adherence. These observations are especially important because&#xD;
      non-adherence to antiretroviral (ARV) medications is highly prevalent and associated with&#xD;
      decreased survival. Non-adherence has been estimated at 55% in North American pooled cohorts,&#xD;
      and is a vital public health concern, as it leads to treatment failure and transmission of&#xD;
      drug-resistant virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many clinical scenarios make the administration of crushed tablets desirable as a potential&#xD;
      strategy to overcome pill aversion. However, there is a theoretical concern that the systemic&#xD;
      absorption of the active ingredients of tablets may be altered by crushing the pills. In&#xD;
      fact, pharmacokinetic and bioequivalence data are lacking for most antiretroviral fixed-dose&#xD;
      combinations used in the treatment of HIV-infected patients. It is therefore of substantial&#xD;
      practical and clinical interest to know whether antiretroviral combinations such as Genvoya&#xD;
      can be taken in crushed form with bioequivalence to whole tablet form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a step-wise bioequivalence single-dose and two sequential design study in healthy&#xD;
      volunteers to evaluate the combination Genvoya to provide this critical information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective: To investigate the bioequivalence of oral single whole tablet and crushed&#xD;
      tablet of Genvoya in healthy volunteers, by characterizing the serum Area Under the Curve 0&#xD;
      to infinity (AUC0-∞) and Cmax of EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF in plasma, after single doses of&#xD;
      whole tablet and crushed tablet of this fixed dose antiretroviral combination in healthy&#xD;
      volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Endpoint:Ratio of serum AUC0-∞ and ratio of Cmax in plasma of EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF&#xD;
      in healthy volunteers after two different dosage forms (whole and crushed tablets).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Endpoints(s): Ratio of Tmax in plasma of EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF in healthy&#xD;
      volunteers after two different dosage forms (whole and crushed tablets).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Projected Study Design: Step-wise, two sequential, single-dose, bioequivalence study in 12&#xD;
      healthy volunteers. The first study sequence will involve a directly observed single dose of&#xD;
      the fixed dose formulation of whole Genvoya tablet, with semi-intensive pharmacokinetic serum&#xD;
      sampling at time points following the dose. After a washout period of seven days, subjects&#xD;
      will then receive a directly observed single dose of a crushed tablet of Genvoya with&#xD;
      subsequent semi-intensive pharmacokinetic serum sampling. Additional information about the&#xD;
      proposed pharmacokinetic sampling time points for each of the antiretroviral components of&#xD;
      Genvoya and safety evaluations is included in the Study Procedures Section of this proposal.&#xD;
      The duration of the washout period of seven days between the two study sequences and proposed&#xD;
      pharmacokinetic sampling time points, was selected for convenience and based on the&#xD;
      antiretroviral component of Genvoya with the longest half-life (EVG).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Projected Duration of Treatment: Two directly observed doses of one table of Genvoya over two&#xD;
      weeks (one single dose of whole and one single dose crushed Genvoya tablets, as specified in&#xD;
      the Regimen Section of this proposal).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration: It will take 6-8 months to complete accrual and follow up of 12 subjects and&#xD;
      an additional three months to complete the data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regimens - Study Sequence:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Period 1: Product: Genvoya - Dose: 1 tablet PO (whole) - Frequency: Single dose Period 2:&#xD;
      Product: Genvoya - Dose: 1 tablet PO (crushed) - Frequency: Single dose&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other Evaluations: Safety will be monitored and evaluated at pre-defined time points&#xD;
      (screening and 2 weeks) throughout the study, and assessments will include: monitoring for&#xD;
      adverse treatment-related events, clinical examinations with vital signs, and collection of&#xD;
      blood for routine safety laboratory tests in accordance with the protocol [e.g. Complete&#xD;
      Blood Count (CBC), chemistry, HIV and hepatitis B (HBV screening, pregnancy test]. Subjects&#xD;
      will receive a single dose of Genvoya whole and crushed tablets. Pharmacokinetic assessment&#xD;
      will be performed, with blood drawn for testing at time zero, and at selected time points&#xD;
      after dosing with for EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF, with more intensive sampling surrounding the&#xD;
      evidence-based Cmax of each drug, and adequate sampling in the tail to estimate AUC with&#xD;
      precision. Plasma will be tested for EVG, COBI, FTC and TAF concentrations using a validated&#xD;
      high-performance liquid chromatography- mass spectroscopy (HPLC-MS) assay. The ARV components&#xD;
      of Genvoya will be sampled as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      EVG -10 time points: 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 9, 12, 24, 48, 72 hours COBI -11 time points: 0, 0.5, 1,&#xD;
      2, 3, 4, 6, 9, 12, 18, 24 hours FTC-14 time points: 0, 0.5, 0.75, 1, 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6, 9, 12,&#xD;
      24, 48, 72 hours TAF-10 time points: (0, 0.25, 0.5, 0.75, 1, 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine serum pharmacokinetic parameters of EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF the Phoenix&#xD;
      WinNonLin non-linear curve-fitting software (V 6.4; Pharsight, Mountain View, CA) will be&#xD;
      employed using standard non-compartmental analytic methods. Pharmacokinetic parameters&#xD;
      calculated will include area under the plasma concentration-time curve from 0 to τ (AUCτ,&#xD;
      calculated using the linear trapezoidal rule); the maximum EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF&#xD;
      concentrations in serum after one dose (Cmax); and the time to maximum observed drug&#xD;
      concentrations in serum (Tmax).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: there will be a 90% confidence interval between 0.8 and 1.25 for the ratio of&#xD;
      Area Under the Curve for the whole tablet (AUCwhole): Area Under the Curve for the crushed&#xD;
      tablet (AUCcrushed); and the ratio of Maximum Concentration whole tablet (Cmaxwhole): Maximum&#xD;
      Concentration crushed tablet (Cmaxcrushed), for the four antiretroviral components of&#xD;
      Genvoya: EVG, COBI, FTC, and TAF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An equivalence approach with no-effect boundaries of 80 to 125% will be employed, in&#xD;
      accordance with the FDA guidance on bioequivalence studies, which define bioequivalence as&#xD;
      &quot;the absence of a significant difference in the rate and extent to which the active moiety&#xD;
      becomes available at the site of action when administered at the same molar dose under&#xD;
      similar conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to test the primary hypothesis, log-transformed AUCτ and Cmax after a single dose&#xD;
      for crushed versus whole tablets will be compared. The adjusted mean differences and ratios&#xD;
      will be estimated and the 90% confidence intervals calculated. In the case of AUCτ and Cmax,&#xD;
      the estimated differences and confidence limits will be exponentiated in order to compare&#xD;
      ratios between tablet forms. For Tmax, arithmetic means will be calculated, whereas for AUCτ&#xD;
      and Cmax, geometric means will be calculated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical methods. The sample size was calculated according to the formulas for a&#xD;
      multiplicative model. Table 2 includes sample size calculations for this proposed study. If&#xD;
      the mean Cmax ratio or AUC ratio is 1, a sample size of 5 subjects produces a two-sided 90%&#xD;
      confidence interval (0.952, 1.048) (i.e., a distance from the mean to the limits that is&#xD;
      equal to 0.048, when the estimated standard deviation is 0.050). A sample size of 10 subjects&#xD;
      produces a two-sided 90% confidence interval (0.855, 1.145) if the mean Cmax ratio or AUC&#xD;
      ratio is 1, and the estimated standard deviation is 0.25. Assuming a dropout rate of 10%, a&#xD;
      sample size of 12 subjects will be required required to provide 90% power to demonstrate the&#xD;
      bioequivalence of Cmax with 90% confidence intervals (CI) of 80% and 125%&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Curve from 0 to infinity (AUC0-∞) for EVG</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>AUC 0 to Infinity for Elvitegravir (mg-hr/mL)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-∞ for COBI</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>AUC 0 to Infinity for Cobicistat (mg-hr/mL)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-∞ for FTC</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>AUC 0 to Infinity for Emtricitabine (mg-hr/mL)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-∞ for Tenofovir (TFV)</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>AUC 0 to Infinity for TFV (mg-hr/mL)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EVG Half-life</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal elimination half-life for EVG (hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COBI Half-life</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal elimination half-life for COBI (hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>FTC Half-life</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal elimination half-life for FTC (hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TFV Half-life</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal elimination half-life for TFV (hours)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Genvoya Oral dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single observed oral dose of Genvoya whole tablet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Genvoya Crushed Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single observed oral dose of Genvoya crushed tablet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Genvoya Oral dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Single Genvoya oral dose directly observed</description>
    <arm_group_label>Genvoya Oral dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>elvitegravir/cobicistat/emtricitabine/ tenofovir alafenamide</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Genvoya Crushed Dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Single Genvoya crushed tablet in water directly observed</description>
    <arm_group_label>Genvoya Crushed Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>elvitegravir/cobicistat/emtricitabine/ tenofovir alafenamide</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy male and female research participants, ≥18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative HIV-1/2 Ag/Ab serology documented within 30 days prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative Hepatitis B surface antigen within 30 days prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability and willingness of subject to provide a signed informed consent and comply&#xD;
             with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative qualitative urine pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must not participate purposely in a conception process (e.g., active&#xD;
             attempt to impregnate, sperm donation, or in vitro fertilization). If participating in&#xD;
             sexual activity that could lead to pregnancy subjects must take every precaution to&#xD;
             avoid risk of pregnancy by using a reliable contraception for the duration of the&#xD;
             study therapy (e.g., condoms, hormonal, barrier).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory values and physical examination as judged by the principal investigator to&#xD;
             be safe to participate including normal renal function.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good peripheral venous access for proposed pharmacokinetic sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness and ability to take oral medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of chronic or acute medical conditions that in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
             would jeopardize safety of subjects participating in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected hypersensitivity to the components of Genvoya.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of prescription or over-the-counter medications, including agents containing&#xD;
             polyvalent cations (e.g., Mg, Al, Fe, or Ca), or any other drugs that in the opinion&#xD;
             of the investigator could interfere with the pharmacokinetics of any of the ARV&#xD;
             components of Genvoya within 2 weeks prior to either study dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active drug or alcohol use or dependence that, in the opinion of the investigator,&#xD;
             would interfere with adherence to study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalization or therapy for serious illness within 30 days prior to study entry as&#xD;
             judged by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in any investigational drug study within 30 days prior to study entry&#xD;
             that in the opinion of the investigator would preclude study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking any medication listed in the package insert that is contraindicated with&#xD;
             Genvoya.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Craig Hendrix, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>JHU</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 22, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 22, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 24, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Crush Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tenofovir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emtricitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cobicistat</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Emtricitabine tenofovir alafenamide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Elvitegravir, Cobicistat, Emtricitabine, Tenofovir Disoproxil Fumarate Drug Combination</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Elvitegravir</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

