<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04911816</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2103260669</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04911816</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neoadjuvant mFOLFIRINOX With Perioperative Oral Hydroxychloroquine in Resectable Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Study of Neoadjuvant mFOLFIRINOX in Combination With Peri-operative Oral Hydroxychloroquine (FHQ) in Subjects With Resectable Adenocarcinoma of the Pancreas.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>West Virginia University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>West Virginia University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This will be a phase I/II trial examining the safety and tolerability of pre-operative&#xD;
      mFOLFIRINOX in combination with peri-operative oral hydroxychloroquine (FHQ) in the treatment&#xD;
      of subjects with adenocarcinoma of the pancreas. Subjects will be staged prior to protocol&#xD;
      entry by contrast-enhanced helical abdominal CT scan done using a pancreas mass protocol or&#xD;
      EUS. Eligible subjects with biopsy-proven, resectable pancreatic adenocarcinoma without&#xD;
      evidence of venous or arterial involvement on CT scan receive HCQ orally in combination with&#xD;
      mFOLFIRINOX prior to surgery. Hydroxychloroquine will begin with the first dose of&#xD;
      mFOLFIRINOX and continue for 2 weeks post-operatively. Three to six weeks after the last dose&#xD;
      of mFOLFIRINOX, patients will undergo surgical exploration and pancreatectomy if technically&#xD;
      feasible and all toxicities have resolved. Pathologic specimens will undergo detailed&#xD;
      histopathologic and immunohistochemical evaluations with particular attention to the six&#xD;
      surgical margins of resection: the bile duct margin (for Whipple specimens), the margin of&#xD;
      pancreatic transection, the retroperitoneal margin, the proximal and distal duodenal margins&#xD;
      (for Whipple specimens), and the portal vein margin along the pancreatic head (for Whipple&#xD;
      specimens) or medial pancreas (for distal pancreatectomies). Tissue specimens will be stored&#xD;
      at -80C for future correlative studies of autophagy and tumor response to protocol therapy.&#xD;
      Ten to fourteen weeks following completion of successful surgical removal of their tumor,&#xD;
      subjects will undergo repeat staging studies per standard of care. Subjects will pursue&#xD;
      standard of care adjuvant therapy options at the discretion of their physician.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A subject is deemed evaluable if they have received at least 3 of 4 cycles of chemotherapy&#xD;
      and at least 80% of the expected HCQ doses and undergo successful surgical extirpation their&#xD;
      disease. Patients will receive daily oral HCQ concurrently with neoadjuvant mFOLFIRINOX,&#xD;
      planned for 4 cycles. Each cycle of mFOLFIRINOX is 14 days, therefore 4 cycles will occur&#xD;
      over a period of 56 days. Oral HCQ will continue after completion of neoadjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
      and extend 2 weeks post-operatively. Patients will undergo restaging scans after completion&#xD;
      of 4 cycles of mFOLFIRINOX. Within 3 to 6 weeks after completion of cycle 4 of mFOLFIRINOX,&#xD;
      patients will proceed for surgical resection. Patients will receive surveillance scans 10 to&#xD;
      14 weeks after completion of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive HCQ every day starting at the first dose of mFOLFIRINOX. Capsules of&#xD;
      HCQ are available in 200 mg strengths. HCQ will be administered in divided doses (BID) for&#xD;
      doses to minimize nausea. Patients should be told to swallow the whole capsule in rapid&#xD;
      succession without chewing. The starting phase I dose for HCQ is 400 mg. Before accrual to&#xD;
      the next dose level may begin, all patients in a given cohort must complete the 2 months of&#xD;
      combination treatment (HCQ + mFOLFIRINOX), permitting toxicities to be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dose will be assigned to patients using 3+3 Algorithm to identify the MTD. Dose level 1 is&#xD;
      400 mg hydroxychloroquine, dose level 2 is 800 mg hydroxychloroquine, and dose level 3 is&#xD;
      1200 mg hydroxychloroquine. If 0 first-dose DLTs are observed out of 3 patients treated with&#xD;
      the first dose-level, the next cohort of 3 patients may be enrolled and treated at the next&#xD;
      dose-level. If 1 out of the 3 patients treated with a dose-level experience a first-dose DLT,&#xD;
      up to 3 additional patients (6 total) will be enrolled at that dose-level. If only 1 out of&#xD;
      these 6 patients experiences a first-dose DLT, then the next cohort of 3 patients may be&#xD;
      enrolled and treated at the next dose-level. If ≥2 out of these 6 patients experience&#xD;
      first-dose DLTs, then dose escalation is stopped. Additional patients will be enrolled at the&#xD;
      prior lower dose-level to achieve a total of 6 patients. If ≥2 out of 3 patients in a cohort&#xD;
      experience a first-dose DLT, dose escalation will be stopped. Additional patients will be&#xD;
      enrolled at the prior lower dose-level, to achieve a total of 6 patients. If 0 or 1 out of 3&#xD;
      patients at the highest dose-level (1200 mg) experiences a DLT, additional patients will be&#xD;
      enrolled to achieve a total of 6 patients. If ≤1 out of these 6 patients experiences a DLT,&#xD;
      the 1200mg dose-level will be declared the maximal safe dose administered in this Phase 1&#xD;
      study. If ≥2 patients experience a DLT, additional patients will be enrolled at the prior&#xD;
      lower dose-level, for a total of 6 patients. If a DLT occurs in the first patient enrolled in&#xD;
      the trial, the first cohort of six patients will be assigned to Level 1. If a cohort of six&#xD;
      patients at Level 1 experiences more than one DLT, accrual to the trial will be paused, and&#xD;
      the trial will be referred to the GI DSMB for appropriate action. At the conclusion of the&#xD;
      dose escalation phase, the DSMB will meet to perform an interim review of safety data prior&#xD;
      to establishing the maximum tolerated dose for the phase 2 phase of the trial. The maximum&#xD;
      sample size of the study is 40 patients. Cohorts will be accrued until a new cohort would&#xD;
      exceed the maximum study size; therefore, the final sample size will be between 35 and 40&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase I - Establishing Maximum tolerated dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose to 30 days after treatment has been discontinued or until death, whichever occurs first.</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) for FHQ which is defined as the highest dose level in which the investigators have treated 6 patients with at most 1 experiencing dose limiting toxicities (DLT). A maximum of 18 patients (3x6) will be accrued for dose finding.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II - Rate of grade IIb or better histopathological response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of patients that have a rate of grade IIb or better histopathological response.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II - To establish the potential biological activity of FHQ by biochemical tumor response, as assessed by Ca 19-9.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment response will be assessed by measuring the change in the tumor marker Ca 19-9 in the serum before and after FHQ.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Adenocarcinoma of the Pancreas</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hydroxychloroquine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hydroxychloroquine sulfate</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydroxychloroquine sulfate</intervention_name>
    <description>Hydroxychloroquine, oral, dose escalated (400mg, 800mg, 1200mg) beginning concurrent with mFOLFIRINOX and extending 2 weeks post-operatively. Dose will be assigned to patients using 3+3 Algorithm to identify the Maximum Dose Tolerated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hydroxychloroquine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Plaquenil</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with biopsy-proven adenocarcinoma of the pancreas&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pancreatic protocol helical CT scan demonstrating absence of venous or arterial&#xD;
             involvement, consistent with NCCN guidelines for resectable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status ≤ 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No active second malignancy except for basal cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal renal, hepatic, and hematologic function at the time of enrollment as evidenced&#xD;
             by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine level ≤1.5 the upper limits of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total bilirubin level ≤1.5 X ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cell count ≥ 3.5x109/ml per ml and platelet count ≥ 100x109 per ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For subjects with obstructive jaundice, the biliary tract must be drained with a&#xD;
             temporary plastic or a short permanent metallic biliary stent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects deemed surgically unresectable or subjects unwilling to undergo surgical&#xD;
             resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have received chemotherapy within 12 months prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are found to have loss-of-function mutations in DPYD or UGTA1 by Oneome&#xD;
             pharmacogenomic testing, resulting in increased risk of mFOLFIRINOX toxicity. DPYD&#xD;
             mutations have been noted in 5% of the overall population. Homozygous UGT1A1 mutations&#xD;
             have been noted in 10% of North Americans.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior use of radiotherapy or investigational agents for pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any evidence of metastasis to distant organs (liver, lung, peritoneum).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cross sectional imaging suggesting portal vein, superior mesenteric artery, hepatic&#xD;
             artery involvement that would make the patient borderline resectable or locally&#xD;
             advanced&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic or endoscopic evidence of gastric outlet obstruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent malignancies with evidence of active or measurable disease except basal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma of the skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to adhere to study and/or follow-up procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions or hypersensitivity to the study drugs (chloroquine,&#xD;
             hydroxychloroquine, 5-Fluorouracil, Leucovorin, Oxaliplatin, Irinotecan).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other concurrent experimental therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effects of HCQ, and mFOLFIRINOX on the developing human fetus are unknown. For&#xD;
             this reason women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate&#xD;
             contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study&#xD;
             entry and for the duration of study participation. All females of childbearing&#xD;
             potential must have a blood test or urine study within two weeks prior to registration&#xD;
             to rule out pregnancy. Should a woman become pregnant while participating in this&#xD;
             study, she should inform her treating physician immediately. If a man impregnates a&#xD;
             woman while participating in this study, he should inform his treating physician&#xD;
             immediately as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Because patients with immune deficiency are at increased risk of lethal infections&#xD;
             when treated with bone marrow-suppressive therapy, HIV-positive patients are excluded&#xD;
             from the study. For patients receiving combination anti-retroviral therapy, the&#xD;
             potential impact of pharmacokinetic interactions with HCQ and mFOLFIRINOX is unknown.&#xD;
             Appropriate studies may be undertaken in patients with HIV and those receiving&#xD;
             combination anti-retroviral therapy in the future.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Due to the risk of disease exacerbation, patients with porphyria are ineligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with psoriasis are ineligible unless the disease is well controlled and they&#xD;
             are under the care of a specialist who agrees to monitor the patient for&#xD;
             exacerbations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients requiring the use of enzyme-inducing anti-epileptic medication that includes:&#xD;
             phenytoin, carbamazepine, phenobarbital, primidone or oxcarbazepine are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with previously documented macular degeneration or diabetic retinopathy are&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline EKG with QTc &gt;470 msec (including subjects on medication). Subjects with&#xD;
             ventricular pacemaker for whom QT interval is not measurable will be eligible on a&#xD;
             case-by-case basis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brian Boone, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>WVU Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Brian Boone</last_name>
    <phone>304-598-4000</phone>
    <email>brian.boone@hsc.wvu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West Virginia University Cancer Institute Mary Babb Randolph Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Morgantown</city>
        <state>West Virginia</state>
        <zip>26506</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brian Boone, MD</last_name>
      <phone>304-598-4000</phone>
      <email>brian.boone@hsc.wvu.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>West Virginia University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Brian Boone, MD, FACS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Surgical Oncology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hydroxychloroquine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

