<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04912895</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00000863</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04912895</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA in Coughed Droplets From Patients With COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA and Biomarkers in Coughed Droplets From Patients With COVID-19 and Controls</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Georgia Tech Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Emory University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to learn how to better detect infection and understand how&#xD;
      severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) causes lung disease and is&#xD;
      spread. The novel device called PneumoniaCheck is a safe way to collect material from the&#xD;
      lung from coughs. Study participants will collect cough specimens over a 24 hour period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A novel coronavirus, severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), was&#xD;
      detected in association with cases of severe respiratory illness and pneumonia (COVID-19) in&#xD;
      Wuhan City, Hubei Province, China in December 2019. The virus subsequently spread widely&#xD;
      throughout China and globally. Addressing this unprecedented global pandemic is requiring all&#xD;
      available tools to diagnose infection, manage ill patients, understand disease pathogenesis&#xD;
      and virus transmission to guide efforts to decrease transmission and rapidly develop&#xD;
      anti-viral drugs and vaccines. The researchers of this study propose to use the&#xD;
      PneumoniaCheck™, a device developed collaboratively by investigators at the Georgia Institute&#xD;
      of Technology (GA Tech) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to help&#xD;
      address these issues. This device, non-invasively, captures coughed droplets onto a filter&#xD;
      with minimal contamination from upper airway secretions. In preliminary studies in cystic&#xD;
      fibrosis, mycobacterium tuberculosis (TB) patients and control patients, the researchers&#xD;
      detected bacterial DNA by PCR, inflammatory cytokines and chemokines by multiplex Luminex&#xD;
      assays, surfactant by enzyme immunoassay (EIA), and amylase by enzymatic assay. These data&#xD;
      show that this device can provide high quality specimens from the lung with minimal risk to&#xD;
      the patient and healthcare provider and much lower risk than invasive procedures such as&#xD;
      bronchioloalveolar lavage. In addition, with this device, we can acquire specimens from&#xD;
      patients who do not have a productive cough (dry cough), a commonly reported symptom for&#xD;
      COVID-19, and specimens with minimal upper respiratory contamination unlike a sputum&#xD;
      specimen. Thus, this device can provide lung secretion specimens to improve detection of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 RNA (lung specimens are better for detecting virus than upper respiratory tract&#xD;
      specimens) and detect inflammatory and other biomarkers to explore pathogenesis of disease,&#xD;
      identify inflammatory processes that might be amenable to intervention, and identify&#xD;
      biomarkers of disease severity for patient management and evaluation of vaccines and&#xD;
      anti-viral drugs. The goal of this study is to determine how PneumoniaCheck™ can help&#xD;
      diagnose, manage, and understand pathogenesis of disease and transmission risk of COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity of Detecting SARS-CoV-2 RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The percent of correct identification of participants with SARS-CoV-2 infection (true positives) detected by RNA in cough-generated droplets captured with the PneumoCheck.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Specificity of Detecting SARS-CoV-2 RNA</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The percent of correct identification of participants without SARS-CoV-2 infection (true negatives) detected by RNA in cough-generated droplets captured with the PneumoCheck.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of granulocyte-macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including GM-CSF, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of interferon (IFN) alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IFN alpha, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IFN gamma</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IFN gamma, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of interleukin (IL)-1 alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-1 alpha, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-1 beta</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-1 beta, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-4</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-4, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-6</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-6, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-8</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-8, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-10</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-10, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-12p70</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-12p70, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-13</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-13, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of IL-17A</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including IL-17A, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of Tumour Necrosis Factor (TNF) alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory cytokines, including TNF alpha, in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of interferon gamma-induced protein 10 (IP-10) C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 10 (CXCL10)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory chemokines, including IP-10, also known as C-X-C motif chemokine ligand 10 (CXCL10), in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of monocyte chemoattractant protein 1 (MCP-1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory chemokines, including MCP-1, also known as C-C motif chemokine ligand 2 (CCL2), in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of Macrophage inflammatory protein-1 (MIP-1) alpha</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory chemokines, including MIP-1 alpha, also known as C-C motif chemokine ligand 3 (CCL3), in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of MIP-1 beta</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting inflammatory chemokines, including MIP-1 beta, also known as C-C motif chemokine ligand 4 (CCL4), in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of Surfactant A</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Hour 24</time_frame>
    <description>The researchers will detect biomarkers of inflammation in coughed specimens from patient with COVID-19 hypothesizing that biomarkers of inflammation from the lung will indicate disease activity, informing pathogenesis of COVID-19 disease. The value of detecting surfactant A chemokines in cough-generated droplets with PneumoniaCheck from COVID-19 patients will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Positive</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who test positive for SARS-CoV-2 with the Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) test.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-COVID-19 Acute Respiratory Illness</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who have an acute respiratory illness other than SARS-CoV-2 infection.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants without any acute respiratory illness.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PneumoniaCheck</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants are asked to do 5 sets of 10 coughs into the PneumoniaCheck device.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Non-COVID-19 Acute Respiratory Illness</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SARS-CoV-2 Positive</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being treated for an acute respiratory illness either as inpatients or outpatients at&#xD;
             Emory University Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English is a primary spoken language&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  none&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria for Healthy Volunteers:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior registration in an adult participant database and agreed to be contacted for&#xD;
             future studies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English is a primary spoken language&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Larry Anderson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Emory University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Larry Anderson, MD</last_name>
    <phone>404-727-1746</phone>
    <email>larry.anderson@emory.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University Hospital Midtown</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory Children's Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wesley Woods Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30329</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Emory University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Larry J. Anderson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data collected during the trial will be made available for sharing, after deidentification, as consistent with Health Information Privacy and Portability Act (HIPPA) regulations.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be available for sharing following the publication of manuscripts related to the primary aims of this study.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Individual participant data will be available for sharing with researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal, in order to achieve the aims stated in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to Dr. Larry Anderson.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

