<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04910269</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INSIGHT12</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-001663-24</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04910269</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Outpatient Treatment With Anti-Coronavirus Immunoglobulin</brief_title>
  <acronym>OTAC</acronym>
  <official_title>An International Multicenter, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Trial of the Safety and Efficacy of Anti-Coronavirus Hyperimmune Intravenous Immunoglobulin for the Treatment of Adult Outpatients in Early Stages of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>International Network for Strategic Initiatives in Global HIV Trials (INSIGHT)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Minnesota</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of the Outpatient Treatment with Anti-Coronavirus Immunoglobulin (OTAC)&#xD;
      (INSIGHT 012) trial is to compare the safety and efficacy of a single infusion of&#xD;
      anti-COVID-19 hyperimmune intravenous immunoglobulin (hIVIG) versus placebo among adults with&#xD;
      recently diagnosed SARS-CoV-2 infection who do not require hospitalization. The primary&#xD;
      endpoint of this double-blind randomized trial is a five-category ordinal outcome that&#xD;
      assesses the participant's clinical status seven days after the infusion of hIVIG or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Asymptomatic and no limitations in usual activity due to COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild COVID-19 illness or minor limitations to usual activity&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate COVID-19 illness and with major limitations to usual activity&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe COVID-19 or serious disease manifestation from COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Critical illness from COVID-19 or Death&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two strata of participants will be identified for analysis purposes. Stratum 1 will be&#xD;
      participants who receive neutralizing monoclonal antibodies (nMAbs) as standard of care&#xD;
      (SOC), estimated to be about 20% of participants. Stratum 2 will be participants who do not&#xD;
      receive nMAbs, estimated to be about 80% of participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective will be addressed by testing two hypotheses aimed at assessing whether&#xD;
      hIVIG + standard of care (SOC) is superior to placebo + SOC for the primary ordinal endpoint&#xD;
      at Day 7. These hypotheses will be tested for the following two groups: a) among all&#xD;
      randomized participants (stratum 1 and 2), and b) among only participants enrolled in stratum&#xD;
      1. For the primary analysis, overall type 1 error will be controlled at 5% by using a 2-sided&#xD;
      significance level of 0.035 for each hypothesis. This significance level was obtained using&#xD;
      the correlation between the test statistics for the proportional log odds ratio for all&#xD;
      randomized participants and for this log odds ratio for those in stratum 1. This correlation&#xD;
      was determined to be 0.895. With this approach hIVIG will be considered superior to placebo&#xD;
      if either of the two hypotheses is rejected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomized to a single infusion of an hIVIG product (1 of 2) or placebo&#xD;
      in a 1:1:2 allocation. After pooling data from each hIVIG product, this will result in 1:1&#xD;
      allocation for hIVIG versus placebo. Randomization will be stratified by study site pharmacy&#xD;
      and the two SOC strata.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Status</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is to compare the safety and efficacy of a single infusion of hIVIG versus placebo on clinical status after seven days. Outcome will be reported as the percent of participants who fall into each of 5 clinical status categories as defined below.&#xD;
Asymptomatic and no limitations in usual activity due to COVID-19&#xD;
Mild COVID-19 illness or minor limitations to usual activity&#xD;
Moderate COVID-19 illness and with major limitations to usual activity&#xD;
Severe COVID-19 or serious disease manifestation from COVID-19&#xD;
Critical illness from COVID-19 or Death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause hospitalization or death through 28 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome reported as the percent of participants who are hospitalized or who expire for any reason by day 28 post treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality through 28 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome reported as the percent of participants who expire for any reason by day 28 post treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Significant Disease Progression</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the number of participants with significant disease progression through 28 days, which is defined by fulfilling criteria for category 4 or 5 on the ordinal scale using a time to event analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ordinal Scale Distribution</measure>
    <time_frame>4, 14, 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome will be reported as the percent of participants who fall into each of 5 clinical status categories as defined below at days 4, 14, and 28 following treatment.&#xD;
Asymptomatic and no limitations in usual activity due to COVID-19&#xD;
Mild COVID-19 illness or minor limitations to usual activity&#xD;
Moderate COVID-19 illness and with major limitations to usual activity&#xD;
Severe COVID-19 or serious disease manifestation from COVID-19&#xD;
Critical illness from COVID-19 or Death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Progression Through 7 Days</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the proportion of participants with any disease progression at Day 7, using a sliding dichotomous scale progression defined by a categorization on the ordinal scale that is worse than the status at entry.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Significant Disease Progression Through 7 Days</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the proportion of participants who progress to categories 3-5 on the clinical ordinal scale at Day 7 among participants in categories 1 or 2 of the ordinal scale at entry.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Progression at Follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the percent of participants who experience severe disease progression during follow-up, defined by the worst health status achieved on the clinical ordinal scale at any point by Day 7, 14, and 28.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Activity Limitations at Follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>7, 14, 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the percent of participants who attain their pre-COVID health status without limitations in usual activity (defined as category 1 on the ordinal scale) at Day 7, 14, and 28.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Viral Burden from Serum Antigen</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the change between Day 0 and Day 7 in viral burden as determined by serum antigen levels from nasal and saliva specimens.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Viral Burden from PCR</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the change between Day 0 and Day 7 in viral burden as determined by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) from nasal and saliva specimens.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in SARS-CoV-2 Antibody Concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the change in SARS-CoV-2 antibody levels between Day 0 and Day 7, including subclasses and neutralizing titers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Healthcare Utilization at Follow-up</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the percent of participants who had health care engagement for the purposes of medical evaluation and/or management of COVID-19 illness (e.g., via telehealth, clinic, urgent care, emergency room, or hospitalization) at 28 days follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Worst Status Through 28 Days</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the number of participants who experience each of the following categories as their worst respiratory status through 28 days, including: a) no respiratory symptoms, b) upper respiratory symptoms, c) lower respiratory symptoms without hypoxia, c) hypoxia requiring conventional oxygen supplementation by nasal canula, d) respiratory failure requiring high-flow oxygen delivery device or non-invasive ventilation, or e) respiratory failure requiring mechanical ventilation or extra-corporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypoxemia Through Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the mean oxygen saturation (percentage) level in each group at 7 days.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Additional COVID-19 Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the number of patients starting other treatments targeting COVID-19 through 28 days post treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">820</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV2 Infection</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will receive the investigational treatment in addition to standard of care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will receive a placebo in addition to standard of care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hyperimmune immunoglobulin to SARS-CoV-2 (hIVIG)</intervention_name>
    <description>The hIVIG product is administered as a single dose of 30 grams, or 300 milliliter at a concentration of 0.1 grams/milliliter. This dose corresponds to 400 milligrams/kilogram for a 75 kilogram adult.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Infusion of standard isotonic saline</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical risk based on age ≥ 55 years or an adult (age ≥ 18 years) with an&#xD;
             immunosuppressed condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for SARS-CoV-2 within ≤5 days (if &gt;1 test, the first positive is within&#xD;
             ≤5 days). Tests may include an institutional-based nucleic acid amplification test&#xD;
             (NAAT), or any protocol-approved rapid test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within ≤5 days from symptom onset, if symptomatic from current SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to not participate in another clinical trial for the treatment or management of&#xD;
             SARS-CoV-2 infection through Day 7, or until hospitalized or significant disease&#xD;
             progression if prior to Day 7 (defined by ordinal category 4 or 5).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant provides written informed consent prior to study procedures, and&#xD;
             understands and agrees to adhere to planned study procedures through Day 28.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Ongoing immunosuppressive condition or immunosuppressive treatment, includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Steroids equivalent to prednisone &gt; 10 mg/day for at least the last 28 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Rheumatologic or autoimmune disorder treated with a biologic or non-biologic&#xD;
             immunosuppressive therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Antirejection medicine after solid organ or stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Cancer treatment with systemic chemotherapy, biologic and/or cell-based therapy in the&#xD;
             last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Primary or acquired severe B- or T-lymphocyte immune dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Splenectomy or functional asplenia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asymptomatic and had prior symptoms from the current infection that have now resolved&#xD;
             (for &gt;24 hours).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asymptomatic and has received a vaccination for COVID-19 (≥1 dose).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing evaluation for possible admission to hospital for medical management (this&#xD;
             does not include evaluation of possible hospitalization for public health purposes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of pneumonia and/or hypoxia due to COVID-19 (NOTE: chest imaging is not&#xD;
             required, but if available it should not show new infiltrates suggestive of pneumonia;&#xD;
             hypoxia is defined by new oxygen supplementation or increase above pre-illness level).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior receipt of immunoglobulin product or passive immune therapy for SARS-CoV-2 in&#xD;
             the past 90 days (i.e., convalescent plasma, SARS-CoV-2 monoclonal antibodies, or any&#xD;
             IVIG).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following thrombotic or procoagulant conditions or disorders:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. acute coronary syndrome, cerebrovascular syndrome, pulmonary embolism, or deep&#xD;
                  venous thrombosis within 28 days of randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. prothrombin gene mutation 20210, homozygous Factor V Leiden mutations,&#xD;
                  antiphospholipid syndrome, or a deficiency in antithrombin III, protein C, or&#xD;
                  protein S.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to blood, plasma or IVIG excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known IgA deficiency or anti-IgA antibodies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical conditions for which receipt of a 300 mL volume of IV fluid from study&#xD;
             treatment may pose specific risk to the patient (e.g., decompensated congestive heart&#xD;
             failure).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the investigator, any condition for which participation would not be&#xD;
             in the best interest of the participant or that could prevent or confound protocol&#xD;
             assessments.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James Neaton, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Minnesota</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Gary Collins</last_name>
    <phone>612-626-9006</phone>
    <email>gary-c@ccbr.umn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MedStar Health Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Washington DC ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacwdc@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Glenn Wortmann, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington DC Veterans Affairs Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20422</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Washintgon ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacwdc@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Virginia Kan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Medical System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>NIH-DCR ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacnih@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Richard Wilkerson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Infusion Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49525</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>NIH-DCR ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacnih@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Khan Nedd, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Beth Israel Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10003</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Washington DC ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacwdc@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sanjana Koshy, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Washington DC ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacwdc@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Judith Aberg, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hendrick Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Abilene</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>79601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>NIH-DCR ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacnih@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Canario, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UT Southwestern Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Washington DC ICC</last_name>
      <email>otacwdc@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mamta Jain, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Odense University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Odense</city>
        <state>C</state>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Copenhagen ICC</last_name>
      <email>otaccph@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Isik Somuncu Johansen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aarhus Universitetshospital, Skejby</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aarhus</city>
        <state>N</state>
        <zip>8200</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Copenhagen ICC</last_name>
      <email>otaccph@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lars Østergaard, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rigshospitalet, CHIP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Copenhagen ICC</last_name>
      <email>otaccph@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marie Helleberg, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Herlev/Gentofte Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hellerup</city>
        <zip>2900</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Copenhagen ICC</last_name>
      <email>otaccph@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jens Ulrik Stæhr Jensen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hvidovre University Hospital, Department of Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hvidovre</city>
        <zip>2650</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Copenhagen ICC</last_name>
      <email>otaccph@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas Benfield, MN</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kolding Sygehus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kolding</city>
        <zip>6000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Copenhagen ICC</last_name>
      <email>otaccph@insight-trials.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Birgit Røge, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>hIVIG</keyword>
  <keyword>early treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins, Intravenous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Antibodies</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>A public data set will be made available at the end of the trial.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

