<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04912323</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TP-1501</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04912323</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of the R3 Vascular Drug-Eluting Bioresorbable Scaffold in Treating Below the Knee Arterial Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>RESOLV I</acronym>
  <official_title>The R3 Vascular Drug-Eluting Bioresorbable Scaffold in Below the Knee Vessels Trial (RESOLV I)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>R3 Vascular Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>VasCore Vascular Ultrasound Core Lab</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cardiovascular Research Foundation Clinical Trials Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>R3 Vascular Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This first-in-human clinical feasibility study will evaluate the safety and performance of&#xD;
      the R3 Vascular MAGNITUDE® Bioresorbable Drug-Eluting Scaffold and Delivery System in&#xD;
      patients undergoing treatment for peripheral arterial disease severe enough to have&#xD;
      significantly reduced the blood supply to their leg. The severe reduction in blood flow&#xD;
      causes lifestyle limiting leg pain for these patients, and may lead to amputation of the&#xD;
      affected limb due to the loss of tissue in the leg or foot from ulcers or gangrene. The&#xD;
      investigational device being studied in this trial is intended to restore blood flow to the&#xD;
      affected limb, providing symptomatic relief to the patient and reducing the risk of limb&#xD;
      amputation. The scaffold is a type of vascular stent placed within the diseased artery below&#xD;
      the knee to improve blood flow. Unlike commercially available metallic stents which are&#xD;
      permanently placed within the artery, the MAGNITUDE® Bioresorbable scaffold is made of a&#xD;
      polymer material that will completely dissolve away over time, providing the support&#xD;
      necessary to the artery while it is healing after the treatment procedure and then slowly&#xD;
      disappearing from the artery once that support is no longer needed. The investigational&#xD;
      scaffold has been successfully used to treat vascular blockages in the coronary arteries of&#xD;
      the heart, but the RESOLV I study will be the first time this device has been used to improve&#xD;
      blood flow in the arteries of the lower leg. Patients enrolled in this study may have up to&#xD;
      three vascular blockages in their lower leg arteries treated with the MAGNITUDE®&#xD;
      Bioresorbable scaffold, and then will be assessed over the course of the following five years&#xD;
      to evaluate whether the investigational treatment was successful in safely alleviating their&#xD;
      leg pain and other symptoms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The prevalence of peripheral artery disease (PAD) is estimated to be over 200 million.&#xD;
      Critical limb ischemia (CLI) is considered the most advanced stage of PAD, occurring in about&#xD;
      10% of PAD patients. CLI patients typically present with ischemic rest pain, nonhealing&#xD;
      ulcerations, infection, and/or gangrene. It is associated with a high risk of major&#xD;
      amputation (lower limb amputations in 10% - 40% of patients at 6 months), cardiovascular&#xD;
      events, and death (mortality rate of 20% within 6 months after the diagnosis and 50% at 5&#xD;
      years). A large percentage of CLI patients have occlusive disease in the infrapopliteal&#xD;
      artery, especially in diabetics where PAD is 3 - 4 times more common. CLI related to diabetes&#xD;
      is often more extensive, with multiple long segmental occlusions resulting in a 5 - 30-fold&#xD;
      increase in the rate of amputations. Surgical and catheter-based revascularization procedures&#xD;
      are typically performed to restore distal perfusion and prevent amputation in symptomatic&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical bypass has been shown to be an effective treatment when anatomic and patient risk&#xD;
      factors permit this approach. However, patients with CLI are often poor surgical candidates&#xD;
      because of the absence of suitable graft vessels or the presence of significant medical&#xD;
      comorbidities. During the past decade, therapies such as percutaneous transluminal&#xD;
      angioplasty (PTA) and percutaneous treatment with balloons or the off-label use of coronary&#xD;
      stents that deliver antiproliferative drugs directly to the vessel wall to inhibit neointimal&#xD;
      hyperplasia have been on the rise and have decreased the rates of open bypass surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Percutaneous transluminal angioplasty has become the first line revascularization therapy for&#xD;
      patients with symptomatic peripheral artery disease. Published literature indicates that&#xD;
      while uncoated balloon angioplasty has a high rate of technical success in obtaining a patent&#xD;
      lumen, restenosis requiring repeat revascularization or amputation is common. For&#xD;
      femoropopliteal (above the knee) disease, percutaneous treatment with a balloon that delivers&#xD;
      an antiproliferative agent (usually paclitaxel) directly to the vessel wall inhibits&#xD;
      neointimal hyperplasia and significantly reduces the rate of target lesion revascularization&#xD;
      and restenosis, while maintaining a safety profile comparable to that of uncoated balloons.&#xD;
      On the other hand, drug-coated balloon (DCB) therapy in the infrapopliteal (below the knee)&#xD;
      arteries has not shown similarly convincing evidence of superiority over PTA, and in general,&#xD;
      the use of DCB below the knee remains controversial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metallic drug-eluting stents have been shown to effective in reducing both abrupt vessel&#xD;
      closure and restenosis rates in the management of peripheral vascular disease. However,&#xD;
      metallic implants also negatively impact the vessel wall by permanently preventing&#xD;
      vasomotion, autoregulation, and adaptive remodeling. In addition, there is a risk of late&#xD;
      vessel failure due to incomplete endothelialization of the implant, stent fracture, or&#xD;
      malapposition. Metallic implants may also cause artifacts with noninvasive imaging and&#xD;
      complicate future revascularization procedures. Bioresorbable scaffolds provide similar&#xD;
      mechanical properties to metallic stents during the blood vessel remodeling phase following&#xD;
      angioplasty, while also delivering an antiproliferative drug to the site of vascular injury&#xD;
      to minimize neointimal hyperplasia. However, once these tasks are complete, the scaffold&#xD;
      begins a reabsorption process and eventually disappears entirely from the vessel, leaving the&#xD;
      native artery free of any implant. For these reasons, bioresorbable scaffolds may offer a new&#xD;
      standard for restorative therapy in the peripheral vasculature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This first-in-human clinical feasibility study of the R3 Vascular MAGNITUDE® scaffold will&#xD;
      evaluate the safety and performance of a bioresorbable scaffold with a thin strut design (98&#xD;
      µm wall thickness) and a coating of the antiproliferative drug Sirolimus for treating&#xD;
      patients with lifestyle limiting claudication or chronic limb threatening ischemia. The&#xD;
      objective is to perform an initial evaluation of the investigational device in a patient&#xD;
      population undergoing percutaneous transluminal intervention with stenting for the treatment&#xD;
      of infrapopliteal artery lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The thin strut design of the MAGNITUDE® scaffold offers improved deliverability and the&#xD;
      potential for higher vessel patency rates compared to other thicker strut bioresorbable&#xD;
      scaffolds currently under investigation for this particular indication. In addition, compared&#xD;
      with metallic stents, the R3 Vascular bioresorbable scaffold provides sustained support to&#xD;
      the vessel wall following revascularization while vascular healing occurs, after which the&#xD;
      scaffold predictably degrades leaving no permanent implant behind. The MAGNITUDE® scaffold&#xD;
      has been shown to be biocompatible, maintain mechanical integrity over time, and provide&#xD;
      controlled drug release through extensive validations in pre-clinical testing and clinical&#xD;
      studies enrolling approximately 200 patients being treated for coronary artery disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The RESOLV I clinical investigation is a prospective, single-arm, multi-center first-in-human&#xD;
      feasibility study of the R3 Vascular MAGNITUDE® Bioresorbable Drug-Eluting Scaffold and&#xD;
      Delivery System for treating vascular disease in the infrapopliteal arteries. It will enroll&#xD;
      a maximum of 30 patients from up to 9 investigational centers in Italy, Austria, and Canada.&#xD;
      Eligible patients who are at least 18 years of age with lifestyle limiting claudication or&#xD;
      chronic limb threatening ischemia (Rutherford-Becker categories 3 - 5) that elect to undergo&#xD;
      revascularization with stenting of up to three different de novo or restenotic infrapopliteal&#xD;
      artery lesions will be treated with the investigational device and followed for five years&#xD;
      post-implantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety of the investigational scaffold will be assessed at 6 months as the composite rate of&#xD;
      Major Adverse Limb Events (above ankle amputation in the index limb or major re-intervention)&#xD;
      and peri-operative (30-day) mortality. Performance of the device will be evaluated as the&#xD;
      primary patency rate of the treated vessels at 6 months, assessed by angiography. Multiple&#xD;
      other angiographic, duplex ultrasound, and clinical assessments will be performed during the&#xD;
      5-year follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is expected that the subjects enrolled in this study will experience the same benefits as&#xD;
      patients treated with the currently available coronary (used off label in the peripheral&#xD;
      arteries) drug-eluting metallic stents. Treatment with the investigational scaffold may&#xD;
      provide physicians with a promising alternative to permanent stenting, which has been shown&#xD;
      to interfere with future treatments such as PTA or surgery. Additionally, since the&#xD;
      investigational scaffold is designed to provide mechanical support to the target lesion for&#xD;
      the required healing period post-treatment and disappear once healing is complete, this may&#xD;
      allow for positive remodeling of the artery and reduce the risk of late complications (i.e.,&#xD;
      endothelial cell proliferation, restenosis, thrombosis, etc.).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>All subjects will receive the investigational device</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>(Safety) Freedom from MALE and POD</measure>
    <time_frame>MALE is assessed at 180 days and POD is assessed at 30 days (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Composite endpoint of freedom from Major Adverse Limb Event (&quot;MALE&quot;, which includes above ankle amputation in the index limb or major re-intervention) and Peri-Operative Death (&quot;POD&quot;)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>(Performance) Primary Patency of the Target Lesion(s)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 180 days (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Freedom from hemodynamically significant stenosis by angiography (≥ 50% diameter stenosis), or duplex ultrasound (absence of flow per core lab) when angiography is not available, without additional target lesion revascularization</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Technical Success</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed from start of treatment procedure to end of treatment procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as delivery and deployment of the scaffold to the target lesion resulting in a final angiographic in-lesion percent diameter stenosis ≤ 30%</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Procedural Success</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed from start of treatment procedure to hospital discharge after treatment procedure, approximately same day or day after treatment procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as Technical Success without procedural Major Adverse Event (which includes thrombosis, distal embolization, or vessel rupture)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Angiographic Acute Gain</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 180 days (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the difference between the post- and pre-procedural minimal lumen diameter within the scaffold and within the scaffolded vessel segment as assessed by angiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Angiographic Late Lumen Loss</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 180 days (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the difference between the post-procedural and follow-up minimal lumen diameter within the scaffold and within the scaffolded vessel segment as assessed by angiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Angiographic Binary Restenosis</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 180 days (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as a &gt; 50% diameter stenosis within the scaffold and within the scaffolded vessel segment at follow-up as assessed by angiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duplex Ultrasound Detection of Arterial Flow</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 6, and 12 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of the presence or absence of blood flow within the target lesion(s) and vessel(s)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-Cause Death</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 3, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as patient mortality due to any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinically Driven Target Lesion Revascularization</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 3, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as revascularization for a target lesion if the target lesion diameter stenosis is &gt; 70% by angiography, or &gt; 50% and the subject has ischemia that cannot be explained by another lesion, or ≤ 50% if severe ischemic signs are attributable to the target lesion.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Freedom from Composite of Target Lesion Occlusion, Clinically Driven Target Lesion Revascularization, and Major Amputation</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 3, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Subject has not experienced occlusion of the target lesion necessitating revascularization due to ischemic symptoms or amputation of the target limb.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Rutherford-Becker Classification from Enrollment</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 3, 6, 12, 24, 36, 48 and 60 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Change between the pre-treatment and follow-up assessments of the symptomatic classification of the subject's chronic limb ischemia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Ankle-Brachial Index (ABI) from Enrollment</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 3, 6, and 12 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Change between the pre-treatment and follow-up assessments of the comparison of the blood pressure measured at the ankle with the blood pressure measured at the arm to gauge the degree of arterial narrowing in the leg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Toe-Brachial Index (TBI) from Enrollment</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 1, 3, 6, and 12 months (post implantation procedure)</time_frame>
    <description>Change between the pre-treatment and follow-up assessments of the comparison of the blood pressure measured at the toes with the blood pressure measured at the arm to gauge the degree of arterial narrowing in the leg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Arterial Disease</condition>
  <condition>Atherosclerotic Lesion</condition>
  <condition>Lower Extremity Ischemia</condition>
  <condition>Lower Extremity Claudication</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MAGNITUDE® Scaffold</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject with up to three study lesions treated by implanting a maximum of 3 R3 Vascular MAGNITUDE® Bioresorbable Drug-Eluting Scaffolds</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Percutaneous Implantation of the MAGNITUDE® Bioresorbable Arterial Scaffold</intervention_name>
    <description>Placement of one or more MAGNITUDE® bioresorbable scaffolds using a percutaneous technique at one or more arterial stenoses.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MAGNITUDE® Scaffold</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is ≥ 18 years and ≤ 90 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject agrees not to participate in any other investigational device or drug study&#xD;
             for a period of at least six months following the index procedure. Questionnaire-based&#xD;
             studies, or other studies that are non-invasive and do not require investigational&#xD;
             devices or medications are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject (or their legally authorized representative) provides written informed consent&#xD;
             prior to any study-related procedure, using the form approved by the local Ethics&#xD;
             Committee.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has lifestyle limiting claudication or chronic limb threatening ischemia&#xD;
             (Rutherford-Becker categories 3 - 5).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject agrees to complete all protocol required follow-up visits, including&#xD;
             angiograms.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has suitable common femoral (contralateral or antegrade ipsilateral) vascular&#xD;
             access. (Note: Radial or pedal access not allowed.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has up to three de novo or restenotic native infrapopliteal lesions with &gt; 70%&#xD;
             stenosis by angiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lesion(s) must be located in the proximal 2/3 of native infrapopliteal vessels and at&#xD;
             least 10 cm above the tibio-talar joint.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reference vessel(s) diameter of 2.5 - 3.5 mm by IVUS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A maximum of three scaffolds can be implanted per patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scaffold(s) must cover at least 2 mm from the pre-dilatation borders, resulting in a&#xD;
             maximum allowed lesion length of 14 mm for a single scaffold, 31 mm for two&#xD;
             overlapping scaffolds (using the marker overlap technique), or 47 mm for three&#xD;
             overlapping scaffolds (using the marker overlap technique).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tandem non-contiguous lesions, if present, having plaque-free zones between the&#xD;
             lesions of ≥ 2 cm can be treated with any combination of up to three scaffolds (1-1-1,&#xD;
             1-2, or 2-1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lesion (most distal lesion if more than one is being treated) must be successfully&#xD;
             crossed in antegrade fashion with a guidewire. (Note: The most distal lesion should be&#xD;
             treated before treating more proximal lesions.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Target lesion(s) preparation prior to scaffold placement with non-compliant balloon&#xD;
             (1:1 balloon:artery ratio) must achieve &lt; 50% residual diameter stenosis by&#xD;
             angiography. (Note: The use of specialty balloons such as cutting, scoring, serration,&#xD;
             or the Chocolate PTA balloon in 1:1 balloon:artery ratio is allowed if required lesion&#xD;
             preparation not achieved with the initial non-compliant balloon. Atherectomy is not&#xD;
             allowed.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inflow above-the-knee lesions (&gt; 50% diameter stenosis by angiography), if present,&#xD;
             must be treated successfully using the standard of care per site prior to target&#xD;
             lesion(s). (Note: Inflow lesions may be treated during the index procedure.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-target below-the-knee lesions in other non-target vessels, if present, may be&#xD;
             treated at the discretion of the investigator per standard of care, but must be&#xD;
             treated successfully prior to the target lesion(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one fully patent below-the-ankle artery (i.e., dorsalis pedis; common,&#xD;
             lateral, or medial plantar arteries) without hemodynamically significant lesions (≥&#xD;
             50% diameter stenosis by angiography) must be present in the target limb.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing subjects and those who plan pregnancy within 6 months following&#xD;
             index procedure. (Note: Subjects of child-bearing potential must have a negative&#xD;
             pregnancy test ≤ 28 days prior to the index procedure and agree to use contraception&#xD;
             for 6 months.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of other significant comorbid conditions, or other medical, social, or&#xD;
             psychological conditions (such as history of substance {alcohol, cocaine, heroin,&#xD;
             etc.} abuse), that in the investigator's opinion may limit the subject's ability to&#xD;
             participate or comply with study instructions and follow-up (includes subjects with&#xD;
             symptomatic COVID-19 infection in the past 2 months or asymptomatic COVID-19 positive&#xD;
             test in the past 1 month).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incapacitated individuals, defined as persons who are mentally ill, mentally&#xD;
             handicapped, or individuals without legal authority to control their activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of &lt; 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is non-ambulatory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has prior major amputation (either limb).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has chronic renal insufficiency stage 4 or above or requires dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has known hypersensitivity or contraindication to device materials and their&#xD;
             degradants (sirolimus, poly (L-lactide), poly (D, L-lactide), lactic acid, or&#xD;
             platinum-iridium) or to study medications (including antiplatelet medications) or to&#xD;
             contrast media and who cannot be adequately premedicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with planned surgery or procedure necessitating discontinuation of&#xD;
             antiplatelet medications within 6 months after the index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has active systemic infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a prior stroke or MI within 3 months of the index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has presence of osteomyelitis or any gangrene above the metatarsal-phalangeal&#xD;
             joints, extensive tissue loss with exposed tendons or requiring complex or recurrent&#xD;
             surgeries, full thickness heel ulcer, or pure neuropathic ulcers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is receiving immunosuppression therapy and/or has known immunosuppressive or&#xD;
             autoimmune disease (e.g., human immunodeficiency virus, systemic lupus erythematosus,&#xD;
             rheumatoid arthritis, severe asthma requiring immunosuppressive medication, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has active malignancy (receiving or scheduled to receive anticancer therapy&#xD;
             for malignancy within 1 year prior to or after the index procedure), active blood&#xD;
             dyscrasia or coagulation disorder (platelet count &lt; 100,000 cells/mm3 or &gt; 700,000&#xD;
             cells/mm3, a WBC &lt; 3,000 cells/mm3, or hemoglobin &lt; 8.0 g/dl).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with uncontrolled diabetes with HbA1c &gt; 10%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with Body Mass Index (BMI) &lt; 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Revascularization procedure within the target vessel in the previous 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned surgical or endovascular procedures within 30 days. (Note: A planned minor&#xD;
             amputation is allowed.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The target vessel(s) have any other distal hemodynamically significant lesions (≥ 50%&#xD;
             diameter stenosis by angiography).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lesions in which successful predilation cannot be achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Target lesion location requires bifurcation treatment method that requires scaffolding&#xD;
             of both branches (provisional treatment, without the need of scaffolding use in a side&#xD;
             branch is acceptable).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of aneurysm or acute thrombus in the aorta or lower extremity arteries.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior below-the-knee bypass in the target limb.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previously stented lesion(s) or the presence of stents in the target vessel.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan F Granada, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Foundation (CRF)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrew J Ford, Jr.</last_name>
    <phone>650-537-4145</phone>
    <email>aford@r3vascular.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University Graz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Priska Hirschmann</last_name>
      <phone>+43 316 385 12344</phone>
      <email>priska.hirschmann@medunigraz.at</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marianne Brodmann, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CRCHUM Université Montreal</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Satterthwaite</last_name>
      <phone>+1 514 8908000</phone>
      <phone_ext>23483</phone_ext>
      <email>jennifer.satterthwaite.chum@ssss.gouv.qc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gilles Soulez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Saint-Francois d'Assise</name>
      <address>
        <city>Québec</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Guylaine Nadeau</last_name>
      <phone>+1 418 5254444</phone>
      <phone_ext>53281</phone_ext>
      <email>guylaine.nadeau@chudequebec.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francois Cote, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Toronto General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Iris Zhong</last_name>
      <phone>+1 416 9464501</phone>
      <phone_ext>4816</phone_ext>
      <email>iris.zhong@uhn.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kong Teng Tan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>San Donato Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arezzo</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Silvia Innocenti</last_name>
      <phone>+39 339 7750594</phone>
      <email>silvia.innocenti@uslsudest.toscana.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francesco Liistro, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maria Cecilia Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cotignola</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria L Lunetto</last_name>
      <phone>+39 0545 217032</phone>
      <email>llunetto@gvmnet.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Luis M Palena, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Multimedica</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tiziana Staine</last_name>
      <phone>+39 022 4209807</phone>
      <email>tiziana.staine@multimedica.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Flavio Airoldi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Claudication</keyword>
  <keyword>Leg Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Lower Extremities</keyword>
  <keyword>Lower Limb</keyword>
  <keyword>Blocked Leg Artery</keyword>
  <keyword>Limb Ischemia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intermittent Claudication</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

