<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04915521</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>09.2020.128</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04915521</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Erector Spinalis Plane Block in Bariatric Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Ultrasound-guided Erector Spinalis Plane Block on Postoperative Pain and Intraoperative Opioid Consumption in Bariatric Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Meliha Orhon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Marmara University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background/objective: Bariatric surgery is often associated with moderate to severe pain. In&#xD;
      obese individuals, opioids have the potential to induce ventilatory impairment; thus, opioid&#xD;
      use needs to be limited. This study aimed to compare the novel ultrasound-guided erector&#xD;
      spinalis plane block (ESPB) technique with controls in terms of intraoperative opioid&#xD;
      consumption and postoperative pain control. Methods: A total of 63 patients with morbid&#xD;
      obesity who underwent laparoscopic bariatric surgery were included in this randomized study.&#xD;
      Patients were randomly assigned to the bilateral erector spina plane block (ESPB) group or&#xD;
      the control group. To evaluate perioperative pain and to adjust opioid dose, analgesia&#xD;
      nociception index (ANI) was monitored during surgery. Total opioid dose was recorded for each&#xD;
      patient. In addition, pain was evaluated using visual analogue scale (VAS) scores for 24&#xD;
      hours following the operation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Obesity represents a major disease burden and healthcare challenge globally due to its&#xD;
      increasing prevalence over the last decades. From 1980 to 2013, worldwide prevalence of&#xD;
      overweight/obesity increased by 27·5% for adults and 47·1% for children, resulting in an&#xD;
      estimated global total number of obese/overweight individuals slightly more than two billion.&#xD;
      Obesity is associated with serious conditions including cardiovascular disease, diabetes,&#xD;
      some cancers, kidney disease, sleep apnea, gout, osteoarthritis, hepatobiliary disease,&#xD;
      resulting in increased mortality and decreased life expectancy among obese individuals. On&#xD;
      the other hand, weight loss leads to improvement of these conditions and outcomes. Life-style&#xD;
      modifications with diet, exercise, and behavioral therapy, pharmacotherapy, and surgery are&#xD;
      used for the management of obesity. Bariatric surgery represents an effective and a&#xD;
      sustainable treatment modality in patients with morbid obesity, laparoscopic sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomy and gastric bypass being the most common procedures. However, these procedures&#xD;
      are mostly associated with moderate to severe postoperative pain, which is often a&#xD;
      combination of abdominal wall pain and visceral pain.Postoperative pain, when not adequately&#xD;
      controlled, has unfavorable consequences such as impaired quality of life and recovery as&#xD;
      well as increased risk of surgical complications and persistent postsurgical pain. Patients&#xD;
      with morbid obesity represent a special group when it comes to perioperative pain management.&#xD;
      These patients have a higher incidence of sleep-disordered breathing; therefore, opioids have&#xD;
      the potential to induce ventilatory impairment resulting in increased morbidity/mortality.&#xD;
      Stepwise and severity based-multi-modal analgesia with opioid-sparing approach can improve&#xD;
      safety; thus, Enhanced Recovery After Surgery (ERAS) guidelines for bariatric surgery&#xD;
      currently recommend opioid reduction in bariatric surgery. Both systemic analgesics and&#xD;
      regional approaches such as transversus abdominis plane (TAP) block, intraperitoneal and&#xD;
      wound modalities, and neuraxial techniques are being used for postoperative pain control in&#xD;
      bariatric surgery with some success.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasound-guided erector spinae plane block is a novel regional anesthesia technique where&#xD;
      local anesthetic agent is injected deep into the erector spinae muscle to the fascial plane&#xD;
      and allowed to diffuse in caudal and cranial direction. It has been shown effective in a&#xD;
      number of conditions such as thoracic surgery/trauma, painful conditions of the limbs,&#xD;
      cardiac surgery, breast surgery, and abdominal surgery. To date, only few studies examined&#xD;
      the use of ESPB in bariatric surgery, all indicating potential benefits of the technique in&#xD;
      terms of opioid sparing and pain control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aimed to compare bilateral ultrasound-guided erector spinalis plane block&#xD;
      technique with controls who received bupivacaine injection to the trocar sites, in terms of&#xD;
      intraoperative opioid consumption, postoperative pain control in the first 24 hours, and need&#xD;
      for rescue analgesic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients Sixty-two patients with morbid obesity who underwent laparoscopic&#xD;
      bariatric/metabolic surgery (sleeve gastrectomy or gastric bypass) were included in this&#xD;
      randomized study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients were required to have a BMI ≥40 kg/m 2 and ASA physical status class 2 or 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion/drop-out criteria were as follows: any complication (allergic reaction or local&#xD;
      anesthesia-related complication), failure, or patient refusal during the block procedure;&#xD;
      switch to open surgery or a change in the planned surgical protocol; analgesia nociception&#xD;
      index (ANI) and/or bispectral index (BIS) monitoring not possible; or patient does not&#xD;
      provide consent or withdraws consent at any point after inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol was approved by local ethics committee (Ethics Committee for Clinical&#xD;
      Studies, Marmara University, Medical Faculty; date, January 3, 2020; number, 09.2020.128).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients provided informed consent prior to study entry and the study was conducted in&#xD;
      accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization to the study groups Patients were randomly assigned to the erector spina plane&#xD;
      block (ESPB) group or the control group using sealed envelopes with 1:1 ratio. ESPB group&#xD;
      received ultrasound-guided bupivacaine and lidocaine injection at T9 vertebral level before&#xD;
      anesthesia induction. Control group received 5 ml 0.5% bupivacaine injection to each trocar&#xD;
      site (total of 25 ml) at the beginning of the operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Erector spinalis plane block technique&#xD;
&#xD;
      An experienced anesthesiologist performed ESPB in all patients in sitting position&#xD;
      bilaterally.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A linear ultrasound probe (6-13 MHz) was used for ultrasound guidance. Injection was done&#xD;
      using in-plane technique. A 22G block needle (100mm, B-Braun, Germany) was inserted 3- cm&#xD;
      lateral to the T9 spinous process and advanced in cranio-caudal direction. To separate&#xD;
      erector spina muscle from the transverse process, initially 1-2 ml saline was injected; then&#xD;
      20ml 0.5% bupivacaine and 5 ml 0.2% lidocaine were injected following separation. Diffusion&#xD;
      of the drugs in erector spina plane at cranio-caudal line was ensured. No analgesic or&#xD;
      sedative was used during the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intraoperative anesthesia management Anesthesia was induced with propofol 2.5-3.5 mg/kg and 1&#xD;
      mcg/kg bolus dose of remifentanil, which was followed by rocuronium 0.6 mg/kg to aid&#xD;
      intubation. Corrected body weight (CBW) was used for the dose adjustment of propofol, and&#xD;
      ideal body weight (IBW) was used for the dose adjustments of remifentanil and rocuronium.&#xD;
      Total intravenous anesthesia with propofol and remifentanil was used for maintenance and the&#xD;
      initial doses were as follows: propofol 6-10 mg/kg/h and remifentanil 0.5 mcg/kg/h. Propofol&#xD;
      and remifentanil dose was adjusted to keep BIS between 40 and 45, and ANI between 50 and 70,&#xD;
      respectively. Electrocardiography, non-invasive blood pressure, bispectral index (BIS,&#xD;
      Medtronic, Mineapolis), and ANI were continuously monitored and recorded at every 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate perioperative pain and to adjust opioid dose, ANI was continuously monitored&#xD;
      throughout the surgical procedure. Two ANI electrodes were placed on the sternum and at the&#xD;
      level of left nipple (to the same places with V1 and V5 ECG electrodes, respectively). Total&#xD;
      remifentanil dose was recorded for each patient. Depth of anesthesia was monitored to adjust&#xD;
      propofol dose using BIS (Aspect Medical Systems, Natick, Mass, ABD).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fifteen minutes before the completion of the surgical procedure, both groups received 1 g&#xD;
      paracetamol and the control group received 150 mg tramadol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessments The primary outcome measure was total intraoperative opioid consumption, and the&#xD;
      secondary outcome measure was the change in postoperative pain as assessed by 10-point visual&#xD;
      analogue scale (VAS). A blinded investigator recorded self-assessed VAS scores of the&#xD;
      patients upon awakening and at 6, 12, and 24 hours. In case VAS ≥ 4, rescue analgesic was&#xD;
      given (100 mg tramadol). Timing of first analgesic requirement was recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis Data were analyzed using SPSS (Statistical Package for Social Sciences)&#xD;
      version 21 software. Mean ± standard deviation or median (range) was used to express&#xD;
      descriptive data. Both hypothesis tests and graphical method were used to test the&#xD;
      distribution of continuous variables. Student t test for independent samples or Mann-Whitney&#xD;
      U test was used to test between-group differences. Fisher's exact test was used to compare&#xD;
      the two groups in terms of complication frequencies. Two-way ANOVA test for repeated&#xD;
      measurements was used to examine the significance of differences between groups in&#xD;
      postoperative VAS scores and intraoperative measurements over time. Two-sided p values&#xD;
      &amp;lt;0.05 were considered indication of statistical significance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 10, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 3, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>total intraoperative opioid consumption,</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperatif first 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate intraoperatif opioid consumption, ANI was continuously monitored throughout the surgical procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>measure vas the change in postoperative pain</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6, 12, and 24 hours.</time_frame>
    <description>measure vas the change in postoperative pain as assessed by 10-point visual analogue scale (VAS).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Postoperative Pain</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Consumption</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>erector spinae plane block group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>ESPB group received ultrasound-guided bupivacaine and lidocaine injection at T9 vertebral level before anesthesia induction.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>non block control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group received 5 ml 0.5% bupivacaine injection to each trocar site (total of 25 ml) at the beginning of the operation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>erector spina plane block (ESPB) group</intervention_name>
    <description>An experienced anesthesiologist performed ESPB in all patients in sitting position bilaterally.&#xD;
A linear ultrasound probe (6-13 MHz) was used for ultrasound guidance. Injection was done using in-plane technique. A 22G block needle (100mm, B-Braun, Germany) was inserted 3- cm lateral to the T9 spinous process and advanced in cranio-caudal direction. To separate erector spina muscle from the transverse process, initially 1-2 ml saline was injected; then 20 ml 0.5% bupivacaine and 5 ml 0.2% lidocaine were injected following separation. Diffusion of the drugs in erector spina plane at cranio-caudal line was ensured. No analgesic or sedative was used during the procedure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>erector spinae plane block group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>non-block control group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients were required to have a BMI ≥40 kg/m&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA physical status class 2 or 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any complication (allergic reaction or local anesthesia-related complication)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  failure, or patient refusal during the block procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  switch to open surgery or a change in the planned surgical protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  analgesia nociception index (ANI) and/or bispectral index (BIS) monitoring not&#xD;
             possible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient does not provide consent or withdraws consent at any point after inclusion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>MELIHA ORHON ERGUN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Marmara University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Marmara University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <state>Maltepe</state>
        <zip>34854</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Marmara University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Meliha Orhon</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>bariatric surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>morbid obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>ultrasound-guidance</keyword>
  <keyword>erector spinalis plane block (ESPB)</keyword>
  <keyword>visual analogue scale (VAS) score</keyword>
  <keyword>opioids</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pain, Postoperative</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

