<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04914585</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0001 (IRB 0485-19)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04914585</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Automatic Optical Identification of the Spine Vertebrate Using Three-dimensional Optical Detection Based on a CT Test</brief_title>
  <official_title>Automatic Optical Identification of the Spine Vertebrate Using Three-dimensional Optical Detection Based on a CT Test</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Deep Health Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Deep Health Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      CT scans of the spine include vertebrae, intervertebral discs and the spinal cord. These&#xD;
      tests are performed in an orderly protocol and allow for three-dimensional reconstruction of&#xD;
      the vertebra in sagittal and coronal guides.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In spinal surgery, there are a number of navigation technologies based on CT scans performed&#xD;
      before surgery (or during surgery) and identify the vertebrae (using special photographs or&#xD;
      markers on the spine), such as Mazor with the Renaissance Robotic Surgical System used in&#xD;
      hospitals, or BrianLab Which uses non-robotic navigation and is based on a marker located on&#xD;
      the patient's back. These technologies are not optimal, and have a number of significant&#xD;
      drawbacks: Because during spinal surgery, there is a displacement, the level of accuracy&#xD;
      decreases as the surgery progresses. In addition, there is extensive use of radiation in&#xD;
      these means since in many cases CT is performed before and during surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Today, in the age of optical detection, it is possible to detect three-dimensional structures&#xD;
      in photography and allow high levels of accuracy (less than 0.5 mm). Optical scanning does&#xD;
      not include radiation and lasts the entire length of the operation. Of the patient and of the&#xD;
      treating staff.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>DEEP HEALTH's detection algorithm for optical detection of vertebrae in the spine in patients undergoing spinal surgery.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Verify an algorithm for automatic detection of vertebrae in the spine, while building an optical model for optical identification in the operating room, and reducing the need for radiation use during spinal surgery.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Spinal Surgery of Vertebrae, Intervertebral Discs and the Spinal Cord</condition>
  <condition>CT Scans</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Candidates for spinal surgery in the Orthopedics department at Hadassah medical center who&#xD;
        have a previous CT scan of the spine. The participant will receive an explanation and will&#xD;
        undergo a process of informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  men and women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 and above years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have available spinal CT tests will be included in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are about to undergo spinal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NA&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ben Metz</last_name>
    <phone>+972-546921978</phone>
    <email>ben.metz@deep-health.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Farah K, Coudert P, Graillon T, Blondel B, Dufour H, Gille O, Fuentes S. Prospective Comparative Study in Spine Surgery Between O-Arm and Airo Systems: Efficacy and Radiation Exposure. World Neurosurg. 2018 Oct;118:e175-e184. doi: 10.1016/j.wneu.2018.06.148. Epub 2018 Jul 3.</citation>
    <PMID>30257292</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gebhard F, Weidner A, Liener UC, Stöckle U, Arand M. Navigation at the spine. Injury. 2004 Jun;35 Suppl 1:S-A35-45. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15183702</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mendelsohn D, Strelzow J, Dea N, Ford NL, Batke J, Pennington A, Yang K, Ailon T, Boyd M, Dvorak M, Kwon B, Paquette S, Fisher C, Street J. Patient and surgeon radiation exposure during spinal instrumentation using intraoperative computed tomography-based navigation. Spine J. 2016 Mar;16(3):343-54. doi: 10.1016/j.spinee.2015.11.020. Epub 2015 Dec 10.</citation>
    <PMID>26686604</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>spinal surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>CT scans</keyword>
  <keyword>surgical navigation</keyword>
  <keyword>optical tracking</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

