<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04911972</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GN17OR618</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04911972</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Functional Muscle Transfers in Lower Limb Sarcoma: 3D Gait Analysis and Environmental Simulation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Functional Muscle Transfers to Restore Normal Function After Major Lower Limb Sarcoma/ Trauma - Assessment by Gait Analysis and Virtual Reality Environmental Simulation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Strathclyde</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess patient's function after functional limb restoring&#xD;
      surgery, performed after ablative tumour surgery or trauma. However, there are no studies as&#xD;
      yet providing objective proof of the recovery of function after this type of surgery. This&#xD;
      study will use 3D Gait Analysis, Environmental simulation and Patient Reported Outcome&#xD;
      Measures to compare patients with function restoring surgery against patients without&#xD;
      function restoring surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to assess patient's function after functional limb restoring&#xD;
      surgery, performed after ablative tumour surgery or trauma. However, there are no studies as&#xD;
      yet providing objective proof of the recovery of function after this type of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background information including literature review&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sarcoma surgery has progressed from limb amputation to limb preserving surgery since the&#xD;
      early 1980s. Although this has been a major advance, a preserved limb does not equate to a&#xD;
      functional limb. Patients may be left with significant disability and reliant on walking aids&#xD;
      or braces, and unable to return to normal activities&#xD;
&#xD;
      The West of Scotland Sarcoma service has developed and refined surgical procedures to restore&#xD;
      function in the lower limb after major resection surgery. This is one of the few centres in&#xD;
      the world that have done significant numbers of function restoring surgeries, and are&#xD;
      recognised as experts in this field, having published the protocol for functional&#xD;
      reconstruction in the Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery and in the book Reconstructive&#xD;
      Surgery of the Lower Extremity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures for functional restoration include Quadriceps reconstruction (to restore knee&#xD;
      extension) - this is the most common type of functional lower limb reconstruction. Hamstring&#xD;
      transfers were originally described for use in polio over a century ago, sartorius transfers,&#xD;
      and free functional muscles transfers such as the latissimus dorsi or contralateral rectus&#xD;
      femoris/ vastus lateralis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other techniques for functional reconstruction include anterior leg compartment&#xD;
      reconstruction (to restore foot dorsiflexion/ prevent foot-drop) and posterior leg&#xD;
      compartment reconstruction (to restore plantar-flexion). Techniques such as the free&#xD;
      functional anterolateral thigh - rectus femoris muscle combined flap are also used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous studies have not provided objective proof of restoration of gait, and have been&#xD;
      limited to scores such as the Musculoskeletal Tumor Society Score (MSTS), range of motion,&#xD;
      and Medical Research Council (MRC) grade power. These scores are of limited value in&#xD;
      establishing whether a patient's gait is normal, and may be subject to investigator bias.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two objective techniques will be used to assess normality of gait after functional&#xD;
      reconstruction:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Three-dimensional clinical gait analysis (3DCGA) provides a robust and objective&#xD;
           technique for measurement of how an individual walks both for clinical use and for&#xD;
           research purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Environmental Simulator (the Motek system at Strathclyde University): this is the only&#xD;
           environmental simulator of its type out-with the Ministry of Defence in the United&#xD;
           Kingdom. It provides simulated environments on a large projected screen with the patient&#xD;
           attached to a safety harness, whilst walking on an adjustable treadmill. This allows&#xD;
           simulation of urban environments, negotiation of trip hazards, walking up hills and&#xD;
           shopping tasks. This will permit more tangible answers regarding the objective return to&#xD;
           function of patients in an environmental context that they can understand eg &quot;Will I be&#xD;
           able to go hillwalking?&quot; &quot;Will I be safe to go shopping without crutches or a brace?&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim/Primary and Secondary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to objectively assess the normality of gait after functional&#xD;
      reconstructive surgery, and to assess whether patients can return to activities of daily&#xD;
      living using the Environmental simulator&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who have undergone functional reconstructive surgery will be identified from a&#xD;
      prospectively held database. The patients will be invited to participate by letter and given&#xD;
      an information sheet. Should the patient wish to participate in the study they will be&#xD;
      invited to clinic to discuss the study with the senior researcher (SL) and sign a consent&#xD;
      form related to gait analysis and the environmental simulator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are 3 components to the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patient Reported Outcome Measurements - using validated questionnaires including the&#xD;
           Toronto Extremity Salvage Score (TESS). Clinical assessment will include MRC grade power&#xD;
           and range of motion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 3D Gait analysis - this employs 3D cameras and pressure sensors to objectively assess&#xD;
           the patient's ability to walk, and can identify subtle differences in gait that cannot&#xD;
           be identified on questionnaires or on simple video analysis. Electromyography may be&#xD;
           used to assess active muscle contraction as part of the gait analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Environmental simulator - this will employ a state-of-the-art simulator that can assess&#xD;
           a patient's ability to navigate simulated environments eg walking up a hill, navigating&#xD;
           an urban environment, and shopping tasks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 5, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Gait Profile Score (GPS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 years after surgery. From date of surgery, but after completion of post-operative rehabilitation at 6 months up to 10 years following surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Objective score from 3D Gait Analysis. This is a continuous score with no minimum or maximum score, where lower scores indicate better gait.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Environmental Simulator assessment of ability to complete Tasks of Daily Living</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 years after surgery. From date of surgery, but after completion of post-operative rehabilitation at 6 months up to 10 years following surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Descriptive outcome measure on ability to complete simulator tasks which replicate activities of daily living.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toronto Extremity Salvage Score (TESS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 10 years after surgery. From date of surgery, but after completion of post-operative rehabilitation at 6 months up to 10 years following surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Patient reported outcome measure on function after surgery. This is a continuous score which is converted to a 0 to 100 score. Higher indicates better functional outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Sarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Muscle Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Muscle Loss</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Functional muscle transfer group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who have undergone functional muscle transfer to restore function after tumour surgery or injury, in which the tumour surgery or injury has resulted in functional loss.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-functional muscle transfer group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who have not undergone functional muscle transfer to restore function after tumour surgery or injury, in which the tumour surgery or injury has resulted in functional loss.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Functional muscle transfer</intervention_name>
    <description>Muscle transfer to restore lower limb function</description>
    <arm_group_label>Functional muscle transfer group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Population study groups will be taken from the Scottish Sarcoma Network Glasgow centre's&#xD;
        patient cohort&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have undergone major surgery for tumour, resulting in significant muscle&#xD;
             loss in the West of Scotland&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 3 months post-surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ongoing surgical complications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &lt; 3 months post-surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients currently undergoing radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known motion sickness (related to Virtual Reality component of gait&#xD;
             analysis)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>95 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Canniesburn Regional Plastic Surgery and Burns Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <state>Scotland</state>
        <zip>G4 0SF</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sarcoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be shared on reasonable written request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

