<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04912102</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HFNO Vs CPAP in ERCP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04912102</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HFNO Versus Nasal CPAP in Obese Patients Undergoing Deep Sedation for ERCP</brief_title>
  <official_title>High Flow Nasal Oxygen Versus Nasal Continuous Positive Airway Pressure in Obese Patients Undergoing Deep Sedation for Endoscopic Retrograde Cholangiopancreatography: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Endoscopic retrograde cholangio-pancreatography (ERCP) is commonly performed under deep&#xD;
      sedation to provide amnesia, comfort, and optimal procedural conditions. However, anesthetic&#xD;
      drugs commonly used such as midazolam and/or propofol and opioids for sedative endoscopy in&#xD;
      clinical practice may depress normal ventilation by blunting central chemoreceptor&#xD;
      responsiveness to CO2, and alveolar hypoventilation and predispose patients to upper airway&#xD;
      obstruction; all of that can result in hypoxemia, hypercarbia, respiratory acidosis,&#xD;
      hypotension, and, in rare cases, brain injury or death.(1-3)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The incidence of hypoxia during ERCP with sedation has been reported to range from 16.2 to&#xD;
      39.2% (4) may be because ERCP procedures can be lengthy and are often performed in the prone&#xD;
      position.(5) Hypoxemia is the most common adverse cardiopulmonary complication during sedated&#xD;
      endoscopy and is caused by respiratory depression, airway obstruction, and decreased chest&#xD;
      wall compliance. (2)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Obese patients are particularly at risk of upper airway obstruction and hypoxemia under&#xD;
      sedation and may benefit from Conventional CPAP, applied nasally to improve ventilation and&#xD;
      oxygenation during spontaneous ventilation in patients under deep sedation through&#xD;
      maintenance of upper airway patency.(6) Recently novel techniques have been shown to be more&#xD;
      effectively help ventilation than conventional low flow nasal oxygen. High flow nasal oxygen&#xD;
      (HFNO) has been utilized in the intensive care setting for over 15 years. Its use in&#xD;
      anaesthesia is rapidly increasing, providing an alternative to low flow oxygen devices during&#xD;
      sedation for procedures such as gastroenterology, non-invasive cardiological, radiological,&#xD;
      emergency medicine and persistent pain procedures.(1) Multiple mechanisms account for the&#xD;
      therapeutic effects of HFNO, including a reduction in dead space, increased positive&#xD;
      end-expiratory pressure, increased functional residual capacity, and delivery of higher&#xD;
      inspired oxygen concentrations to the distal airways.(7) Moreover the heated and humidified&#xD;
      HFNO provides adequate oxygenation with less drying of the upper airway mucosa, thereby&#xD;
      improving patient comfort.(8) The use of HFNO in the gastroenterological suite had reduced&#xD;
      critical incidents by providing high-inspired oxygen and slowing carbon dioxide rises related&#xD;
      to respiratory depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maintaining patient safety while successfully completing the procedures under sedation&#xD;
      requires careful monitoring. Australian and New Zealand College of Anaesthetists (ANZCA)&#xD;
      Guidelines on Monitoring during Anaesthesia, the Association of Anaesthetists of Great&#xD;
      Britain &amp; Ireland (AAGBI) and the American Society of Anesthesiologists Standards for Basic&#xD;
      Anesthetic Monitoring had all emphasized the importance of monitoring exhaled Co2 during&#xD;
      moderate to deep sedation to improve patients' safety. (9) Monitoring EtCO2 for the&#xD;
      anesthesiologist is more superior to the pulse oximeter for immediately detecting an&#xD;
      obstructed airway, opiate-induced apnea, or other airway problems that only much later may be&#xD;
      detected by the pulse oximeter.(9) Unfortunately, it would be expected that the high oxygen&#xD;
      flow rates during HFNO would severely dilute expired carbon dioxide and make sampling&#xD;
      impossible.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>A hypoxemia event</measure>
    <time_frame>for 15 consecutive secondes</time_frame>
    <description>Spo2 &lt;92% for at least 15 consecutive seconds (we based our definition on prior studies)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The lowest Spo2 reading</measure>
    <time_frame>during the whole procedure</time_frame>
    <description>the lowest spo2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of hypercapnia</measure>
    <time_frame>before induction, 5 min after induction and then every 10 min till end of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>PaCo2 will be assessed in an venous blood gas sample drawn before induction of anaesthesia and second sample 5 min. after induction and then every 10 min till the end of the procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">270</enrollment>
  <condition>Obese</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group H</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oxygen will be delvered via HFNO canula at 20 L/min, Fio2 0.4 and temperature of 37o c using Vapotherm Precision Flow.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group M</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mask group will be provided with nasal CPAP (10cmH2O) at an oxygen flow rate of 15 L/min.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the Control group, oxygen via a nasal cannula at a flow rate of 5 L/min will be delivered</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>high flow nasal oxygen device (HFNO)</intervention_name>
    <description>it is a novel technique by which heated humidified oxygen is supplied via nasal prongs at flow rates ranging from 40 to 70 L/minute. The Fio2 ranges from 0.21 to 1.0.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group H</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group M</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients undergoing elective ERCP with deep sedation will be enrolled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age 18 - 70 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  obesity (BMI 30-35 kg/m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anaesthesiologists' physical status classification of 1 to 3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipated duration of the procedure is &gt; 15 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • BMI &gt;35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Simple procedures of &lt; 15 minutes duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  untreated or unstable cardiac conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nasal or oral disease resulting in difficulty of either nasal breathing or mouth&#xD;
                  breathing.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute or chronic respiratory disorders as asthma and chronic obstructive&#xD;
                  pulmonary disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant patients and patients having procedures with planned endotracheal&#xD;
                  intubation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Expected difficult intubation patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Menna M Bakri, assisstant lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>01090692006</phone>
    <email>mennatallah1990@aun.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shimaa A Hassan, lecturer</last_name>
    <phone>01002953253</phone>
    <email>shimaa.abbas@med.aun.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bhananker SM, Posner KL, Cheney FW, Caplan RA, Lee LA, Domino KB. Injury and liability associated with monitored anesthesia care: a closed claims analysis. Anesthesiology. 2006 Feb;104(2):228-34.</citation>
    <PMID>16436839</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amornyotin S. Sedation-related complications in gastrointestinal endoscopy. World J Gastrointest Endosc. 2013 Nov 16;5(11):527-33. doi: 10.4253/wjge.v5.i11.527.</citation>
    <PMID>24255744</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mazzeffi MA, Petrick KM, Magder L, Greenwald BD, Darwin P, Goldberg EM, Bigeleisen P, Chow JH, Anders M, Boyd CM, Kaplowitz JS, Sun K, Terrin M, Rock P. High-Flow Nasal Cannula Oxygen in Patients Having Anesthesia for Advanced Esophagogastroduodenoscopy: HIFLOW-ENDO, a Randomized Clinical Trial. Anesth Analg. 2021 Mar 1;132(3):743-751. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0000000000004837.</citation>
    <PMID>32398433</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang CY, Ling LC, Cardosa MS, Wong AK, Wong NW. Hypoxia during upper gastrointestinal endoscopy with and without sedation and the effect of pre-oxygenation on oxygen saturation. Anaesthesia. 2000 Jul;55(7):654-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10919420</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Müller S, Prolla JC, Maguilnik I, Breyer HP. Predictive factors of oxygen desaturation of patients submitted to endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography under conscious sedation. Arq Gastroenterol. 2004 Jul-Sep;41(3):162-6. Epub 2005 Jan 21.</citation>
    <PMID>15678200</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Andrade RG, Piccin VS, Nascimento JA, Viana FM, Genta PR, Lorenzi-Filho G. Impact of the type of mask on the effectiveness of and adherence to continuous positive airway pressure treatment for obstructive sleep apnea. J Bras Pneumol. 2014 Nov-Dec;40(6):658-68. doi: 10.1590/S1806-37132014000600010. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25610507</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nishimura M. High-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy in adults. J Intensive Care. 2015 Mar 31;3(1):15. doi: 10.1186/s40560-015-0084-5. eCollection 2015. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25866645</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Greenland KB. A potential method for obtaining wave-form capnography during high flow nasal oxygen. Anaesth Intensive Care. 2019 Mar;47(2):204-206. doi: 10.1177/0310057X19836430. Epub 2019 May 1.</citation>
    <PMID>31042046</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weaver J. The latest ASA mandate: CO(2) monitoring for moderate and deep sedation. Anesth Prog. 2011 Fall;58(3):111-2. doi: 10.2344/0003-3006-58.3.111.</citation>
    <PMID>21882985</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mennat Allah Mahmoud Bakri</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assisstant lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

