<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04916314</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15434</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04916314</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>REmote SUpport for Low-Carbohydrate Treatment of Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>RESULT</acronym>
  <official_title>Testing the Effectiveness of a Low Carbohydrate Diet With Remote Support for Patients With Type 2 Diabetes in Primary Care, on Weight and Glycaemic Control: a Randomised Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Second Nature</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Excess adiposity is a key causal factor in developing type 2 diabetes and weight loss&#xD;
      improves glycaemia and can put diabetes in to remission. There is evidence that low&#xD;
      carbohydrate diets also reduce glycaemia. The aim of this trial is to test a behavioural&#xD;
      support programme delivered remotely to reduce energy intake and carbohydrate intake in&#xD;
      particular to improve glycaemic control in people recently diagnosed with type 2 diabetes. We&#xD;
      will recruit participants from general practice diabetes registers who were diagnosed within&#xD;
      the past six years and who want to and are able to follow an app-based behavioural support&#xD;
      programme to change their diet and have a BMI of at least 27kg/m2 (≥30kg/m2 if of white&#xD;
      European ethnicity). They will be individually randomised 1:1 using simple randomisation to&#xD;
      either intervention or a no-intervention control. Blinding of participants or their&#xD;
      clinicians is impossible. The intervention comprises a 12-week behavioural support programme&#xD;
      delivered by app or web, which provides group-based peer support, recipes for food providing&#xD;
      low energy meals that are low in carbohydrate. The programme is delivered by a commercial&#xD;
      company, Second Nature. Clinicians will adjust medication for hypertension and diabetes as&#xD;
      needed. The co-primary outcomes are change in participants' HbA1c from baseline to 3 months&#xD;
      and baseline to 1 year, with p-value adjustment to reflect multiple testing. The secondary&#xD;
      outcomes are remission from diabetes, weight change, change in cardiovascular risk factors,&#xD;
      and change in quality of life at 3 months and 1 year. The trial will assess whether this&#xD;
      app-based programme improves outcomes for people with type 2 diabetes relative to usual care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an individually randomised controlled trial. Participants, recruited via GP&#xD;
      practices, will be randomised 1:1 with simple randomisation and no stratification to either&#xD;
      the intervention group or control (usual care). They will be enrolled in the study for 1&#xD;
      year, of which the intervention (dietary support via the app) will run for 3 months. Most&#xD;
      study procedures will be conducted online or remotely (by telephone) including: screening,&#xD;
      eligibility assessment, informed consent, randomisation, engagement with the app-based&#xD;
      intervention. Participants will be asked to attend 3 face to face appointments for the&#xD;
      research study at their local GP practice for measurements to be taken (weight, blood&#xD;
      pressure) and blood tests, at baseline, 3 months and 1 year, and will have 1 additional&#xD;
      telephone contact with their GP or practice nurse before starting the intervention. Face to&#xD;
      face appointments will be incorporated with routine clinical appointments when possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators aim to recruit 100 participants via their GP practices. Based on a&#xD;
      conservative response rate of 10% from similar previous studies, the investigators will&#xD;
      approach approximately 1000 eligible individuals from approximately 10 GP practices in&#xD;
      England. The primary care provider will search their electronic registers for eligible&#xD;
      individuals and GPs will screen out those to whom it would be inappropriate to send a letter&#xD;
      inviting them to enrol and referring them to a website to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once consent has been given, participants will click on a link to the electronic data capture&#xD;
      system database which will be activated following their consent, to complete the baseline&#xD;
      assessment. All participants will complete a 2 part baseline assessment, firstly online and&#xD;
      then at their GP practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Online:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Participants will be asked to complete a baseline questionnaire requesting demographic&#xD;
           information and their current medication, and the standard questionnaires that will be&#xD;
           used in the study (the Problem Areas in Diabetes (PAID) score, the EQ5D (quality of life&#xD;
           assessment), and a 24 hour dietary recall questionnaire (&quot;Intake24 dietary assessment&#xD;
           tool&quot;, where participants are asked to record all food and drink intake in the last 24&#xD;
           hours). This will also further assess whether people are sufficiently able to complete&#xD;
           online trial procedures, and only those who complete the questionnaire will be&#xD;
           randomised. Participants will be informed in the Participant Information Sheet that they&#xD;
           will only be able to enter the study after completing the questionnaire fully in one&#xD;
           attempt as the system will not allow them to go back into the questionnaire to answer&#xD;
           the remaining questions later. This should take less than 30 minutes to complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. At the GP practice (visit 1) Having completed the online assessment, participants will&#xD;
           be asked (via message on their screen on completing the assessment, and followed up via&#xD;
           email) to book the in-person portions of their baseline assessment at their GP practice&#xD;
           for measures which cannot be conducted online. At this appointment, their height, weight&#xD;
           and blood pressure will be measured and recorded, and a blood sample taken for baseline&#xD;
           values (HbA1c, lipid profile, liver function tests).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinician will randomise the participant at the baseline appointment. This is an&#xD;
      individually randomised 1:1 to 2 arms: Intervention (12 week, app-based dietary support), or&#xD;
      control (usual care; no active additional intervention). The randomisation will be conducted&#xD;
      using the in-built randomisation software. This ensures full allocation concealment as&#xD;
      information on future allocations is not accessible to the person randomising. Due to the&#xD;
      nature of the intervention it will not be possible to blind members of the study team or&#xD;
      participants to allocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomised to the intervention group will receive an email giving 12 weeks of&#xD;
      access to the app/website. The intervention, provided by Second Nature, involves diet,&#xD;
      activity and behaviour change components. It comprises a three-month remote behavioural&#xD;
      change programme with mentoring from a registered dietitian or nutritionist (health coach),&#xD;
      peer group support, structured education articles and activity tracking technology. These&#xD;
      elements are accessed via a smartphone or web-based application. Each participant will also&#xD;
      receive a hard copy of an instructional handbook and a recipe book.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomised to the intervention group will consult their GP to adjust medication&#xD;
      as appropriate to avoid hypotension or hypoglycaemia following a guideline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants randomised to the control group will receive no additional intervention, and&#xD;
      will continue to receive their usual NHS diabetes care from their general practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All Participants will be followed up after 3 months (visit 2) and at 12 months (visit 3). At&#xD;
      this appointment they will have the same procedures as at their baseline assessment repeated:&#xD;
      their weight and blood pressure will be recorded, and blood tests taken (3 sample tubes - for&#xD;
      HbA1c, lipid profile and liver function). Participants will be asked to complete the same&#xD;
      online questionnaires (PAID score, EQ5D, and 24 hour dietary recall) as they completed at&#xD;
      baseline, and serious adverse events and events of concern (serious hypoglycaemia) will be&#xD;
      recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A purposively sampled proportion of participants from the intervention group (aiming to&#xD;
      achieve diversity of age, race, and success and engagement with the programme measured by&#xD;
      weight/HbA1c outcomes and engagement metrics respectively) will be contacted via telephone&#xD;
      for a semi-structured interview to discuss their experience of the intervention, after they&#xD;
      complete the 3 month intervention period. Interviews will last approximately 30 minutes. With&#xD;
      participants consent this will be audio-recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The duration of the SAE recording period for each participant lasts from their enrolment on&#xD;
      to the study, to their completion of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study results will be reported in accordance with the CONSORT (Consolidated Standards of&#xD;
      Reporting Trials) 2010 statements. A full analysis plan will be prepared and finalised before&#xD;
      any data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary statistical analysis of efficacy outcomes will be carried out on the basis of&#xD;
      intention-to-treat (ITT). This is, after randomisation, participants will be analysed&#xD;
      according to their allocated intervention group irrespective of what intervention they&#xD;
      actually receive. The investigators will endeavour to obtain full follow-up data on every&#xD;
      participant to allow full ITT analysis, but the investigators will inevitably experience the&#xD;
      problem of missing data due to withdrawal, loss to follow up, or non-response to&#xD;
      questionnaire items.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will analyse the primary continuous outcome with a linear model adjusting&#xD;
      for baseline value of the relevant variable where relevant. For exploratory analyses, the&#xD;
      investigators will use analogous models, but interpret the data in an exploratory manner&#xD;
      rather than confirmatory. For binary outcomes (e.g. remission), the investigators will test&#xD;
      for a difference in proportions using logistic regression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on previous studies of this intervention(5) and studies in similar populations(3), an&#xD;
      8-10mmol/mol change in HbA1c at 12 months in the intervention group in those who engage with&#xD;
      the programme (SD 8.6mmol/mol), with a 1-2mmol/mol (SD 6mmol/mol) change in the control group&#xD;
      is estimated. With α and β set at 0.05 this would require approximately 48 participants;&#xD;
      however to power for a co-primary outcome would require 72 to 88 participants in total&#xD;
      (allowing for variability in estimated effect size). In similar trials of behavioural&#xD;
      interventions an expected retention to follow up of &gt;80%; allowing for the online nature of&#xD;
      this trial, and the retention rates of observational studies of this intervention the&#xD;
      investigators will aim to recruit 100 participants to allow for cumulative attrition at the&#xD;
      intervention sign-up, engagement, and follow up stages. The results from the trial will be&#xD;
      prepared as comparative summary statistics (difference in proportions or means) with 95%&#xD;
      confidence intervals. All the tests will be done at a 5% two-sided significance level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>The nature of the intervention means it is not possible to mask providers or patients</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' HbA1c</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' HbA1c</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diabetes remission</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants meeting consensus definition for remission from type 2 diabetes at 1 year</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months,1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' weight</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' systolic blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' diastolic blood pressure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lipid profile; LDL cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' LDL cholesterol</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lipid profile; total cholesterol:HDL ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' total cholesterol:HDL ratio</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lipid profile; HDL cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' HDL cholesterol</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lipid profile; triglycerides</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' triglycerides</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ALT</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' ALT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diabetes related quality of life and distresses; Problem Areas In Diabetes (PAID) score</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' PAID score. (Minimum- maximum score; 0-100). Lower score indicating lower diabetes burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diabetes related quality of life and distresses; EQ5D score</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Change in participants' EQ5D score. (Score minimum-maximum is 0-1, VAS is 0-100).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Dietary Intake patterns</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Data will be collected on change in dietary intake patterns (via Intake24 24 hour dietary recall questionnaire)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Engagement with programme; 'learn' component of the programme</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Data will be collected on measures of engagement with one of the three main components of the programme (&quot;Learn&quot;) via the app programme</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Engagement with programme; 'track' component of the programme</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Data will be collected on measures of engagement with one of the three main components of the programme (&quot;Track&quot;) via the app programme</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Engagement with programme; 'support' component of the programme</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 months, 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Data will be collected on measures of engagement with one of the three main components of the programme (&quot;Support&quot;), via the app programme</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Participants' experience of using the app-based support</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Interviews with participants</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus in Obese</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low Carbohydrate Diet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>. The intervention, provided by &quot;Second Nature&quot;, involves diet, activity and behaviour change components. It comprises a three-month remote behavioural change programme with mentoring from a registered dietitian or nutritionist (health coach), peer group support, structured education articles and activity tracking technology. These elements are accessed via a smartphone or web-based application. Each participant will also receive a hard copy of an instructional handbook and a recipe book.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard NHS type 2 diabetes care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomised to the control group will receive no additional intervention, and will continue to receive their usual NHS diabetes care from their general practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Low Carbohydrate diet</intervention_name>
    <description>Second Nature is a three-month remote behavioural change programme with mentoring from a registered dietitian or nutritionist (health coach), encouraging adoption of a low energy, low-carbohydrate diet, peer group support, structured education articles and activity tracking technology. These elements are accessed via a smartphone or web-based application; each participant additionally receives an instructional handbook, and recipe book (+/-wireless weighing and activity tracking technology).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Low Carbohydrate Diet</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Second Nature</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female, aged 40 years or above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with current type 2 diabetes (i.e. not in remission) in the last 6 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI of ≥27kg/m2 (≥30kg/m2 if ethnicity recorded as white)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a smartphone or computer with internet access (and the correct operating system&#xD;
             requirements to use the intervention programme)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Are able to complete the eligibility and baseline assessments online&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Would like to make changes to their diet or lifestyle to improve their diabetes&#xD;
             control, lose weight, or improve their general health&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to understand the study materials and interventions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently following a weight loss programme (defined as a structured, prescribed and&#xD;
             monitored programme and not a self-directed weight loss attempt)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant, breastfeeding, or planning to become pregnant during the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bariatric surgery, including gastric banding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently using insulin therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proliferative diabetic retinopathy, or maculopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent myocardial infarction or stroke (&lt;3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal failure (chronic kidney disease stage 4 or 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current active treatment for cancer (other than skin cancer treated with curative&#xD;
             intent by local treatment only)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Their doctor does not feel they are appropriate to participate for another reason&#xD;
             (e.g. active eating disorder diagnosis, significant psychological disturbance)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paul Aveyard, FRCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Paul Aveyard, FRCP</last_name>
    <phone>1865 617 860</phone>
    <phone_ext>+44 (0)</phone_ext>
    <email>paul.aveyard@phc.ox.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diet</keyword>
  <keyword>Low-Carbohydrate</keyword>
  <keyword>Digital Intervention</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will be available upon direct request to the study team</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be available indefinitely when the investigators have completed their analysis, about 1 year after final follow-up.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Request is for bona fide reasons from an organisation whose mission is to benefit the public good.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

