<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04916002</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CMP-001-009</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04916002</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CMP-001 in Combination With IV PD-1-Blocking Antibody in Subjects With Certain Types of Advanced or Metastatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Open-label, Phase 2 Study of Intratumoral CMP-001 in Combination With an Intravenous PD-1-Blocking Antibody in Subjects With Selected Types of Advanced or Metastatic Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Checkmate Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>IQVIA Biotech</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Checkmate Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      CMP-001-009 is a Phase 2 study of intratumoral CMP-001 in combination with an intravenous&#xD;
      PD-1-blocking antibody administered to participants with certain types of advanced or&#xD;
      metatastic cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of the study is to determine the Investigator-assessed confirmed&#xD;
      objective response with CMP-001 in combination with a programmed cell death protein&#xD;
      (PD-1)-blocking antibody in subjects with certain types of advanced or metatastic cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the safety and tolerability of CMP-001 administered by intratumoral (IT)&#xD;
           injection in combination with a PD-1-blocking antibody in study subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the efficacy of CMP-001 in combination with a PD-1-blocking antibody in&#xD;
           study subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will continue to receive treatment of CMP-001 in combination with a&#xD;
      PD-1-blocking antibody according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment&#xD;
      discontinuation is reached.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>3 cohorts each with 2 sub cohorts</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) with CMP-001 in combination with a programmed cell death protein 1 (PD-1)-blocking antibody (cemiplimab-rwlc) in study subjects with metastatic or advanced/unresectable CSCC, MCC, or TNBC</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of CMP-001 (Week 1 Day 1) until 30 days after the last CMP-001 injection (until a reason for treatment discontinuation occurs)</time_frame>
    <description>CSCC is defined as cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma, MCC is defined as Merkel cell carcinoma, and TNBC is defined as triple negative breast cancer. ORR is further defined as the proportion of subjects with a confirmed objective response of complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) based on Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors version 1.1 (RECIST v1.1).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of CMP-001 administered by intratumoral (IT) injection in combination with a PD-1-blocking antibody (cemiplimab-rwlc) in the study subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of CMP-001 (Week 1 Day 1) until 30 days after the last CMP-001 injection (until a reason for treatment discontinuation occurs)</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability is defined as the presence of Adverse events (AEs), serious adverse events (SAEs), and AEs leading to discontinuation or death, and severity of AEs as assessed by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events Version 5.0 (CTCAE v5.0)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of CMP-001 in combination with a PD-1-blocking antibody (cemiplimab-rwlc) in the study subjects</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dose of CMP-001 (Week 1 Day 1) until 30 days after the last CMP-001 injection (until a reason for treatment discontinuation occurs)</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy is measured by: Duration of response (DOR), defined as the time from date of first documented response (CR or PR) to date of documented progressive disease (PD), based on RECIST v1.1 Immune ORR, DOR, and progression-free survival (iORR, iDOR, and iPFS) based on immunotherapy Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (iRECIST) treatment response in noninjected target lesions based on RECIST v1.1. Response in injected and noninjected target lesions per RECIST v1.1. Progression-free survival (PFS), defined as the time from date of first dose of study treatment to date of documented PD based on RECIST v1.1 or death, whichever occurs first. Overall survival (OS), defined as the time from date of first dose of study treatment to date of death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">279</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma (CSCC) (A1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who have not received prior systemic therapy for CSCC will receive CMP-001 IT and cemiplimab-rwlc IV according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment discontinuation is reached.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for CSCC (A2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who have progressed while receiving PD-1-blocking antibody(ies) or are within 3 months of discontinuation of treatment for CSCC will receive CMP-001 IT and cemiplimab-rwlc IV according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment discontinuation is reached.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for Merkel cell carcinoma (MCC) (B1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who have not received prior systemic therapy for MCC will receive CMP-001 IT and cemiplimab-rwlc IV according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment discontinuation is reached.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for MCC (B2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who have progressed while receiving PD-1-blocking antibody(ies) or are within 3 months of discontinuation of treatment for MCC will receive CMP-001 IT and cemiplimab-rwlc IV according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment discontinuation is reached.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) (C1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who have not received prior therapy with immune checkpoint inhibitors (iCPIs) for TNBC will receive CMP-001 IT and cemiplimab-rwlc IV according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment discontinuation is reached.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for TNBC (C2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects who have received prior treatment for PD-1-blocking antibody(ies) for TNBC will receive CMP-001 IT and cemiplimab-rwlc IV according to the treatment schedule until a reason for treatment discontinuation is reached.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CMP-001</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive CMP-001 10mg IT weekly for 7 doses after which CMP-001 will be administered every 3 weeks (Q3W). The first dose of CMP-001 may be administered subcutaneously (SC) or IT at the discretion of Investigator. All subsequent doses will be IT. The initial 7 doses of CMP-001, delivered on a weekly dosing schedule, must be completed before starting the Q3W CMP-001 dosing schedule.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for CSCC (A2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for MCC (B2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for Merkel cell carcinoma (MCC) (B1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for TNBC (C2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma (CSCC) (A1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) (C1)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cemiplimab-rwlc</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive cemiplimab-rwlc 350 mg IV over 30 minutes at W1D1 and Q3W thereafter.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for CSCC (A2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for MCC (B2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for Merkel cell carcinoma (MCC) (B1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for TNBC (C2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for cutaneous squamous cell carcinoma (CSCC) (A1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>CMP-001 and cemiplimab-rwlc for triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) (C1)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Libtayo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects enrolled in the study must meet all of the following inclusion criteria to be&#xD;
        eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histopathologically-confirmed diagnosis of cancer that is metastatic or unresectable&#xD;
             at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Subjects with metastatic or locally and/or regionally advanced unresectable CSCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Note 1: CSCC subjects without radiographically measurable disease are not&#xD;
                  excluded if there is at least 1 lesion ≥ 10 mm in at least 1 dimension documented&#xD;
                  by color photography. Note 2: Subjects with tumors that arise in the setting of&#xD;
                  chronic inflammation (Marjolin's ulcer) such as chronic wounds and/or scars are&#xD;
                  excluded. Cohort A1: Subjects who have not received prior systemic therapy for&#xD;
                  CSCC. Cohort A2: Subjects who have progressed while receiving a PD-1-blocking&#xD;
                  antibody or within 3 months of discontinuation. PD-1-blocking antibody treatment&#xD;
                  may have been administered in the adjuvant and/or neoadjuvant and/or metastatic&#xD;
                  setting. The PD-1-blocking antibody must have been the most recent therapy&#xD;
                  received.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subjects with metastatic or locally and/or regionally advanced unresectable MCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Note: MCC subjects without radiographically measurable disease are not excluded&#xD;
                  if there is at least 1 lesion ≥ 10 mm in at least 1 dimension documented by color&#xD;
                  photography. Cohort B1: Subjects who had not received prior systemic therapy for&#xD;
                  MCC. Cohort B2: Subjects who have progressed while receiving PD-1-blocking&#xD;
                  antibody(ies) or within 3 months of discontinuation. PD-1-blocking antibody&#xD;
                  treatment may have been administered in the adjuvant and/or neoadjuvant and/or&#xD;
                  metastatic setting. The PD-1-blocking antibody must have been the most recent&#xD;
                  therapy received.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Previously treated subjects with advanced or metastatic TNBC must have disease&#xD;
                  that is HER2-negative, estrogen and progesterone receptor-negative, or &lt; 5%&#xD;
                  expression based on American Society of Clinical Oncology/College of American&#xD;
                  Pathologists guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Patients with disease recurrence or progression following neoadjuvant or adjuvant&#xD;
                  therapy are eligible. Patients with advanced or metastatic disease may have up to&#xD;
                  5 lines of systemic therapy. Cohort C1: Subjects who had not received prior&#xD;
                  therapy with iCPIs. Cohort C2: Subjects who had received prior treatment with a&#xD;
                  PD-1-blocking antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Subjects enrolled in Cohorts A2, B2, and C2 must have PD on or within 3 months of&#xD;
                  discontinuation of prior PD-1-blocking antibody therapy, either as a single agent&#xD;
                  or in combination with a standard or an investigational therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Subjects who progressed on/within 3 months of adjuvant or neoadjuvant therapy&#xD;
                  with iCPI will be allowed in Cohorts A2, B2, and C2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Measurable disease, as defined by RECIST v1.1 and all of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. At least 1 accessible lesion amenable to repeated IT injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. A previously irradiated lesion may be used as a target lesion if subsequent&#xD;
                  disease progression in that lesion (at least 20% increase in dimensions with a 5&#xD;
                  mm absolute increase) was documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to provide tissue from a core or excisional/incisional biopsy (fine needle&#xD;
             aspirate is not sufficient). A newly obtained biopsy (within 90 days before the start&#xD;
             of study treatment) is preferred but an archival sample is acceptable if no&#xD;
             intervening therapy was received.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Adequate organ function based on most recent laboratory values within 3 weeks before&#xD;
             first dose of study treatment on Week 1 Day 1 (W1D1):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Bone marrow function:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  neutrophil count ≥ 1500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  hemoglobin concentration ≥ 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Liver function:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 times the upper limit of normal (ULN) with the&#xD;
                       following exception: subjects with Gilbert Disease total serum bilirubin ≤ 3&#xD;
                       times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  aspartate aminotransferase and alanine aminotransferase ≤ 3 times the ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Renal function: estimated (Cockcroft-Gault) or measured creatinine clearance&#xD;
&#xD;
                  ≥ 30 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Coagulation:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  International normalized ratio or prothrombin time (PT) ≤ 1.5 times ULN&#xD;
                       unless subject is receiving anticoagulant therapy, as long as PT or partial&#xD;
                       thromboplastin time (PTT) is within therapeutic range of intended use of&#xD;
                       anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Activated partial thromboplastin time or PTT ≤ 1.5 times ULN unless subject&#xD;
                       is receiving anticoagulant therapy, as long as PT or PTT is within&#xD;
                       therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Age ≥ 18 years at time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status of 0 to 1 at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Capable of understanding and complying with protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing potential must have negative serum pregnancy test during&#xD;
             Screening and be willing to use an adequate method of contraception from the time of&#xD;
             consent until at least 150 days after last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Able and willing to provide written informed consent and to follow study instructions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects unable to provide written informed consent on their own behalf will not be&#xD;
        eligible for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects presenting with any of the following will not qualify for entry into the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Received radiation therapy (or other nonsystemic therapy) within 2 weeks before first&#xD;
             dose of study treatment on W1D1. Subjects should have recovered (ie, Grade ≤ 1 or at&#xD;
             baseline) from radiation-related toxicities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Treatment with complementary medications (eg, herbal supplements or traditional&#xD;
             Chinese medicines) to treat the disease under study within 2 weeks prior to start of&#xD;
             study treatment or at any time during the treatment phase of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Received systemic pharmacologic doses of corticosteroids &gt; 10 mg/day prednisone within&#xD;
             30 days before first dose of study treatment on W1D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Subjects who are currently receiving steroids at a prednisone-equivalent dose of&#xD;
&#xD;
                  ≤ 10 mg/day do not need to discontinue steroids prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Replacement doses, topical, ophthalmologic, and inhalational steroids are&#xD;
                  permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Stress-dose corticosteroids will be required in subjects with adrenal&#xD;
                  insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of immune-mediated AE leading to permanent discontinuation due to prior&#xD;
             PD-1-blocking antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Not fully recovered from AEs due to prior treatment (to Grade 1 or less, per CTCAE),&#xD;
             with the exception of persistent vitiligo, alopecia, hypothyroidism, or diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus, and adrenal and/or pituitary insufficiency, due to prior treatment. Note:&#xD;
             Subjects previously treated with a CTLA-4-blocking antibody, subjects receiving&#xD;
             corticosteroids with daily doses &gt;5mg and ≤10mg of prednisone equivalent for &gt;2 weeks,&#xD;
             and subjects with clinical symptoms and/or laboratory findings suggesting risk for&#xD;
             adrenal insufficiency should undergo diagnostic tests for adrenal insufficiency via&#xD;
             local laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active pneumonitis or history of noninfectious pneumonitis that required steroids, or&#xD;
             history of interstitial lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Severe uncontrolled cardiac disease within 6 months of Screening, including but not&#xD;
             limited to poorly controlled hypertension, unstable angina, myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association Class II or greater),&#xD;
             pericarditis within the previous 6 months, cerebrovascular accident, or implanted or&#xD;
             continuous use of a pacemaker or defibrillator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known history of immunodeficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known additional malignancy that is progressing or required active treatment within&#xD;
             the past 3 years. Exceptions include cancers that have undergone potentially curative&#xD;
             therapy, e.g. basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
             that has undergone potentially curative therapy, curatively treated localized prostate&#xD;
             cancer with prostate-specific antigen level below 4.0 ng/mL, in situ cervical cancer&#xD;
             on biopsy or a squamous intraepithelial lesion on Papanicolaou smear, and thyroid&#xD;
             cancer (except anaplastic),in situ breast cancer and adjuvant hormonal therapy for&#xD;
             breast cancer &gt; 3 years from curative-intent surgical resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Active autoimmune disease that required systemic treatment in past 2 years;&#xD;
             replacement therapy is not considered a form of systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Untreated, symptomatic, or enlarging central nervous system metastases or&#xD;
             carcinomatous meningitis (including leptomeningeal metastases from solid tumors).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Prior allogenic tissue/solid organ transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Known or suspected active infection with severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus&#xD;
             2 (SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Known or suspected infection with human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis B virus, or&#xD;
             hepatitis C virus (testing is not required unless suspected).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Received a live virus/attenuated vaccination within 30 days before first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment on W1D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Received blood products (including platelets or red blood cells) or colony stimulating&#xD;
             factors (including granulocyte colony stimulating factor, granulocyte/macrophage&#xD;
             colony stimulating factor, or recombinant erythropoietin) within 3 weeks before the&#xD;
             W1D1 visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. History of permanent discontinuation of cemiplimab-rwlc due to infusion reactions.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Any concurrent uncontrolled illness, including mental illness or substance abuse,&#xD;
             which in the opinion of the Investigator would make the subject unable to cooperate or&#xD;
             participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Participation in another clinical study of an investigational anticancer therapy or&#xD;
             device within 30 days before first dose of study treatment on W1D1. Note:&#xD;
             Participation in the follow-up phase (receiving no study treatment) of a prior study&#xD;
             is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Requires prohibited treatment (ie, non-protocol specified anticancer pharmacotherapy,&#xD;
             surgery, or conventional radiotherapy) for treatment of malignant tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Has a life expectancy of less than 3 months and/or has rapidly progressing disease&#xD;
             (eg, tumor bleeding, uncontrolled tumor pain) in the opinion of the treating&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Received previous CMP-001 treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Pregnant or breastfeeding or expecting to conceive children within the projected&#xD;
             duration of the study, from the time of consent until at least 150 days after last&#xD;
             dose of study treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Checkmate Medical Monitor</last_name>
    <phone>617-682-3625</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrials@checkmatepharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GenesisCare USA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32204</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Orlando Health Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orlando</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32806</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Second Primary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cemiplimab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

