<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04910802</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Catch-up vaccination</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04910802</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Concomitant HPV Vaccination and HPV Screening HPV Infection and Cervical Cancer in Sweden</brief_title>
  <official_title>Concomitant HPV Vaccination and HPV Screening for Rapid Elimination of HPV Infection and Cervical Cancer in Sweden</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Miriam Elfström</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Karolinska University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Region Stockholm</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study aims to evaluate whether organised, concomitant HPV vaccination and HPV screening&#xD;
      offered to all resident women aged 22-27 will result in a more rapid elimination of HPV&#xD;
      infection in Sweden. This objective will be examined at the population level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In Sweden, 150 women die of and 550 women are diagnosed with cervical cancer each year. The&#xD;
      average age at diagnosis is about 55 years and every third woman is under 40 years of age.&#xD;
      World-wide, there half a million new cases of cervical cancer each year. The underlying cause&#xD;
      of cervical cancer is a human papillomavirus (HPV), an infection that can be prevented by&#xD;
      vaccination. The first-generation vaccine protects against HPV infection of the two types (16&#xD;
      and 18) that cause to about 70% of all cervical cancer. Since 2015, a second-generation&#xD;
      vaccine (Gardasil 9, Sanofi Pasteur MSD SNC) has been available that provides protection&#xD;
      against 9 HPV types of which 7 types (16, 18, 31, 33, 35, 45, 52 and 58) cause 90% of all&#xD;
      cervical cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2016, the World Health Organization (WHO) called on the countries of the world to&#xD;
      eliminate cervical cancer as a public health problem. On 17 November 2020, all 194 WHO member&#xD;
      states adopted a global strategy to increase the rate of elimination of cervical cancer. The&#xD;
      strategy involves three main actions: vaccination, screening, and treatment. In Sweden, girls&#xD;
      have been offered school-based vaccination against HPV with Gardasil 4 since 2012. Starting&#xD;
      in the autumn of 2020, schoolboys have also been offered vaccination. Since 2019, the&#xD;
      second-generation vaccine has been used in the school-based vaccination program. Sweden's&#xD;
      vaccination strategy means that the virus will be eliminated among individuals born in 2007&#xD;
      and beyond. It will thus take another 20 years before Sweden can stop the infection in&#xD;
      Sweden. Today, the infection continues to spread only among young adults. Studies have shown&#xD;
      that vaccination up to age 26 can be effective and within the European Union, 10 out of 29&#xD;
      countries have a so-called catch-up on vaccination program targeting women over the age of 20&#xD;
      but such a catch-up has not been formally introduced in Sweden.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal is to investigate whether offering women ages 22-26 years vaccination with&#xD;
      Gardasil 9 in connection with screening may involve a faster eradication of cervical cancer&#xD;
      as a public health problem in Sweden. A regional pilot study will be conducted in 2021&#xD;
      followed by a subsequent scale-up to other regions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>All women in the targeted age-range will be offered vaccination in conjunction with screening.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of HPV</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at recruitment.</time_frame>
    <description>Overall and type-specific prevalence of HPV will be obtained from the routine HPV screening programs in the regions that offer HPV screening to this age group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of HPV</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured 3 years after recruitment, at the second cervical screening attendance.</time_frame>
    <description>Overall and type-specific prevalence of HPV will be obtained from the routine HPV screening programs in the regions that offer HPV screening to this age group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of HPV</measure>
    <time_frame>Measure 6 years after recruitment, at the third cervical screening attendance.</time_frame>
    <description>Overall and type-specific prevalence of HPV will be obtained from the routine HPV screening programs in the regions that offer HPV screening to this age group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of women with histopathologically confirmed cervical intraepithelial neoplasia grade 2, 3, or cervical cancer (CIN2+)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at recruitment, and subsequently at 3 year intervals.</time_frame>
    <description>CIN2+ measured through registry linkages, by HPV type in the lesion.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Consumption of resources</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at recruitment, and subsequently at 3 year intervals.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of screening and treatment visits.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of women with obstetrical complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at recruitment, and subsequently at 3 year intervals.</time_frame>
    <description>Obstetrical complications such as preterm births measured through registry linkages.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of women with cervical specimens found to be benign</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at recruitment, and subsequently at 3 year intervals.</time_frame>
    <description>Treatments for cervical abnormalities, measured as excised cervical specimens, found to be benign. Measured through registry linkages.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150000</enrollment>
  <condition>HPV Infection</condition>
  <condition>CIN 2/3</condition>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HPV-vaccination</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Women ages 22-26 will be offered concomitant vaccination (1 dose of Gardasil9) and HPV screening. A second dose of Gardasil9 will be administered 3 years later.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gardasil9</intervention_name>
    <description>Concomitant vaccination and HPV screening. Gardasil9 will be administered using standard dosage. 1 dose at recruitment and the 2nd dose 3 years later.</description>
    <arm_group_label>HPV-vaccination</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible women will include resident women within the age range of 22-26, who have not&#xD;
             opted out of the screening program and who consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women who respond to the invitation and attend screening will be screened with HPV testing&#xD;
        by the current routine practise. Women who consent to participate will also be offered HPV&#xD;
        vaccination. The HPV vaccine (Gardasil 9) will be offered regardless of whether the woman&#xD;
        reports having had prior vaccination with a first-generation vaccine (Gardasil 4) and&#xD;
        regardless of screening test result.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Known history of severe allergic reaction or hypersensitivity to any of the components&#xD;
             of the HPV vaccine.For GARDASIL 9: Amorphous aluminium hydroxyphosphate sulphate&#xD;
             adjuvant, Sodium chloride, L-histidine, Polysorbate 80 or Sodium borate&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known history of immune-related disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current acute severe febrile illness, except for minor infections such as a cold, mild&#xD;
             upper respiratory infection or low-grade fever.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Administration of immunoglobulin or blood-derived products within 6 months prior to&#xD;
             scheduled HPV vaccine first dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current pregnancy (reported)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women with a total hysterectomy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Gender eligibility is based on the sex coded in the personal identification number used in civil society in Sweden</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>27 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joakim Dillner, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska University Hospital Laboratory</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Miriam Elfström, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46703816277</phone>
    <email>miriam.elfstrom@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Helena Andersson, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46768871126</phone>
    <email>helena.t.andersson@sll.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cancer prevention, screening, and counseling unit, Regional Cancer Center of Stockholm-Gotland</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <zip>10239</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Malin Vikström, BSN</last_name>
      <phone>+46(0)8-123 131 14</phone>
      <email>malin.vikstrom@sll.se</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Region Stockholm</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Miriam Elfström</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief development officer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Papillomavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Documents related to the study can be shared. Data, once collected, will be made available.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The study protocol and informed consent form are available. The SAP will be made available and the analytic code will be available once the first round of results have been analyzed.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data can be shared with other researchers upon written request. Possibilities to share the data on a digital platform will be investigated.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

