<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04917263</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AIRC IG2019 23381 IMMUNOREACT2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04917263</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>IMMUNOlogical Microenvironment in REctal Adenocarcinoma Treatment.</brief_title>
  <acronym>IMMUNOREACT2</acronym>
  <official_title>IMMUNOlogical Microenvironment in REctal Adenocarcinoma Treatment. Predictors of Sustained Complete Response After Neoadjuvant Chemo/Radiotherapy for Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Padova</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Associazione Italiana per la Ricerca sul Cancro</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Azienda Ospedaliera di Padova</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Istituto Oncologico Veneto IRCCS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Azienda ULSS 3 Serenissima</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Azienda Ulss 2 Marca Trevigiana</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Padova</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background The current management on rectal cancer based on TNM staging has some limitations.&#xD;
      In locally advanced rectal cancer after neoadjuvant therapy the persistence of a complete&#xD;
      response to therapy cannot be accurately predicted by the simple tumor regression grade. The&#xD;
      current guidelines recommend the complete rectal resection with a total mesorectal excision.&#xD;
      The implications for patients' quality of life are evident even in case of sphincter sparing&#xD;
      surgery. Moreover, in both cases the cancer sample available for the analysis can be small or&#xD;
      inexistent. Hypothesis The main hypothesis underlying our research is that the aggressiveness&#xD;
      of rectal cancer is determined by the complex interactions between the malignant cells and&#xD;
      their immune microenvironment. The second hypothesis is that relevant trace of this cross&#xD;
      talk between tumor cells and immune microenvironment can be detected in the normal mucosa&#xD;
      surrounding the cancer according to the concept of field cancerization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims The aim of this project is to analyze the healthy rectal mucosa surrounding the cancer&#xD;
      to identify traces of immunosurveillance mechanisms and of field cancerization and to use&#xD;
      them to obtain a composite prognostic test to predict recurrence after complete response at&#xD;
      neoadjuvant therapy in case of locally advanced rectal cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental Design This prognostic test will be constructed on the combinatory analysis of&#xD;
      the transcriptome, immune and epithelial cells cross-talk, immune checkpoints and miRNA&#xD;
      expression in normal rectal mucosa surrounding cancer. The project aim is to identify, among&#xD;
      locally advanced rectal cancer, those with sustained complete response to neoadjuvant&#xD;
      chemo/radiotherapy. The study is articulated in two steps. In step A, we will retrospectively&#xD;
      analyze archival tissue samples in order to identify the most performing biomarkers; in step&#xD;
      B, we will validate the prognostic performance of the markers identified in phase I through a&#xD;
      prospective analysis of rectal mucosa specimen.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Locally advanced rectal cancer: which treatment after complete response after neoadjuvant&#xD;
      therapy? Combined treatment for locally advanced rectal cancer achieves a 5-year overall&#xD;
      survival close to90% [15]. This multimodal approach can be also applied to elderly patients&#xD;
      with stage III rectal cancer obtaining improved oncological outcomes [16]. Some patients with&#xD;
      rectal cancer who receive neoadjuvant chemoradiotherapy (nCRT) achieve a pathologic complete&#xD;
      response (pCR) and may be eligible for less radical surgery or non-operative management [17].&#xD;
      Moreover, complete regression of the rectal cancer after neoadjuvant chemoradiation therapy&#xD;
      have been confirmed by clinical and radiographic evaluation-this is known as complete&#xD;
      clinical response (cCR). The &quot;watch and wait&quot; approach was first proposed by Dr. Angelita&#xD;
      Habr-Gama in Brazil in 2009. Those patients with cCR are followed with rigorousphysical,&#xD;
      endoscopical, and imaging surveillance [18]. Several studies aimed to identify variables that&#xD;
      predict pCR after nCRT for rectal cancer. A large retrospective review of the NCDB performed&#xD;
      from 2006 to 2011, including a total of 23,747 patients identified the clinical factors&#xD;
      associated with pCR. They were lower tumor grade, lower clinical T and N stage, higher&#xD;
      radiation dose, and delaying surgery by more than 6-8weeks after the end of radiation, while&#xD;
      lack of health insurance was linked with a lower likelihood of pCR [17]. Another study&#xD;
      identified predictive factors in the models included tumor length, tumor circumferential&#xD;
      extent, age, and ApoA1 [19]. A different study showed that responders after neoadjuvant&#xD;
      chemoradiation had a lower incidence of cytokeratin 20 positive circulating tumor cells&#xD;
      compared to non-responders, which might be a result of effective systemic and local treatment&#xD;
      prior to surgery [20]. Finally, the role of immune microenvironment was investigated&#xD;
      analyzing Foxp3(+), CD3(+), CD4(+), CD8(+) and IL-17(+) cell density in post-CRT surgical&#xD;
      samples from 128 patients with rectal cancer. Stromal Foxp3(+) cell density was strongly&#xD;
      associated with tumor regression grade. A low stromal Foxp3(+) cell density was observed in&#xD;
      84% of patients who had a pathologic complete response (pCR) compared to41% of patients who&#xD;
      did not. Low stromal Foxp3(+) cell density was also associated with improved recurrence-free&#xD;
      survival. Regulatory T cells in the tumor microenvironment may inhibit response to&#xD;
      neoadjuvant CRT and may represent a therapeutic target in rectal cancer [21].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses and Specific aims The main hypothesis underlying our research is that&#xD;
      aggressiveness of rectal cancer is determined by the complex interactions between the&#xD;
      malignant cells and the local immune microenvironment. Our hypothesis is that the local&#xD;
      immune activation may involve the &quot;healthy&quot; rectal mucosa surrounding the cancer and the&#xD;
      sampling of this mucosa may provide useful information about rectal cancer behavior. In fact,&#xD;
      a combination of different factors, including molecular signaling networks (i.e. checkpoint&#xD;
      genes) within different cell population, presence of soluble chemical factors and&#xD;
      quantity/quality of immune cells infiltrate will decide rectal cancer behavior and its&#xD;
      response to neoadjuvant chemoradiation. Moreover, tumor cells actively interact with the&#xD;
      microenvironment secreting and degrading extracellular matrix components, and the release of&#xD;
      soluble molecules (e.g. miRNA) can significantly influence the inflammatory and immune&#xD;
      responses of the &quot;healthy&quot; rectal mucosa surrounding the cancer. By using state of the art&#xD;
      histological/molecular/immunological markers and bio-statistical analysis tools we aim to&#xD;
      identify clinically relevant molecular targets to design effective therapeutic strategies for&#xD;
      rectal cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the aim of the study is to identify a prognostic test that accurately predicts&#xD;
      rectal cancer behavior even in case when the tumor samples are scarce (due to small size of&#xD;
      early rectal cancer) or absent (in case of complete response to therapy). This prognostic&#xD;
      test will be constructed on the combinatory analysis of the transcriptome, immune cells&#xD;
      activation and checkpoints, epithelial cells activity as antigen presenting cells and miRNA&#xD;
      expression in normal tissue specimens of prospectively collected rectal cancers. The question&#xD;
      is how to identify, among locally advanced rectal cancer, those with immediate and sustained&#xD;
      complete response to neoadjuvant chemo/radiotherapy. These patients might safely avoid a low&#xD;
      rectal resection with all the consequences for their quality of life. In patients with&#xD;
      locally advanced rectal cancer (N+) an ideal biomarker should be able to identify the cohort&#xD;
      of patients that will have a complete response to neoadjuvant therapy and will not require&#xD;
      further treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design Tissue samples will be obtained from cancer tissue (if possible) and from normal&#xD;
      rectal mucosa adjacent to the cancer at surgery. The very large number of patients need to&#xD;
      answer the two questions imply a multicentric design. Complete medical record and follow-up&#xD;
      will be collected from each center. The analysis will be centralized mostly in Azienda&#xD;
      Ospedaliera di Padova. The study will be articulated in two parts each of them aiming to&#xD;
      answer to one of the above described questions. Each part of the study will be articulated in&#xD;
      a retrospective and exploratory step (A) and in a prospective validation step (B).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>pathological complete response on the operative specimen</measure>
    <time_frame>first post operative month</time_frame>
    <description>pathological complete response to neoadjuvant chemo/radiotherapy in locally advanced rectal cancer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">544</enrollment>
  <condition>Rectal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Immunohistochemistry, Flow citometry, Trascriptome analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>we will perform immunohistochemistry, flow cytometry, transcriptomic analysis, mRNA microarray and mutational profiling</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Retrospective</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Mucosal samples from healthy tissue surrounding the cancer&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        We aim to analyze 66 patients with pathological complete response and 66 patients without&#xD;
        complete response after neoadjuvant therapy for locally advanced rectal cancer. Given an&#xD;
        expected proportion of 20% of patients with complete response, we estimate to enroll a&#xD;
        total number of 66/0.20=330 patients with early rectal cancer. However, we will performed&#xD;
        flow cytometry, transcriptomic analysis, mRNA microarray and mutational profiling only in&#xD;
        132 patients (66 patients with complete response and 66 patients without complete response)&#xD;
        in order to test the non-inferiority of AUC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Taking into account a 15-20% of locally advanced rectal cancer patients with pathological&#xD;
        complete response to neoadjuvant therapy and a maximum of 7 prognostic factors (including&#xD;
        markers and clinical factors) in the model, we aim to enroll 412 patients in this part of&#xD;
        the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. locally advanced (cT3-4 and/or N+, TNM stage II-III) low and medium rectal cancer (&lt;11&#xD;
             cm) or low rectum adenocarcinoma cT≤2, at risk for abdominoperineal amputation,&#xD;
             undergoing neoadjuvant therapy will be included in the study group.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Only neoadjuvant therapy protocols including long course radiotherapy (45 Gy) and&#xD;
             fluoropyrimidine-based regimens will be included while short radiation therapy of&#xD;
             radiation therapy or chemotherapy alone will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. at least 6 weeks after the end of the neoadjuvant therapy will be included&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Full availability of clinical records at least 1 year of follow up&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marco Scarpa, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinica Chirurgica I, Azienda Ospedale Università di Padova</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marco Scarpa, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>#39 049 821 2672</phone>
    <email>marco.scarpa@aopd.veneto.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedale Università di Padova</name>
      <address>
        <city>Padova</city>
        <zip>35128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marco Scarpa, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>#39 049 821 2055</phone>
      <email>marco.scarpa@aopd.veneto.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>rectal cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>complete response</keyword>
  <keyword>neoadjuvant therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>immune surveillance</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

