<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04917770</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HX20210601</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04917770</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Efficacy and Safety of Sintilimab in Combination With Multimodal Radiotherapy in Patients With Recurrent or Metastatic Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Efficacy and Safety of Sintilimab in Combination With Multimodal Radiotherapy in Patients With Recurrent or Metastatic Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma After Multi-line Treatment (Including Immunotherapy)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>West China Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Chengdu City No.2 People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>No.3 People's Hospital of Chengdu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The First People's Hospital of Ziyang</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>No.5 People's Hospital of Chengdu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>West China Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Nasopharyngeal carcinoma is the most common malignant tumor of head and neck in southern&#xD;
      China. After standard treatment, about 20% of the patients had local recurrence or distant&#xD;
      metastasis, and the patients faced death in a short time. Currently, there is no recommended&#xD;
      treatment for patients with recurrent or metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma who have&#xD;
      unsatisfactory results of first-line chemotherapy and subsequent immunotherapy. Patients who&#xD;
      have failed multiline therapy have a low survival rate and no drugs are available.This&#xD;
      project aims to evaluate the efficacy and safety of sintilimab in combination with multimodal&#xD;
      radiotherapy for patients with recurrent or metastatic nasopharyngeal carcinoma who have&#xD;
      previously received immunotherapy and still progress after multiline therapy, and to seek a&#xD;
      new therapeutic approach for such patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Sintilimab in combination with Multimodality Radiotherapy group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of remission</measure>
    <time_frame>up to approximately 2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1 year overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>1 years after treatment finished</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: from the first drug administration to within 30 days for the last therapy</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sintilimab in combination with Multimodality Radiotherapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The dose of sintilimab was 200mg per dose, intravenously, once every 3 weeks. Multimodal radiotherapy methods: ①SBRT: ≥1 independent lesion was selected, with a single dose of 8-10Gy and a total dose of 40-60Gy, divided into 5-6 times of radiotherapy. The final frequency and total dose of radiotherapy were determined by the radiologist.② Low-dose radiotherapy: ≥1 independent lesion was selected, and the single dose, the final frequency of radiotherapy and the total dose were determined by the radiologist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sintilimab in combination with Multimodality Radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be treated with sintilimab in combination with multimodality radiotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sintilimab in combination with Multimodality Radiotherapy group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The histopathological diagnosis was recurrent or distant metastatic nasopharyngeal&#xD;
             carcinoma;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have received two or more lines of treatment, including at least one immunocheckpoint&#xD;
             inhibitor related therapy containing PD-1/L1, and have achieved clinical benefit;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Aged between 18 and 65 at the date of signing the informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG score 0-1;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. At least ≥1 measurable lesion according to Recist v1.1, or ≥1 measurable lesion with&#xD;
             definite progression after local treatment (based on Recist v1.1 criteria);At the same&#xD;
             time, there were more than 1 radiotherapy foci and lesions with radiographic&#xD;
             evaluation of distant effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Life expectancy ≥12 weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Major organ functions within 28 days prior to treatment meet the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A. Routine blood test criteria (without blood transfusion within 14 days) : hemoglobin (Hb)&#xD;
        ≥80g/L;Neutrophils absolute value (ANC) ≥1.5×109/L;Platelet (PLT) ≥80×109/L; B. Biochemical&#xD;
        tests should meet the following criteria: total bilirubin (TBIL) ≤1.5 times the upper limit&#xD;
        of normal (ULN);Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST)&#xD;
        ≤2.5×ULN, if accompanied by liver metastasis, ALT and AST≤5×ULN;Serum creatinine (CR)&#xD;
        ≤1.5×ULN or creatinine clearance rate (CCR)≥60ml/min; C. Coagulograms should meet the&#xD;
        following criteria: International Standardized Ratio (INR) or Prothrombin Time (PT) ≤&#xD;
        1.5ULN;Activated partial thromboplastin time (APTT) ≤1.5 ULN (if the patient is receiving&#xD;
        anticoagulant therapy, as long as PT and APTT are within the expected treatment range); D.&#xD;
        centrifuge markers and urinary natriuretic peptide (BNP) ≤ULN; E. Thyroid function: T3 and&#xD;
        T4 levels were normal after medication; 8. Women of reproductive age should agree to use&#xD;
        contraceptives (such as intrauterine devices, contraceptives or condoms) during the study&#xD;
        period and for 120 days after the end of the study;Negative serum or urinary pregnancy test&#xD;
        within 7 days prior to study enrollment; 9. With my consent and signed the informed&#xD;
        consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous use of immunocheckpoint inhibitors combined with radiotherapy after&#xD;
             recurrence and metastasis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A history of other malignant tumors within the previous 5 years or at the same time,&#xD;
             except cured basal cell carcinoma of the skin, carcinoma in situ of the cervix and&#xD;
             papillary carcinoma of the thyroid;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. known allergic reactions to active ingredients of PD-1 monoclonal antibody or any&#xD;
             excipients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Symptomatic central nervous system metastasis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Those who had received potent CYP3A4 inhibitor treatment within one week before&#xD;
             enrollment, or inducer CYP3A4 treatment within two weeks before enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The New York Heart Association's cardiac function classification is Grade III-IV&#xD;
             congestive heart failure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. An ischemic cardiovascular event occurred within 1 year prior to treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. QT interval of ECG &gt;500 ms;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Have received systemic immunosuppressive therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participate in clinical trials of other interventional drugs within 4 weeks before the&#xD;
             first administration;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects who require systematic treatment with corticosteroids (greater than 10mg&#xD;
             equivalent daily dose of prednisone) or other immunosuppressant within 2 weeks prior&#xD;
             to the first use of the study drug;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Have received an anti-tumor vaccine or a live vaccine within 4 weeks before the first&#xD;
             administration of the investigational drug;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Major surgery or severe trauma within 4 weeks before the first use of the study drug;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Severe infections (CTCAE &gt; grade 2) occurred within 4 weeks before the first use of&#xD;
             the study drug, such as severe pneumonia, bacteremia, infection complications, etc.,&#xD;
             requiring hospitalization;Baseline chest imaging examination suggests active pulmonary&#xD;
             inflammation, signs and symptoms of infection within 2 weeks prior to the first use of&#xD;
             the study drug, or the need for oral or intravenous antibiotic treatment (excluding&#xD;
             prophylactic use of antibiotics);&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Have a history of active autoimmune diseases or autoimmune diseases (such as&#xD;
             interstitial pneumonia, colitis, hepatitis, pituitaritis, vasculitis, nephritis,&#xD;
             hyperthyroidism, hypothyroidism, including but not limited to these diseases and&#xD;
             syndromes);Autoimmune-mediated hypothyroidism treated with a steady dose of&#xD;
             thyroid-replacement hormone and with a steady dose of insulin in type 1 diabetes were&#xD;
             included;This does not include patients with vitiligo or cured childhood&#xD;
             asthma/allergies who do not need any intervention as adults;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Have a history of immunodeficiency, including HIV positive or other acquired or&#xD;
             congenital immunodeficiency diseases, or have a history of organ transplantation or&#xD;
             bone marrow transplantation;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. History of non-infectious pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Patients with active tuberculosis infection found by medical history or CT&#xD;
             examination, or patients with active tuberculosis infection found within 1 year before&#xD;
             enrollment, or patients with active tuberculosis infection found before 1 year but&#xD;
             without formal treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subsubjects had active hepatitis (HBV DNA≥2000IU/ mL or 10000 copies/ mL) and&#xD;
             hepatitis C (HCV antibody positive and HCV-RNA above the detection limit of the assay&#xD;
             method);&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. A history of known abuse of psychotropic substances, alcoholism and drug abuse;&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Being pregnant or lactating;&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. There is any history, disease, treatment, or abnormal laboratory result that may&#xD;
             interfere with the results of the study and prevent subjects from participating fully&#xD;
             in the study, or the investigator deems that participation is not in the best interest&#xD;
             of the subjects.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Xingchen Peng, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>18980606753</phone>
    <email>pxx2014@scu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>West China Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Xingchen Peng</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor and Doctoral Advisor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sintilimab</keyword>
  <keyword>nasopharyngeal carcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nasopharyngeal Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

