<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04913363</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HSR210100</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04913363</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Emotional, Physical and Cognitive Benefits of Purposeful Green Space Activities on Seniors</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Emotional, Physical and Cognitive Benefits of Purposeful Green Space Activities on Seniors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Virginia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jefferson Area Board of Aging</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Virginia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This project explores if various nature based activities can lead to acute improvements in&#xD;
      emotional, physical and cognitive health outcomes and encouraging senior center (JABA)&#xD;
      service users to return to a safe environment. The activities the investigators will use&#xD;
      include walking in nature, engaging in physical planting and cerebral, citizen science based&#xD;
      activities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study builds on the previous experimental work and expands it to focus on older adults&#xD;
      in the Charlottesville area. The study objective is to understand the impact of different&#xD;
      types of activities in green settings on physical and mental health outcomes in older adults&#xD;
      at JABA centers using a repeated measures, crossover design in 20 participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are three activity sessions in this project; walking (contemplative), planting&#xD;
      (physical) and citizen science (cerebral). The walking condition will be a short green walk&#xD;
      (10-15 minutes). The planting session will be run by JABA staff and a Master Gardener and&#xD;
      will allow participants an opportunity to be outdoors and plant and tend to plants. The&#xD;
      citizen science session will be run by JABA staff and a consultant and will rely less on&#xD;
      physical exertion but rather focus on understanding green space at a more academic level. All&#xD;
      sessions will be outdoors and will follow COVID-19 guidelines in place at the time of&#xD;
      testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures The investigators will use various measures to assess the impact of green&#xD;
      activity on emotional, physical and cognitive health outcomes, including;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Loneliness; measured by the UCLA Loneliness Scale, a 3-item scale that captures feelings&#xD;
           of loneliness.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Belonging; measured by the General Belonging Scale (GBS), a 12-item scale capturing&#xD;
           social acceptance/inclusion and social rejection/exclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Acute Mood; pre and post measures of mood will be taken using the UWIST Mood Adjective&#xD;
           Checklist (MACL), an acute measure of hedonic tone, stress and arousal.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Restoration; Psychological restorative qualities of the setting measured by the&#xD;
           Perceived Restorativeness Scale, a three point scale determining the restorative quality&#xD;
           of activity spaces.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical Activity; In addition to the arousal measure of the MACL, the investigators&#xD;
           will use the 10 point scale of the OMNI Perceived Exertion scale, to understand how&#xD;
           physically exerted participants feel between activities. To understand baseline physical&#xD;
           activity, the investigators use the international physical activity questionnaire (IPAQ)&#xD;
           to compare between studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Accelerometer; the investigators will use accelerometers to measure participant movement&#xD;
           throughout the activities to correlate with physical activity measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All outcome measures will be scored and subsequently analysed using a one-way ANOVA to&#xD;
      determine if experimental condition leads to any statistically significant difference between&#xD;
      outcome scores. The investigators will look for correlations between outcome measures in&#xD;
      order to establish relationships between variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will also send a short survey to a number of JABA service users (n=30) to&#xD;
      understand mood, wellbeing and current barriers to returning to their local JABA center. This&#xD;
      survey will include the UCLA Loneliness Scale, the GBS, mood and physical activity measures&#xD;
      included above, as well as broader questions assessing their experience of the lockdown and&#xD;
      their needs for safe return to the center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be sent consent information in advance and have an opportunity to talk to&#xD;
      the research time prior to attending their first session. For all conditions, participants&#xD;
      would meet at a pre-determined location near their local JABA center and taken to the&#xD;
      activity site directly. Participants will complete the short surveys, listed above, both pre&#xD;
      and post their activity. All activities will last around 20 minutes. Participants will return&#xD;
      for two consecutive weeks to undertake the alternative activities to which they originally&#xD;
      completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Activities Participants will undertake three activities, on separate days, throughout this&#xD;
      project.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Walking; this contemplative activity will see users taken to a local green space area&#xD;
           near their center and encouraged to walk around the space. It is anticipated that walks&#xD;
           will last around 15-20 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Planting; this physical activity will see users, lead by a local Master Gardener, engage&#xD;
           with planting vegetables/fruit in raised beds. Not only will this allow users a chance&#xD;
           to engage physically with nature, but it is anticipated that the grown produce will be&#xD;
           used for center users.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Citizen Science; this cerebral activity sees users engage with local green spaces, under&#xD;
           the instruction of a citizen scientist, to learn about the intricacies of the space.&#xD;
           This may include lichen counts (or similar) where the main outcome is learning based.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Repeated measures, crossover design where participants undertake each of the purposeful green space activities.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Loneliness (Time 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre activity</time_frame>
    <description>measured by the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) Loneliness Scale, a 3-item scale that captures feelings of loneliness. Scores range from 3 to 9 with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived loneliness</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Loneliness (Time 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Post activity (20 minutes after pre-activity measure)</time_frame>
    <description>measured by the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) Loneliness Scale, a 3-item scale that captures feelings of loneliness. Scores range from 3 to 9 with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived loneliness</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Social Isolation (Time 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre activity</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the General Belonging Scale (GBS), a 12-item scale capturing social acceptance/inclusion and social rejection/exclusion. Scores will range from 12 to 84, with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived belonging.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Social Isolation (Time 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Post activity (20 minutes after pre-activity measure)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the General Belonging Scale (GBS), a 12-item scale capturing social acceptance/inclusion and social rejection/exclusion. Scores will range from 12 to 84, with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived belonging.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood (Time 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre activity</time_frame>
    <description>pre and post measures of mood will be taken using the University of Wales Institute of Science and Technology (UWIST) Mood Adjective Checklist (MACL), an acute measure of hedonic tone, stress and arousal. Each subscale will range from 4 to 12, with higher scores indicating higher valence, stress and arousal, respectively.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood (Time 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Post activity (20 minutes after pre-activity measure)</time_frame>
    <description>pre and post measures of mood will be taken using the University of Wales Institute of Science and Technology (UWIST) Mood Adjective Checklist (MACL), an acute measure of hedonic tone, stress and arousal. Each subscale will range from 4 to 12, with higher scores indicating higher valence, stress and arousal, respectively.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Well Aging (Time 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre activity</time_frame>
    <description>Psychological restorative qualities of the setting measured by the Perceived Restorativeness Scale, a three point scale determining the restorative quality of activity spaces. Scores range from 4 to 28, with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived restoration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Well Aging (Time 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Post activity (20 minutes after pre-activity measure)</time_frame>
    <description>Psychological restorative qualities of the setting measured by the Perceived Restorativeness Scale, a three point scale determining the restorative quality of activity spaces. Scores range from 4 to 28, with higher scores indicating higher levels of perceived restoration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Activity (Time 1)</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre activity</time_frame>
    <description>In addition to the arousal measure of the MACL, the investigators will use the 10 point scale of the OMNI Perceived Exertion scale, to understand how physically exerted participants feel between activities. To understand baseline physical activity, the investigators will use the international physical activity questionnaire (IPAQ) to compare between studies. For the OMNI, scores range from 1 to 11 with higher scores indicating increased ease of the task and tiredness, respectively. For the IPAQ, this is a composite of multiple scores that depend on participant minutes exercising; final scores however determine low, medium and high levels of exertion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Activity (Time 2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Post activity (20 minutes after pre-activity measure)</time_frame>
    <description>In addition to the arousal measure of the MACL, the investigators will use the 10 point scale of the OMNI Perceived Exertion scale, to understand how physically exerted participants feel between activities. To understand baseline physical activity, the investigators will use the international physical activity questionnaire (IPAQ) to compare between studies. For the OMNI, scores range from 1 to 11 with higher scores indicating increased ease of the task and tiredness, respectively. For the IPAQ, this is a composite of multiple scores that depend on participant minutes exercising; final scores however determine low, medium and high levels of exertion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobility Limitation</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout activity (measure taken for 20 minutes)</time_frame>
    <description>we will use accelerometers to measure participant movement throughout the activities to correlate with physical activity measures.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Loneliness</condition>
  <condition>Social Isolation</condition>
  <condition>Mood</condition>
  <condition>Well Aging</condition>
  <condition>Physical Activity</condition>
  <condition>Mobility Limitation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Walking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This contemplative activity will see users taken to a local green space area near their center and encouraged to walk around the space. It is anticipated walks will last around 15-20 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Citizen Science</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This cerebral activity sees users engage with local green spaces, under the instruction of a citizen scientist, to learn about the intricacies of the space. This may include lichen counts (or similar) where the main outcome is learning based.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Planting</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This physical activity will see users, lead by a local Master Gardener, engage with planting vegetables/fruit in raised beds. Not only will this allow users a chance to engage physically with nature, but it is anticipated that the grown produce will be used for center users.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Green space</intervention_name>
    <description>Green space in which activities take place</description>
    <arm_group_label>Citizen Science</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Planting</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Walking</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A JABA center user&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can walk unassisted for 20 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to comply with COVID-19 regulations&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Never used a JABA center&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unable to walk unassisted for 20 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to comply with COVID-19 regulations&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jenny Roe</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Virginia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jenny Roe</last_name>
    <phone>4349824567</phone>
    <email>jjr4b@virginia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Chris Neale</last_name>
    <email>cn5nr@virginia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Virginia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Roe</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mobility Limitation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

