<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04910256</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>XiyuanH-huatuo zaizao pill</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04910256</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>We Plan to Use Huato Zaizao Pills for Stroke Patients to Evaluate Their Efficacy and Safety and Divide 80 Subjects Into Two Groups at Random.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Investigation of Huatuo Zaizao Pill in Treating Phlegm and Blood-stasis Blocking Collaterals Pattern of Ischemic Stroke Patients: Study Protocol for a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Xiyuan Hospital of China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Xiyuan Hospital of China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is aiming to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Huatuo Zaizao pill in ischemic&#xD;
      stroke patients who diagnosed as the phlegm and blood-stasis blocking collaterals syndrome in&#xD;
      TCM. A total of 80 subjects will be randomly assigned to Huatuo Zaizao pill group or the&#xD;
      control group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized controlled clinical trial. Eighty patients with phlegm and&#xD;
      blood stasis block syndrome of ischemic stroke were randomly assigned to Hua Hua&#xD;
      reconstruction group or control group at a ratio of 1:1. The treatment period is 12 weeks.&#xD;
      The purpose is to evaluate its efficacy and safety, provide an objective basis for precise&#xD;
      treatment of traditional Chinese medicine, and improve clinical efficacy. The main result is&#xD;
      the changes of NIHSS, Fugl-Meyer, and MAS 90 days after taking the drug. The secondary result&#xD;
      is the change in ADL and TCM symptom scale (CM-SS).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 20, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 20, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants are randomly and evenly assigned to 2 groups using block randomization.Random numbers are generated by the stratified random method using the Statistical Analysis Software （SAS） statistical software and assigned by an independent statistician at the Good Clinical Practice Institute of XiYuan Hospital.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>National Institute of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS )</measure>
    <time_frame>The change from baseline in National institute of health stroke scale (NIHSS ) score at week 6 and 12 [Time Frame: Baseline,6th week±3 days, 12th week±3 days]</time_frame>
    <description>The National Institutes of Health Stroke Scale (NIHSS) is a 15-item measure of the effect of acute stroke on a variety of areas including level of consciousness, neglect, motor strength, facial palsy, ataxia, dysarthria, and sensory loss.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Ashworth Scale (MAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The change from baseline in Modified Ashworth Scale (MAS) score at week 6 and 12 [Time Frame: Baseline,6th week±3 days, 12th week±3 days]</time_frame>
    <description>Modified Ashworth Scale (MAS) measure spasticity. During the administration of MAS , the examiner passively moves the joint being tested and rates the perceived level of resistance in the muscle groups opposing the movement.It is single-item measures ranging from 0 to 4, where 0 indicates no increase in muscle tone and 4 indicates that the affected part is rigid in flexion or extension.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fugl-Meyer</measure>
    <time_frame>The change from baseline in Fugl-Meye score at week 6 and 12 [Time Frame: Baseline,6th week±3 days, 12th week±3 days]</time_frame>
    <description>The Fugl-Meyer Assessment of Sensorimotor Impairment (FM) is one of the first scales developed to quantitatively measure the recovery from hemiplegic stroke. It assesses recovery in five domains, including motor functioning of the upper and lower extremities, balance, sensation, joint range of motion, and joint pain in post-stroke patients. Each task is scored on a scale of 0-2, with 0 indicating the patient cannot perform the task and 2 indicating the patient can fully perform the task.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Activities of Daily Living (ADL)</measure>
    <time_frame>The change from baseline in Activities of Daily Living (ADL) total score at week 6 and 12 [Time Frame: Baseline,6th week±3 days, 12th week±3 days]</time_frame>
    <description>The ADL is a test used in healthcare to evaluate the people's daily self care activities.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chinese Medicine Symptom Scale (CM-SS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The change from baseline in The Chinese Medicine Symptom Scale (CM-SS) total score at week 6 and 12 [Time Frame: Baseline,6th week±3 days, 12th week±3 days]</time_frame>
    <description>The CM-SS is a tool, designed according to the Guiding Principles of Clinical Research on New Drugs of Traditional Chinese Medicine issued in 2002, to evaluate the effects of treatments on Traditional Chinese medicine patterns. Scoring is mainly based on some typical TCM symptoms, such as tongue coating and pulse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Ischemic Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HuaTuo ZaiZao group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this arm, patients take 8g of HuatuoZaizao pill three times a day. Besides，participants will receive basic treatment in accordance with the &quot;Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of ischemic stroke in China&quot;,and the drug and dosage will be formulated by the researchers according to the clinical situation.Treatment lasts for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>participants will receive basic treatment in accordance with the &quot;Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of ischemic stroke in China&quot;,and the drug and dosage will be formulated by the researchers according to the clinical situation.Treatment lasts for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HuaTuo Zaizao pill</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients take 8g of HuaTuo Zaizao pill three times a day. Treatment lasts for 12 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>HuaTuo ZaiZao group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>basic treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>It accordance with the &quot;Guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of ischemic stroke in China&quot;,and the drug and dosage will be formulated by the researchers according to the clinical situation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>HuaTuo ZaiZao group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1.Aged between 35 and 75 years old 2.With a disease course between 2 weeks- 24weeks&#xD;
             3.Meeting the diagnostic criteria of ischemic stroke 4.Meeting the diagnostic criteria&#xD;
             of phlegm and blood-stasis blocking collaterals pattern in T traditional Chinese&#xD;
             medicine 5.Signed and dated written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1.Unstable vital signs, or serious heart, liver, lung, kidney and other organ diseases&#xD;
             2.Exclude Transient Ischemic Attack(TIA) 3.Patients who are participating in clinical&#xD;
             trials of other drugs within the past 1 month 4.Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yanqiu Ding</last_name>
    <phone>(+86)18513123006</phone>
    <email>dingyanqiu001@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Xiyuan Hospital, China Academy of Chinese Medical Sciences</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>10091</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemic Stroke</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

