<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04911452</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H21-00527</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04911452</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Creating a Calmer NICU: Optimizing Brain Development in Preterm Infants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Creating a CALMER NICU: Pilot Testing a Robot for Optimizing Brain Development in Preterm Infants in the NICU</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Women's Health Research Institute of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Infants born preterm can spend months in the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU) where they&#xD;
      experience stressful but essential procedures. Untreated stress is associated with altered&#xD;
      brain development. Skin-to-skin holding (SSH) is one of the most effective behavioral&#xD;
      strategies for mitigating preterm infant stress and improving brain maturation. However,&#xD;
      parents may not be always available to provide SSH; some infants cannot be held for long&#xD;
      periods for medical reasons. To address this problem, investigators designed Calmer, a&#xD;
      patented, prototype therapy bed, for reducing stress in preterm infants. Calmer fits into&#xD;
      NICU incubators and provides simultaneously an artificial skin surface, heartbeat sounds and&#xD;
      breathing motion, mimicking aspects of SSH; the latter 2 features are individualized for each&#xD;
      infant based on their parents' recordings. The 1st randomized controlled trial (RCT) in 58&#xD;
      preterm babies showed that during a routine blood test: Calmer lowered infant behavioral and&#xD;
      heart stress responses and stabilized brain blood flow no differently than facilitated&#xD;
      tucking; infants could be cared for safely on Calmer up to 6 hours in 1 day; Calmer was well&#xD;
      accepted by mothers and staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal now is to determine the efficacy of Calmer use over 3 weeks to support optimal brain&#xD;
      maturation and physical growth in preterm infants. A 2-group (treatment, control) pilot RCT&#xD;
      to test the implementation of an increased &quot;dose&quot; of Calmer exposure over 3 continuous weeks&#xD;
      is proposed. 10 infants born between 26-30 weeks gestational age in the NICU will be&#xD;
      randomized to receive either Calmer, for a minimum of 3 hours in total/day for 3 continuous&#xD;
      weeks, or to 3 weeks of standard NICU care. Functional brain monitoring using a combined&#xD;
      near-infrared spectroscopy/electroencephalography (EEG) device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Is it feasible to enrol 12 infants, complete a 3-week treatment period, and measure&#xD;
           brain maturation and growth outcomes in preterm infants in the NICU in a pilot RCT of&#xD;
           daily Calmer treatment versus standard care to inform a larger, definitive RCT?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Are there differences in brain maturation markers, as measured by EEG, between babies in&#xD;
           Calmer vs control group, measured during 2 resting/sleeping sessions (start and end of&#xD;
           study)?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Are there differences in brain oxygen signalling, physical growth markers (e.g. daily&#xD;
           weight gain) between groups measured at start of the study and after 3 weeks of daily&#xD;
           Calmer exposure?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pilot trial implementation targets:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Targets for success would be that the informed consent rate will be at least 40%,12 patients&#xD;
      will be enrolled in 6 months, 95% of infants will receive the 3 hour minimum treatment, and&#xD;
      patient assessment completion rate will be at least 85%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this pilot trial will be used to inform the design of a larger RCT. The&#xD;
      results of this pilot trial will allow to assess patient accrual, protocol adherence, and to&#xD;
      monitor the completeness and quality of the outcome data. If implementation targets are met,&#xD;
      an application for further funding to use this protocol in a larger, multisite,&#xD;
      non-inferiority trial comparing SSH + Calmer to SSH alone will be put forth.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single-site, single-blind, two-group (treatment and control), randomized pilot trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Data outcomes for brain, growth and behaviour will be blind to group allocation</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frontal electroencephalography (EEG) power</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>During the 2 resting/sleeping assessments, frontal EEG power (an index of electrocortical activity) in 10 frequency bands, with a specific focus on delta frequency activity (1-3 Hz), which is a quintessential feature of the developing brain, will be examined.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frontal cerebral tissue oxygenation</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>During the 2 resting/sleeping assessments, frontal cerebral tissue oxygenation variation will be captured from the near-infrared spectroscopy (NIRS) signals measured by the EEG/NIRS probe. The dynamic (temporal) relationship between EEG and NIRS signals to assess neurovascular coupling as a measure of brain neuronal and blood flow integration will also be examined. This will allow investigation of the cerebral hemodynamic responses and their relationship to spontaneous neuronal activity (e.g. non-specific neuronal activity bursts, or &quot;delta brushes&quot;) during the sleep/resting state.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep/wake states</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep/wake state assessment is required to interpret the EEG findings accurately. During each of the two brain measurement sessions, sleep/wake states will be coded using the Newborn Developmental Care and Assessment Program (NIDCAP) in 20 second blocks over the 30-minute recording.&#xD;
This coding system was chosen specifically because it describes behavioural state characteristics of preterm infants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight gain</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The change in average infant weight gain between Calmer and control groups in grams/day (g/d) will be measured on the day before the start of the treatment (baseline), at the mid-way point (~day 11), and at the end of the 3-week period, then divided by the number of treatment days. Sex and gestational age (GA) age-specific percentiles for the measures will be calculated using the Fenton Growth charts. Changes in weight percentiles between baseline and end of treatment will then be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nutritional status for route, type, nutritional additive and frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measures of daily feeding and nutritional data will include: method of feeding (intravenous, nasogastric, oral-gastric, oral), type (total parenteral nutrition, breastmilk (mother's or donor), formula, additives (Human milk fortifier, lipids), frequency/timing and method (breast/bottle) of transition from tube to oral feeds at transfer/discharge.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Head circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline, mid-point and end-of-treatment measures of head circumference in cm (occipito-frontal circumference [OCP]) will be reported. Sex and GA age-specific percentiles for the measures will be calculated using the Fenton Growth charts. Changes in OFC percentiles between baseline and end of treatment will then be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body length</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline, mid-point and end-of-treatment measures of body length in cm will be reported. Sex and GA age-specific percentiles for the measures will be calculated using the Fenton Growth charts. Changes in body length percentiles between baseline and end of treatment wil then be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Trial feasibility: Consent rates</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The following trial management data will be recorded:&#xD;
The overall average consent rate of infants/month</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Trial feasibility: Protocol delivery rate</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The following trial management data will be recorded:&#xD;
The percent of on/off protocol infants for the trial period</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Trial feasibility: Complete outcome measures</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The following trial management data will be recorded:&#xD;
The percent of infants with complete clinical primary and secondary outcome measures</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Trial feasibility: Safety issues</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The following trial management data will be recorded:&#xD;
Rate/nature of safety issues identified</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Prematurity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU) care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Calmer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Calmer placed and left in infant incubator for the 3-week study period. Calmer treatment provided for minimum total of 3 hours/day (can be discontinuous).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Calmer</intervention_name>
    <description>Once randomized, infants in the Calmer group will receive treatment for a minimum cumulative total of 3 hours/day during periods when the infant may be too ill to be held or when parents do not wish to hold their infant or are not present. Calmer does not replicate a parent's contact and so the minimum exposure has been tripled. No upper limit of Calmer use will be set. Each day, the research and/or bedside nurse will record the heart and respiratory rates for a two-minute period. The one-minute average will be used to program Calmer for each infant that day to better simulate day-to-day changes in infant-parent contact. The Neonatal Intensive Care Unit (NICU) research nurse will also train the parents/caregivers to self-measure their resting heart and breathing rates so that if they are away from the NICU for more than one day, these values can be sent to the research/ bedside nurse by phone.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Calmer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm infants admitted to the neonatal intensive care unit (NICU) at the British&#xD;
             Columbia (BC) Women's Hospital born at 26-30 completed weeks gestational age (GA). GA&#xD;
             is determined accurately using early gestation ultrasonogram (standard of care in BC),&#xD;
             or calculated using the last menstrual period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants who are on continuous positive airway pressure or are ventilated;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one parent/caregiver must speak sufficient English to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants who have congenital anomalies, small for GA (per medical admission history),&#xD;
             or have a history of maternal abuse of controlled drugs and substances; - Infants with&#xD;
             an ongoing infection at the time of enrolment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants that have pre-existing cardiovascular instability defined by&#xD;
             shock/hypotension/need for cardiovascular drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants receiving paralytic drugs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants that have major neurological injury (e.g. hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy,&#xD;
             hemorrhage/stroke);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants who are beyond the 30th completed week GA (30 weeks + 6 days) at enrolment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>26 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Weeks</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Liisa Holsti, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manon Ranger, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Manon Ranger, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>1-604-827-1382</phone>
    <email>manon.ranger@ubc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Esther Alonso Prieto, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>1-604-875-2000</phone>
    <phone_ext>7408</phone_ext>
    <email>esther.alonsoprieto@cw.bc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>British Columbia Women's Hospital and Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V6H 3N1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Manon Ranger, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>1-604-827-1382</phone>
      <email>manon.ranger@ubc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Esther Alonso Prieto, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>1-604-875-2000</phone>
      <phone_ext>7408</phone_ext>
      <email>esther.alonsoprieto@cw.bc.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Manon Ranger, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Liisa Holsti, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Johnston C, Campbell-Yeo M, Disher T, Benoit B, Fernandes A, Streiner D, Inglis D, Zee R. Skin-to-skin care for procedural pain in neonates. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017 Feb 16;2:CD008435. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD008435.pub3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28205208</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holsti L, MacLean K, Oberlander T, Synnes A, Brant R. Calmer: a robot for managing acute pain effectively in preterm infants in the neonatal intensive care unit. Pain Rep. 2019 Mar 14;4(2):e727. doi: 10.1097/PR9.0000000000000727. eCollection 2019 Mar-Apr.</citation>
    <PMID>31041426</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ranger M, Albert A, MacLean K, Holsti L. Cerebral hemodynamic response to a therapeutic bed for procedural pain management in preterm infants in the NICU: a randomized controlled trial. Pain Rep. 2021 Jan 12;6(1):e890. doi: 10.1097/PR9.0000000000000890. eCollection 2021 Jan-Feb.</citation>
    <PMID>33490850</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Williams N, MacLean K, Guan L, Collet JP, Holsti L. Pilot Testing a Robot for Reducing Pain in Hospitalized Preterm Infants. OTJR (Thorofare N J). 2019 Apr;39(2):108-115. doi: 10.1177/1539449218825436. Epub 2019 Feb 15.</citation>
    <PMID>30770034</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Whitehead K, Pressler R, Fabrizi L. Characteristics and clinical significance of delta brushes in the EEG of premature infants. Clin Neurophysiol Pract. 2016 Dec 5;2:12-18. doi: 10.1016/j.cnp.2016.11.002. eCollection 2017. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30214965</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fenton TR, Kim JH. A systematic review and meta-analysis to revise the Fenton growth chart for preterm infants. BMC Pediatr. 2013 Apr 20;13:59. doi: 10.1186/1471-2431-13-59. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23601190</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of British Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Manon Ranger</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prematurity</keyword>
  <keyword>Neonatal intensive care</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain maturation</keyword>
  <keyword>Growth</keyword>
  <keyword>Robotic device</keyword>
  <keyword>Skin-to-skin holding</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

