<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00454428</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>27579</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00454428</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Randomized Trial of Pulsatile vs Non Pulsatile Perfusion on Short Term Changes in Kidney Function Using an Intra-Aortic Ballooon Pump During Cardioplegic Arrest in Patients Undergoing Myocardial Reperfusion</brief_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Catanzaro</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Catanzaro</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Linear flow during cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) frequently induces renal damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will evaluate whether automatic intra-aortic balloon pump (IABP) induce pulsatile&#xD;
      perfusion preserves renal function in patients undergoing myocardial revascularization at&#xD;
      different risk for renal damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      100 patients undergoing preoperative IABP will be stratified for renal function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention. The patients will be randomized to non-pulsatile CPB during cardioplegic arrest&#xD;
      or automatic IABP induced pulsatile CPB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Renal function, daily diuretics, complication rate, lactatemia and other biochemical indices&#xD;
      will be compared in patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will prospectively enrolle 100 patients undergoing isolated primary high-risk coronary&#xD;
      artery bypass grafting for severe left main stem disease (70% narrowing) or left-main&#xD;
      equivalent three-vessels coronary disease. On admission to our institution, the patients will&#xD;
      be stratified for renal function according to KDOQI and randomly assigned to Group A or Group&#xD;
      B. We will exclude from the study patients older than 75 years, and/or with kidney disease ≥&#xD;
      Stage 4 (GFR 15 - 29 ml/min/1.73 m2), and/or with other splanchnic organ comorbidities (liver&#xD;
      or mesenteric impairment, abdominal aortic aneurysm, abdominal arteries vasculopathy), and/or&#xD;
      severe autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients randomized to Group A (n=50) will receive a preoperative IABP treatment before&#xD;
      induction of anesthesia, with IABP turned off during cardioplegic arrest, and restarted with&#xD;
      a 1:1 IABP mode immediately after cross-clamp removal (as is the traditionally adopted&#xD;
      perioperative IABP support); the other 50 (Group B) will receive standard preoperative&#xD;
      treatment with IABP, which will switche into an automatic 80 bpm mode during cross-clamp&#xD;
      time, and switche again into a 1:1 IABP after cross-clamp removal, in order to achieve a&#xD;
      pulsatile perfusion during the entire intra-operative time-course.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients will be stratified in 2 subgroups according to the preoperative renal function:&#xD;
      a subgroup will include 64 patients (32 allocated in Group A and 32 in Group B) with stage 1&#xD;
      or 2 [Stage 1: GFR ≥90 ml/min/1.73 m2 - Stage 2: GFR 60 - 89 ml/min/1.73 m2] and therefore&#xD;
      considered at lower-risk for post-CPB renal damage; the remaining 36 (18 for each group) with&#xD;
      KDOQI Stage 3 of kidney disease (GFR 30 - 59 ml/min/1.73 m2) will be considered at&#xD;
      higher-risk for perioperative renal complications [19].&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Linear flow during cardiopulmonary bypass (CPB) frequently induces renal damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will evaluate whether automatic intra-aortic balloon pump (IABP) induced pulsatile&#xD;
      perfusion preserves renal function in patients undergoing myocardial revascularization at&#xD;
      different risk for renal damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      100 patients undergoing preoperative IABP will be stratified for renal function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention. The patients will be randomized to non-pulsatile CPB during cardioplegic arrest&#xD;
      or automatic IABP induced pulsatile CPB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Renal function, daily diuretics, complication rate, lactatemia and other biochemical indices&#xD;
      will be compared in patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will prospectively enrolle 100 patients undergoing isolated primary high-risk coronary&#xD;
      artery bypass grafting for severe left main stem disease (70% narrowing) or left-main&#xD;
      equivalent three-vessels coronary disease. On admission to our institution, the patients will&#xD;
      be stratified for renal function according to KDOQI and randomly assigned to Group A or Group&#xD;
      B. We will exclude from the study patients older than 75 years, and/or with kidney disease ≥&#xD;
      Stage 4 (GFR 15 - 29 ml/min/1.73 m2), and/or with other splanchnic organ comorbidities (liver&#xD;
      or mesenteric impairment, abdominal aortic aneurysm, abdominal arteries vasculopathy), and/or&#xD;
      severe autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients randomized to Group A (n=50) will receive a preoperative IABP treatment before&#xD;
      induction of anesthesia, with IABP turned off during cardioplegic arrest, and restarted with&#xD;
      a 1:1 IABP mode immediately after cross-clamp removal (as is the traditionally adopted&#xD;
      perioperative IABP support); the other 50 (Group B) will receive standard preoperative&#xD;
      treatment with IABP, which will switche into an automatic 80 bpm mode during cross-clamp&#xD;
      time, and switche again into a 1:1 IABP after cross-clamp removal, in order to achieve a&#xD;
      pulsatile perfusion during the entire intra-operative time-course.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients will be stratified in 2 subgroups according to the preoperative renal function:&#xD;
      a subgroup will include 64 patients (32 allocated in Group A and 32 in Group B) with stage 1&#xD;
      or 2 [Stage 1: GFR ≥90 ml/min/1.73 m2 - Stage 2: GFR 60 - 89 ml/min/1.73 m2] and therefore&#xD;
      considere at lower-risk for post-CPB renal damage; the remaining 36 (18 for each group) with&#xD;
      KDOQI Stage 3 of kidney disease (GFR 30 - 59 ml/min/1.73 m2) will be considered at&#xD;
      higher-risk for perioperative renal complications [19].&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol has been approved by the institution's Ethical Committee/Institutional&#xD;
      Review Board, and informed consent will be obtained from each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anesthesia Anesthetic technique will be standardized: induction will consiste of i.v.&#xD;
      propofol infusion (3 mg/kg) combined with fentanyl (0.10 mg/Kg). Neuromuscular blockade will&#xD;
      be achieved by 4 mg/h pancuronium bromide, and lungs will be ventilated to normocapnia with&#xD;
      air and oxygen (45-50%). Propofol infusion (150-200 μg/Kg per min) and isoflurane (0.5%&#xD;
      inspired concentration) will maintaine anesthesia. Inotropes will be started immediately&#xD;
      after aortic cross-clamp removal to maintain adequate mean systemic pressure, always starting&#xD;
      with enoximone at a dosage of 5 μg/Kg/min. The need for further increase in inotropes will be&#xD;
      record: inotropes will be defined as &quot;low-dose&quot; when enoximone will be administered at a&#xD;
      dosage 5 μg/Kg/min, &quot;medium-dose&quot; when enoximone will be between 6 and 10 μg/Kg/min, or&#xD;
      dobutamine will add at a dosage between 5 and 10 μg/Kg/min, and &quot;high-dose&quot; when enoximone or&#xD;
      dobutamine will be &gt;10 μg/Kg/min or epinephrine add at any dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical technique and cardiopulmonary bypass According to our Institutional policy we will&#xD;
      insert IABP (7.5 or 8 Fr, 34 or 40 ml according to the body surface area; balloon Datascope&#xD;
      Corp., Fairfield, NJ, connected to a Datascope pump [Datascope Corp, Fairfield, NJ])&#xD;
      percutaneously with the &quot;sheetless&quot; technique, through the best femoral artery, before&#xD;
      induction of anesthesia, in order to better support the perioperative hemodynamic of patients&#xD;
      undergoing surgery for severe left main stem or 3-vessels left-main equivalent disease. The&#xD;
      correct placement of IABP will be always assessed by postoperative chest X-ray or&#xD;
      transesophageal echocardiography. Patients will receive anticoagulation with enoxaparin, with&#xD;
      a target activated partial thromboplastin time &gt;40 seconds, starting when the postoperative&#xD;
      bleeding was controlled (usually within 6 hours). IABP will be withdrawn when hemodynamic&#xD;
      stability will restore (i.e., a cardiac index 2.0 L/m2 per minute with only minimal&#xD;
      pharmacologic inotropic support, dobutamine or enoximone at 5 µg/kg per minute). CPB and&#xD;
      surgical techniques will be standardized and not changed during the study period. Heparin&#xD;
      will be given at a dose of 300 IU/kg to achieve a target activated clotting time of 480&#xD;
      seconds or above. Blood recovery with an autotransfusion device (Autotrans Dideco, Mirandola,&#xD;
      Modena, Italy) will be performed intraoperatively in all cases. A level of hemoglobin lower&#xD;
      than 8 g/dl will be used as an indication for blood transfusion. Standard CPB circuit will be&#xD;
      used. The extracorporeal circuit will be primed with 1000 ml of Ringer's Lactate solution and&#xD;
      40 mg of heparin. Systemic temperature will be kept between 32 and 34° C. Myocardial&#xD;
      protection will be achieved with intermittent antegrade and retrograde hyperkalemic blood&#xD;
      cardioplegia. Total CPB flow will be maintained at 2.6 L/min-1/m-2. In Group A patients, IABP&#xD;
      will be turned off during cardioplegic arrest, maintaining a standard non-pulsatile CPB;&#xD;
      Group B patients will undergo IABP-induced pulsatile CPB during cardioplegic arrest, with&#xD;
      pulsatile flow maintained by an automatic 80 bpm mode until aortic declamping.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints The primary endpoint of this study is the evaluation of the renal function as&#xD;
      assessed by measuring GFR in the perioperative period. In all patients will be evaluated&#xD;
      perioperative renal function, in-hospital mortality and morbidity, and complications,&#xD;
      in-hospital and intensive therapy unit (ITU) stay, IABP-related complications. Renal function&#xD;
      is primarily evaluated by GFR calculated using the abbreviated Modification of Diet in Renal&#xD;
      Disease (MDRD) study equation, recommended by KDOQI as the preferred equation for the&#xD;
      calculation of GFR in adults (taking into account serum creatinine, age, race, gender) [22]&#xD;
      and, secondarily, by other indices, such as urine output, need for diuretics, blood urea&#xD;
      nitrogen (BUN). Plasma lactate concentrations will be measured to indirectly assess the&#xD;
      adequacy of tissue perfusion [20] Acute renal insufficiency (ARI) is defined as a decrease&#xD;
      greater than 50% over preoperative value of calculated GFR. Acute renal failure (ARF) is&#xD;
      defined as any postoperative renal insufficiency requiring first-time hemofiltration,&#xD;
      dialysis or any other renal replacement therapy (RRT). In-hospital mortality is defined as&#xD;
      any death occurring during hospital stay or in the first 30 postoperative days. Hospital&#xD;
      morbidity is defined as any complication requiring specific therapy or causing a delay in&#xD;
      hospital or ITU discharge. IABP-related complications is defined as any aortic dissection or&#xD;
      perforation, limb or mesenteric ischemia, or infection or hemorrhage at the balloon entry&#xD;
      point.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biochemical analysis All patients will undergo pre- and perioperatively routine laboratory&#xD;
      investigations, including standard hemogram, serum levels of creatinine, urea nitrogen,&#xD;
      calcium, phosphate, glucose, albumin, electrolytes, albumin, transaminases,&#xD;
      -glutamyl-transpeptidase, lactic acid dehydrogenase, bilirubin, acid-base parameters,&#xD;
      troponin I and lactic acid. The determinations of the majority of these parameters will be&#xD;
      conducted preoperatively before anesthetic induction, and at 12, 24, 48, and 72 hours&#xD;
      postoperatively. In order to evaluate the adequacy of myocardial protection techniques,&#xD;
      Troponin I will be measured on coronary sinus blood samples, obtained from the retrograde&#xD;
      cardioplegic cannula, 10 minutes following completion of proximal anastomoses. The Troponin I&#xD;
      assays will be carried out using diagnostic kits provided by Beckman Coulter (Fullerton,&#xD;
      California; AccuTnITM Access Immunoassay System).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis Statistical analysis will be performed by the SPSS program for Windows,&#xD;
      version 10.1 (SPSS Inc, Chicago, IL). Continuous variables will be presented as mean ±&#xD;
      standard deviation, and categorical variables as absolute numbers and/or percentages. Data&#xD;
      will be checked for normality before statistical analysis. Normally-distributed continuous&#xD;
      variables will be compared using the unpaired t test, whereas the Mann-Whitney U test will be&#xD;
      used for those variables that are not normally distributed. Categorical variables will be&#xD;
      analyzed using either the chi-square test or Fischer's exact test. Comparison between and&#xD;
      within groups will be made using two-way analysis of variance for repeated measures.&#xD;
      Comparisons will be considered significant if p&lt;0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <condition>Aortocoronary Bypass</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pulsatile intra-aortic balloon pump</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing isolated primary high-risk coronary artery bypass grafting for&#xD;
             severe left main stem disease (70% narrowing) or left-main equivalent three-vessels&#xD;
             coronary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients older than 75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With kidney disease ≥ Stage 4 (GFR 15 - 29 ml/min/1.73 m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With other splanchnic organ comorbidities (liver or mesenteric impairment, abdominal&#xD;
             aortic aneurysm, abdominal arteries vasculopathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe autoimmune disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Francesco Onorati, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>cardiac surgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiac Surgery and Nephrology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catanzaro</city>
        <zip>88100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 30, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 29, 2007</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 29, 2007</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 30, 2007</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Bypass Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronary Artery</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

