<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00458926</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>6742</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00458926</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enhancing Utilization of Non-Invasive Positive Pressure Ventilation in Critical Care</brief_title>
  <official_title>Enhancing Utilization of Non-Invasive Positive Pressure Ventilation in Critical Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tufts Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tufts Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (NIV) refers to the provision of mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation without an artificial airway (for example, an endotracheal tube). Over the past&#xD;
      decade, evidence from randomized control trials has accumulated to demonstrate effectiveness&#xD;
      of the technique in avoiding intubation, reducing complications associated with intubation,&#xD;
      shortening ICU and hospital lengths of stay, and reducing mortality rates in selected&#xD;
      patients with acute respiratory failure. However, NIV is still underutilized at many medical&#xD;
      centers. The purposes of this project will be to acquire information related to NIV use, to&#xD;
      identify reasons for underutilization, to implement interventions that encourage more&#xD;
      appropriate use of NIV, and to evaluate the effectiveness of the interventions. Reliable&#xD;
      information on NIV use as well as analysis of reasons for underutilization will provide&#xD;
      insight into ways of enhancing NIV use. We will determine utilization rate, technology used,&#xD;
      patient diagnoses, duration of ventilator use and hospital stay, and success rates as&#xD;
      recorded on case report forms (CRFs). After completing the survey, we will provide an&#xD;
      educational program to randomly selected institutions (one-half of the total) aimed at&#xD;
      increasing the knowledge and skill of physicians, nurses, and therapists regarding use and&#xD;
      implementation of NIV. Data will be gathered for a second round with the same data-gathering&#xD;
      instruments used during&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Project Focus The focus of this project is to improve the ventilatory management of patients&#xD;
      with acute respiratory failure in the critical care setting by enhancing the use of&#xD;
      non-invasive ventilation, a goal that should lead to improved outcomes and efficiency of&#xD;
      care. Within the framework of the funding agency, the Chest Foundation, this proposal aims to&#xD;
      promote the use of alternative therapies in treating patients with critical illness, educate&#xD;
      practitioners, and disseminate new knowledge regarding the therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background Non-invasive positive pressure ventilation (NPPV) provides mechanical ventilation&#xD;
      without the need for airway invasion through the use of either nasal or oronasal masks&#xD;
      (covering both the nose and mouth) attached to positive pressure ventilators. Published&#xD;
      evidence from randomized control trials has demonstrated the effectiveness of the technique&#xD;
      in avoiding intubation, reducing complications associated with intubation, shortening ICU and&#xD;
      hospital lengths of stay, and reducing mortality rates in selected patients with acute&#xD;
      respiratory failure. Randomized trials have demonstrated effectiveness in patients with acute&#xD;
      exacerbations of COPD (1-3), cardiogenic pulmonary edema (4), immunocompromised patients with&#xD;
      hypoxemic respiratory failure (5,6), facilitating the weaning process in patients ventilated&#xD;
      invasively (7), and in patients who develop respiratory insufficiency after lung resection&#xD;
      (8). In addition, evidence that is not quite as strong supports the use of NPPV in patients&#xD;
      with acute asthma (9), cystic fibrosis (10), community-acquired pneumonia if there is&#xD;
      underlying COPD (11), and patients with a do-not-intubate status (12).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on this evidence, consensus groups have recommended the use of NPPV in treating&#xD;
      patients with COPD exacerbations and for selected patients with other diagnoses (13).&#xD;
      However, NPPV is still underutilized at many medical centers throughout the world (14) and it&#xD;
      is fair to presume that many patients are being deprived of NPPV's advantages and that ICU&#xD;
      resources are being wasted. Similar surveys have not been performed in the US, and my firm&#xD;
      impression from polling audiences when I speak on this subject is that a similar proportion&#xD;
      of US centers are not using NPPV. The purposes of this project are to acquire this&#xD;
      information in a US setting, to identify reasons for underutilization, to implement&#xD;
      interventions that encourage more appropriate use of NPPV, and then to evaluate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The successful implementation of this project may have a major impact on the practice of&#xD;
      critical care medicine. Reliable information on utilization of NPPV as well as analysis of&#xD;
      reasons for underutilization will provide insight into ways of enhancing utilization.&#xD;
      Educational programs designed to enhance practitioners' skills in implementing NPPV should&#xD;
      lead to greater utilization and improved success rates. Optimal utilization of NPPV should&#xD;
      lead to improved outcomes for patients with respiratory failure, more rational use of&#xD;
      resources, and lower ICU costs for our health care system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Project A. Major Hypothesis: An educational intervention will increase utilization and&#xD;
      success rates of NPPV in hospitals that currently underutilizing it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. General Outline 1. Site selection&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Select 8 sites that use NPPV in &lt; 10% of patients receiving mechanical ventilatory&#xD;
           assistance, based on a survey mailed to acute care hospitals in Massachusetts and Rhode&#xD;
           Island during 2002. Sites will be selected based on: (i) willingness to participate (as&#xD;
           per request of Respiratory Therapy director), (ii) &gt; 30 mechanical ventilation&#xD;
           initiations/month as reported in the survey, and (iii) n more than 90 minute drive from&#xD;
           Boston.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Perform prospective evaluation of use of NPPV that will determine rate of utilization,&#xD;
           technology used, patient diagnoses, duration of ventilator use and hospital stay, and&#xD;
           success rates as recorded on case report forms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Intervention (or control) phase. After completion of survey, provide&#xD;
           education/in-servicing program to 5 randomly selected sites aimed at increasing&#xD;
           knowledge and skill of physicians, nurses, and respiratory therapists in the use and&#xD;
           implementation of NPPV.&#xD;
&#xD;
           C. Evaluation phase&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Re-survey targeted institutions with regard to use of NPPV and patient outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Methods A. Prospective Survey at 8 Selected Institutions Underutilize NPPV&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Random selection will be performed using computer-generated number sequence,&#xD;
                selecting sites based on alphabetical listing.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Data will be gathered on CRFs that will document utilization of mechanical&#xD;
                ventilation; number of NPPV starts; patient diagnoses; date, time, and location of&#xD;
                NPPV use; equipment and settings used to ventilate; success rate of NPPV; duration&#xD;
                of NPPV use; and eventual patient outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Data collectors from Tufts or respiratory therapists at each site will initiate CRF&#xD;
                use. Personal health information will be de-identified by using study code numbers.&#xD;
                The patient medical record number cross-referenced to the patient code will be kept&#xD;
                on a separate list kept in a locked area, so that the patient's medical record can&#xD;
                be located to retrieve missing data and recorded data can be verified.&#xD;
&#xD;
           B. Education and In-Servicing&#xD;
&#xD;
           Educational and in-servicing sessions will be provided to randomly selected&#xD;
           underutilizing sites and will review guidelines provided in the literature by the PI&#xD;
           (15,16) as well as other investigators (17). Grand rounds and other lecture venues for&#xD;
           the physicians working in emergency and critical care settings will describe the skills&#xD;
           needed to select patients who will benefit from the use of NPPV. Workshops for&#xD;
           respiratory therapists will review patient selection, proper use of equipment, and&#xD;
           monitoring and weaning techniques. In-servicing sessions for emergency and critical care&#xD;
           nurses will review the rationale behind NPPV use and how to monitor patients who are&#xD;
           placed on NPPV. At control sites, no intervention will be undertaken prior to the second&#xD;
           data survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
           C. Evaluation Phase&#xD;
&#xD;
           Mechanical ventilation and NPPV utilization will be tracked with the same data gathering&#xD;
           instruments used during the initial phase. Initial and follow-up data gathering will be&#xD;
           staggered. The follow-up evaluation in the control group will be timed to correspond&#xD;
           with follow-up in institutions receiving the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Main Outcome Variables&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Rate of NPPV utilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. NPPV success.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Compliance with guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Analysis The main outcome variables will be analyzed as categorical variables by chi&#xD;
           square analysis or the Mann-Whitney test as appropriate. Initial data will be compared&#xD;
           to follow-up data obtained during the follow-up phase using paired t-tests, Mann-Whitney&#xD;
           tests, as appropriate. Comparisons between the intervention and control groups at&#xD;
           baseline and follow-up will be made using unpaired t-tests or chi square analyses as&#xD;
           appropriate. Because randomization is by site, data will be clustered by institution,&#xD;
           although we will be limited by resources as to the number of sites in this study. Using&#xD;
           linear regression analysis, we will be able to determine risk ratios for failure for a&#xD;
           number of initial characteristics, including diagnosis, vital signs, blood gases,&#xD;
           presence of cough and airway secretions, body mass index, sedation, kind of equipment&#xD;
           used, in-hospital locations for NPPV implementation, and other characteristics.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Anticipated Results We anticipate that results from the sites selected to receive the&#xD;
           training intervention and control sites will be similar at baseline and that the&#xD;
           intervention will increase utilization and success rates of NPPV compared to baseline.&#xD;
           Utilization and training rates also may increase at control sites, because of an&#xD;
           increased trend toward NPPV use in acute care settings. However, the important&#xD;
           comparison will be between the intervention and control sites at follow-up. If&#xD;
           intervention is effective, NPPV utilization and success rates will be increased at&#xD;
           intervention sites compared to controls. Other key differences may be detectable, such&#xD;
           as shorter ICU lengths of stay and reduced mortality rates among respiratory failure&#xD;
           patients treated at the intervention sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Risk/Benefit Analysis This is a prospective observational trial that involves no patient&#xD;
           intervention. Patients are to be managed by their primary caregivers, and guidelines are&#xD;
           provided to randomly selected institutions. These guidelines, derived from standards in&#xD;
           the literature (15-17) aim to improve the outcomes of patients receiving NPPV. Because&#xD;
           the trial is observational, involves no direct patient intervention, and poses&#xD;
           essentially no direct risk to patients, we are requesting waiver of consent. The patient&#xD;
           data that we are collecting aims to track standard clinical information and will be&#xD;
           de-identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Protection of Personal Health Information CRFs will be de-identified for the purposes of&#xD;
           the study. CRFs will be kept in a locked office. A cross-referenced sheet containing&#xD;
           medical record numbers and patient code numbers will be kept in a locked file until&#xD;
           missing data are retrieved and data verified using chart review. Once the data set is&#xD;
           complete and validated, the cross-referenced sheet will be shredded and discarded.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Limitations, Potential Problems, and Strengths One limitation is that optimal&#xD;
           utilization rates for NPPV in the acute care setting have not been established. In&#xD;
           addition, overutilization (use in inappropriate candidates) at some centers is also a&#xD;
           concern, as noted in the European survey (14). Although this project will focus on&#xD;
           underutilization of NPPV, we will able to track evidence of inappropriate applications.&#xD;
           Another concern is that there can be no blinding as to study condition at individual&#xD;
           centers, introducing the possibility of center-based bias. Randomization of intervention&#xD;
           and control centers should minimize this concern.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The study also has several strengths. Compared to the European ICU survey that only&#xD;
           included selected centers that had volunteered to serve in a consortium, this project&#xD;
           will obtain information on NPPV use in all acute care centers in a geographic region,&#xD;
           giving a more accurate glimpse of actual usage rates. In addition, the survey will&#xD;
           provide information on reasons for under-utilization and the inclusion of an&#xD;
           intervention will shed light on the effectiveness of strategies to enhance utilization.&#xD;
           These results can then be applied to achieve more appropriate use of NPPV. The study&#xD;
           might also provide insight into techniques that could also be applied to other critical&#xD;
           care practices, such as use of particular ventilator settings for invasive mechanical&#xD;
           ventilation, or use of certain pharmacological agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
           References&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Kramer N, Meyer TJ, Meharg J et al: Randomized, prospective trial of noninvasive&#xD;
                positive pressure ventilation in acute respiratory failure. Am J Respir Crit Care&#xD;
                Med 1995; 151: 1799-1806.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Brochard L, Mancebo J, Wysocki M et al: Noninvasive ventilation for acute&#xD;
                exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease. N Engl J Med 1995; 333:&#xD;
                817-822.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Plant PK, Owen JL, and Elliott MW: Early use of noninvasive ventilation for acute&#xD;
                exacerbations of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease on general respiratory&#xD;
                wards: a multicenter randomized controlled trial. Lancet 2000; 355:1931-1935.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Masip J, Betbese AJ, Paez J, Vecilla F, Canizares R, Padro J, Paz Marco A, Otero J,&#xD;
                Bllus J: Non-invasive pressure support ventilation versus conventional oxygen&#xD;
                therapy in acute cardiogenic pulmonary oedema; a randomized study. Lancet 2000;&#xD;
                356:2126-2132.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Antonelli M, Conti G, Bufi M, Costa MG, Lappa A, Rocco M, Gasparetto M, Meduri GU:&#xD;
                Noninvasive ventilation for treatment of acute respiratory failure in patients&#xD;
                undergoing solid organ transplantation. JAMA 2000, 283: 235-241.&#xD;
&#xD;
             6. Hilbert G, Gruson D, Vargas F, Valentino R, Gbikpi-Benissan G, Dupon M, Reiffers J,&#xD;
                and Cardinaud JP. Noninvasive ventilation in Immunosuppressed patients with&#xD;
                pulmonary infiltrates, and acute respiratory failure. N Engl J Med 2001;&#xD;
                344:481-487.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7. Nava S, Ambrosino N, Clini E, Prato M, Orlando G, et al. Non-invasive mechanical&#xD;
                ventilation in the weaning of patients with respiratory failure due to chronic&#xD;
                obstructive pulmonary disease: a randomized study. Ann Intern Med 1998; 128:&#xD;
                721-728.&#xD;
&#xD;
             8. Auriant I, Jallot A, Herve P, et al. Noninvasive ventilation reduces mortality in&#xD;
                acute respiratory failure following lung resection. Am J Respir Crit Care Med 2001;&#xD;
                164: 1231-1235.&#xD;
&#xD;
             9. Meduri GU, Cook TR, Turner RE, Cohen M and Leeper KV. Noninvasive positive pressure&#xD;
                ventilation in status asthmaticus. Chest 1996; 110: 767-774&#xD;
&#xD;
            10. Hodson ME, Madden BP, Steven MH et al. Noninvasive mechanical ventilation for&#xD;
                cystic fibrosis patients - a potential bridge to transplantation. Eur Respir J&#xD;
                1991; 4: 524-527.&#xD;
&#xD;
            11. Confalonieri M, Potena A, Carbone G, Della Porta R, Tolley EA, and Meduri GU. Acute&#xD;
                respiratory failure in patients with severe community-acquired pneumonia. Am J&#xD;
                Respir Crit Care Med 1999, 160: 1585-1591.&#xD;
&#xD;
            12. Meduri GU, Fox RC, Abou-Shala N, et al. Noninvasive mechanical ventilation via face&#xD;
                mask in patients with acute respiratory failure who refused endotracheal&#xD;
                intubation. Crit Care Med 1994; 22: 1584-1590.&#xD;
&#xD;
            13. Bach JR, Brougher P, Hess DR et al. Consensus statement: Noninvasive positive&#xD;
                pressure ventilation. Respir Care 1997; 42: 365-369. 6. 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
            14. Carlucci A, Richard J-C, Wysocki M, Lepage E, Brochard L. Noninvasive versus&#xD;
                conventional mechanical ventilation: and epidemiological survey. Am J Respir Crit&#xD;
                Care Med 2001; 163:874-880.&#xD;
&#xD;
            15. Criner GJ, Kreimer DT, Tomaselli M, Pierson W, and Evans D. Financial implications&#xD;
                of noninvasive positive pressure ventilation (NPPV). Chest 1995; 108: 475-481.&#xD;
&#xD;
            16. Hill NS, ed. Noninvasive Positive Pressure Ventilation; Principles and&#xD;
                Applications. Futura, Armonk, NY, 2001.&#xD;
&#xD;
            17. Sinuff T, Cook DJ, Randall J, Allen CJ. Evaluation of a practice guideline for&#xD;
                noninvasive positive pressure ventilation for acute respiratory failure. Chest&#xD;
                2003; 123(6):2062-73.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">800</enrollment>
  <condition>COPD</condition>
  <condition>Congestive Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <condition>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Adult</condition>
  <condition>Pneumonia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients 18 years of age or older who require mechanical ventilation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Starting on mechanical ventilation (including: invasive, noninvasive, CPAP or BiPAP&#xD;
             for purpose of treatment of respiratory failure)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of home mechanical ventilation, including nocturnal ventilation, continuous&#xD;
             mechanical ventilation,BiPAP.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuous use of CPAP or BiPAP for treatment of obstructive sleep apnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Placed on mechanical ventilation for purposes of surgical anesthesia or use of&#xD;
             anesthesia for a diagnostic procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has tracheostomy or was intubated endotracheally prior to admission.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicholas S. Hill, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Tufts Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tufts Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.tuftsmedicalcenter.org/OurServices/Pulmonology/NonInvasiveVentilationWebSite</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 9, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 9, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 11, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ventilation, mechanical</keyword>
  <keyword>intubation, endotracheal</keyword>
  <keyword>respiratory insufficiency</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

