<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04690738</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20052109</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04690738</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Role of Pancreatic Exocrine Secretion in Weight Gain After Pancreas Transplantation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Role of Pancreatic Exocrine Secretion in Weight Gain After Pancreas Transplantation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rush University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rush University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pancreas transplantation is currently the most reliable method for glycemic control in&#xD;
      insulin dependent diabetic patients. Outcomes of pancreas transplantation have improved&#xD;
      significantly over the years due to improved surgical techniques, medical management and&#xD;
      immunosuppression. However, weight gain after pancreas transplantation remains a common&#xD;
      problem with associated consequences such as development of type 2 diabetes, coronary artery&#xD;
      disease, graft loss, metabolic syndrome and increased risk of cardiovascular death. Excessive&#xD;
      weight gain is well known after liver and kidney transplantation; however there are very few&#xD;
      studies that have looked at weight gain after pancreas transplantation. In a recent study by&#xD;
      Knight et al, 26% of the pancreas transplant recipients had excessive weight gain, defined as&#xD;
      more than 30% of their baseline weight by 1-year post transplant. The study focused mainly on&#xD;
      the endocrine function of the pancreas, explaining that excessive peripheral insulin&#xD;
      circulation post-transplant may explain the weight gain. Other factors like&#xD;
      immunosuppression, increased oral intake and potentially reduced activity may also have&#xD;
      played a role. However no study has looked at the possible role of exocrine secretion from&#xD;
      the new pancreatic allograft, combined with exocrine secretion of the old pancreas, leading&#xD;
      to excessive availability of digestive juices like trypsin, chymotrypsin, lipase, amylase,&#xD;
      gelatinase, elastase etc. Our hypothesis is that the excessive weight gain after pancreas&#xD;
      transplant, which is more than in other solid organ transplants, is driven by the excessive&#xD;
      digestive juice leading to improved conversion of available food and nutrient into storable&#xD;
      energy and subsequently leading to weight gain. The patient will therefore need to either&#xD;
      increase physical activity to avoid weight gain post-transplant or significantly reduce&#xD;
      caloric intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fecal elastase test (FE-1)-elastase is a proteolytic enzyme produced by pancreatic acinar&#xD;
      cells. They bind to bile salt and pass through the gut without degradation. These levels&#xD;
      correlate well with the other pancreatic enzyme levels. Fecal elastase concentration (FEC)&#xD;
      has been used routinely to screen for pancreatic exocrine insufficiency (PEI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exocrine pancreatic juice has been a target for the management of obesity lately, with the&#xD;
      use of drugs like Orlistat (Xenical) that inhibits pancreatic lipase and therefore interfere&#xD;
      with the absorption of fat. If our theory of excessive pancreatic juice availability after&#xD;
      pancreas transplant can be proven, it can help guide the targeted use and appropriate dosing&#xD;
      of such drugs based on the level of the pancreatic juice as measured by the FEC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 23, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 23, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of Fecal Elastase-1, measured in mcg/g.</measure>
    <time_frame>Once, up to 10 years after pancreas transplant</time_frame>
    <description>FE-1 results &gt;200 mcg/g represent normal pancreatic function, 100-200 mcg/g represent moderate pancreatic insufficiency, &lt;100 mcg/g represent severe pancreatic insufficiency.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Exocrine Pancreatic Insufficiency</condition>
  <condition>Weight Gain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Post Pancreas Transplant Patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients that have received a pancreas transplant (Pancreas After Kidney or Simultaneous Pancreas Kidney) from 2012 through present will have a fecal elastase stool sample collected.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fecal Elastase Concentration</intervention_name>
    <description>Each patient will provide a stool sample for Fecal Elastase Concentration to measure Fecal Elastase-1, a proteolytic enzyme</description>
    <arm_group_label>Post Pancreas Transplant Patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A single FEC will be obtained in patients that have received pancreas transplant at Rush&#xD;
        University Medical Center from 2012 till date.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipients of pancreas transplant with or without other organs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 - 80 yrs&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness to consent or participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oyedolamu Olaitan, MBBS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amanda Van Jacobs, MS</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Knight RJ, Islam AK, Pham C, Graviss EA, Nguyen DT, Moore LW, Kagan A, Sadhu AR, Podder H, Gaber AO. Weight Gain After Simultaneous Kidney and Pancreas Transplantation. Transplantation. 2020 Mar;104(3):632-639. doi: 10.1097/TP.0000000000002862.</citation>
    <PMID>31335775</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ewald N, Raspe A, Kaufmann C, Bretzel RG, Kloer HU, Hardt PD. Determinants of Exocrine Pancreatic Function as Measured by Fecal Elastase-1 Concentrations (FEC) in Patients with Diabetes mellitus. Eur J Med Res. 2009 Mar 17;14(3):118-22.</citation>
    <PMID>19380282</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Domínguez-Muñoz JE, D Hardt P, Lerch MM, Löhr MJ. Potential for Screening for Pancreatic Exocrine Insufficiency Using the Fecal Elastase-1 Test. Dig Dis Sci. 2017 May;62(5):1119-1130. doi: 10.1007/s10620-017-4524-z. Epub 2017 Mar 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28315028</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Forsmark C, Adams PC. Pancreatic function testing--valuable but underused. Can J Gastroenterol. 2009 Aug;23(8):529-30.</citation>
    <PMID>19668794</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 31, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pancreas transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>weight gain</keyword>
  <keyword>pancreatic insufficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>kidney pancreas transplant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Exocrine Pancreatic Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Body Weight</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Weight Gain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

