<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04695392</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>828061</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04695392</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Restore Resilience in Critically Ill Children</brief_title>
  <acronym>R2</acronym>
  <official_title>Restore Resilience in Critically Ill Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Boston Children's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study design will allow investigators to describe usual care in each PICU and identify&#xD;
      the facilitating and restraining factors impacting the implementation of R2 at each PICU. The&#xD;
      purpose of this pilot study is to improve the care, environment, daily routine and sleep&#xD;
      patterns of children in the PICU. The goal of this study is to learn what can be improved to&#xD;
      support a critically ill child's healing and circadian rhythms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hospitals should do the sick no harm. That noted, modern day pediatric intensive care units&#xD;
      (PICUs) are not healing milieus. Immediately upon admission to the PICU, the child's daily&#xD;
      routine and sleep patterns are replaced by a well-intended but not patient-centered PICU&#xD;
      routine. The interprofessional investigative team believes that PICU care and environments&#xD;
      can be modulated to sustain a young child's circadian rhythm (CR) and support their&#xD;
      physiological resilience and capacity to heal. The first step in this program of research is&#xD;
      to pilot-test RESTORE resilience (R2), a 7-item individualized bundle that we hypothesize&#xD;
      will restore CR in critically ill children using a pre-posttest design. Two separate PICUs&#xD;
      will each enroll 10 baseline subjects followed by 20 intervention subjects, 6 months to 18&#xD;
      years of age, who are intubated and mechanically ventilated for acute respiratory failure.&#xD;
      Specifically, as soon as possible after PICU admission, parents will be interviewed to create&#xD;
      an individualized chronotherapeutic bundle to include (1) focused effort to replicate the&#xD;
      child's pre-hospitalization daily routine (bedtime/wake time, bedtime/arousal routine, nap&#xD;
      time, feeding schedule, active periods), (2) cycled day-night lighting and modulation of&#xD;
      sound to match the child's routine, (3) minimal yet effective sedation using a&#xD;
      nurse-implemented goal-directed sedation plan (RESTORE), (4) night fasting with bolus enteral&#xD;
      daytime feedings, (5) early, developmentally-appropriate, progressive exercise and mobility&#xD;
      (PICU Up!), (6) continuity in nursing care, and (7) parent diaries. The overall objective of&#xD;
      this study is to pilot-test an intervention that can be implemented in any PICU that will&#xD;
      improve sleep-wake patterns with restoration/maintenance of circadian rhythms in critically&#xD;
      ill children with acute respiratory failure. Results of this pilot study will be used to&#xD;
      inform the design of an adequately powered multicenter randomized trial of R2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 5, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective Cohort Study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circadian activity ratio (CAR) - Acute Phase</measure>
    <time_frame>From study enrollment to immediately after endotracheal extubation</time_frame>
    <description>CAR = Daytime activity/total 24-hr actigraphy activity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Melatonin levels</measure>
    <time_frame>8 samples over 24 hours on Days 2 and 5 of PICU hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary melatonin levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Slow-wave EEG activity</measure>
    <time_frame>First 72 hours of PICU hospitalization</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of slow-wave EEG activity during endotracheal intubation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily R2 bundle feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of the seven R2 elements implemented per day per enrolled subject</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily R2 bundle adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of daily feeding and sleep activities that match the subject's preadmission routine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily R2 bundle system barriers</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Daily survey of non-patient related factors that prevented R2 bundle implementation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain free days</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of PICU days without pain (Pain score &gt; 3)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Agitation free days</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of PICU days without agitation (SBS &gt; 0)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Delirium free days</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of PICU days without delirium (Cornell Assessment for Pediatric Delirium positive)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Iatrogenic withdrawal syndrome free days</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of PICU days without IWS (WAT-1 &gt; 2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak daily dose of all sedative agents</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Highest daily mg/kg dose of all sedative agents</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative dose of all sedative agents</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Total PICU mg/kg dose of all sedative agents received</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total PICU days of sedation</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of PICU days exposed to sedatives</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to physiological stability</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of PICU discharge, assessed for up to 2 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time between the start and stop of vasoactive medications, mechanical ventilation, PICU care</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent perception of being well-cared-for</measure>
    <time_frame>On the date of PICU discharge, assessed once within an average of 2 weeks post PICU admission</time_frame>
    <description>Percent match on the 7-item family-centered care scale (FCCS); range from 0-100% match; where higher scores are better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in circadian activity ratio (CAR) - Recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>From immediately after endotracheal extubation to immediately after PICU discharge</time_frame>
    <description>CAR = Daytime activity/total 24-hr actigraphy activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>R2 Bundle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>R2 Bundle</intervention_name>
    <description>During the intervention phase subjects will receive R2.&#xD;
Focused effort to replicate the child's pre-hospitalization daily routine (bedtime/wake time, bedtime/arousal routine, nap time, feeding schedule, active periods),&#xD;
Cycled day-night lighting and modulation of sound to match the child's routine,&#xD;
Minimal yet effective sedation using a nurse-implemented goal-directed sedation plan (RESTORE),&#xD;
Night fasting with bolus enteral daytime feedings,&#xD;
Early, developmentally-appropriate, progressive exercise and mobility (PICU Up!),&#xD;
Continuity in nursing care, and&#xD;
Parent diaries.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PICU admission at one of the study sites in which elements of R2 are typically but&#xD;
             sporadically implemented&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Transferred to the PICU from another hospital unit/ward with ≤4 nights in the hospital&#xD;
             (≤2 nights in PICU)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between the ages 6 months and 18 years at the time of enrollment (has not had their&#xD;
             18th birthday)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intubated and mechanically ventilated for acute airway or parenchymal disease within&#xD;
             last 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected to be intubated for more than 12 hours past enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent/Guardian providing consent, provides primary care for subject&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A baseline cognitive dysfunction, measured by the Pediatric Cerebral Performance&#xD;
             Category (PCPC ≥4)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of an uncontrolled seizure disorder (seizure within past 3 months), cerebral&#xD;
             hypertension, neuromuscular respiratory failure, ventilator dependence (excluding&#xD;
             BiPAP or CPAP at night)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of inability to tolerate bolus enteral feeds (full J-Tube fed patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of any of the following within 24 hours of admission:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Modal pain scores greater than 4&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Persistent hypotension/hypertension unresponsive to standard therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of High Frequency Oscillatory Ventilation or Extracorporeal Membrane&#xD;
                  Oxygenation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administered melatonin within the past week&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active do-not-resuscitate plan&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martha AQ Curley, RN, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins University - Charlotte Bloomberg Children's Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wieczorek B, Burke C, Al-Harbi A, Kudchadkar SR. Early mobilization in the pediatric intensive care unit: a systematic review. J Pediatr Intensive Care. 2015;2015:129-170. Epub 2015 Sep 3.</citation>
    <PMID>26380147</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pollack MM, Holubkov R, Funai T, Berger JT, Clark AE, Meert K, Berg RA, Carcillo J, Wessel DL, Moler F, Dalton H, Newth CJ, Shanley T, Harrison RE, Doctor A, Jenkins TL, Tamburro R, Dean JM; Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Collaborative Pediatric Critical Care Research Network. Simultaneous Prediction of New Morbidity, Mortality, and Survival Without New Morbidity From Pediatric Intensive Care: A New Paradigm for Outcomes Assessment. Crit Care Med. 2015 Aug;43(8):1699-709. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000001081.</citation>
    <PMID>25985385</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pollack MM, Holubkov R, Funai T, Clark A, Berger JT, Meert K, Newth CJ, Shanley T, Moler F, Carcillo J, Berg RA, Dalton H, Wessel DL, Harrison RE, Doctor A, Dean JM, Jenkins TL; Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Collaborative Pediatric Critical Care Research Network. Pediatric intensive care outcomes: development of new morbidities during pediatric critical care. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2014 Nov;15(9):821-7. doi: 10.1097/PCC.0000000000000250.</citation>
    <PMID>25226501</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hopkins RO, Choong K, Zebuhr CA, Kudchadkar SR. Transforming PICU Culture to Facilitate Early Rehabilitation. J Pediatr Intensive Care. 2015 Dec;4(4):204-211.</citation>
    <PMID>27134761</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kamdar BB, Niessen T, Colantuoni E, King LM, Neufeld KJ, Bienvenu OJ, Rowden AM, Collop NA, Needham DM. Delirium transitions in the medical ICU: exploring the role of sleep quality and other factors. Crit Care Med. 2015 Jan;43(1):135-141. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000000610.</citation>
    <PMID>25230376</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gehlbach BK, Chapotot F, Leproult R, Whitmore H, Poston J, Pohlman M, Miller A, Pohlman AS, Nedeltcheva A, Jacobsen JH, Hall JB, Van Cauter E. Temporal disorganization of circadian rhythmicity and sleep-wake regulation in mechanically ventilated patients receiving continuous intravenous sedation. Sleep. 2012 Aug 1;35(8):1105-14. doi: 10.5665/sleep.1998.</citation>
    <PMID>22851806</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang HW, Zheng BL, Jiang L, Lin ZT, Zhang GB, Shen L, Xi XM. Effect of oral melatonin and wearing earplugs and eye masks on nocturnal sleep in healthy subjects in a simulated intensive care unit environment: which might be a more promising strategy for ICU sleep deprivation? Crit Care. 2015 Mar 19;19:124. doi: 10.1186/s13054-015-0842-8.</citation>
    <PMID>25887528</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hu RF, Jiang XY, Hegadoren KM, Zhang YH. Effects of earplugs and eye masks combined with relaxing music on sleep, melatonin and cortisol levels in ICU patients: a randomized controlled trial. Crit Care. 2015 Mar 27;19:115. doi: 10.1186/s13054-015-0855-3.</citation>
    <PMID>25881268</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kudchadkar SR, Aljohani OA, Punjabi NM. Sleep of critically ill children in the pediatric intensive care unit: a systematic review. Sleep Med Rev. 2014 Apr;18(2):103-10. doi: 10.1016/j.smrv.2013.02.002. Epub 2013 May 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23702219</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kudchadkar SR, Yaster M, Punjabi AN, Quan SF, Goodwin JL, Easley RB, Punjabi NM. Temporal Characteristics of the Sleep EEG Power Spectrum in Critically Ill Children. J Clin Sleep Med. 2015 Dec 15;11(12):1449-54. doi: 10.5664/jcsm.5286.</citation>
    <PMID>26194730</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Oyarzun F. [Perception of a person's face and the process of personalization-depersonalization]. Actas Luso Esp Neurol Psiquiatr Cienc Afines. 1985 Mar-Apr;13(2):74-6. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>4061156</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aitken LM, Rattray J, Hull A, Kenardy JA, Le Brocque R, Ullman AJ. The use of diaries in psychological recovery from intensive care. Crit Care. 2013 Dec 18;17(6):253. doi: 10.1186/cc13164. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24351578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jones C, Bäckman C, Capuzzo M, Egerod I, Flaatten H, Granja C, Rylander C, Griffiths RD; RACHEL group. Intensive care diaries reduce new onset post traumatic stress disorder following critical illness: a randomised, controlled trial. Crit Care. 2010;14(5):R168. doi: 10.1186/cc9260. Epub 2010 Sep 15.</citation>
    <PMID>20843344</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kamdar BB, Yang J, King LM, Neufeld KJ, Bienvenu OJ, Rowden AM, Brower RG, Collop NA, Needham DM. Developing, implementing, and evaluating a multifaceted quality improvement intervention to promote sleep in an ICU. Am J Med Qual. 2014 Nov-Dec;29(6):546-54. doi: 10.1177/1062860613509684. Epub 2013 Nov 22.</citation>
    <PMID>24270169</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kamdar BB, Knauert MP, Jones SF, Parsons EC, Parthasarathy S, Pisani MA; Sleep in the ICU (SLEEPii) Task Force. Perceptions and Practices Regarding Sleep in the Intensive Care Unit. A Survey of 1,223 Critical Care Providers. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2016 Aug;13(8):1370-7. doi: 10.1513/AnnalsATS.201601-087OC.</citation>
    <PMID>27104770</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benloucif S, Burgess HJ, Klerman EB, Lewy AJ, Middleton B, Murphy PJ, Parry BL, Revell VL. Measuring melatonin in humans. J Clin Sleep Med. 2008 Feb 15;4(1):66-9.</citation>
    <PMID>18350967</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Curley MA, Harris SK, Fraser KA, Johnson RA, Arnold JH. State Behavioral Scale: a sedation assessment instrument for infants and young children supported on mechanical ventilation. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2006 Mar;7(2):107-14.</citation>
    <PMID>16446601</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Franck LS, Harris SK, Soetenga DJ, Amling JK, Curley MA. The Withdrawal Assessment Tool-1 (WAT-1): an assessment instrument for monitoring opioid and benzodiazepine withdrawal symptoms in pediatric patients. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2008 Nov;9(6):573-80. doi: 10.1097/PCC.0b013e31818c8328.</citation>
    <PMID>18838937</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 22, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 31, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Martha A.Q. Curley, PhD, RN</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 18, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/92/NCT04695392/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>November 6, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/92/NCT04695392/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

