<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04693624</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18/20/DD-BV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04693624</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Early Luteal Hormones and IVF Outcomes After hCG Triggering</brief_title>
  <official_title>Reproductive Outcome of IVF Treatment in Relation to the Early Luteal Phase Trajectory of Progesterone and Other Corpus Luteum Related Hormones</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mỹ Đức Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mỹ Đức Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It has recently been demonstrated that a bolus trigger of hCG induces various unphysiological&#xD;
      conditions in the early luteal phase that may negatively affect an IVF treatment cycle's&#xD;
      reproductive outcome. The bolus trigger of hCG differ from the natural cycle in mainly three&#xD;
      different ways: 1) The timing of the initiation of hCG and progesterone rise is much faster&#xD;
      after an hCG trigger than in the natural menstrual cycle 2) the maximal concentrations of hCG&#xD;
      and progesterone considerably exceed those naturally observed 3) The timing of the peak&#xD;
      progesterone concentration following an hCG trigger is advanced several days compared to the&#xD;
      natural cycle. These characteristics may affect the reproductive outcome in treatment cycles&#xD;
      but are not explored. The aim of this study is to monitor whether specific trajectories of&#xD;
      important luteal phase hormones may predict the chances of conception?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The early luteal phase after ovarian stimulation and final oocyte maturation using a bolus&#xD;
      trigger of hCG is an area that has not received the same attention as regimes and protocols&#xD;
      for ovarian stimulation during the follicular phase. The hCG trigger has been considered the&#xD;
      golden standard since the beginning of the IVF era almost four decades ago. The hCG trigger&#xD;
      serves two main functions: 1) it induces oocytes to advance meiosis to the metaphase of the&#xD;
      second meiotic division ready for fertilization and further development, 2) secures&#xD;
      stimulation of the corpora lutea to secrete progesterone (P4) during the early luteal phase&#xD;
      due to its relatively long half-life. However, recent studies have suggested that each of&#xD;
      these two functions may be optimized on their own and that better alternatives to the hCG&#xD;
      trigger may be developed including a more physiological trigger for final maturation of&#xD;
      follicles and individualized luteal phase support. However, only recently has the early&#xD;
      luteal phase after IVF treatment using an hCG bolus trigger been described in studies&#xD;
      involving more than just a few patients. These studies suggested that the unphysiological&#xD;
      effects of the hCG trigger may be divided into three different categories: 1) The timing of&#xD;
      the initiation of hCG and progesterone rise is much faster after an hCG trigger than in the&#xD;
      natural menstrual cycle 2) the maximal concentrations of hCG and progesterone considerably&#xD;
      exceed those naturally observed 3) The timing of the peak progesterone concentration&#xD;
      following an hCG trigger is advanced several days compared to the natural cycle. How each of&#xD;
      these effects influences pregnancy outcome in treatment cycles are currently unknown.&#xD;
      Further, does characteristics shortly after administration of the hCG trigger for final&#xD;
      oocyte maturation subsequently affect the reproductive outcome, and does this provide an&#xD;
      opportunity for correcting or improving the luteal phase support given, with the improvement&#xD;
      of clinical pregnancy rate as a result is also unknown. The aim of this study is to evaluate&#xD;
      the trajectories of four hormones important for corpora lutea function (i.e. P4, 17-OH-P4,&#xD;
      hCG, and inhibin-A) during the early luteal phase in women undergoing IVF treatment with&#xD;
      luteal phase support given in the form of exogenous P4 administration and evaluate whether&#xD;
      clinical pregnancy rates are related to specific characteristics of the early luteal phase.&#xD;
      By including the measurements of 17-OH-P4 and inhibin-A the study will obtain an evaluation&#xD;
      of the function of corpora lutea itself independent of the P4 administration provided.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The clinical pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of progesterone in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 5 weeks after embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with at least one gestational sac on ultrasound at 7 weeks' gestation with the detection of heart beat activity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The ongoing pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of progesterone in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 10 weeks or beyond after the embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with detectable heart rate at 12 weeks' gestation or beyond</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The clinical pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of hCG in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 5 weeks after embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with at least one gestational sac on ultrasound at 7 weeks' gestation with the detection of heart beat activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The ongoing pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of hCG in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 10 weeks or beyond after the embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with detectable heart rate at 12 weeks' gestation or beyond</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The clinical pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of inhibin-A in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 5 weeks after embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with at least one gestational sac on ultrasound at 7 weeks' gestation with the detection of heart beat activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The ongoing pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of inhibin-A in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 10 weeks or beyond after the embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with detectable heart rate at 12 weeks' gestation or beyond</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The clinical pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of 17-OH-progesterone in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 5 weeks after embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with at least one gestational sac on ultrasound at 7 weeks' gestation with the detection of heart beat activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The ongoing pregnancy rate in relation to the trajectory of 17-OH-progesterone in the early luteal phase</measure>
    <time_frame>At 10 weeks or beyond after the embryo placement</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy with detectable heart rate at 12 weeks' gestation or beyond</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Luteal Phase</condition>
  <condition>in Vitro Fertilisation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hormonal levels</arm_group_label>
    <description>Blood samples are collected for analysis of progesterone, hCG, inhibin-A, and 17-OH-Progesterone levels.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hormonal levels</intervention_name>
    <description>A total of ten (10) blood samples (2ml/each) will be collected during the study for subsequent analysis of progesterone, hCG, inhibin-A, and 17-OH-progesterone:&#xD;
Day of triggering (before the injection of hCG, appx. 6 pm) Twelve (12 hours) after hCG injection (appx. at 6 am) Twenty-four (24) hours after hCG injection (appx. at 6 pm) Thirty-six (36) hours after hCG injection (appx. at 8 am, 2 hours after OPU) One (1) day after OPU (60h after hCG) (appx. at 6 am) Two (2) days after OPU (84h after hCG) (appx. at 6 am) Three (3) days after OPU 108h after hCG) (appx. at 6 am) Four (4) days after OPU (132h after hCG) (appx. at 6 am) Five (5) days after OPU (156h after hCG) (appx. at 6 am) Six (6) days after OPU (180h after hCG) (appx. at 6 am)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hormonal levels</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Vietnamese women who will be indicated for IVF treatment with hCG administration for final&#xD;
        oocytes maturation and undergo fresh embryo transfers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 - 38&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt; 28kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having 4 to 19 follicles with diameter of 12mm or above on the day of hCG triggering&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving a standard GnRH-antagonist protocol for ovarian stimulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having indication for fresh embryo transfer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to participate in the study, and to disclose any medical conditions to the&#xD;
             investigator. The patient must be prepared and willing to comply with the requirements&#xD;
             of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient should after appropriate oral and written consent understand the study and&#xD;
             be informed that she may withdraw consent at any time without prejudice to future&#xD;
             medical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous poor ovarian response (≤ 3 follicles) after appropriate FSH stimulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hyper-response defined as &gt;20 follicles ≥ 14 mm on the day of trigger&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronical medical conditions like Diabetes, Crohns disease, Thyroid disease, Hepatitis&#xD;
             B, Sexually Transmitted Diseases and simultaneous participation in an interventional&#xD;
             clinical trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>38 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lan N Vuong, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mỹ Đức Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Vu NA Ho, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+84935843336</phone>
    <email>bsvu.hna@myduchospital.vn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lan N Vuong, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+84903008889</phone>
    <email>drlan@yahoo.com.vn</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mỹ Đức Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ho Chi Minh City</city>
        <state>Tan Binh</state>
        <country>Vietnam</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Vu NA Ho, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+84935843336</phone>
      <email>bsvu.hna@myduchospital.vn</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lan N Vuong, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+843008889</phone>
      <email>drlan@yahoo.com.vn</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Vietnam</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

