<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04696497</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHRO-2020-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04696497</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Muscle Function and Muscle Ultrasound in ICU</brief_title>
  <acronym>DYNAMIQUE</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Muscle Function at Discharge From ICU: Evaluation of the Correlation Between Manual Muscle Testing, Dynamometric and Peripheral Ultrasound Parameters</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Hospitalier Régional d'Orléans</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Hospitalier Régional d'Orléans</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of intensive care therapists is to be able to detect as early as possible the&#xD;
      muscle weakness acquired in intensive care, in order to implement curative strategies such as&#xD;
      adapted nutrition and early rehabilitation. Various diagnostic tools are available for this&#xD;
      purpose. To evaluate muscle mass, CT and MRI remain the gold standard but are difficult to&#xD;
      implement in routine practice in ICU and are extremely expensive and can generate radiation&#xD;
      for the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Functional muscle evaluation is based on different voluntary tests which are not all able to&#xD;
      predict muscle weakness acquired in ICU. In addition, some of the voluntary tests are&#xD;
      expensive and require expert staff for practice and interpretation of results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, a muscle test such as MRC, although having an intraclass coefficient of 0.94,&#xD;
      has little predictive value on clinical parameters such as mechanical ventilation duration&#xD;
      and is not associated with mortality in the ward. However, it remains the test of choice to&#xD;
      define a ICUAW with a threshold value of 48/60 points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dynamometry is a tool for measuring muscle strength. The patient is asked to perform a short&#xD;
      and intense maximal muscular effort against manual or instrumental resistance. The limb&#xD;
      segments must not move, it is an isometric effort. The most common measurement in intensive&#xD;
      care units is the dynamometric grip force, called &quot;handgrip&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In ICU, the patient may have touble with awareness, arousal or even comprehension, which will&#xD;
      lead to biases in the evaluation of the motor force.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasound is a tool available in ICU and the muscle component can be assessed qualitatively&#xD;
      or quantitatively without the patient's participation. Several studies have also demonstrated&#xD;
      that muscle ultrasound is capable of reliably detecting pathological changes, particularly&#xD;
      when repeated. Muscle ultrasound could thus help identify patients at higher risk of&#xD;
      prolonged complications. Nevertheless, this technique lacks standardization and normative&#xD;
      criteria (patient position, probe position, type and number of measurements, target muscle,&#xD;
      etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective is to show that the dynamometric force relative to ultrasound thickness of&#xD;
      several muscle groups (arm flexors/knee extensors/foot lifters) is correlated with manual MRC&#xD;
      testing in intensive care unit (ICU) patients&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      When the patient will be under invasive ventilatory support and coma, and will present the&#xD;
      inclusion criteria, the investigator will perform ultrasound measurements of muscle thickness&#xD;
      on four muscle groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Shoulder Side muscular compartment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anterior Arm muscular compartment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anterior thigh muscular compartment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antero-lateral leg muscular compartment The ultrasound measurements will be made once a&#xD;
           day each weekday, until the discharge from ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasound measurements will be stopped if the patient's condition deteriorates and the ICU&#xD;
      team chooses to limit active therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the patient condition get better, the investigator will perform the first volitional&#xD;
      muscle function assessment, as soon as the patient Glasgow scale will score 15/15:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Medical Research Council sum score (MRC-ss)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Dynamometric strength assessment with the muscular groups used for the MRC-ss Then the&#xD;
           volitional muscle assessment will be made once every 3 days, until patient discharges&#xD;
           from ICU.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 14, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 14, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation coefficient between force/thickness ratio and MRC testing.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>To show that the dynamometric force relative to ultrasound thickness of several muscle groups (arm flexors/knee extensors/foot lifters) is correlated with manual MRC testing in intensive care medicine patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Modification in millimeters of ultrasound muscle thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Modification in millimeters of ultrasound muscle thickness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in force measured by dynamometry in patients with more than 2 evaluations</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Change in force measured by dynamometry in patients with more than 2 evaluations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medical Research Council sum-score (MRC-ss)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Following the same positions as for the dynamometer evaluation, the examiner will evaluate the 12 motor functions according to the following 60-point rating. With the maximum quote of 5 point representing normal strength and 0 point the total absence of any muscular contraction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">59</enrollment>
  <condition>Muscle Weakness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Muscular Assessment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>All the patients will received the muscular assessments</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>Ultrasound measurements of muscle thickness, using a linear probe (high frequency) on four muscle groups:&#xD;
Shoulder Side muscular compartment&#xD;
Anterior Arm muscular compartment&#xD;
Anterior thigh muscular compartment&#xD;
Antero-lateral leg muscular compartment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Muscular Assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dynamometric muscular assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>The principle of electronic dynamometry is to measure an isometric force. To carry out these measurements, the examiner will stand on the side who has to be tested by exerting a pressure diametrically opposite to the patient's movement, thus preventing him/her from carrying out the movement. The patient will perform 3 tests for each movement, the best value will be collected by the examiner.&#xD;
The reference position is :&#xD;
Patient elbowed to the body bent at 90°, with trunk inclination at 30° in the resuscitation bed, lower limbs flat.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Muscular Assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Manual muscular Assessment (MRC-SS)</intervention_name>
    <description>Following the same positions as for the dynamometer, the examiner will evaluate the 12 motor functions according to the following 60-point rating. With the maximum quote of 5 point representing normal strength and 0 point the total absence of any muscular contraction</description>
    <arm_group_label>Muscular Assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major patient &gt; 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission for more than 24 hours in the ICU ward&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stay must be at least 72 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person with a neuromuscular pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person presenting an osteoarticular contraindication to mobilization&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Amputee&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person under guardianship or curatorship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person not affiliated to a social security system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant Women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Guillaume FOSSAT</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHR d'Orléans</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aurélie DESPUJOLS</last_name>
    <phone>+33238744071</phone>
    <email>aurelie.despujols@chr-orleans.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Elodie POUGOUE TOUKO</last_name>
    <phone>+33238744086</phone>
    <email>elodie.pougoue-touko@chr-orleans.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHR d'Orléans</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orléans</city>
        <zip>45067</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Guillaume FOSSAT</last_name>
      <email>guillaume.fossat@chr-orleans.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kress JP, Hall JB. ICU-acquired weakness and recovery from critical illness. N Engl J Med. 2014 Apr 24;370(17):1626-35. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1209390. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24758618</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hermans G, Van den Berghe G. Clinical review: intensive care unit acquired weakness. Crit Care. 2015 Aug 5;19:274. doi: 10.1186/s13054-015-0993-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26242743</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cheung AM, Tansey CM, Tomlinson G, Diaz-Granados N, Matté A, Barr A, Mehta S, Mazer CD, Guest CB, Stewart TE, Al-Saidi F, Cooper AB, Cook D, Slutsky AS, Herridge MS. Two-year outcomes, health care use, and costs of survivors of acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2006 Sep 1;174(5):538-44. Epub 2006 Jun 8.</citation>
    <PMID>16763220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cuthbertson BH, Roughton S, Jenkinson D, Maclennan G, Vale L. Quality of life in the five years after intensive care: a cohort study. Crit Care. 2010;14(1):R6. doi: 10.1186/cc8848. Epub 2010 Jan 20.</citation>
    <PMID>20089197</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Herridge MS, Cheung AM, Tansey CM, Matte-Martyn A, Diaz-Granados N, Al-Saidi F, Cooper AB, Guest CB, Mazer CD, Mehta S, Stewart TE, Barr A, Cook D, Slutsky AS; Canadian Critical Care Trials Group. One-year outcomes in survivors of the acute respiratory distress syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2003 Feb 20;348(8):683-93.</citation>
    <PMID>12594312</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Intensive care unit</keyword>
  <keyword>Dynamometric</keyword>
  <keyword>Ultrasound</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical Research Council sum score</keyword>
  <keyword>Ultrasonography</keyword>
  <keyword>Muscle Strength</keyword>
  <keyword>Critical Care</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscle Weakness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

