<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04699669</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CBL-16001(Phase 1)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04699669</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 1 Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of CBL-514 Injection on Convexity or Fullness of Abdominal Subcutaneous Fat in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A 2-stage, Phase 1/2a Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, and Preliminary Efficacy of CBL-514 Injection for Reducing Convexity or Fullness of Abdominal Subcutaneous Fat (Phase 1)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Caliway Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Caliway Biopharmaceuticals Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Phase 1 component of the study is a double-blind, placebo-controlled, single ascending&#xD;
      dose (SAD) design intended to assess the safety, tolerability, and PK of CBL-514. The SAD&#xD;
      part will involve 9 proposed dosing cohorts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Phase 1 part of the study was a first-in-human, single ascending dose, double-blind,&#xD;
      randomized (except Cohorts 6 to 9 [open-label]) study in healthy subjects to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety, tolerability and PK of CBL-514, and to determine the dose levels to be used for the&#xD;
      Phase 2a part of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 27, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 20, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 20, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of treatment emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 4 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants experiencing TEAEs and number of individual TEAEs among treatment groups by severity and relationship to investigational product (IP)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with clinically significant abnormalities in clinical laboratory values</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical laboratory tests include Biochemistry, Hematology, Coagulation and Urinalysis testinjection site reactions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with clinically significant abnormalities in vital signs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Vital signs measurements include temperature, pulse rate, blood pressure, and respiratory rate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with clinically significant abnormalities in Electrocardiogram (ECG)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>ECG parameters include heart rate, RR interval, PR interval, QT interval, QTc interval, and QRS interval</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with clinically significant abnormalities in physical examination</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Physical examinations include assessment of cardiovascular, respiratory, gastrointestinal, and neurological systems</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with injection site reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 weeks after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Injection site reactions include but not limited to redness, swelling, bruising, tenderness, itching, pain, warmth, discoloration and hardness</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess maximum concentration of CBL-514 in plasma (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate maximum concentration of CBL-514 in plasma (Cmax) after single dose injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess time to Cmax of CBL-514 in plasma (tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate time to Cmax of CBL-514 in plasma (tmax) after single dose injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess area under the concentration-time curve of CBL-514 in plasma (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate area under the concentration-time curve of CBL-514 in plasma (AUC) after single dose injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess terminal rate constant and half-life of CBL-514 in plasma (λz and t1/2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate terminal rate constant and half-life of CBL-514 in plasma (λz and t1/2) after single dose injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess apparent clearance and volume of distribution of CBL-514 in plasma (CL/F and Vz/F).</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate apparent clearance and volume of distribution of CBL-514 in plasma (CL/F and Vz/F) after single dose injection.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>9</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Subcutaneous Fat</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: CBL-514 2 mg, 0.5 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individual placebo control. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 4 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: CBL-514 10 mg, 0.5 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individual placebo control. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 4 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: CBL-514 20 mg, 0.5 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individual placebo control. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 4 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 4: CBL-514 40 mg, 1.0 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individual placebo control. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 4 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 5: CBL-514 40 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individual placebo control. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 2 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 6: CBL-514 80 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CBL-514 only. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 2 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 7: CBL-514 160 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CBL-514 only. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 2 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 8: CBL-514 240 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CBL-514 only. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 2 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 9: CBL-514 320 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CBL-514 only. CBL-514 will be administrated with the grid spacing of 2 cm^2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CBL-514, placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>One side of the abdominal region will receive CBL-514, while the other will receive placebo with equal volume.&#xD;
Which side of the abdominal region to receive CBL-514 or placebo would be randomized.&#xD;
No PK samples will be collected in this cohort.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: CBL-514 2 mg, 0.5 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: CBL-514 10 mg, 0.5 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CBL-514, placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>One side of the abdominal region will receive CBL-514, while the other will receive placebo with equal volume.&#xD;
Which side of the abdominal region to receive CBL-514 or placebo would be randomized.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: CBL-514 20 mg, 0.5 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 4: CBL-514 40 mg, 1.0 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 5: CBL-514 40 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CBL-514</intervention_name>
    <description>Both sides of the abdominal region will receive CBL-514.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 6: CBL-514 80 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 7: CBL-514 160 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 8: CBL-514 240 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 9: CBL-514 320 mg, 2 mg/cm^2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A subject can participate in the study only if all the following criteria are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male/female aged 18 years to 64 years old (at Screening), inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index &gt;18.5 and &lt;35 kg/m2 and body weight ≥50 kg at Screening and Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Has MWC ≥80.0 cm at Screening and Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subcutaneous fat thickness of at least 3.00 cm (30.0 mm) by pinch method (measured by&#xD;
             calibrated caliper) surrounding the navel at Screening and Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Voluntarily signs the Informed Consent Form and, in the opinion of the Investigator or&#xD;
             delegate, is physically and mentally capable of participating in the study, and&#xD;
             willing to adhere to study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A subject who meets any of the following criteria will not be eligible to enter the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female subject of childbearing potential who is not willing to commit to an acceptable&#xD;
             contraceptive regimen with her partner from the time of Screening and throughout study&#xD;
             participation until 12 weeks after the last study drug dose, or who is currently&#xD;
             pregnant or lactating. Male subject who is not willing to commit to an acceptable&#xD;
             contraceptive method. Females who have been surgically sterilized (hysterectomy or&#xD;
             bilateral oophorectomy) or who are postmenopausal (e.g., defined as at least 50 years&#xD;
             with ≥12 months of amenorrhea with a follicle stimulating hormone &gt;40 IU/L) are&#xD;
             considered to be of nonchildbearing potential. Subjects who are not of childbearing&#xD;
             potential are not required to use contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject diagnosed with coagulation disorders or is receiving&#xD;
             anticoagulant/antiplatelet therapy or medications or dietary supplements, which impede&#xD;
             coagulation or platelet aggregation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject has diabetes or glycated hemoglobin ≥6.5% (48 mmol/mol) or fasting blood sugar&#xD;
             ≥7 mmol/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject has a cardiovascular disease, or shows clinically significant abnormal&#xD;
             findings in ECG at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject with active or prior history of malignancies (except for successfully treated&#xD;
             non-invasive basal cell carcinoma) or being worked-up for a possible malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject with a history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-1, hepatitis B, or&#xD;
             hepatitis C infections or subjects with active HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C&#xD;
             infections at Screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Active HIV infection: positive HIV Ag/Ab combo test;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Active hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection: positive HBV surface antigen (HBsAg).&#xD;
                  Subjects with negative HBsAg but with positive HBV core antibody with or without&#xD;
                  positive HBV surface antibody will also be excluded. However, subjects with&#xD;
                  negative HBsAg, negative HBV core antibody, and positive HBV surface antibody may&#xD;
                  be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Active hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection: positive HCV antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has abnormal skin or local skin conditions, which in the opinion of&#xD;
             Investigator is inappropriate to participate in the study, including but not limited&#xD;
             to any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Skin manifestations of a systemic disease,&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Any abnormality of the skin or soft tissues of the abdominal wall in the area to&#xD;
                  be treated,&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Skin or superficial tissue that does not lie flat on its own when the subject is&#xD;
                  in the supine position,&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Sensory loss or dysesthesia in the area to be treated,&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Evidence of any cause of enlargement in the abdominal area other than localized&#xD;
                  subcutaneous fat,&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Tattoos on the area to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject who has undergone the following procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Previous open or laparoscopic abdominal surgery in the anticipated treatment&#xD;
                  area,&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Cardiac pacemakers or any implantable electrical device,&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Metal implants of any type in the area to be treated,&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Esthetic procedure to the region to be treated within 6 months before Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject is on prescription or over-the-counter weight reduction medication or weight&#xD;
             reduction programs within 3 months before Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject is undergoing chronic steroid or immunosuppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Requiring continual use of the following therapeutic agents during the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
             S-mephenytoin, terfenadine, buspirone, fexofenadine, breast cancer resistance protein&#xD;
             (BCRP) substrates (such as mitoxantrone, methotrexate, topotecan, nitrofurantoin,&#xD;
             dipyridamole, statins, etc.), cytochrome P450 3A4 inhibitor, or non-steroidal&#xD;
             anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs). If a subject needs to use the above mentioned&#xD;
             therapeutic agents during the study for any reason, these therapeutic agents should&#xD;
             not be used at least for 48 hours prior to dosing until 24 hours post-dose or the&#xD;
             collection of the last PK sample, whichever is later.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Unable to receive topical anesthesia (e.g., history of hypersensitivity to lidocaine).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subjects with known allergies or sensitivities to the study drug and/or excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects with inadequate liver function at Screening defined as aspartate&#xD;
             aminotransferase, alanine aminotransferase, alkaline phosphatase, total bilirubin, or&#xD;
             gamma-glutamyl transferase &gt;1.5 × ULN. A subject with an elevated liver chemistry test&#xD;
             up to 1.5 × ULN at Screening should be evaluated by the Investigator to exclude&#xD;
             pre-existing liver disease associated with mild elevation of liver chemistry tests. If&#xD;
             the mild elevation is assessed by the Investigator as not clinically significant or&#xD;
             related to non-alcoholic fatty liver, the subject may be eligible if the follow-up&#xD;
             tests show an unchanged or reducing value from the initial Screening value. A subject&#xD;
             with marginally elevated fasting unconjugated serum bilirubin with documented&#xD;
             Gilbert's syndrome, and no other cause for the elevated bilirubin on investigation,&#xD;
             may be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subjects with inadequate renal function, defined as abnormal serum creatinine, and&#xD;
             urea &gt;1.5 × ULN or estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;60 mL/min/1.73 m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Subjects who are currently on dialysis should be excluded. A subject with serum urea&#xD;
             between 1 to 1.5 × ULN at Screening, but an eGFR &gt;60mL/min/1.73 m2 and no other renal&#xD;
             risk factors, should be re-tested prior to declaring the subject as eligible. The&#xD;
             subject may be eligible if the fasting serum creatinine is not rising nor the eGFR&#xD;
             falling, the urinary albumin/creatinine ratio remain &lt;3 mg/mmol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Use of other investigational drug or device within 4 weeks prior to Screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

