<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04698330</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020LADACP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04698330</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects Of Berberine Plus Inulin On Diabetes Care in Elder Patients With LADA</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Berberine Plus Inulin on Diabetes Care in Elder Patients With Latent Autoimmune Diabetes in Adults: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Second Xiangya Hospital of Central South University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Xiangya Hospital of Central South University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to evaluate the effects of oral berberine (BBR) and&#xD;
      inulin combined with insulin therapy on diabetes care in patients with LADA aged over 60&#xD;
      years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Latent autoimmune diabetes in adults (LADA) is a hybrid form of diabetes, characterized by&#xD;
      autoimmune destruction of pancreatic β-cells as well as insulin resistance and is triggered&#xD;
      by environmental factors in the context of genetic susceptibility. Meanwhile，blood glucose&#xD;
      management is the cornerstone of diabetes care and poor glycemic control will cause a series&#xD;
      of diabetes complications，which is especially true for the elderly. This study will focus on&#xD;
      improving the quality of life of elderly LADA patients and blood glucose management as the&#xD;
      starting point to explore the improvement effects of combined drugs on the development of&#xD;
      diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inulin is a common prebiotic that has been shown to improve glycemic control, alter the gut&#xD;
      microbiota and suppress inflammation. Berberine(BBR), a small alkaloid isolated from&#xD;
      medicinal plants, has been reported to have many therapeutic effects, including&#xD;
      anti-bacteria, anti-diabetes, and lipid-lowering. Besides, studies revealed that BBR exerts&#xD;
      antidiabetic effects by modulating gut microbiota. In a multicentre, randomized,&#xD;
      double-blinded, placebo-controlled 12-week clinical trial conducted in 409 drug-naive T2D&#xD;
      patients, Wang et al. confirmed the hypoglycaemic effect of BBR in Chinese participants and&#xD;
      demonstrated the BBR-induced changes in the human gut microbiome in comparison with the&#xD;
      placebo. Moreover, Ho et al. conducted a randomized, placebo-controlled trial in 38 children&#xD;
      with type 1 diabetes using placebo or prebiotic oligofructose-enriched inulin for 12 weeks,&#xD;
      and found that oral supplement of the prebiotic could improve glycemic status and β cell&#xD;
      function. So we speculate that BBR and inulin combination can also improve glycemic control&#xD;
      in the patients with LADA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is a prospective, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. The study&#xD;
      comprises once screening, the 1-month run-in period, the 3-month treatment period and the&#xD;
      9-month follow-up period. After obtaining the informed consent from the patient who is&#xD;
      willing to participate the 3-month treatment will enter to the 1-month run-in period.&#xD;
      According to the inclusion/exclusion criteria, the eligible patients will be randomized to&#xD;
      the 3-month treatment period. Patients will be randomized into four groups : BBR-alone,&#xD;
      inulin+BBR, inulin-alone, or placebo. The primary outcome is to assess the change in glycated&#xD;
      hemoglobin levels. Dynamic blood glucose parameters, β-cell function and gut microbiota, as&#xD;
      well as adverse events and quality of life will be monitored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in C-peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of acute and chronic diabetes complications</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in gut permeability</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
    <description>Gut permeability is measured by amount of mannitol and lactulose in urine.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in gut microbiota composition</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
    <description>The changes of gut microbiota are mainly detected by multi omics technology.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life will be assessed by the Chinese version of the Audit of Diabetes Dependent Quality of Life (ADDQoL-19).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gastrointestinal side effects and other drug-related side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
    <description>The gastrointestinal side effects need to be self-reported by the patient, such as nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, constipation, flatulence, etc.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypoglycemic events</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after start of trial</time_frame>
    <description>Hypoglycemia events are divided into mild hypoglycemia and severe hypoglycemia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">240</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Autoimmune Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LADA patients are assigned to receive berberine and inulin for 3-month.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LADA patients are assigned to receive berberine and placebo(for inulin) for 3-month.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LADA patients are assigned to receive placebo(for berberine) and inulin for 3-month.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group D</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>LADA patients are assigned to receive placebo(for berberine) and placebo(for inulin) for 3-month.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Berberine</intervention_name>
    <description>0.6g (6 pills) of Berberine tablets administered twice a day orally before meal for 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Inulin</intervention_name>
    <description>0.6g (6 pills) of Inulin tablets administered twice a day orally before meal for 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Berberine placebo tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>0.6g (6 pills) of Berberine placebo tablets administered twice a day orally before meal for 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group C</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Inulin placebo tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>0.6g (6 pills) of Inulin placebo tablets administered twice a day orally before meal for 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group D</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diabetes diagnosed according to the report of WHO in 1999；&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Meet the Chinese Diabetes Society diagnostic criteria (2012) for LADA: (1)glutamic&#xD;
             acid decarboxylase antibody (GADA) positive; (2) age at diagnosis ≧ 18 years old; (3)&#xD;
             independent on insulin for more than 6 months after diagnosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age ≧ 60 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. 7.0%≤HbA1c ≤10.0%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. BMI ≥ 18.5 kg/m2, and no more than 37.5 kg/m2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Written informed consent from the patient or family representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Severe liver dysfunction (ALT and AST greater than 3 times the upper limit of&#xD;
             detection);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. eGFR &lt; 50ml/(min • 1.73 m2);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of acute or chronic infection affecting glycemic control within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
             to the first visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of any malignancy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnancy, breastfeeding, or planned pregnancy during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Secondary diabetes;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence of acute complications (ketoacidosis, lactic acidosis or hyperosmolar coma);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Severe organic heart disease, including but not limited to congenital heart disease,&#xD;
             rheumatic heart disease, hypertrophic or dilated cardiomyopathy, etc., New York Heart&#xD;
             Association (NYHA) heart function classification ≥Grade III;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Chronic use of systemic glucocorticoids or other immunosuppressive agents for over 3&#xD;
             months，or use of antibiotic medications or other interventions that could affect the&#xD;
             gastrointestinal tract for 2 months before the screening and during the whole study&#xD;
             period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of hemolytic anemia or glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase deficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Allergic to berberine or any components in the combinations.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yang Xiao, MD/PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute of Metabolism and Endocrinology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University, China</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yang Xiao, MD/PhD</last_name>
    <phone>86-731-85292154</phone>
    <email>xiaoyang29@csu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Metabolism and Endocrinology, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changsha</city>
        <state>Hunan</state>
        <zip>410011</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yang Xiao, MD/PhD</last_name>
      <phone>86-0731-85292154</phone>
      <email>xiaoyang29@csu.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang Y, Gu Y, Ren H, Wang S, Zhong H, Zhao X, Ma J, Gu X, Xue Y, Huang S, Yang J, Chen L, Chen G, Qu S, Liang J, Qin L, Huang Q, Peng Y, Li Q, Wang X, Kong P, Hou G, Gao M, Shi Z, Li X, Qiu Y, Zou Y, Yang H, Wang J, Xu G, Lai S, Li J, Ning G, Wang W. Gut microbiome-related effects of berberine and probiotics on type 2 diabetes (the PREMOTE study). Nat Commun. 2020 Oct 6;11(1):5015. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-18414-8.</citation>
    <PMID>33024120</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ho J, Nicolucci AC, Virtanen H, Schick A, Meddings J, Reimer RA, Huang C. Effect of Prebiotic on Microbiota, Intestinal Permeability, and Glycemic Control in Children With Type 1 Diabetes. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2019 Oct 1;104(10):4427-4440. doi: 10.1210/jc.2019-00481.</citation>
    <PMID>31188437</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Second Xiangya Hospital of Central South University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yang Xiao</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor, Department of Metabolism and Endocrinology, Institute of Metabolism and Endocrinology, National Clinical Research Center for Metabolic Diseases, Second Xiangya Hospital, Central South University</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>LADA</keyword>
  <keyword>Berberine</keyword>
  <keyword>Inulin</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes Care</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

