<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04692337</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-009226</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04692337</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ommaya Reservoir Placement for Brain Tumor Biomarker Access</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ommaya Reservoir Placement for Brain Tumor Biomarker Access</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mayo Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the safety and feasibility of intra-operative&#xD;
      Ommaya Reservoir placement during a clinically indicated operation for brain tumor. The&#xD;
      Ommaya reservoir will facilitate a longitudinal access to cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) for&#xD;
      analysis of potential biomarkers for brain tumor research and individualized monitoring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Most brain tumors remain incurable. Progress in clinical trials to identify better treatments&#xD;
      has been slow. We hypothesize that longitudinal CSF access can provide insights regarding&#xD;
      tumor identity, behavior and the efficacy of candidate therapies. Although multiple studies&#xD;
      have evaluated CSF from patients with brain tumors, very few have collected CSF at multiple&#xD;
      timepoints throughout the course of disease. However, multiple samples over time are needed&#xD;
      to determine if candidate biomarkers accurately reflect the evolution of disease. CSF is&#xD;
      typically obtained via lumbar puncture which is inconvenient and often uncomfortable. This&#xD;
      protocol will evaluate the safety and feasibility of placing Ommaya reservoirs at the time of&#xD;
      surgery. It is anticipated that reducing barriers to CSF access through placement of an&#xD;
      Ommaya reservoir may expedite brain tumor research and facilitate the development of&#xD;
      individualized treatment strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An Ommaya Reservoir will be placed during a planned brain tumor operation. Following the&#xD;
      routine portion of the planned procedure, the Ommaya reservoir will be placed under the scalp&#xD;
      with the catheter tip placed either within the ventricle or the resection cavity. Presence of&#xD;
      the Ommaya reservoir will enable CSF to be easily accessed at any time in the future. It is&#xD;
      expected that CSF will be collected at 2 or more timepoints. CSF will be stored in the Mayo&#xD;
      Clinic neuro-oncology biorepository and made available in a de-identified manner for multiple&#xD;
      research projects. The patient and his/her provider(s) may take advantage of the Ommaya&#xD;
      reservoir and/or banked CSF samples to facilitate participation in any relevant IRB-approved&#xD;
      research study(s), and/or to facilitate individualized management. The details of each time&#xD;
      the Ommaya is accessed will be documented as part of this trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events of intra-operative Ommaya Reservoir placement</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, approximately 42 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects to develop persistent adverse events deemed related (possibly, probably, definitely) to the insertion or use of Ommaya Reservoirs. Adverse events will be measured by CTCAE 5.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intra-operative Ommaya Reservoir placement</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, approximately 42 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects whom Ommaya reservoir is successfully placed at the time of surgery without complication.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ommaya Reservoir placement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects undergoing surgery for a confirmed or suspected brain tumor will have an Ommaya Reservoir placed at the time of surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intra-operative Ommaya Reservoir placement</intervention_name>
    <description>An Ommaya reservoir is a small device implanted under the scalp that enables percutaneous access to cerebrospinal fluid.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ommaya Reservoir placement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical and radiographic evidence suggesting a diagnosis of a brain tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned neurosurgical procedure resection of suspected or previously diagnosed brain&#xD;
             tumor as part of routine clinical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to undergo neurosurgical resection at Mayo Clinic (Rochester, MN).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing to have their Ommaya sampled on at least 2 future occasions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients is willing to have CSF banked through the neuro-oncology biorepository&#xD;
             (requires a separate signature)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vulnerable populations including pregnant women, prisoners and individuals &lt;18 years&#xD;
             old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are not appropriate candidates for surgery due to current or past medical&#xD;
             history or uncontrolled concurrent illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior history of any wound infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient who the surgeon feels is not an optimal candidate for Ommaya reservoir&#xD;
             placement. Such reasons could (but need not necessarily) include factors related to&#xD;
             surgical anatomy, clinical evidence of significant immunosuppression, and/or elevated&#xD;
             risk of wound infection due to diabetes, smoking history, morbid obesity, or any other&#xD;
             concerns.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Terry C Burns, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bambi Wessel</last_name>
    <phone>(507) 293-1963</phone>
    <email>Wessel.Bambi@mayo.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bambi Wessel</last_name>
      <email>Wessel.Bambi@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mayo.edu/research/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Mayo Clinic Clinical Trials</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mayo Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Terry Burns</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Protocol details and individualized de-identified patient data will be provided as supplemental files in the resulting publication. Any additional information not otherwise provided may be requested from the primary investigator.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Any time after publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Requests will be honored that could help advance the care of patients with brain tumors.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

