<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04696653</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00269855</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04696653</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Quality Improvement Process to Support Delivery of Cardiovascular Care in Community Mental Health Organizations</brief_title>
  <official_title>Using an Innovative Quality Improvement Process to Increase Delivery of Evidence-based Cardiovascular Risk Factor Care in Community Mental Health Organizations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This pilot study will examine whether an implementation strategy will improve delivery of&#xD;
      evidence-based care for cardiovascular risk factors for people with serious mental illness.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this pilot study, the investigators will work with health home programs and pilot test an&#xD;
      adapted Comprehensive Unit Safety Program (CUSP) implementation strategy to improve mental&#xD;
      health providers' delivery of evidence-based cardiovascular risk factor care for&#xD;
      hypertension, dyslipidemia and diabetes for individuals with serious mental illness. The&#xD;
      project will also characterize implementation processes, organizational and provider-level&#xD;
      factors, and cardiovascular disease risk factor care and control.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality improvement culture as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Each of the 34 items in the modified survey is scored individually on 1-5 Likert scales. An average score is calculated by summing responses across all 34 items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher average score signifies an organizational culture that is more supportive of quality improvement.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-efficacy as assessed by an adapted version of Compeau &amp; Higgins' task-focused self-efficacy scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Each of the nine items is scored individually on a 1-10 Likert scale, where 1=not at all confident and 10=totally confident. An average score is calculated by summing responses across all 9 items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-10. A higher score signifies greater self-efficacy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in acceptability as assessed by the Acceptability of Intervention Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use a validated 4-item instrument measuring intervention acceptability, using the Acceptability of Intervention Measure. Each of the 4 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=completely disagree and 5=completely agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across all four items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies greater acceptability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in appropriateness as assessed by the Intervention Appropriateness Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use a validated 4-item instrument measuring intervention appropriateness, using the Intervention Appropriateness Measure. Each of the 4 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=completely disagree and 5= completely agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across all four items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies greater appropriateness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in feasibility as assessed by the Feasibility of Intervention Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use a validated 4-item instrument measuring intervention feasibility, using the Feasibility of Intervention Measure. Each of the 4 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=completely disagree and 5=completely agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across all four items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies greater feasibility.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Hypertension control</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured with blood pressure (BP) readings (Controlled BP defined as &lt;130/80 mmHg).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dyslipidemia control</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured with cholesterol readings (controlled dyslipidemia defined as total cholesterol &lt;200 mg/dL and low-density lipoprotein (LDL) &lt;130 mg/dL).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in diabetes control</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using HbA1c tests (controlled diabetes defined as HbA1c&lt;7.0).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received HBA1c measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received a lipid panel</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received statin therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received a dilated eye exam</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received a foot exam</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with dyslipidemia who received a lipid panel</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in teamwork within units as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 4 items measuring teamwork. Each of the 4 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies better teamwork within units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in supervisor promotion of quality improvement as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 4 items measuring the degree to which a provider's supervisor promotes quality improvement. Each of the 4 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies greater promotion of quality improvement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in organizational learning as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 3 items measuring organizational learning environment. Each of the 3 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies greater organizational learning.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in management support for quality improvement as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 3 items measuring the degree to which organization management supports quality improvement. Each of the 3 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies greater management support for quality improvement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in overall perceptions of quality improvement culture as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 3 items measuring the perception's of the organization's quality improvement culture. Each of the 3 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies better quality improvement culture.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in feedback and communication as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 3 items measuring feedback and communication about quality improvement. Each of the 3 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=never and 5=always. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies better feedback and communication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in communication openness as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 3 items measuring perceptions of communication openness in the organization. Each of the 3 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=never and 5=always. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies better communication openness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mistake reporting as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 3 items assessing the degree to which mistakes are reported at the organization. Each of the 3 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=never and 5=always. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies more frequent mistake reporting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in teamwork across units as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 4 items assessing teamwork across units. Each of the 4 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies better teamwork across units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in staffing capacity as assessed by the modified version of the validated Survey on Patient Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>We will use 2 items assessing staffing capacity. Each of the 2 items will be measured on a 5-point Likert scale, where 1=strongly disagree and 5=strongly agree. An average score is calculated by summing responses across items and dividing by the total number of items. The average score ranges from 1-5. A higher score signifies better staffing capacity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals with systolic blood pressure with poorly controlled hypertension who had a blood pressure measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measured with blood pressure (BP) readings (Poorly controlled BP defined as &gt;130/80 mmHg).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received a urine-protein-creatinine test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with dyslipidemia who are on a statin medication</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with hypertension who received lifestyle counseling</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with diabetes mellitus who received lifestyle counseling</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the percent of individuals diagnosed with dyslipidemia who received lifestyle counseling</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1200</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Dyslipidemias</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Comprehensive unit based safety (CUSP) intervention arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>CUSP is a quality improvement strategy developed by the Johns Hopkins University Armstrong Institute for Patient Safety and Quality that is used to improve care delivery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Comprehensive Unit Based Safety Program (CUSP)</intervention_name>
    <description>CUSP is a quality improvement strategy developed by the Johns Hopkins University Armstrong Institute for Patient Safety and Quality that is used to improve care delivery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Comprehensive unit based safety (CUSP) intervention arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study population 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric rehabilitation program and health home team staff, including providers and&#xD;
             leadership are those employed by the psychiatric rehabilitation program or health home&#xD;
             program.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English-speaking.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study population 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with serious mental illness participating in psychiatric rehabilitation health&#xD;
             home programs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Emma E McGinty, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emma E McGinty, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>410-614-4018</phone>
    <email>bmcginty@jhu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gail L Daumit, MD</last_name>
    <phone>410-614-6460</phone>
    <email>gdaumit@jhmi.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Adult Psychiatric Rehabilitation Program</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joyce Rohlfing, LCSW-C</last_name>
      <phone>410-550-5150</phone>
      <email>jrohlfi1@jhmi.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyslipidemias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

