<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04695236</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>INHPTAIS-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04695236</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial of Intravascular Hypothermia Therapy in Acute Ischemic Stroke Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Multicenter, Randomized Clinical Trial to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Intravascular Hypothermia Therapy of Patients With Acute Ischemic Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>jiaoliqun</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Xuanwu Hospital, Beijing</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cerebral stroke (stroke) is a group of diseases whose main clinical manifestations are&#xD;
      cerebral hemorrhage and ischemic injury symptoms. It has a very high mortality and disability&#xD;
      rate and is one of the most important fatal diseases in the world. From the previous domestic&#xD;
      and foreign literatures, hypothermia can prevent and treat secondary injury caused by&#xD;
      ischemia-reperfusion injury and cerebral edema of acute cerebral ischemia. Prevent and treat&#xD;
      ischemia-reperfusion injury and secondary injury caused by cerebral edema caused by acute&#xD;
      cerebral ischemia, so as to achieve the role of brain protection. In this study,&#xD;
      intravascular cooling was used. As soon as possible, intravascular cooling was performed&#xD;
      during thrombectomy and temperature management was performed. The temperature was controlled&#xD;
      at 33 ° C for 48-72 hours. The study is a parallel controlled study to systematically study&#xD;
      the effects of vascular hypothermia and early hypothermia treatment on ischemic stroke&#xD;
      reperfusion. Research treatment results and explore hypothermia treatment options to provide&#xD;
      more solutions for brain protection and improve patient prognosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the target patients were patients with moderate or severe acute stroke who&#xD;
      were satisfied with mTICI 2b-3 reperfusion. Ultra-early intravascular hypothermia brain&#xD;
      protection therapy was given to patients with intravascular hypothermia during thrombectomy&#xD;
      to evaluate its safety and effectiveness.To study the cerebral protective effect of&#xD;
      endovascular hypothermia therapy, the improvement in bleeding conversion rate, the&#xD;
      improvement in infarct volume and cerebral edema, the improvement in prognosis quality of&#xD;
      life and neurological function recovery, as well as the improvement in mortality and&#xD;
      disability rate, etc., the specific evaluation criteria are detailed in the following&#xD;
      experimental design.The endovascular hypothermia treatment of ischemia-reperfusion patients&#xD;
      was explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Assessment by independent investigators</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>intracranial hemorrhages conversion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>7days after thrombectomy operation or discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Compare intracranial hemorrhages conversion rate between study group and control group</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the rate of 90-day mRS (0-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the rate of 90-day mRS (0-2) between the two groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infarct volume</measure>
    <time_frame>7days after thrombectomy operation or discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Compare infarct volume between two groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain edema (incidence and volume)</measure>
    <time_frame>7days after thrombectomy operation or discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Compare brain edema (incidence and volume)between two groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of lung infection</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the incidence of lung infection between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Intravascular Hypothermia Treatment in Thrombectomy Operation and Brain Protection for Ischemia-reperfusion in AIS Patients</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study Group: intravascular hypothermia therapy group ZOLL Intravascular Temperature Management system, Quattro catheter will be used in study group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group: Without intravascular hypothermia therapy group&#xD;
ZOLL Intravascular Temperature Management system, Quattro catheter will not be used in control group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ZOLL Intravascular Temperature Management system, Quattro catheter</intervention_name>
    <description>ZOLL Intravascular Temperature Management system, Quattro catheter</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Study group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age between 18 and 80 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ASPECTS score 5-10.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with acute onset stroke in the 0-24 hours time window from symptom onset to&#xD;
             femoral artery puncture, internal carotid artery or middle cerebral artery M1 or M2&#xD;
             segment occlusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. (NIHSS) score ≥ 13, with or without intravenous t-PA treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subject' recanalization of vessel achieves mTICI 2b-3, the subject has not type II&#xD;
             parenchymal hematoma (PH2) in CT examination. If the subject' recanalization of vessel&#xD;
             could not achieve mTICI 2b-3, the subject could not enter the per-protocol analysis&#xD;
             and will separate another group.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Informed consent form signed by subjects or their legal guardian .&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Subject who suffer serious infection, multiple organ failure. 2. Subject who need to&#xD;
        place the inferior vena cava filter. 3. Subject who suffer from late renal failure who&#xD;
        require dialysis. 5. Subjects known to be allergic to study medical devices, related&#xD;
        products and medicine; 6. Subjects known active bleeding or known bleeding tendency (eg,&#xD;
        preoperative anticoagulant therapy or coagulation dysfunction before operation, INR &gt; 3.0);&#xD;
        8. Subjects with the history of platelet count lower than 40×10^9/L; 9. Subject with the&#xD;
        history of ventricular arrhythmia leading to cardiac arrest; 10. Subjects with blood&#xD;
        glucose concentration &lt;2.7 or&gt; 22.2 mmol / L; 11. Life expectancy &lt;6 months; 12. Subjects&#xD;
        with known dementia or mental illness cannot complete neurological function assessment; 13.&#xD;
        Subjects not included for other reasons from the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Xuanwu Hospital, Beijing</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>jiaoliqun</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ischemic Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

