<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04692038</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20201215</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04692038</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluate the Diagnostic Value of Puncture Biopsy for PPL Under the Guidance of Navigation and Radial EBUS: a Real-World Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Real-World Study to Evaluate the Diagnostic Value of Puncture Biopsy for Peripheral Lung Nodules Under the Guidance of Augmented Reality Navigation System Combined With Radial EBUS</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Guangzhou Institute of Respiratory Disease</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Guangzhou Institute of Respiratory Disease</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed to evaluate the safety and effectiveness of biopsy forceps combined&#xD;
      with puncture biopsy for the diagnosis of peripheral pulmonary nodules under the guidance of&#xD;
      Augmented Reality Navigation System combined with radial endobronchial ultrasound (r-EBUS),&#xD;
      and to explore the factors influencing the diagnosis rate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will last for no longer than 12 months. Patients will be first screened, and only&#xD;
      after meeting all the inclusion criteria, not meeting any exclusion criteria, and signing the&#xD;
      informed consent, could they be enrolled in the group to receive forceps biopsy combined with&#xD;
      puncture biopsy to sample the target nodules. The primary endpoint is the combined diagnostic&#xD;
      yield of forceps biopsy and puncture biopsy. The secondary endpoints include the success rate&#xD;
      of biopsy, the operation time of the bronchoscope and so on.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 20, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Combined Diagnostic yield</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnostic yield is defined as the proportion of nodules diagnosed by combined technologies in all nodulesundergoing bronchoscopy biopsy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnostic yield</measure>
    <time_frame>Six months</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnostic yield is defined as the proportion of nodulesdiagnosed by forceps biopsy (or puncture biopsy) in all nodulesundergoing bronchoscopy biopsy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The success rate of biopsy</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after bronchoscopy biopsy</time_frame>
    <description>The success rate of biopsy is defined as the number of nodules with at least one qualified abnormal lung tissue that can be used for pathological diagnosis divided by the number of all nodules diagnosed by combined technologies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Operation time of the bronchoscopy</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after bronchoscopy biopsy</time_frame>
    <description>The operation time of the bronchoscopy is defined as the total time from insertion of the bronchoscope to withdrawal of the bronchoscope.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung; Nodes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>The subjects would receive forceps biopsy combined with puncture biopsy under the guidance of Augmented Reality Navigation and Radial EBUS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Forceps biopsy combined with puncture biopsy under the guidance of Augmented Reality Navigation and Radial EBUS</intervention_name>
    <description>During the operation, under the guidance of Augmented Reality Navigation, the bronchoscope will reach the location of the target pulmonary nodules, and the EBUS probe will be inserted through the bronchoscope working channel, and gradually approach the target nodules to obtain EBUS images. After typical EBUS images are observed and the location is confirmed, the EBUS probe will be withdrawn and biopsy forceps and puncture biopsy needle will be used to obtain samples at the target locations respectively.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who meet all inclusion criteria and do not meet any exclusion criteria will be&#xD;
        enrolled in the study consecutively.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Age ≥ 18 years old; 2. Chest CT shows that the peripheral lung noduleswith&#xD;
             uncertain diagnosis are adjacent or far from the airway, and/or are difficult to&#xD;
             obtain samples by routine biopsy as assessed by investigators; 3. Understand the&#xD;
             research and sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Contraindications for bronchoscopy; 2. Severe cardiopulmonary dysfunction and other&#xD;
             diseases that may significantly increase the risk of surgery; 3. Bronchoscopy shows&#xD;
             visible intra-airway nodules above the 3rd bronchus; 4. The investigator believes that&#xD;
             the patient has other conditions that are not suitable for inclusion in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shiyue Li, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <phone>8620-83062896</phone>
    <email>lishiyue@188.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Changhao Zhong, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <phone>86-13570290214</phone>
    <email>vast1982@126.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Guangzhou Institute of Respiratory Disease, The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guangzhou</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <zip>510120</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Guangzhou Institute of Respiratory Disease</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>ShiYue Li</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Peripheral pulmonary nodules</keyword>
  <keyword>biopsy</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

