<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04696796</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-9.1/45</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04696796</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Episiotomy Scissors and BasIQ-4 Episiotomy Device in Mediolateral Episiotomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of Episiotomy Scissors and BasIQ-4 Episiotomy Device in Mediolateral Episiotomy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ege University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ege University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Episiotomy is an obstetric intervention performed to facilitate, accelerate and / or prevent&#xD;
      third and fourth degree perineal tears by cutting the vagina at the end of the second stage&#xD;
      of labor. Postpartum perineal pain affects patients' lives significantly and causes negative&#xD;
      effects on work life, social life and family relations. Median episiotomy is associated with&#xD;
      3-4 times increased anal sphincter injury as well as easy recovery. Therefore, mediolateral&#xD;
      episiotomy is preferred in Europe. The common feature was that scissors are used in previous&#xD;
      studies and the incision was made from the central to the distal. A randomized controlled&#xD;
      clinical study is planned to compare the scissors and episiotomy device BasIQ-4, which&#xD;
      carries scalpel, holding apparatus, and cuts from distal to the center in mediolateral&#xD;
      episiotomy. This is the first study in humans in this field.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pregnant women who applied to Ege University Gynecology and Obstetrics Department Delivery&#xD;
      Room Service and had vaginal delivery will be included in the study after obtaining their&#xD;
      consent. When the cases meeting the inclusion criteria will be taken to the delivery table&#xD;
      for delivery, verbal consent will be obtained by the physician if the need for episiotomy is&#xD;
      determined by the physician in the second stage of delivery. Following the administration of&#xD;
      10 ml of 1% lidocaine, mediolateral episiotomy will be opened with scissors or Basiq-4&#xD;
      according to computer generated randomization. The presence of shoulder dystocia during&#xD;
      delivery, the number of moves for episiotomy incision, the duration of stage 2, fetal weight,&#xD;
      the degree of perineal injury, any additional injury, and urethral injury will be recorded in&#xD;
      the prepared case form. Then, the episiotomy incision will be continuously sutured with 2-0&#xD;
      slow dissolving polyglactin 910 suture material for all cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The length of episiotomy after suturing and the length of perineal injury, if any, will be&#xD;
      measured with a sterile ruler and recorded on the case form. Postpartum discharge is carried&#xD;
      out 48 hours after birth in accordance with the Ministry of Health Regulations. Participants&#xD;
      will be reassessed during discharge in terms of pain with the Visual Pain Scale (VAS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The cases will be evaluated by the study team again, and notes regarding episiotomy length,&#xD;
      infection, pain, incision separation, fecal incontinence, rectovaginal fistula, and painful&#xD;
      defecation will be recorded on the case form six months after delivery. Participants will be&#xD;
      requested to fill FSFI forms to evaluate their sexual lives.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Assessed by VAS at 48 Hours After Birth</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will be reassessed during discharge in terms of pain with the Visual Pain Scale (VAS). The participants will asked to rate current pain on a 10-cm visual analog scale (VAS), with 0 being no pain and 10 the worst pain imaginable 48 hours after operation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FSFI Score</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will be requested to fill FSFI (Female Sexual Function Index) forms to evaluate their sexual lives six months after birth. The FSFI consists of 19 questions and is a validated questionnaire for the assessment of sexual function. The questions are grouped into the domains of libido, arousal, lubrication, orgasm, satisfaction, and pain. Higher scores reflect better sexual function (maximum score 36), including pain, in which 0 reflects lots of pain and 5 reflects the absence of pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Episiotomy Wound</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BasIQ-4 Surgical Knife</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following the administration of 10 ml of 1% lidocaine, mediolateral episiotomy will be preformed with BasIQ-4 Surgical Knife according to computer generated randomization.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Episiotomy Scissors</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following the administration of 10 ml of 1% lidocaine, mediolateral episiotomy will be preformed with episiotomy scissors according to computer generated randomization.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mediolateral Episiotomy with BasIQ-4 Surgical Knife</intervention_name>
    <description>Mediolateral episiotomy will be performed with BasIQ-4 Surgical Knife which cuts from distal to the center with inner knife.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BasIQ-4 Surgical Knife</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mediolateral Episiotomy with Episiotomy Scissors</intervention_name>
    <description>Mediolateral episiotomy will be made from the central to the distal with episiotomy scissors</description>
    <arm_group_label>Episiotomy Scissors</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Nulliparous singleton pregnancies &gt; 37th gestational week&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Estimated fetal weight between 3000-4000g&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The need for an episiotomy in the second stage of labor&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Vertex presentation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Additional internal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Inability to communicate in Turkish and English&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Multiple pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Episiotomies in emergency situations without crowning the baby's head&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Using vacuum device at birth&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Pregnant women</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ege University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sabahattin Anıl Arı</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

