<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04691648</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2215-PV-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04691648</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Assess the Safety of Xospata in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) With FMS-Like Tyrosine Kinase 3 (FLT3) Mutation</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Observational Study to Assess the Safety of Xospata® 40 mg Tablet When Administered in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML) With FMS-Like Tyrosine Kinase 3 (FLT3) Mutation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Astellas Pharma Korea, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Astellas Pharma Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to describe the observed safety profile of Xospata® 40 mg&#xD;
      tablet when administered in patients with relapsed or refractory AML with FLT3 mutation in&#xD;
      routine clinical practice in Korea.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is being mandated by Ministry of Food and Drug Safety (MFDS) as a part of the&#xD;
      Korea-Risk Management Plan (K-RMP) to assess safety in patients with relapsed or refractory&#xD;
      AML with FLT3 mutation in routine clinical practice in Korea. This study collects data for 24&#xD;
      months according to the purpose of this study in routine clinical practice as an&#xD;
      observational study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with Adverse Drug Reactions (ADRs) related to important identified and/or potential risks</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a maximum of 25 months (until 30 days after the last dose)</time_frame>
    <description>An Adverse Drug Reaction refers to any unfavorable and unintended reaction occurring with a normal administration or use of the medicinal product that a causal relationship to the medicinal product cannot be ruled out. Number of ADRs related to important identified risks such as posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome (PRES), QT prolongation, differentiation syndrome, and/or important potential risks such as pancreatitis, embryo-fetal lethality, suppressed fetal growth and teratogenicity, will be recorded.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with serious ADRs related to important identified and/or potential risks</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a maximum of 25 months (until 30 days after the last dose)</time_frame>
    <description>An ADR refers to any unfavorable and unintended reaction occurring with a normal administration or use of the medicinal product that a causal relationship to the medicinal product cannot be ruled out. Number of ADRs related to important identified risks such as posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome (PRES), QT prolongation, differentiation syndrome, and/or important potential risks such as pancreatitis, embryo-fetal lethality, suppressed fetal growth and teratogenicity, will be recorded. An ADR is considered &quot;serious&quot; if, in the view of either the investigator or sponsor, it results in any of the following outcomes: results in death, is life-threatening, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity or substantial disruption of the ability to conduct normal life functions, results in congenital anomaly or birth defect, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, or other medically important event.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with ADRs related to identified risks and considered not important</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a maximum of 25 months (until 30 days after the last dose)</time_frame>
    <description>An ADR refers to any unfavorable and unintended reaction occurring with a normal administration or use of the medicinal product that a causal relationship to the medicinal product cannot be ruled out. Number of ADRs related to identified risks but considered not important, such as other ADRs described by the Korean package insert, will be recorded. An ADR is considered &quot;serious&quot; if, in the view of either the investigator or Sponsor, it results in any of the following outcomes: results in death, is life-threatening, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity or substantial disruption of the ability to conduct normal life functions, results in congenital anomaly or birth defect, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, or other medically important event.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a maximum of 25 months (until 30 days after the last dose)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a subject administered a study drug, and which does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. An AE is considered &quot;serious&quot; if, in the view of either the investigator or Sponsor, it results in any of the following outcomes: results in death, is life-threatening, results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity or substantial disruption of the ability to conduct normal life functions, results in congenital anomaly or birth defect, requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of hospitalization, or other medically important event. Causal relationship between the study drug is judged by medically qualified investigator either as certain, probable/likely, possible, unlikely, conditional/unclassified or unassessable/unclassifiable.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Myeloid Leukemia With FMS-like Tyrosine Kinase (FLT3) Mutation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Xospata</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who receive Xospata® 40 mg tablet in routine clinical practice according to the drug label approved at the time of marketing authorization.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gilteritinib Exposure</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral</description>
    <arm_group_label>Xospata</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Xospata</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients receiving Xospata® 40 mg tablet according to the drug label for 2 years from the&#xD;
        start date of marketing in Korea.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who receive Xospata® 40 mg tablet according to the drug label approved at the&#xD;
             time of marketing authorization in routine clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who voluntarily signed the written informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who meet the section 'Do not administer to the following patients' in the&#xD;
             precautions for use given at the time of marketing authorization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who use the drug for an off-label purpose.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Astellas Pharma Korea, Inc.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Astellas Pharma Korea, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Astellas Pharma Korea, Inc.</last_name>
    <phone>+82 (0)10-5254-3389</phone>
    <email>Astellas.registration@astellas.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Gilteritinib</keyword>
  <keyword>Xospata</keyword>
  <keyword>Relapsed or refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Access to anonymized individual participant level data will not be provided for this trial as it meets one or more of the exceptions described on www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com under &quot;Sponsor Specific Details for Astellas.&quot;</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

