<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00879840</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999909121</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>09-C-N121</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00879840</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of Screening Modalities for Gynecologic Cancers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of Screening Modalities for Gynecologic Cancers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Endometrial and ovarian cancers are, respectively, the fourth and eighth most common&#xD;
           cancers among women in the United States. Although some routine Pap tests may detect the&#xD;
           presence of cancer cells, there are no convincing early detection approaches for either&#xD;
           cancer. Better methods of detection are needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Two possible methods for cancer detection involve samples taken with a tampon or a&#xD;
           special kind of brush, called a Tao brush. Researchers would like to know more about how&#xD;
           well these methods work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the quality of DNA collected by the tampon and Tao brush sampling methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To detect genetic markers in collected DNA and determine if these markers are related to&#xD;
           an individual s cancer status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Women age 45 years and older with confirmed or suspected endometrial or ovarian cancer,&#xD;
           who will be having surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A control group of postmenopausal women having surgery for benign gynecological&#xD;
           conditions will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Shortly before hysterectomy or more extensive procedures to treat either cancer or the&#xD;
           benign condition:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A tampon will be inserted into the vagina to collect cell samples, and removed after 30&#xD;
           minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the tampon is removed, the cervix will be swabbed with the Tao brush to collect&#xD;
           cell samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Following the hysterectomy, samples of healthy and cancerous tissue will be taken, and&#xD;
           tested by researchers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, there are no convincing early detection approaches for endometrial and ovarian&#xD;
      cancers. Although it is well established that some endometrial and ovarian tumors shed&#xD;
      cytologically recognizable cells in routinely prepared Pap tests, it is clear that this&#xD;
      approach rarely detects occult tumors. Accordingly, efforts to develop means of collecting&#xD;
      biological samples that have high patient acceptability, good sensitivity for detecting early&#xD;
      disease, and excellent specificity are needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this project, we want to assess the feasibility of using alternative sampling techniques&#xD;
      in combination with molecular assays to detect endometrial and ovarian cancers. We will&#xD;
      compare sampling using a Tampon and a sheathed endometrial brush, the Tao brush. We want to&#xD;
      assess the quality of DNA extracted from the different samplers. We will assess the&#xD;
      correlations between methylation of somatic DNA for a selected marker panel and cancer&#xD;
      status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We wish to include 117 women age 45 years and older with suspected endometrial cancer, or&#xD;
      ovarian cancer, and 53 age-matched (plus/minus 5 years) controls without malignancy, all of&#xD;
      whom are referred to surgery at the Mayo clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We plan to conduct a pilot study of women with confirmed or suspected endometrial cancer, or&#xD;
      ovarian cancer, and women treated for benign conditions. DNA will be extracted from samples&#xD;
      collected using a vaginal Tampon and an endometrial brushing using an FDA approved device&#xD;
      (Tao brush) prior to surgery. A panel of methylation markers will be analyzed from samples&#xD;
      yielding sufficient DNA. The results of the methylation analysis will be compared to the&#xD;
      final histology for all patients in the study. We will set the detection of methylation at&#xD;
      one or more loci in 50% of women in each arm as a technical success.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 9, 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 16, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Endometrial Cancer, ovarian cancer</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Histologically confirmed endometrial or ovarian cancer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">118</enrollment>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Controls Without Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Controls Without Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Females</arm_group_label>
    <description>With endometrial cancer, ovarian cancer, and women undergoing hysterectomy for benign reasons.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women with endometrial cancer, ovarian cancer, and women undergoing hysterectomy for benign&#xD;
        reasons.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study will enroll a total of 170 women consented for hysterectomy. One hundred and&#xD;
             seventeen (117) will either have 1) suspected ovarian cancer based on clinical&#xD;
             impression, cytologic or histologic diagnoses (effusions, Pap tests or other&#xD;
             biopsies), or 2) suspected endometrial cancer based on biopsy diagnoses of atypical&#xD;
             endometrial hyperplasia (or its equivalent endometrial intraepithelial neoplasia),&#xD;
             endometrial intraepithelial carcinoma (i.e. in-situ/ early serous carcinoma) or&#xD;
             carcinoma. Fifty-three (53) will be undergoing definitive treatment for benign&#xD;
             conditions (uterine fibroids, benign appearing adnexal pathology and normal CA 125,&#xD;
             pelvic floor dysfunction not to exceed grade 1 or 2 uterine descensus). Since the&#xD;
             analyzed cancers do not occur in children, they will not be included in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgical candidates for recurrent disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preoperative neoadjuvant chemotherapy or radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of tubal ligation, salpingitis, or hysterectomy (ovarian cancer patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Control patients who are less than 45 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving treatment for active endometriosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cervical stenosis recognized clinically by not accepting the Tao Brush&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Endometrial sampling within 5 days of anticipated surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior history of endometrial ablation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cervical cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicolas Wentzensen, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic, Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ries LA. Ovarian cancer. Survival and treatment differences by age. Cancer. 1993 Jan 15;71(2 Suppl):524-9.</citation>
    <PMID>8420672</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buys SS, Partridge E, Greene MH, Prorok PC, Reding D, Riley TL, Hartge P, Fagerstrom RM, Ragard LR, Chia D, Izmirlian G, Fouad M, Johnson CC, Gohagan JK; PLCO Project Team. Ovarian cancer screening in the Prostate, Lung, Colorectal and Ovarian (PLCO) cancer screening trial: findings from the initial screen of a randomized trial. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005 Nov;193(5):1630-9. Erratum in: Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2005 Dec;193(6):2183-4.</citation>
    <PMID>16260202</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vine MF, Ness RB, Calingaert B, Schildkraut JM, Berchuck A. Types and duration of symptoms prior to diagnosis of invasive or borderline ovarian tumor. Gynecol Oncol. 2001 Dec;83(3):466-71.</citation>
    <PMID>11733956</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 10, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 10, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 13, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Screening</keyword>
  <keyword>Modalities</keyword>
  <keyword>Gynecological Cancers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Ovarian Epithelial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

