<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04971005</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>inims-009</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04971005</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ocrelizumab or Alemtuzumab Compared With Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation in Multiple Sclerosis - a Phase-2 Randomised Controlled Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>COAST</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomised Controlled Trial to Compare Ocrelizumab or Alemtuzumab With Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation (aHSCT) in High Inflammatory Multiple Sclerosis (COAST)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Neovii Biotech</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Clinical Trial Center North (CTC North GmbH &amp; Co. KG)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A multicentre controlled phase II trial to compare the efficacy and safety of ocrelizumab or&#xD;
      alemtuzumab and autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation (aHSCT). Active&#xD;
      relapsing-remitting MS-Patients will be included and randomised to ocrelizumab or alemtuzumab&#xD;
      versus aHSCT. Primary endpoint will be the time to treatment failure as assessed by failure&#xD;
      of NEDA (no evidence of disease activity) as represented by: no expanded disability status&#xD;
      scale (EDSS) progression, no relapse, no new T2 lesion and no Gd-enhancing lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial offers the opportunity to gain further information about efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      all treatments and will give new insights into the immunology of highly active RRMS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A rater-blinded multicentre randomised controlled phase II trial to compare the efficacy and&#xD;
      safety of ocrelizumab or alemtuzumab and aHSCT. Active RRMS-Patients will be included and&#xD;
      randomised to ocrelizumab or alemtuzumab versus aHSCT. Primary endpoint will be the time to&#xD;
      treatment failure as assessed by failure of NEDA (no evidence of disease activity) as&#xD;
      represented by: no expanded disability status scale (EDSS) progression, no relapse, no new T2&#xD;
      lesion and no Gd-enhancing lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      aHSCT appears highly efficacious in reducing inflammatory disease activity and relapses in&#xD;
      active relapsing-remitting MS. Cohort data show a long-term stagnation of inflammatory&#xD;
      disease activity for up to 10 years and more after aHSCT. However, efficacy data from&#xD;
      randomised controlled trials comparing aHSCT with approved treatments are still lacking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The best available data concerning disease activity in MS patients with a documented&#xD;
      treatment failure are from the CARE-MS II trial. The rate of patients without clinical or&#xD;
      radiological disease activity after 2 years was 32% with alemtuzumab. aHSCT trial data on&#xD;
      absence of disease activity show NEDA rates between 70 and 90% after 2 years. Here we assume&#xD;
      40% and 80% after 2 years for the ocrelizumab/alemtuzumab and aHSCT groups, respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all three treatments, a potential long-term benefit has to be balanced with potentially&#xD;
      harmful treatment related risks. A randomised controlled trial offers the opportunity to gain&#xD;
      further information about efficacy and safety of all treatments and will give new insights&#xD;
      into the immunology of high active RRMS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will be randomised to control (ocrelizumab or alemtuzumab) or intervention (aHSCT).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to treatment failure as assessed by failure of NEDA (no evidence of disease activity)</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time to treatment failure as assessed by failure of NEDA (no evidence of disease activity) during follow-up as defined by:&#xD;
3 months confirmed EDSS (Expanded disability status scale) progression&#xD;
confirmed relapse&#xD;
new/enlarging T2-hyperintense lesion on MRI (Magnetic resonance imaging)&#xD;
any Gd-enhancing lesion on MRI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by EDSS</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>EDSS change and EDSS improvement will be considered. EDSS improvement defined as confirmed improvement after 3 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by the annualized relapse rate</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>calculated as number of relapses per year</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by the number of new T2 lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>calculated as cumulative number of new T2 lesions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by the number of Gd-enhancing lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>calculated as cumulative number of GD-enhancing lesions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by multiple sclerosis functional composite (MSFC) change</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>based on summed up Z-scores for individual measures (SDMT, 9 HPT, 25 FWT)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by Hamburg quality of life scale in MS (HAQUAMS)</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>based on HAQUAMS sum score ratings (values between 1 and 5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by the Percentage Brain Volume Change (PBVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Brain tissue volume (grey matter, white matter) will be evaluated on T1 weighted images to compute absolute percentage brain volume change</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy of treatment defined by grey and white matter atrophy</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>based on grey and white matter volume change evaluated on T1 weighted images</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of AE / SAE including NCI grade 3 and 4 non-haematological toxicities</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, on average at least 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Safety of treatment defined by the rate of AE / SAE including NCI grade 3 and 4 non-haematological toxicities</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Relapsing-Remitting Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention (aHSCT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation. Mobilisation will be performed with 2 g/m2 cyclophosphamide and 10 μg/kg G-CSF from day 5 until apheresis is completed. Conditioning will be 200 mg/kg cyclo-phosphamide and Anti-T-lymphocyteglobuline (Grafalon®, Neovii) with cu-mulative doses of 20 mg/kg given on day +1 (10 mg/kg) and day +2 (10 mg/kg).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the control arm patient and physician will decide which treatment to choose. Patients will be either treated with ocrelizumab according to the SmPC (600 mg every 6 months continuously) or with alemtuzumab according to the SmPC (12 mg/day for 5 consecutive days and again after 365 days for 3 days).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation</intervention_name>
    <description>Autologous Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention (aHSCT)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ocrelizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>600 mg every 6 months continuously</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alemtuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>12 mg/day for 5 consecutive days and again after 365 days for 3 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria (Based on CARE-MS-II3, guidelines and Rio-criteria for treatment&#xD;
        failure):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent and agreement to comply to study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 18-55 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  EDSS: 0.0 - 6.0&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RRMS according to McDonald 2010&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &lt; 10 years of disease course after symptom onset&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active disease with one of the following treatment failures occur-ring not earlier&#xD;
             than 6 months after initiation of an approved DMT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2 or more relapses within the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1 relapse within the last 12 months and a Gd-enhancing lesion on MRI &gt; 3 mm &gt; 3 months&#xD;
             before or after relapse onset or 2 new T2-lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On-going signs of MRI activity in the last 6 months (either Gd-en-hancing of ≥ 3 mm&#xD;
             lesion at any exam in the last year; or more than 5 new T2 lesions (≥ 3 mm)&#xD;
&#xD;
        or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients stable under natalizumab but who have to stop treatment due to an increasing&#xD;
             PML risk are defined as active, if a MRI within 6 months after termination of&#xD;
             natalizumab shows new T2 or Gd-enhancing lesions and at least one other treatment&#xD;
             fail-ure prior to natalizumab is documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Secondary or primary progressive MS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, or other medical condition incompatible with aHSCT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any treatment or medical condition that, according to the haematologist / transplant&#xD;
             specialist precludes the use of aHSCT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  John Cunningham virus (JCV) antibody index of &gt; 1.5 in previ-ously natalizumab-treated&#xD;
             patients, if a negative CSF JCV-PCR prior to screening is not available&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Relapse during 30 days before initiation of treatment. If a relapse occurs during this&#xD;
             period and eligibility criteria are otherwise ful-filled, start of treatment will be&#xD;
             delayed until at least 30 days after receiving steroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent clinically significant (as determined by the investiga-tors and&#xD;
             haematologist / transplant specialist) cardiac, immuno-logical, pulmonary,&#xD;
             neurological, renal or other major disease such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prominent cardial disease (Left ventricular ejection frac-tion (LVEF) &lt; 40%,&#xD;
                  myocardial infarction or ischemia, un-controlled arrhythmias, pericardial&#xD;
                  effusion &gt; 1 cm)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cerebrovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal disease (creatinine clearance &lt; 30 ml/min/m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Respiratory disease (DLCO &lt; 40% predicted)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active bleeding or clotting disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or posi-tive HIV antibody testing&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any uncontrolled acute or chronic infection, including HIV, hepatitis B surface&#xD;
                  antigen positivity and hepatitis C PCR positivity&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cancer except in situ cervix or cutaneous&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness or inability to comply with the requirements of this protocol including&#xD;
             the presence of any condition (physical, men-tal, or social) that is likely to affect&#xD;
             the patient returning for follow-up visits on schedule. Unwillingness to use&#xD;
             contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous participation in this study, previous treatment with aHSCT or already both&#xD;
             comparators&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing immunotherapy. Treatment with interferon or glati-rameracetate will need no&#xD;
             wash-out. Treatment pause before oc-relizumab/alemtuzumab or aHSCT will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  for dimethylfumarate and fingolimod: 8 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  for natalizumab: 8 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  for ocrelizumab: 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  for alemtuzumab: 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  for teriflunomide: 4 weeks after elimination with cholesty-ramine&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  for cladribine: 24 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cognitive impairments who are unable to provide written, informed&#xD;
             consent prior to any testing under this protocol, including screening and baseline&#xD;
             investigations that are not con-sidered part of routine patient care.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicolaus Kröger, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Medical Center Hamburg-Eppendorf, Department of Stem Cell Transplantation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nicolaus Kröger, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+49 (0) 40 7410 55864</phone>
    <email>n.kroeger@uke.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Christoph Heesen, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+49 (0) 40 7410 53776</phone>
    <email>heesen@uke.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20246</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicolaus Kröger, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+4940741055864</phone>
      <email>n.kroeger@uke.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Christoph Heesen, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+4940741053776</phone>
      <email>heesen@uke.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicolaus Kröger, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christoph Heesen, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Mannheim</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mannheim</city>
        <zip>68167</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stefan Klein, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <email>Stefan.Klein@umm.de</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lucas Schirmer, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <email>lucas.schirmer@umm.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stefan Klein, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lucas Schirmer, PD Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>autologous hematopoetic stem cell transplantation</keyword>
  <keyword>alemtzumab</keyword>
  <keyword>ocrelizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>randomised controlled trial</keyword>
  <keyword>aggressive highly active multiple sclerosis</keyword>
  <keyword>no evidence of diseae activity (NEDA)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis, Relapsing-Remitting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ocrelizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

