<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04971967</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-0496</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R34MH119963</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04971967</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enhancing Partner Services Among Men Who Have Sex With Men Living With HIV</brief_title>
  <official_title>Enhancing Partner Services Among Men Who Have Sex With Men Living With HIV: A Pilot Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Individuals will participate in a pilot randomized controlled trial (RCT) that implements and&#xD;
      evaluates the feasibility, acceptability, and effectiveness of crowdsourced partner services&#xD;
      (PS) or conventional PS among Chinese men who have sex with men (MSM) living with HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pilot RCT will include 120 newly identified MSM HIV cases who were born biologically&#xD;
      male, aged 18 years old or older, newly identified as HIV positive, had oral or anal sex with&#xD;
      a man, had at least one sexual partner in the previous 6 months and live in Guangzhou.&#xD;
      Participants will undergo a series of computer-based interviews (baseline and 2 months after&#xD;
      enrollment) and will be randomly assigned into two groups in 2:1 ratio (intervention:&#xD;
      control) and receive crowdsourced PS and conventional PS, respectively.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a pilot RCT, and the primary outcomes of this study are: 1) to test the feasibility&#xD;
      and acceptability of the crowdsourced intervention, and 2) to pilot the preliminary impact of&#xD;
      crowdsourced PS intervention in promoting HIV testing among partners of the newly identified&#xD;
      HIV cases. In addition, this pilot RCT aimed to collect preliminary data for the designing of&#xD;
      a full RCT, which aimed to measure the efficacy of the crowdsourced PS intervention in&#xD;
      promoting PS. Thus, the sample size of this study is not designed and will be not powered&#xD;
      enough to test the difference between the two arms. However, with a sample size of 120 (80&#xD;
      for intervention arm and 40 for the control arm, respectively), this pilot study would be&#xD;
      able to observe the differences between the two arms and collect preliminary data for&#xD;
      adequate sample size calculation of a full RCT. With a sample size of 120 (ratio of 2:1),&#xD;
      alpha=0.05, power=0.80, and the partner return rate in the conventional PS arm is 30% (around&#xD;
      31% in 2016 in Guangzhou), the minimal detectable effect size would be 26.7% for this pilot&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analyses: For the primary outcomes of feasibility and acceptability of the intervention:&#xD;
      this will be analyzed through descriptive analysis to assess the feedback on the feasibility&#xD;
      and acceptability of the crowdsourced PS intervention at baseline and the follow-up survey.&#xD;
      For the primary outcome of the proportion of partners returning for HIV testing within 2&#xD;
      months of the index participant's enrolment in the study, log-binomial regression&#xD;
      (generalized linear model with binomial distribution and log link) will be used to calculate&#xD;
      95% confidence intervals for the proportion of notifiable partners visiting by arm. Risk&#xD;
      differences and risk ratios will also be calculated in these models. As this study is a pilot&#xD;
      RCT, adjustment for covariates is not necessary and will not be conducted in the primary&#xD;
      analysis. In secondary analyses, pre-specified potential confounding variables will be&#xD;
      adjusted that might bias the estimate if not accounted for (e.g. index age, index marital&#xD;
      status). If a partner reports more than one index referred him, he will be counted as a&#xD;
      returning partner for each identified index.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subgroup analyses will be performed by partner sex, partner type (e.g. main male partner vs.&#xD;
      casual male partner) and sexual orientation. Time to presentation will also be assessed among&#xD;
      all notifiable partners using Cox proportional hazards with a robust variance estimator. In&#xD;
      the time-to-event analyses, censoring will occur at the end of 2-months. Note that for the&#xD;
      primary outcome, the assumption is that any partner without an identifiable record at the&#xD;
      community center or in the centralized electronic medical record (EMR) did not present for&#xD;
      HIV testing. Therefore, this study assumes no missing outcome data. Sensitivity analyses will&#xD;
      be conducted using alternative definitions of presentation for testing, including using the&#xD;
      self-reported data from index cases and partners. For count variables expressed as the mean&#xD;
      number of partners, the investigators will use either Poisson regression or negative binomial&#xD;
      regression if overdispersion is identified.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>120 newly identified MSM HIV cases will be randomly assigned into two groups in 2:1 ratio (intervention: control) and receive crowdsourced PS and conventional PS, respectively.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of MSM index cases that respond to the follow-up survey at 2 months after enrollment</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Intervention feasibility, measured by the proportion of MSM index cases that respond to the follow-up survey at 2 months after enrollment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability degree of the intervention using an acceptability questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Intervention acceptability, measured by an acceptability questionnaire among index patients in the intervention group after given the intervention. The questionnaire asks index patients about their responses to statements regarding the acceptability of the crowdsourced intervention materials, and is rated on a 1~4 scale, where 1 means 'strongly disagree', 2 means 'somewhat disagree', 3 means 'somewhat agree' and 4 means 'strongly agree'.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of partners who perform HIV-testing within 2 months of the index patient's enrollment</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The preliminary impact of the intervention, measured by the proportion of partners who perform HIV-testing within 2 months of the index patient's enrollment. HIV testing is verified by the partners presenting to the study centers, or uploading testing results identifiable from the Centers for Disease Control (CDC) electronic medical record central database.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of partners who have positive HIV tests among all tested partners</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of partners tested as HIV positive among partners who perform HIV-testing in the last 2 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of presenting partners reporting receptive anal intercourse in the last 2 months</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of presenting partners reporting receptive anal intercourse in the last 2 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean number of sexual partners reported by presenting partners (other than the index) in the last two months</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The mean number of sexual partners reported by presenting partners (other than the index) in the last two months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of presenting partners that report condom use during the last anal intercourse</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of presenting partners reporting condom use by presenting partners during the last anal intercourse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Contact Tracing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the intervention group will receive crowdsourced partner services intervention, including postcards from the crowdsourcing contest that promote PS, provider referral and dual referral services, and take-home HIV self testing kits.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the control group will receive traditional partner services intervention, including referral cards that encourage the index patient to notify their partners by themselves.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Crowdsourced partner services intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention includes the provision of provider referral and dual referral services, crowdsourced materials such as postcards and an HTML aiming to promote PS, as well as free take-home HIV self-testing kits.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  born biologically male,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aged 18 years old or older,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  newly identified as HIV positive,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  had oral or anal sex with a man,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  had at least one sexual partner in the previous 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  live in Guangzhou&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not meet inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not given informed consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Weiming Tang, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Carolina Project-China</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Weiming Tang, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>+86-15920567132</phone>
    <email>weiming_tang@med.unc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Xumeng Yan, MA</last_name>
    <phone>+86-15330225941</phone>
    <email>xumeng_yan@seshglobal.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Guangzhou Center for Diseases Control and Prevention</name>
      <address>
        <city>Guangzhou</city>
        <state>Guangdong</state>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Xumeng Yan</last_name>
      <email>xumeng_yan@seshglobal.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yingshi Liu</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Partner notification services</keyword>
  <keyword>Crowdsourcing</keyword>
  <keyword>MSM</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Deidentified individual data that supports the results will be shared beginning 9 to 36 months following publication provided the investigator who proposes to use the data has approval from an Institutional Review Board (IRB), Independent Ethics Committee (IEC), or Research Ethics Board (REB), as applicable, and executes a data use/sharing agreement with University of North Carolina (UNC).</ipd_description>
    <ipd_time_frame>Deidentified individual data that supports the results will be shared beginning 9 to 36 months following publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The investigator who proposes to use the data needs to have approval from an IRB, IEC, or REB and an executed data use/sharing agreement with UNC.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

