<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04972435</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Naris001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04972435</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Multifocal Intraocular Lens on Contrast Sensitivity in Primary Angle-Closure Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Multifocal Intraocular Lens on Contrast Sensitivity in Primary Angle-Closure Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Siriraj Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Siriraj Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This prospective study included patients with primary angle-closure (PAC or primary&#xD;
      angle-closure glaucoma (PACG) and visually significant cataract. Phacoemulsification with&#xD;
      multifocal intraocular lens (MIOL) or monofocal IOL (mIOL) (patient preference) was&#xD;
      performed. Collected data included best-corrected distant visual acuity (BCVA), intraocular&#xD;
      pressure (IOP), anterior chamber depth (ACD), and contrast sensitivity (CS) measured at&#xD;
      spatial frequency 1.5, 3.0, 6.0, 12.0, and 18.0 cycles per degree (CPD) preoperatively, and&#xD;
      at 2-6 months postoperatively. Preoperative and postoperative parameters were compared to&#xD;
      evaluate the effect of MIOL on CS in eyes with PAC or PACG.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This prospective non-randomized clinical study was conducted at the Department of&#xD;
      Ophthalmology of the Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok,&#xD;
      Thailand during January 2014 to December 2015. The study protocol and informed consent&#xD;
      procedures were both approved by our center's institutional review board (IRB) (approval&#xD;
      number Si 384/2014). Each patient provided written informed consent prior to participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary angle closure was defined as an eye with invisible non-pigmented trabecular meshwork&#xD;
      greater than 180 degrees and evidence of peripheral anterior synechiae on gonioscopy without&#xD;
      glaucomatous optic disc appearance, glaucomatous pattern visual field damage, or history of&#xD;
      increased IOP. Primary angle closure glaucoma was defined as an eye with invisible&#xD;
      non-pigmented trabecular meshwork greater than 180 degrees on gonioscopy with glaucomatous&#xD;
      optic damage (cup-to-disc ratio greater than 0.5 and/or localized neuro-retinal rim defect)&#xD;
      and history of increased IOP raising. Patients with PACG must have been under good disease&#xD;
      control, which was defined as IOP under 20 mmHg with 1 to 3 topical anti-glaucoma medications&#xD;
      without deterioration of visual field, except generalized depression from cataract.&#xD;
      Intra-ocular lens calculation was performed at the baseline visit using IOL Master. All&#xD;
      patients received information about the advantages and disadvantages of MIOLs (Tecnis ZMB00&#xD;
      or Acrysof IQ Restore SN6AD1) and of mIOLs (Tecnis ZCB00 or Acrysof IQ SN60WF) before&#xD;
      choosing the type of IOL that they individually preferred. Cataract surgery was performed by&#xD;
      a single surgeon. Topical anesthesia was applied before standard phacoemulsification (2.2 mm&#xD;
      temporal clear cornea incision and continuous curvilinear capsulorhexis) and IOL implantation&#xD;
      into the capsular bag. Eyes with any intraoperative or postoperative complication were&#xD;
      excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data specific to uncorrected and best-corrected distant visual acuities (UCVA and BCVA) in&#xD;
      logMar, auto-refraction, slit-lamp ophthalmoscopic examination, intraocular pressure (IOP)&#xD;
      measurement with Goldmann applanation tonometry, contrast sensitivity (CS), anterior chamber&#xD;
      depth (ACD), central corneal thickness (CCT), and axial length (AL) were collected on the&#xD;
      preoperative screening day, and at the 2 to 6-month postoperative follow-up. CS was measured&#xD;
      under normal room light (photopic) conditions to evaluate patient quality of vision during&#xD;
      the performance of their daily activities using a Functional Vision Analyzer. This test&#xD;
      produces sine-wave gratings of different spatial frequencies. The absolute values of distance&#xD;
      CS were obtained at five spatial frequencies (1.5, 3, 6, 12, and 18 cycles per degree; CPD).&#xD;
      Visante® AS-OCT was used to determine CCT and ACD. ACD was defined as the distance between&#xD;
      the corneal endothelium and the anterior surface of the crystalline lens (preoperative) or&#xD;
      iris plane (postoperative). Axial length was obtained using IOL Master.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Comparisons of continuous data with normal distribution were made using Student's t-test for&#xD;
      unpaired data, and using Mann-Whitney U test for non-normally distributed data. A p-value of&#xD;
      less than 0.05 was defined as denoting statistical significance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Cataract patients with PAC or PACG who schedule for phacoemulsification with intraocular lens implantation. The patients must decide preoperatively to use multifocal IOL or monofocal IOL (patient preference) after receiving clear information about those 2 IOL models. Postoperatively, the contrast sensitivity (CS)will be measured with the same method. The postoperative CS were compared between groups.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Contrast sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Preoperative (on screening day)</time_frame>
    <description>Contrast sensitivity at partial frequency 1.5, 3.0, 6.0, 12.0, and 18.0 cycles per degree (CPD)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Contrast sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>At 2nd month postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Contrast sensitivity at partial frequency 1.5, 3.0, 6.0, 12.0, and 18.0 cycles per degree (CPD)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>Preoperative (on screening day)</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity at distance in LogMar</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>At 2nd month postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity at distance in LogMar</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anterior chamber depth</measure>
    <time_frame>Preoperative (on screening day)</time_frame>
    <description>Anterior chamber depth</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anterior chamber depth</measure>
    <time_frame>At 2nd month postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Anterior chamber depth</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Angle Closure Glaucoma</condition>
  <condition>Primary Angle Glaucoma Closure Suspect</condition>
  <condition>Senile Cataract</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multifocal intraocular lens group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cataract patients with PAC or PACG who underwent phacoemulsification with multifocal intraocular lens implantation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Monofocal intraocular lens group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cataract patients with PAC or PACG who underwent phacoemulsification with monofocal intraocular lens implantation which are the standard IOL.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Contrast sensitivity</intervention_name>
    <description>All subjects performed the contrast sensitivity measurement preoperatively and one time at 2 months postoperatively.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Monofocal intraocular lens group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Multifocal intraocular lens group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visually significant cataract patients aged &gt;18 years with PAC or PACG who underwent&#xD;
             prophylaxis peripheral iridotomy at least 2 months prior to participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with preexisting glaucomatous visual field defect, except generalized&#xD;
             depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other concurrent ocular diseases that could affect visual acuity, except cataract&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of ocular inflammation or ocular surgery, except laser peripheral iridotomy,&#xD;
             which is a routine procedure for treating PAC/PACG&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Naris Kitnarong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bangkoknoi</city>
        <state>Bangkok</state>
        <zip>10700</zip>
        <country>Thailand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Thailand</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Teichman JC, Ahmed II. Intraocular lens choices for patients with glaucoma. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2010 Mar;21(2):135-43. doi: 10.1097/ICU.0b013e3283365154. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20040877</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kim CY, Chung SH, Kim TI, Cho YJ, Yoon G, Seo KY. Comparison of higher-order aberration and contrast sensitivity in monofocal and multifocal intraocular lenses. Yonsei Med J. 2007 Aug 31;48(4):627-33.</citation>
    <PMID>17722234</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kumar BV, Phillips RP, Prasad S. Multifocal intraocular lenses in the setting of glaucoma. Curr Opin Ophthalmol. 2007 Feb;18(1):62-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17159450</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Montés-Micó R, Alió JL. Distance and near contrast sensitivity function after multifocal intraocular lens implantation. J Cataract Refract Surg. 2003 Apr;29(4):703-11.</citation>
    <PMID>12686237</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Siriraj Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Naris Kitnarong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>primary angle closure</keyword>
  <keyword>primary angle closure glaucoma</keyword>
  <keyword>cataract surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>contrast sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>intraocular lens</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glaucoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cataract</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glaucoma, Angle-Closure</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

