<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04977908</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>291543</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04977908</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Closing the Loop in Adults With Type 1 Diabetes (CLEAR)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Single-centre, Randomised, Two-period, Crossover Study to Assess the Efficacy, Safety and Utility of Closed-loop Glucose Control Compared to Standard Insulin Pump Therapy Combined With Continuous Glucose Monitoring in Adults With Type 1 Diabetes (CLEAR Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Cambridge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cambridge</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this study is to determine whether home use of fully closed-loop&#xD;
      glucose control applying ultra-rapid Lispro insulin is superior to standard insulin pump&#xD;
      therapy with continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) in adults with type 1 diabetes on insulin&#xD;
      pump therapy with sub-optimal glycaemic control (HbA1c ≥ 8.0%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an open-label, single centre, randomised, crossover design study, involving a run-in&#xD;
      period followed by two study periods during which glucose levels will be controlled either by&#xD;
      an automated closed-loop system using ultra-rapid Lispro insulin or by participants usual&#xD;
      insulin pump therapy with continuous glucose monitoring in random order. A total of up to 30&#xD;
      adults (aiming for 24 completed participants) with T1D on insulin pump therapy will be&#xD;
      recruited through diabetes clinics and other established methods. Participants who drop out&#xD;
      of the study within the first 4 weeks of the first intervention arm will be replaced.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will receive appropriate training in the safe use of the closed-loop devices.&#xD;
      Participants will have access to the study team during the home study phase with 24/7&#xD;
      telephone support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome is time spent in target range between 3.9 and 10.0 mmol/L as recorded by&#xD;
      CGM over the 8 week period. Secondary outcomes are HbA1c, time spent with glucose levels&#xD;
      above and below target as recorded by CGM, and other CGM-based metrics in addition to insulin&#xD;
      requirements. Safety evaluation comprises severe hypoglycaemic episodes, diabetic&#xD;
      ketoacidosis (DKA) events and other adverse and serious adverse events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of the clinical trial:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine whether home use of fully closed-loop applying ultra-rapid Lispro insulin is&#xD;
      superior to insulin pump therapy with continuous glucose monitoring (CGM).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study objective is to compare home use of fully closed-loop glucose control applying&#xD;
      ultra-rapid Lispro insulin with standard insulin pump therapy with CGM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. EFFICACY: The objective is to assess the efficacy of fully closed-loop glucose control&#xD;
           applying ultra-rapid Lispro insulin in maintaining CGM glucose levels within the target&#xD;
           range from 3.9 to 10.0 mmol/l, as compared to standard insulin pump therapy combined&#xD;
           with CGM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. SAFETY: The objective is to evaluate the safety of fully closed-loop glucose control in&#xD;
           terms of episodes of severe hypoglycaemia, hyperglycaemia and other adverse events and&#xD;
           adverse device effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. UTILITY: The objective is to determine the percentage of time when closed-loop was&#xD;
           operational, and usability and acceptance of the closed-loop system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participating clinical centres:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Addenbrooke's Hospital, Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust, Cambridge&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      24 adults completing the study. Up to 30 participants will be recruited to allow for&#xD;
      dropouts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maximum duration of study for a participant:&#xD;
&#xD;
      20 weeks (5 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment The participants will be recruited through the adult diabetes outpatient clinics&#xD;
      or other established methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline Assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible participants will undergo a baseline evaluation including a blood sample for the&#xD;
      measurement of HbA1c, renal, liver functions, full blood count, thyroid functions and coeliac&#xD;
      antibody screen (if not done in the previous 3 months). Urine pregnancy test will be done in&#xD;
      females of child bearing age. Human factor questionnaires will be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Run-in Period During the 2-3 week run-in period, participants will use their own insulin pump&#xD;
      and wear a masked CGM system. At the end of the run-in period, for compliance, at least 10&#xD;
      days of CGM data need to be recorded. CGM data during the run-in period will be used to&#xD;
      assess baseline glucose control before the start of the first home study phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible participants will be randomised using randomisation software to the use of&#xD;
      closed-loop glucose control or to standard pump therapy with CGM. There will be no washout&#xD;
      period between the two intervention periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Automated closed-loop:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Training on the use of closed-loop will be provided by the research team during a 2 to 3 hour&#xD;
      session in an outpatient setting (clinical research facility) or may be done remotely.&#xD;
      Competency on the use of study insulin pump, study CGM and closed-loop system will be&#xD;
      evaluated using a competency assessment tool developed by the research team. Further training&#xD;
      may be delivered as required. Participants will be advised to use the closed-loop system with&#xD;
      ultra-rapid Lispro insulin for next 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conventional insulin pump therapy with CGM:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will use their own insulin pump and study CGM. Training on the use of real-time&#xD;
      CGM and how to interpret real-time will be provided. Participants will use standard insulin&#xD;
      pump therapy, with their usual insulin, and real-time CGM for the next 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cross-over Assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the first intervention period, a blood sample for the measurement of HbA1c will&#xD;
      be taken and human factor questionnaires will be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End of study assessments:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A blood sample will be taken for measurement of HbA1c and human factor questionnaires will be&#xD;
      administered. Study devices will be returned and participants will resume usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures for safety monitoring during trial:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard operating procedures for monitoring and reporting of all adverse events and adverse&#xD;
      device events will be in place, including serious adverse events (SAE), serious adverse&#xD;
      device effects (SADE) and specific adverse events (AE) such as severe hypoglycaemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A data monitoring and ethics committee (DMEC) will be informed of all serious adverse events&#xD;
      and any unanticipated adverse device/method effects that occur during the study and will&#xD;
      review compiled adverse event data at periodic intervals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for withdrawal of patients on safety grounds:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A participant may terminate participation in the study at any time without necessarily giving&#xD;
      a reason and without any personal disadvantage. An investigator can stop the participation of&#xD;
      a subject after consideration of the benefit/risk ratio. Possible reasons are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Serious adverse events&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Significant protocol violation or non-compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Failure to satisfy competency assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Decision by the investigator, or the sponsor, that termination is in the participant's&#xD;
           best medical interest&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnancy, planned pregnancy, or breast feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Allergic reaction to insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Technical grounds (e.g. participant relocates)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>An open-label, single-centre, randomised, two-period, crossover study comparing closed-loop glucose control compared to standard insulin pump therapy combined with continuous glucose monitoring</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in target glucose range</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent in the target glucose range from 3.9 to 10.0 mmol/l (70 to 180mg/dl) based on continuous glucose monitoring (CGM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent above the target glucose range</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent above target glucose (10.0 mmol/l) (180 mg/dl) based on CGM</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent below the target glucose range</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent below target glucose (3.9mmol/l) (70mg/dl) based on CGM</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Average of sensor glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Standard deviation and coefficient of variation of glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Standard deviation and coefficient of variation of CGM glucose levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in hypoglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Time with glucose levels &lt; 3.5 mmol/l (63mg/dl), &lt; 3.0 mmol/l (54mg/dl), and &lt;2.8 mmol/l (50mg/dl) based on CGM</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in hyperglycaemia</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Time with glucose levels in the significant hyperglycaemia (glucose levels &gt; 20.0 mmol/l) (360mg/dl)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>after 8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Glycated haemoglobin measured at the end of the treatment period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total, basal, and bolus insulin dose</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Total, basal, and bolus insulin dose</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>The number of episodes of hypoglycaemia, DKA and / or significant ketonemia (&gt; 3.0mmol/l) as well as nature and severity of any other adverse events including SADEs and SAEs.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Utility evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency and duration of use of the closed-loop system at home</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Human Factor assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8-week home use</time_frame>
    <description>Expectations, attitudes and responses to the closed-loop system will be assessed using questionnaires.&#xD;
INSPIRE questionnaire PAID questionnaire Hypoglycaemia Confidence Scale</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fully closed-loop system with ultra-rapid Lispro insulin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The fully closed-loop system (CamAPS HX) will consist of:&#xD;
Dana insulin pump (Diabecare, Sooil, Seoul, South Korea)&#xD;
Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)&#xD;
An Android smartphone hosting CamAPS HX app with the Cambridge model predictive control algorithm&#xD;
Cloud upload system to review CGM/insulin data.&#xD;
Participants will use ultra-rapid Lispro insulin in the closed-loop system</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard insulin pump therapy with CGM</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will use their own insulin pump and usual insulin throughout this study period.&#xD;
The CGM will be the Dexcom G6 real-time CGM sensor (Dexcom, Northridge, CA, USA)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CamAPS HX</intervention_name>
    <description>Fully automated closed-loop system (CamAPS HX) with ultra-rapid Lispro insulin</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fully closed-loop system with ultra-rapid Lispro insulin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard insulin pump therapy with CGM</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants usual insulin pump therapy with Dexcom G6 CGM</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard insulin pump therapy with CGM</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant has type 1 diabetes as defined by WHO for at least 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant will have been on an insulin pump for at least 6 months with good&#xD;
             knowledge of insulin self-adjustment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is treated with one of the rapid acting or ultra-rapid acting insulin&#xD;
             analogues (Insulin Aspart, faster acting insulin Aspart, Insulin Lispro, ultra-rapid&#xD;
             Lispro insulin or Insulin Glulisine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c ≥8.0% (64 mmol/mol) based on analysis from local laboratory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is willing to wear closed-loop devices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is willing to follow study specific instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants of child bearing age should using effective contraception and must&#xD;
             have a negative urine-HCG pregnancy test at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any physical or psychological disease or condition likely to interfere with the normal&#xD;
             conduct of the study and interpretation of the study results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected allergy against insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total daily insulin dose &gt; 2 IU/kg/day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of a closed-loop system within the past 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is pregnant or breast feeding or planning pregnancy within next 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe visual impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe hearing impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of reliable telephone facility for contact&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant not proficient in English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Charlotte Boughton</last_name>
    <phone>+441223769066</phone>
    <email>cb2000@medschl.cam.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cambridge University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <zip>CB2 0QQ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Charlotte Boughton</last_name>
      <email>cb2000@medschl.cam.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Cambridge</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Roman Hovorka</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Metabolic Technology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Study protocol, statistical analysis plan and fully anonymised individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the manuscript will be available 6 months following publication and ending 36 months following manuscript publication to investigators whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, to achieve aims in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to rh347@cam.ac.uk and may be submitted up to 36 months following article publication. To gain access, data requestors will need to sign a data access agreement.&#xD;
Fully anonymised data may be shared with third parties (EU or non-EU based) for the purposes of advancing management and treatment of diabetes.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Study protocol, statistical analysis plan and fully anonymised individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the manuscript will be available 6 months following publication and ending 36 months following manuscript publication to investigators whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, to achieve aims in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to rh347@cam.ac.uk and may be submitted up to 36 months following article publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Study protocol, statistical analysis plan and fully anonymised individual participant data that underlie the results reported in the manuscript will be available 6 months following publication and ending 36 months following manuscript publication to investigators whose proposed use of the data has been approved by an independent review committee identified for this purpose, to achieve aims in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to rh347@cam.ac.uk and may be submitted up to 36 months following article publication.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

