<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04977505</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>M2021132</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04977505</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Absorption Rate and Bone Ingrowth of Absorbable Anchors Used in Shoulder Dislocation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Absorption Rate and Bone Ingrowth of Absorbable Anchors Used in Shoulder Dislocation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking University Third Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking University Third Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to analyze the absorption rate of Pushlock anchors and Gryphon anchors and&#xD;
      the bone ingrowth of the anchor channel by consulting the postoperative CT images of patients&#xD;
      with recurrent shoulder dislocation completed by myself. The investigators will analyze the&#xD;
      influence factors of anchor absorption and bone ingrowth, which will provide a reference for&#xD;
      improving anchor design and the improvement of surgical techniques.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &quot;Recurrent anterior dislocation of the shoulder joint is a common disease of the shoulder&#xD;
      joint. The standard treatment methods include soft tissue repair surgery and bone tissue&#xD;
      repair surgery. The former refers to arthroscopic labral suture (Bankart repair surgery), and&#xD;
      the latter includes Latarjet surgery, Bristow surgery and Cuistow surgery pioneered by our&#xD;
      team. Whether it is soft tissue repair surgery or bone tissue repair surgery, anchors are&#xD;
      required for suture fixation during the operation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The anchors currently in use include non-absorbable anchors and absorbable anchors.&#xD;
      Non-absorbable anchors include metal anchors and peek material anchors, which remain in the&#xD;
      body forever after the operation and cannot be absorbed. The absorbable anchors, in theory,&#xD;
      will be absorbed 2 years after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-absorbable anchors have inherent limitations that limit their use. If the non-absorbable&#xD;
      anchor loosens and shifts, it can cause severe cartilage damage. If complications such as&#xD;
      re-dislocation occurred, revision surgery is required. Revision surgery is complicated&#xD;
      because the non-absorbable anchor inserted in the initial surgery occupies the best anchor&#xD;
      position. Metal anchors can cause artifacts and affect postoperative MRI imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, absorbable anchors have gradually become routinely used in shoulder joint&#xD;
      dislocation surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The anchors currently used in our hospital for shoulder joint instability include Pushlock&#xD;
      anchors from Arthrex and Gryphon anchors from Depuy Mitek. The materials are PLLA/β-TCP and&#xD;
      PLGA/β-TCP. The absorption anchor starts to absorb in 1 year and completes absorption in&#xD;
      about two years. The anchor tunnel will be filled with bone tissue. However, the&#xD;
      investigators have found that the anchor cannot be wholly absorbed as scheduled. During the&#xD;
      revision surgery, the original absorbable anchor can still be seen. Clear anchor tunnels can&#xD;
      also be seen in CT films after 2 years postoperatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Published literature also show that the degradation rate of absorbable anchors is not the&#xD;
      same. The literature report that anchors have not completed degradation and bone ingrowth&#xD;
      within the time advertised by the manufacturers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, this study aims to analyze the absorption rate of Pushlock anchors and Gryphon&#xD;
      anchors and the bone ingrowth of the anchor tunnel by consulting the postoperative CT films&#xD;
      of subjects with recurrent shoulder dislocation completed by myself. The factors that affect&#xD;
      anchor absorption and bone ingrowth provide a reference for improving anchor design and the&#xD;
      improvement of surgical techniques.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 21, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>hounsfield unit of anchor tunnel</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>It is an index used to evaluate the status of bone resorption. It was recorded of last CT films.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the diameter of anchor tunnel</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>It is an index used to evaluate the status of bone resorption. It can be measured in the last CT films.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hounsfield unit of ossification site</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>It is an index used to evaluate the status of bone resorption. It was recorded of last CT films.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>unossified area of anchor tunnel</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>It is an index used to evaluate the status of bone resorption. It can be measured in the last CT films.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ossification quality score</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>It is a standard score used to qualify the status of ossification.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">114</enrollment>
  <condition>Shoulder Dislocation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pushlock</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with recurrent shoulder dislocation received surgery fixed by pushlock</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gryphon</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with recurrent shoulder dislocation received surgery fixed by Gryphon</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>pushlock</intervention_name>
    <description>The surgery procedure was performed with pushlock for fixation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pushlock</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>gryphon</intervention_name>
    <description>The surgery procedure was performed with Gryphon for fixation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Gryphon</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who underwent Cuistow surgery, Bristow surgery, Latarjet surgery or Bankart&#xD;
        surgery in Peking University Third Hospital for fixing the dislocated shoulder.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (1) The subject underwent Cuistow surgery, Bristow surgery, Latarjet surgery or&#xD;
             Bankart surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (2) The surgeon was chief physician Cui Guoqing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (3) Pushlock anchor (2.9mm) or Gryphon anchor (3.0mm) was used during the operation,&#xD;
             and the placement position was the glenoid.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (1) Ipsilateral shoulder joint, with a history of surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (2) Subjects with postoperative infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (3) Subjects with incomplete data (no immediate postoperative CT or no postoperative&#xD;
             CT films for more than 2 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (4)Subjects with diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (5)Revision surgery for shoulder dislocation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Guoqing Cui</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Peking University Third Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>PekingUTH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anterior dislocation</keyword>
  <keyword>anchor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Joint Dislocations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Dislocation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

