<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04979949</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Hibrid COV-Rapel TR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04979949</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Booster Vaccination Against SARS-CoV-2</brief_title>
  <official_title>Double-Blind, Randomized, Controlled, Multi-Center Phase 2 Clinical Trial to Determine Safety, Efficacy, and Immunogenicity of Booster Vaccination Against SARS-CoV-2</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Health Institutes of Turkey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Health Institutes of Turkey</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A booster dose of vaccine (Turkovac or CoronaVac) will be administered to subjects who have&#xD;
      passed at least 90 days and at most 270 days after the second dose of the first course of&#xD;
      CoronaVac vaccine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      To determine the safety and immunogenicity of booster doses of vaccine against SARS-CoV2&#xD;
      after a minimum of 90 days and a maximum of 270 days after the 2nd dose of a homologous 2&#xD;
      dose primary regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is planned to recruit 111 subjects for 2 vaccines (Turkovac or CoronaVac). There will be a&#xD;
      total of 222 subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 12, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-Blind, Randomized, Controlled, Multi-Center Phase 2 Clinical Trial to Determine Safety, Efficacy, and Immunogenicity of Booster Vaccination Against SARS-CoV-2 (Hybrid COV-Rapel TR)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-Blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of adverse reactions within 7 days of vaccination in all subjects</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Serious Adverse Events (SAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>168 days after vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of Serious Adverse Events (SAE) in all subjects 168 days after vaccination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neutralizing antibody and anti-spike protein immunoglobulin G</measure>
    <time_frame>On days 0, 28 and 84</time_frame>
    <description>Amount of SARS-CoV2 anti-spike protein immunoglobulin G and SARS-CoV2 neutralizing antibody amount</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">222</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Sars-CoV-2 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CoronaVac</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>600 Subunit of SARS-CoV-2 virus antigen, intramuscular injection. One dose vaccine will be administered to subjects who have passed at least 90 days and at most 270 days after the second dose of the first course of CoronaVac vaccine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Turkovac</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>600 Subunit of SARS-CoV-2 virus antigen, intramuscular injection. One dose vaccine will be administered to subjects who have passed at least 90 days and at most 270 days after the second dose of the first course of CoronaVac vaccine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CoronaVac</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses at 28-day interval, each inoculation dose is 0.5 mL. Two doses of dosage (vaccine contains 600 subunit of SARS-CoV-2 virus antigen) vaccine at the schedule of day 0, 28</description>
    <arm_group_label>CoronaVac</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Turkovac</intervention_name>
    <description>Two doses at 28-day interval, each inoculation dose is 0.5 mL. Two doses of dosage (vaccine contains 600 subunit of SARS-CoV-2 virus antigen) vaccine at the schedule of day 0, 28</description>
    <arm_group_label>Turkovac</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy male or female aged 18 - 60 years (including both groups)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who were vaccinated with CoronaVac for 2 doses and who had a minimum of 90&#xD;
             days and a maximum of 270 days after the second dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects may have a controlled or moderate comorbidity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential should be willing to ensure that they or&#xD;
             their partner use effective birth control methods continuously from 1 month before and&#xD;
             up to 3 months after vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects agreed to comply with all study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are willing to share their medical history with their physician and allow&#xD;
             access to all medical records when relevant to study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are willing to agree to abstain from donating blood during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects meeting any of the following criteria will be excluded from the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any vaccine (registered or investigational) other than study intervention&#xD;
             within 30 days before and after each study vaccine (one week for authorized seasonal&#xD;
             flu vaccine or pneumococcal vaccine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive for COVID-19 after primary vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-or planned use of another vaccine or product likely to affect the study (e.g.&#xD;
             adenovirus vectored vaccines, any coronavirus vaccine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who were pregnant at the time of enrollment or who plan to become pregnant&#xD;
             within the first 3 months following vaccination and who are breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with fever (above 38°C) at the time of vaccination and/or up to 72 hours&#xD;
             before&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood product within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficiency state; asplenia;&#xD;
             recurrent severe infections and use of immunosuppressants (less than ≤14 days) in the&#xD;
             last 6 months, excluding topical steroids or short-term oral steroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Possible history of allergic disease or reaction (eg to the active substance) by any&#xD;
             component of the study vaccines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of anaphylaxis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current cancer diagnosis or treatment (excluding basal cell carcinoma of the skin and&#xD;
             cervical carcinoma in situ)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bleeding disorder (e.g. factor deficiency, coagulopathy or platelet&#xD;
             disorder), or prior history of significant bleeding or bruising following&#xD;
             intramuscular injections or venipuncture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continued use of anticoagulants such as coumarins and related anticoagulants (ie&#xD;
             warfarin) or new oral anticoagulants (ie apixaban, rivaroxaban, dabigatran and&#xD;
             edoxaban)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cerebral venous sinus thrombosis, antiphospholipid syndrome, or a history of&#xD;
             heparin-induced thrombocytopenia and thrombosis (HITT or HIT type 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected or known current alcohol or drug addiction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other significant disease, disorder or finding that could significantly increase&#xD;
             the subject's risk for participation in the study, affect the subject's ability to&#xD;
             participate in the study, or impair the interpretation of study data; severe and/or&#xD;
             uncontrolled cardiovascular disease, respiratory disease, gastrointestinal disease,&#xD;
             liver disease, kidney disease, endocrine disorder, and neurological disease&#xD;
             (mild/moderate well-controlled comorbidities are permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of active or previous autoimmune neurological disorders (eg multiple&#xD;
             sclerosis, Guillain-Barre syndrome, transverse myelitis) (Bell's palsy will not be an&#xD;
             exclusion criterion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with severe renal impairment or liver failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who will undergo scheduled elective surgery during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a life expectancy of less than 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who participated in another clinical trial study involving an investigational&#xD;
             product in the past 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In case of clinical necessity, a COVID-19 PCR (polymerase chain reaction) test will be&#xD;
             requested from the subjects, and subjects who are positive will be excluded from the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute respiratory disease (moderate or severe illness with or without fever) (Subjects&#xD;
             may be screened again after acute condition has resolved)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fever (oral temperature &gt; 37.8°C) (Subjects can be enroll again after acute condition&#xD;
             improves)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient level of Turkish to perform the informed consent, except where briefing&#xD;
             by an independent witness can be provided and is available&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Participant eligibility is based on self-representation of gender identity.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ahmet Omma, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty Member</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ahmet Omma, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+90 (312) 552 60 00</phone>
    <email>ahmetomma@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>İhsan Ateş, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
    <email>dr.ihsanates@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ankara City Hospital Internal Medicine Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ahmet Omma, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+90 (312) 552 60 00</phone>
      <email>ahmetomma@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ahmet Omma, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sancaktepe Martyr Professor Dr. İlhan Varank Training and Research Hospital Infectious Diseases and Clinical Microbiology Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Fatma Yılmaz Karadağ, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+90 (0216) 606 33 00</phone>
      <email>dr_fatma@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fatma Yılmaz Karadağ, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>T.R. Ministry of Health Kartal Dr. Lütfi Kirdar City Hospital Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ayşe Batırel, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+90 (0216) 458 30 00</phone>
      <email>aysebatirel@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ayşe Batırel, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ümraniye Training and Research Hospital Infectious Diseases</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mehtap Aydın, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+90 (0216) 632 18 18</phone>
      <email>mehtapaydin10@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mehtap Aydın, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kumar A, Singh R, Kaur J, Pandey S, Sharma V, Thakur L, Sati S, Mani S, Asthana S, Sharma TK, Chaudhuri S, Bhattacharyya S, Kumar N. Wuhan to World: The COVID-19 Pandemic. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2021 Mar 30;11:596201. doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2021.596201. eCollection 2021. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33859951</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dan JM, Mateus J, Kato Y, Hastie KM, Yu ED, Faliti CE, Grifoni A, Ramirez SI, Haupt S, Frazier A, Nakao C, Rayaprolu V, Rawlings SA, Peters B, Krammer F, Simon V, Saphire EO, Smith DM, Weiskopf D, Sette A, Crotty S. Immunological memory to SARS-CoV-2 assessed for up to 8 months after infection. Science. 2021 Feb 5;371(6529). pii: eabf4063. doi: 10.1126/science.abf4063. Epub 2021 Jan 6.</citation>
    <PMID>33408181</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Doria-Rose N, Suthar MS, Makowski M, O'Connell S, McDermott AB, Flach B, Ledgerwood JE, Mascola JR, Graham BS, Lin BC, O'Dell S, Schmidt SD, Widge AT, Edara VV, Anderson EJ, Lai L, Floyd K, Rouphael NG, Zarnitsyna V, Roberts PC, Makhene M, Buchanan W, Luke CJ, Beigel JH, Jackson LA, Neuzil KM, Bennett H, Leav B, Albert J, Kunwar P; mRNA-1273 Study Group. Antibody Persistence through 6 Months after the Second Dose of mRNA-1273 Vaccine for Covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021 Jun 10;384(23):2259-2261. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2103916. Epub 2021 Apr 6.</citation>
    <PMID>33822494</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu K, Werner AP, Koch M, Choi A, Narayanan E, Stewart-Jones GBE, Colpitts T, Bennett H, Boyoglu-Barnum S, Shi W, Moliva JI, Sullivan NJ, Graham BS, Carfi A, Corbett KS, Seder RA, Edwards DK. Serum Neutralizing Activity Elicited by mRNA-1273 Vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2021 Apr 15;384(15):1468-1470. doi: 10.1056/NEJMc2102179. Epub 2021 Mar 17.</citation>
    <PMID>33730471</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Madhi SA, Baillie V, Cutland CL, Voysey M, Koen AL, Fairlie L, Padayachee SD, Dheda K, Barnabas SL, Bhorat QE, Briner C, Kwatra G, Ahmed K, Aley P, Bhikha S, Bhiman JN, Bhorat AE, du Plessis J, Esmail A, Groenewald M, Horne E, Hwa SH, Jose A, Lambe T, Laubscher M, Malahleha M, Masenya M, Masilela M, McKenzie S, Molapo K, Moultrie A, Oelofse S, Patel F, Pillay S, Rhead S, Rodel H, Rossouw L, Taoushanis C, Tegally H, Thombrayil A, van Eck S, Wibmer CK, Durham NM, Kelly EJ, Villafana TL, Gilbert S, Pollard AJ, de Oliveira T, Moore PL, Sigal A, Izu A; NGS-SA Group; Wits-VIDA COVID Group. Efficacy of the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 Covid-19 Vaccine against the B.1.351 Variant. N Engl J Med. 2021 May 20;384(20):1885-1898. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2102214. Epub 2021 Mar 16.</citation>
    <PMID>33725432</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2 Vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>Booster</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficacy</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunogenicity</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

