<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04973150</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>dpf199438</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04973150</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study on the Effect of Eye-covering Pretreatment on Acute Delirium After General Anesthesia in Pre-school Aged Children</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study on the Effect of Eye-covering Pretreatment on Acute Delirium After General Anesthesia in Pre-school Aged Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Participants (preschool children), because their cognitive ability and anti pressure ability&#xD;
      are obviously weaker than adults, most of the children who have this kind of operation and&#xD;
      anesthesia stressors will have perioperative anxiety. After eye surgery, they need to bandage&#xD;
      their eyes with gauze (single or double), so that the participants are in a state of complete&#xD;
      or partial darkness for a certain period of time, which is easy to produce dark phobia. In&#xD;
      clinical practice, investigators found that more than 80% of children with advanced&#xD;
      ophthalmology were prone to leprosy, resistance, crying and other symptoms after general&#xD;
      anesthesia, which brought greater difficulties to nursing. How to improve the cognitive&#xD;
      ability of preschool children, reduce the anxiety level of children during the perioperative&#xD;
      period, the incidence of postoperative detention and the difficulty of nursing are new topics&#xD;
      worthy of exploration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 20, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Yale preoperative anxiety scale (m-ypas) was used to evaluate the preoperative anxiety. The scale has high reliability and validity (Cronbach's) α The reliability coefficient was 0.936; 91). The scale is often used to evaluate the preoperative anxiety level of children aged 2-12 in the waiting room, going to the operating room, entering the operating room and anesthesia induction period. The questionnaire consists of 5 parts and 22 items, which are language (4 items), vocalization (6 items), emotional expression (4 items), obvious alertness (4 items), and the role of parents (4 items). In addition to the vocal part of 1-6 points, the rest are 1-4 points, the minimum is 0 points, the maximum is 100 points, the higher the score, the higher the anxiety level of the subjects. The scale was evaluated by the anesthesiologist when the child entered the operating room, and the evaluation time was about 2 minutes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">350</enrollment>
  <condition>Ophthalmology</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>the children were given gauze covering training in one eye or both eyes</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>According to the operation method, the children were given gauze covering training in one eye or both eyes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Using regular tablet computer to play cartoon animation video</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>To explore whether pretreatment with eye covering can reduce the incidence of acute delirium and the score of delirium after general anesthesia in ophthalmology pre-age children.</intervention_name>
    <description>To explore whether pretreatment with eye covering can reduce the incidence of acute delirium and the score of delirium after general anesthesia in ophthalmology pre-age children. Methods A total of 300 preschool-age children who underwent general anesthesia of selective ophthalmic surgery in a 3A grade hospital from August 2019 to July 2020 were selected as the research object, who were divided into experimental group and control group with 150 cases each by random number table. Children in the control group received regular education on cartoon animation videos before surgery; children in the experimental group received eye-covering pretreatment on the basis of cartoon animation videos. The differences in preoperative anxiety degree score, postoperative acute delirium incidence, delirium degree score, and postoperative nursing care difficulty score were compared between the two groups.</description>
    <arm_group_label>the children were given gauze covering training in one eye or both eyes</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ages 3-7;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Selective ophthalmological general anesthesia (static inhalation compound: propofol +&#xD;
             fentanil intravenous administration; heptaflurane inhalation);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No mental disorders, stunting and low intelligence;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. There is no other history of surgical hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those who have completed the operation under local anesthesia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. People with visual impairment of both eyes;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Eyeball removal and/or eye socket implanter;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Hearing and language impairment cannot communicate normally;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have a history of taking psychotropic drugs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. People with severe organs such as the heart, lungs, brains and kidneys.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>peifang Dong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>DONG Peifang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head nurse</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pre-school Aged Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute Delirium</keyword>
  <keyword>Eye-covering Pretreatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

