<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04979585</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-ME-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04979585</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Camrelizumab Plus Amlotinib and Chemotherapy in the First-line Treatment of Melanoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Camrelizumab Combined With Anlotinib and Nab-paclitaxel in Patients With Untreated Advanced Mucosal Melanoma:a Single-arm, Multicenter, Open-label Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Di Wu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The First Hospital of Jilin University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the objective response rate of camrelizumab combined with anlotinib and&#xD;
      nab-paclitaxel in patients with untreated advanced mucosal melanoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The current traditional cytotoxic single agent or combination chemotherapy cannot clearly&#xD;
      improve the overall survival rate of patients with advanced melanoma.From the current point&#xD;
      of view, combination therapy will be one of the inevitable trends in the future development&#xD;
      of tumor immunotherapy. So carry out this research To evaluate the objective response rate of&#xD;
      camrelizumab combined with anlotinib hydrochloride and albumin paclitaxel in the first-line&#xD;
      treatment of patients with advanced mucosal melanoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 14, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 14, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>camrelizumab combined with anlotinib and nab-paclitaxel</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>defined as the proportion of patients whose tumor volume has shrunk to a predetermined value and can maintain the minimum time limit. The sum of complete remission plus partial remission.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The time from the beginning of randomization to the onset of disease progression or the death of the patient.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>DCR</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of cases that achieved remission (PR+CR) and stable disease (SD) after treatment accounted for the number of evaluable cases.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">66</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with untreated advanced mucosal melanoma</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Camrelizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>200mg ,IV,d1,Q3W.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anlotinib</intervention_name>
    <description>8mg,oral, d1-14,Q3W.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>nab-Paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>260mg/m2,IV,d1,Q3W.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18-75 years old, gender ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. It was confirmed by histopathology that patients with recurrence, unresectable or&#xD;
             metastatic mucosal melanoma after surgery (stage III/IV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have not received any systemic anti-tumor drug therapy in the past, and allow previous&#xD;
             adjuvant therapy or neoadjuvant therapy (except PD-1/PDL1 monoclonal antibody and&#xD;
             VEGFR TKI), but it is required to be completed at least 4 weeks before the first&#xD;
             administration of the study drug, and All related toxic events have returned to normal&#xD;
             or CTCAE4.03 grade I or below, except for hair loss).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG 0or1。&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The expected survival time is ≥12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Can swallow medicine normally.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. According to the RECIST 1.1 standard, there is at least one measurable lesion, and the&#xD;
             lesion has not been irradiated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients are allowed to have a history of brain/meningeal metastasis, but they must&#xD;
             undergo local treatment (surgery/radiotherapy) before the start of the study, and be&#xD;
             clinically stable for at least 3 months (allowing corticosteroids before the first use&#xD;
             of the study drug, but before starting the study drug Need to stop for 2 weeks);&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients have good organ function: no blood transfusion or collection stimulation&#xD;
             factors and plateplate production in the 14 days before the first drug was given,&#xD;
             neutral granulocyte count ≥1.5×109/L, plate count≥ × 80×109/L, hemoglobin ≥80 g/L,&#xD;
             serum creatinine ≤1.5x normal upper limit (ULN), total bilium ≤1.5x normal upper limit&#xD;
             Value (ULN) ALT, AST≤2.5x ULN (no liver transfer) or ≤5x ULN (e.g. liver transfer),&#xD;
             albumin ≥30 g/L, blood clotting function requirements: international standardized&#xD;
             ratio Value (INR≤ 1.5x ULN, coagulase original time (PT) ≤1.5x ULN, active partial&#xD;
             clotting enzyme time (APTT) ≤1.5x ULN. Electrolyte requirements: corrected serum&#xD;
             calcium, blood potassium,&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Women of childbearing age must have a negative serum pregnancy test result within 7&#xD;
             days before the first administration of the trial drug; reproductive men or women who&#xD;
             are likely to become pregnant must use highly effective contraceptive methods (such as&#xD;
             oral contraceptives, uterine contraceptives, etc.) during the entire trial. Internal&#xD;
             contraceptive device, sexual desire control or barrier contraception combined with&#xD;
             spermicide), and continue contraception for 12 months after the end of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. The subjects voluntarily joined the study, signed an informed consent form, had good&#xD;
             compliance, and cooperated with the follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have previously received anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, anti-PD-L2 therapy and or&#xD;
             VEGFR TKI therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients currently undergoing anti-tumor therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who have participated in or are participating in clinical trials of other&#xD;
             drugs/therapies within 4 weeks before the first use of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The study drug has undergone a major surgical operation or has not recovered from the&#xD;
             side effects of this operation within 4 weeks before the first administration of the&#xD;
             study drug, live vaccination, immunotherapy, and radiotherapy within 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The patient has any active autoimmune disease or a history of autoimmune disease (such&#xD;
             as the following, but not limited to autoimmune hepatitis, interstitial pneumonia,&#xD;
             uveitis, enteritis, hepatitis, hypophysitis, vasculitis, nephritis, thyroid&#xD;
             Hyperfunction; patients suffering from vitiligo; asthma has been completely relieved&#xD;
             in childhood, and can be included in adults without any intervention; patients with&#xD;
             asthma that require bronchodilators for medical intervention cannot be included).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The patient is using immunosuppressive agents or systemic hormone therapy to achieve&#xD;
             immunosuppressive purposes (dose&gt;10mg/day prednisone or other curative hormones), and&#xD;
             continues to use it within 2 weeks before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. In the past 5 years, there is a history of other malignant tumors other than mucosal&#xD;
             melanoma, except for cured skin basal cell carcinoma, skin squamous cell carcinoma,&#xD;
             early prostate cancer and cervical carcinoma in situ.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who have received hematopoietic stimulating factors, such as granulocyte&#xD;
             colony stimulating factor (G-CSF), erythropoietin, etc., within 1 week before the&#xD;
             first administration of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The HIV antibody or Treponema pallidum antibody test result is positive.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with active hepatitis B or C: If HBsAg or HBcAb is positive, add HBV DNA (the&#xD;
             test result is higher than the upper limit of the normal range). If the HCV antibody&#xD;
             test result is positive, add HCV RNA (the test result is higher than the upper limit&#xD;
             of the normal range).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Those who are known to be allergic to recombinant humanized PD-1 monoclonal antibody&#xD;
             drugs and their components; those who are known to be allergic to anlotinib and any of&#xD;
             its excipients; those who are known to be allergic to albumin paclitaxel and its&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. A large amount of pleural fluid or ascites with clinical symptoms that require&#xD;
             symptomatic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Active lung disease (interstitial pneumonia, pneumonia, obstructive lung disease,&#xD;
             asthma) or a history of active tuberculosis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Di Guo</last_name>
    <phone>0431-88782013</phone>
    <email>guodi17790060921@126.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The first hospital of Jilin University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Changchun</city>
        <state>Jilin</state>
        <zip>130021</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Di Wu, MD</last_name>
      <phone>13944888991</phone>
      <phone_ext>13944888991</phone_ext>
      <email>Wudi991202@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The First Hospital of Jilin University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Di Wu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

