<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04976049</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY02000990</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04976049</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Use of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid to Assess Bone and Tissue Profusion in Orthopaedic Infection Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Use of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid to Assess Bone and Tissue Profusion in Orthopaedic Infection Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The focus of this study is to explore the variability distribution of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid&#xD;
      (ALA)associated with bone and soft tissue perfusion in infection patients, using 5-ALA&#xD;
      fluorescence imaging. In additional this study plans to evaluate the change in 5-ALA&#xD;
      distribution from pre to post debridement and to preliminarily determine whether an orally&#xD;
      administered dose of 20mg/kg 5-ALA can predict recurrent infection/treatment failure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The focus of this study is to (1) Explore variability in distribution of 5-Aminolevulinic&#xD;
      Acid (ALA) in bone and soft tissue infection (2) Evaluate the change in 5-ALA distribution&#xD;
      from pre to post debridement (3) Preliminarily determine whether 5-ALA has the possibility&#xD;
      predict infection / treatment failure&#xD;
&#xD;
      Infection following trauma is one of the most prevalent and challenging complications faced&#xD;
      by orthopedic surgeons in both military and civilian populations, occurring after up to 60%&#xD;
      of open bone fractures. Several factors specific to this trauma place patients at high risk&#xD;
      for infectious complications, including: traumatized tissues, open contaminated fracture,&#xD;
      soft tissue coverage issues, catabolic state due to poly-trauma, prolonged hospitalization&#xD;
      with exposure to nosocomial bacteria, and presence of metallic implants8. Infection requires&#xD;
      one or more unplanned surgical procedures and leads to prolonged morbidity, loss of function,&#xD;
      and potential loss of limb1. Failed treatment for bone infection results in recurrent&#xD;
      infection, requiring repeat surgical procedures in approximately 30% of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies are currently being conducted to evaluate the utility of first window Indocyanine&#xD;
      Green (ICG) to identify areas of deficient perfusion. This is based upon the concept&#xD;
      deficient perfusion prevents delivery of antibiotics and endogenous immune cells to&#xD;
      traumatized tissues. In the setting of established infection, poorly perfused bone can be a&#xD;
      nidus for biofilm formation creating resistance to antibiotics. However, in the context of&#xD;
      this work it is becoming increasingly clear that acute (rather than chronic) infections&#xD;
      display hyper vascularity with increased blood flow and neovascularization. Infection is&#xD;
      known to display the enhanced permeability and retention effect with increased vascular&#xD;
      permeability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are currently no accepted intraoperative tools that can be used to make objective&#xD;
      decisions about which bone and tissue is infected and which is normal. Methods currently used&#xD;
      to guide debridement are quite rudimentary. Clinical judgement is based on the gross&#xD;
      appearance of soft tissue and bone, including color, turgor, and extent of soft tissue&#xD;
      stripping. A burr may be used to look for bleeding bone. More extensive debridement is&#xD;
      thought to minimize risk of index infection or reduce the rate of persistent infection;&#xD;
      however, this comes at the cost of increasingly complex reconstructive procedures to fill&#xD;
      bony defects. Clearly what is needed is a functional imaging system which can identify&#xD;
      infected tissues to guide surgeons in the amount of tissue to debride. In turn, this will&#xD;
      lead to fewer infections and a more effective treatment of surgical site infections (SSIs) at&#xD;
      the fracture site. Both scenarios will allow patients to return to duty or work sooner.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>5-Aminolevulinic Acid distribution variability</measure>
    <time_frame>One Day</time_frame>
    <description>Distribution of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid in the bone and soft tissue of infection patients, measured using fluorescent imaging.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5-Aminolevulinic Acid distribution pre and post debridement.</measure>
    <time_frame>One Day</time_frame>
    <description>Distribution of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid in bone and soft tissue prior to and following debridement, measure using fluorescent imaging</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>5-Aminolevulinic Acid Dose Effectiveness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who do not experience a recurrent infection following the experimental dose of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Trauma</condition>
  <condition>Infection</condition>
  <condition>Bone Fracture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Orthopedic infection</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects who have undergone previous trauma surgeries and have developed an infection will be assessed for protocol inclusion criteria. Patients will be administered a single, oral, 20mg/kg dose of 5-Aminolevulinic Acid (ALA) by a qualified member of their care team. This dose will be administered ideally 3 hours prior to surgery. Fluorescent imaging will be obtained pre and post irrigation and debridement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Imaging using 5-Aminolevulinic Acid (5-ALA) during surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will be administered FDA approved oral 5-ALA and imaged by a FDA approved surgical fluorescence imaging device (Spy Elite) which is 0.5 meter away from the subject.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Orthopedic infection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients 18 years of age or older who present to Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center with an&#xD;
        orthopaedic infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients 18 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of an extremity fracture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior definitive fracture management with external fixation, internal fixation, or&#xD;
             joint fusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Superficial, deep, or organ space surgical site infection (SSI) (as per Center for&#xD;
             Disease Control criteria) at the fracture site that requires operative management.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Will have all planned SSI care surgeries performed by a participating surgeon or&#xD;
             delegate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Provision of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Fractures of the hand cannot be imaged.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Iodine allergy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Burns at the SSI site.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Incarceration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Expected survival of less than 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Problems, in the judgment of study personnel, with maintaining follow-up with the&#xD;
             patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adults unable to consent or whom do not have a legal authorized representative&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Individuals who are not yet adults (infants, children, teenagers)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of cutaneous photosensitivity, porphyria, hypersensitivity to porphyrins,&#xD;
             photodermatosis, exfoliative dermatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of liver disease within the last 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Elevated liver function tests (aspartate aminotransferase, alanine aminotransferase,&#xD;
             alkaline phosphatase or bilirubin levels greater than 2.5 times the normal limit) from&#xD;
             laboratory tests conducted within 30 days prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Serum creatinine in excess of 180 µmol/L within 30 days prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Inability to comply with the photosensitivity precautions associated with the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amy E Hall, MS</last_name>
    <phone>603-653-3306</phone>
    <email>amy.e.hall@hitchcock.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Melanie L Christian</last_name>
    <phone>6036503556</phone>
    <email>melanie.l.christian@hitchcock.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dartmouth Hitchcock Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lebanon</city>
        <state>New Hampshire</state>
        <zip>03756</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ida L Gitajn, MD</last_name>
      <phone>603-650-5000</phone>
      <email>ida.l.gitajn@hitchcock.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Amy E Hall, MS</last_name>
      <phone>603-653-3306</phone>
      <email>amy.e.hall@hitchcock.org</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dartmouth-Hitchcock Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ida Leah Gitajn</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Orthopaedics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>5-Aminolevulinic Acid, infection, orthopedics, imaging</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fractures, Bone</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aminolevulinic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

