<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04975659</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UKM PPl/111/8/JEP-2020-011</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04975659</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Placebo Versus Nocebo: Effects on Pain and Anxiety During Local Anaesthetic Infiltration in Parturient Undergoing Elective Caesarean Delivery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Placebo Versus Nocebo: Effects on Pain and Anxiety During Local Anaesthetic Infiltration in Parturient Undergoing Elective Caesarean Delivery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This randomized trial compared placebo and nocebo effect over anaesthetist-patient&#xD;
      communication on pain and anxiety score during local anaesthetic (LA) skin infiltration in&#xD;
      parturient undergoing caesarean delivery under regional anaesthesia (RA). A secondary&#xD;
      objective was to determine if education level and previous RA experience affect pain and&#xD;
      anxiety scores. Parturients scheduled for elective caesarean delivery were randomised into&#xD;
      Placebo (P) or Nocebo (N) group. Baseline Amsterdam Preoperative Anxiety &amp; Information Scale&#xD;
      (APAIS0) were obtained. Standardised scripts describing the LA skin infiltration for RA were&#xD;
      used during the pre-anaesthetic review. (N) group were explained with words like &quot;pain,&#xD;
      prick, sharp&quot; while words like &quot;numb, comfort, tolerable&quot; were used in the (P) group,&#xD;
      avoiding &quot;painful&quot; expressions. The same scripts will be repeated before skin infiltration&#xD;
      during the RA procedure. On the day of surgery, a second (APAIS1) was obtained upon arrival&#xD;
      to the theatre. Pain score using the numerical rating scale (NRS) was assessed after LA&#xD;
      infiltration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We randomised participants into either the nocebo (N) or placebo (P) group. We obtained a&#xD;
      baseline anxiety score (APAIS0) using the Amsterdam Preoperative Anxiety and Information&#xD;
      Scale (APAIS) during the pre-anaesthesia visit. Following that, we informed subjects in the N&#xD;
      group a negative suggestion, using the following script: &quot;During the local anaesthetic&#xD;
      injection, you are going to feel a sharp prick at your back; this is usually the most painful&#xD;
      part of the procedure&quot;. On the other hand, we used a positive suggestion on the P group: &quot;We&#xD;
      will administer some local anaesthetic to numb your back; this will allow the procedure to be&#xD;
      more comfortable and tolerable for you.&quot; We obtain a second anxiety score (APAIS1) in the&#xD;
      operating theatre before the caesarean section. We carried out either spinal anaesthesia or&#xD;
      continuous spinal epidural according to standard hospital protocol and indication. Before the&#xD;
      LA skin infiltration, the anaesthetist repeats the same script to the subjects according to&#xD;
      the prior randomisation. Five millilitres of lignocaine 2% is injected intradermally and&#xD;
      subcutaneously by the anaesthetist into interspinous space in a single pass through a&#xD;
      22-gauge needle to create a skin wheal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the LA infiltration, only the attending anaesthetist performing the procedure gave&#xD;
      participants verbal instructions; other personnel remained silent throughout. We recorded the&#xD;
      presence of vocalisation of pain, withdrawal movement or facial grimacing. Immediately after&#xD;
      the LA infiltration, a blinded and trained general anaesthetic nurse or personnel enters the&#xD;
      operating theatre to assess the subjects' pain score using the numerical rating scale (NRS).&#xD;
      After collection of the pain score, the anaesthetist performed the remaining anaesthetic&#xD;
      procedure as per clinical routine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 21, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We randomised participants into either the nocebo (N) or placebo (P) group using computer generated numbers</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants are blinded from their randomization. Personnel assessing the pain score is blinded.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>Throughout study completion, average of 10 months</time_frame>
    <description>Pain score during local anaesthetic infiltration using Numerical Rating Scale (NRS) (range 0-10) where 0 is &quot;no pain at all&quot; and 10 is &quot; worst pain ever felt&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline anxiety score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, average of 10 months</time_frame>
    <description>Validated questionnare using the Amsterdam Preoperative Anxiety &amp; Information Scale. (APAIS) (Range 6-30). Higher scores mean higher anxiety level</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Preoperative anxiety score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, average of 10 months</time_frame>
    <description>Validated questionnare using the Amsterdam Preoperative Anxiety &amp; Information Scale. (Range 6-30). Higher scores mean higher anxiety level</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of Education level on Pain and anxiety score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, average of 10 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between subjects education level on pain score (NRS) and anxiety score (APAIS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of past history of regional anesthesia on Pain and anxiety score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, average of 10 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between subjects previous experience of regional anesthesia on pain score (NRS) and anxiety score (APAIS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">76</enrollment>
  <condition>Communication</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nocebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>We informed subjects in the N group a negative suggestion, using the following script: &quot;During the local anaesthetic injection, you are going to feel a sharp prick at your back; this is usually the painful part of the procedure&quot;</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>We informed subjects in the P group a positive suggestion, using the following script: &quot;We will administer some local anaesthetic to numb your back; this will allow the procedure to be more comfortable and tolerable for you.&quot;</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo and Nocebo effect</intervention_name>
    <description>Positive suggestion and words is used on Placebo group Negative suggestion and words is used on Nocebo group</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nocebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anaesthesiology (ASA) II category parturient listed for elective&#xD;
             caesarean delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can understand intended verbal communication&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  receiving any form of analgesia within 6 hours before the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic pain,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anxiety disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergy to Local Anaesthetic drugs&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Canselor Tuanku Muhriz,</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cheras</city>
        <state>Kuala Lumpur</state>
        <zip>56000</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mohd Fahmi Z, Lai LL, Loh PS. Validation of the Malay version of the Amsterdam Preoperative Anxiety and Information Scale (APAIS). Med J Malaysia. 2015 Aug;70(4):243-8.</citation>
    <PMID>26358022</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dutt-Gupta J, Bown T, Cyna AM. Effect of communication on pain during intravenous cannulation: a randomized controlled trial. Br J Anaesth. 2007 Dec;99(6):871-5. Epub 2007 Oct 30.</citation>
    <PMID>17977860</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Varelmann D, Pancaro C, Cappiello EC, Camann WR. Nocebo-induced hyperalgesia during local anesthetic injection. Anesth Analg. 2010 Mar 1;110(3):868-70. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0b013e3181cc5727. Epub 2009 Dec 30.</citation>
    <PMID>20042440</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Moerman N, van Dam FS, Muller MJ, Oosting H. The Amsterdam Preoperative Anxiety and Information Scale (APAIS). Anesth Analg. 1996 Mar;82(3):445-51.</citation>
    <PMID>8623940</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia Medical Centre</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rufinah Teo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer and Consultant Anesthesiologist , Department of Anesthesia and Intensive Care</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Placebo</keyword>
  <keyword>Nocebo</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Local Skin Infiltration</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

