<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04971720</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300007789</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04971720</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Natriuretic Peptide-Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System Rhythm Axis and Nocturnal Blood Pressure</brief_title>
  <official_title>Natriuretic Peptide-Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System Rhythm Axis and Nocturnal Blood Pressure</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Obese individuals have a higher prevalence of nocturnal hypertension and non-dipping blood&#xD;
      pressure (BP) and are associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular (CV) events and&#xD;
      death as compared with lean individuals. The Natriuretic Peptides (NPs) are hormones produced&#xD;
      by the heart which directly regulate BP by causing dilation of blood vessels and by removing&#xD;
      sodium and water from the body. NPs have a 24-hour day-night rhythm and controls the&#xD;
      day-night rhythm of BP as well. The NP-BP rhythm relationship is broken down in obese&#xD;
      individuals. Lower circulating levels of NPs, elevated renin hormone (a part of the&#xD;
      Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System [RAAS]) at nighttime may also contribute to the high&#xD;
      nocturnal blood pressure in obese individuals and put them at a higher risk of developing CV&#xD;
      events. This current study seeks to determine the biological implications of&#xD;
      chronopharmacology for synchronizing NP-RAAS-based blood pressure therapy with the&#xD;
      physiological diurnal rhythms to restore the normal diurnal rhythm of blood pressure in obese&#xD;
      individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators have demonstrated that there exists a diurnal rhythm of natriuretic&#xD;
      peptides (NPs) which tracks closely with the BP rhythm and is in an antiphase relationship&#xD;
      with the rhythm of the RAAS (Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System) hormones. The NP levels&#xD;
      are lowest at night, and the renin and aldosterone levels are highest at nighttime.&#xD;
      Furthermore, the investigators have demonstrated that obese individuals have a putative&#xD;
      deficiency of NPs, and this is due to decreased production alongside increased clearance of&#xD;
      NPs. LCZ696 is an FDA-approved inhibitor of neprilysin (an NP degrading enzyme) that augments&#xD;
      the NP levels and also suppresses the RAAS. Hence, the confluence of putative NP deficiency&#xD;
      among obese alongside the lower levels of NPs at nighttime and the increased activity of RAAS&#xD;
      at night may contribute to the high-risk nocturnal non-dipping BP profile among obese&#xD;
      individuals. Chronopharmacology (controlling the time of medication administration) to&#xD;
      synchronize the NP-RAAS axis targeting anti-hypertensive medications with the inherent&#xD;
      biological NP-RAAS-BP rhythm axis may help in controlling the high-risk nocturnal BP&#xD;
      non-dipping in obese. Investigators hypothesize that nighttime administration of NP&#xD;
      augmenting and/or RAAS inhibition therapy in obese hypertensive individuals will help to&#xD;
      improve their nocturnal BP rhythm. The investigators aim to conduct a patient-oriented&#xD;
      physiological clinical trial to assess the effect of timing of administration of NP-RAAS axis&#xD;
      therapy on restoring the normal BP rhythm. The investigators will conduct a 2x2 factorial&#xD;
      design trial, wherein individuals will be randomized to either daytime dosing or nighttime&#xD;
      dosing of either LCZ696 or valsartan. The investigators will study the effect of timing of NP&#xD;
      augmenting and/or RAAS inhibiting therapy on the nighttime BP profile in obese hypertensive&#xD;
      patients with nondipping nocturnal BP. The investigators will also assess the effect of NP&#xD;
      augmentation in an NP deficient population on the nocturnal BP profile in obese hypertensives&#xD;
      with nondipping nocturnal BP. The investigators will also examine the impact of NP&#xD;
      augmenting-RAAS inhibiting therapy on the NP levels and the physiological diurnal rhythms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will assess the physiological implications of chronopharmacology of&#xD;
      anti-hypertensive therapy and assess a potentially novel approach of using the inherent&#xD;
      biological rhythms to reduce the normal BP rhythmicity in a high-risk population&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mean nocturnal systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean nocturnal systolic blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in percent nocturnal dipping blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in percent nocturnal dipping blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 24-hour mean systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in 24-hour mean systolic blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 24-hour mean diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in 24-hour mean diastolic blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mean daytime systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean daytime systolic blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mean daytime diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean daytime diastolic blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mean nocturnal diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>Change in mean nocturnal diastolic blood pressure will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the daytime, nocturnal, and total urinary excretion parameters (Urine Sodium, Urine Potassium, Urine Creatinine, Urine Albumin).</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the daytime, nocturnal, and total urinary excretion parameters (Urine Sodium, Urine Potassium, Urine Creatinine, Urine Albumin) will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal ANP, BNP, NTproBNP, and renin levels</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal ANP, BNP, NTproBNP, and renin levels will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal MRproANP levels</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal MRproANP levels will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal Aldosterone levels</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in 24-hour, daytime, and nocturnal Aldosterone levels will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for ANP, BNP, NTproBNP, renin, and melatonin rhythms.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for ANP, BNP, NTproBNP, renin, and melatonin rhythms will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for MRproANP.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for MRproANP will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for aldosterone rhythms.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for aldosterone rhythms will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for cortisol rhythms.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for cortisol rhythms will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for systolic BP, and diastolic BP rhythms.</measure>
    <time_frame>At Baseline and after 7 days of intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Change in rhythm parameters (mesor, amplitude, and phase) for systolic BP, and diastolic BP rhythms will be analyzed in the two study arms (morning vs. evening dose of sacubitril/valsartan or valsartan) from baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Nocturnal Blood Pressure</condition>
  <condition>Natriuretic Peptides</condition>
  <condition>Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sacubitril/Valsartan Morning Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>We will enroll 40 adult obese individuals. Each participant will take the assigned dose of medication once in the morning and a placebo pill in the evening for 7 days. We evaluate Natriuretic Peptide-Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System Rhythm Axis and Nocturnal Blood Pressure at baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sacubitril/Valsartan Evening Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>We will enroll 40 adult obese individuals. Each participant will take the assigned dose of medication once in the evening and a placebo pill in the morning for 7 days. We evaluate Natriuretic Peptide-Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System Rhythm Axis and Nocturnal Blood Pressure at baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Valsartan Morning Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>We will enroll 40 adult obese individuals. Each participant will take the assigned dose of medication once in the morning and a placebo pill in the evening for 7 days. We evaluate Natriuretic Peptide-Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System Rhythm Axis and Nocturnal Blood Pressure at baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Valsartan Evening Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>We will enroll 40 adult obese individuals. Each participant will take the assigned dose of medication once in the evening and a placebo pill in the morning for 7 days. We evaluate Natriuretic Peptide-Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System Rhythm Axis and Nocturnal Blood Pressure at baseline and after 7 days of intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sacubitril-Valsartan 49 Mg-51 Mg Oral Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject will be randomized, in a double-blind manner to sacubitril/valsartan 49/51 mg once in the morning or once in the evening for a period of 7 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sacubitril/Valsartan Evening Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sacubitril/Valsartan Morning Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sacubitril/Valsartan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Valsartan 80 mg Oral Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>The subject will be randomized, in a double-blind manner to valsartan 80 mg once in the morning or once in the evening for a period of 7 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Valsartan Evening Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Valsartan Morning Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Valsartan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standardized Study Diet</intervention_name>
    <description>The standardized diet consisted with eucaloric meals of 4.5 gm sodium per day for 14 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sacubitril/Valsartan Evening Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sacubitril/Valsartan Morning Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Valsartan Evening Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Valsartan Morning Dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age more than or equal to 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index between 30 to 45 kg/m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood pressure: Systolic BP more than or equal to 140mmHg and less than or equal to&#xD;
             160 mmHg and diastolic blood pressure more than or equal to 80mmHg and less than or&#xD;
             equal to 100mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 18, at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systolic BP &lt;140 or &gt;160 mm Hg at baseline, or diastolic BP &lt;80 or &gt;100 mm Hg at&#xD;
             baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt;30 kg/m^2 or &gt;45 kg/m^2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pulmonary hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any past or present illness of cardiovascular disease including myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, angina, cardiac arrhythmia, diabetes, stroke, TIA, or seizure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who are taking more than 2 hypertension medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of angioedema;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estimated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 60 ml/min/1.73 m2 (CKD-EPI equation);&#xD;
             urine albumin creatinine ratio ≥30 mg/g.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatic Transaminase (AST and ALT) levels &gt;3x the upper limit of normal;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant psychiatric illness (assessed using validated MINI International&#xD;
             Neuropsychiatry Interview questionnaires);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anemia (men, Hct &lt; 38%; women, Hct &lt;36%);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants working night shifts or swing shifts.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any past or present illness of sleeping disorders including sleep apnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding or who can become pregnant and not practicing&#xD;
             an acceptable method of birth control during the study (including abstinence).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pankaj Arora, MD, FAHA</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Vibhu Parcha, MD</last_name>
    <phone>205-934-7936</phone>
    <email>vparcha@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Deborah Weber, BSN, RN</last_name>
    <phone>205-975-9964</phone>
    <email>dlowe@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Parcha V, Patel N, Gutierrez OM, Li P, Gamble KL, Musunuru K, Margulies KB, Cappola TP, Wang TJ, Arora G, Arora P. Chronobiology of Natriuretic Peptides and Blood Pressure in Lean and Obese Individuals. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2021 May 11;77(18):2291-2303. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2021.03.291.</citation>
    <PMID>33958126</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arora P, Wu C, Hamid T, Arora G, Agha O, Allen K, Tainsh RET, Hu D, Ryan RA, Domian IJ, Buys ES, Bloch DB, Prabhu SD, Bloch KD, Newton-Cheh C, Wang TJ. Acute Metabolic Influences on the Natriuretic Peptide System in Humans. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2016 Feb 23;67(7):804-812. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2015.11.049.</citation>
    <PMID>26892417</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bajaj NS, Gutiérrez OM, Arora G, Judd SE, Patel N, Bennett A, Prabhu SD, Howard G, Howard VJ, Cushman M, Arora P. Racial Differences in Plasma Levels of N-Terminal Pro-B-Type Natriuretic Peptide and Outcomes: The Reasons for Geographic and Racial Differences in Stroke (REGARDS) Study. JAMA Cardiol. 2018 Jan 1;3(1):11-17. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2017.4207.</citation>
    <PMID>29167879</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arora P, Reingold J, Baggish A, Guanaga DP, Wu C, Ghorbani A, Song Y, Chen-Tournaux A, Khan AM, Tainsh LT, Buys ES, Williams JS, Heublein DM, Burnett JC, Semigran MJ, Bloch KD, Scherrer-Crosbie M, Newton-Cheh C, Kaplan LM, Wang TJ. Weight loss, saline loading, and the natriuretic peptide system. J Am Heart Assoc. 2015 Jan 16;4(1):e001265. doi: 10.1161/JAHA.114.001265.</citation>
    <PMID>25595796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Parcha V, Kalra R, Li P, Oparil S, Arora G, Arora P. Nocturnal blood pressure dipping in treated hypertensives: insights from the SPRINT trial. Eur J Prev Cardiol. 2020 Nov 29. pii: zwaa125. doi: 10.1093/eurjpc/zwaa125. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33624057</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Pankaj Arora, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor, Division of Cardiovascular Disease, Department of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Natriuretic Peptides</keyword>
  <keyword>Nocturnal Blood Pressure</keyword>
  <keyword>Renin-Angiotensin-Aldosterone System</keyword>
  <keyword>Obesity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Valsartan</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sacubitril and valsartan sodium hydrate drug combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

