<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04972955</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REB20-1660</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04972955</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Predicting Dysglycemia in Individuals With Gestational Diabetes Immediately Postpartum Using Flash Glucose Monitoring</brief_title>
  <acronym>PREDISPOSE</acronym>
  <official_title>Predicting Dysglycemia in Individuals With Gestational Diabetes Immediately Postpartum Using Flash Glucose Monitoring</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Calgary</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Calgary</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Gestational diabetes is one of the most common medical disorders in pregnancy and is a major&#xD;
      risk factor for the postpartum development of dysglycemia. Despite the high risk of&#xD;
      developing dysglycemia, 50-80% of women with gestational diabetes are not receiving testing&#xD;
      within a year postpartum. The investigators will conduct a prospective cohort pilot study to&#xD;
      examine the use of flash glucose monitoring immediately postpartum to estimate the risk of&#xD;
      maternal dysglycemia postpartum.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Gestational diabetes is one of the most common medical disorders in pregnancy and affects up&#xD;
      to 18% of pregnancies. It is associated with an increased risk of both maternal and neonatal&#xD;
      complications. Importantly, gestational diabetes is a major risk factor for the postpartum&#xD;
      development of pre-diabetes or type 2 diabetes (together referred to as dysglycemia).&#xD;
      Specifically, half of women with gestational diabetes will develop dysglycemia within 10&#xD;
      years of delivery. Despite the high risk of developing dysglycemia, 50-80% of women with&#xD;
      recent gestational diabetes are not receiving testing within a year postpartum.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are likely many factors contributing to this low screening rate. These include&#xD;
      individual factors such as socioeconomic status and maternal age, as well as the nature of&#xD;
      the guideline recommended test itself. The Diabetes Canada 2018 Clinical Practice Guidelines&#xD;
      recommend screening for maternal dysglycemia between &quot;6 weeks to 6 months postpartum&quot; with a&#xD;
      75g oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT). This recommendation is based on expert opinion. While&#xD;
      the 75g OGTT is thought to be the &quot;gold-standard&quot; for screening for dysglycemia postpartum,&#xD;
      it has many pitfalls. First, the OGTT is widely disliked by women as it is time consuming and&#xD;
      inconvenient. It requires consuming a sugary drink in addition to two separate venipunctures.&#xD;
      Second, the 75g OGTT is notoriously unreproducible. Third, when including the direct medical&#xD;
      costs, transportation costs, and the indirect time costs, it is estimated that the 75g OGTT&#xD;
      costs $108/woman screened. Finally, it takes only a &quot;snap shot&quot; of a woman's glucose and&#xD;
      insulin response with only two measurements over two-hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Emerging technologies are changing the landscape of diabetes care. Flash glucose monitoring&#xD;
      (Freestyle Libre Pro IQ) is one such technology. People easily insert a small cannula just&#xD;
      under the skin using an applicator. While the device is in place, it measures interstitial&#xD;
      glucose concentrations every 15 minutes. It is a small disc (~size of a quarter) that is&#xD;
      placed by a research assistant and removed by the participant. It can be worn during typical&#xD;
      daily activities such as sleeping, showering, and exercising. Fourteen days of data from the&#xD;
      Freestyle Libre Pro IQ can be downloaded and reviewed retrospectively by a clinician and/or&#xD;
      researcher. With 1344 glucose measurements taken over a 14-day period, flash glucose&#xD;
      monitoring gives a detailed picture of glycemic excursions throughout the day including both&#xD;
      fasting and postprandial states.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are currently no studies examining the use of flash glucose monitoring postpartum.&#xD;
      Furthermore, no studies have examined flash glucose monitoring's potential role in diagnosis&#xD;
      of maternal dysglycemia. There is an unmet need to improve postpartum screening for women&#xD;
      with gestational diabetes so that high risk women do not miss the opportunity for early&#xD;
      treatment. To address this, the investigators will perform a pilot study examining the use of&#xD;
      flash glucose monitoring immediately postpartum to estimate the risk of maternal dysglycemia&#xD;
      postpartum. This is an observational study which aims to see if CGM can be used to diagnose&#xD;
      diabetes. The CGM device in this study will be used for diagnosis and not as an intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of recruitment</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants recruited at each site per year</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of devices returned</measure>
    <time_frame>15-17 days postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Devices will be returned using a pre-paid envelope with biohazard labelling</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of missing glucose data</measure>
    <time_frame>Delivery to 2 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Glucose data will be collected using the Libre Freestyle Pro IQ flash glucose monitoring system</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who complete 75g OGTTs</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who complete HbA1c testing</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New diagnosis of maternal diabetes based on postpartum 75g OGTT</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Diabetes defined as fasting plasma glucose ≥ 7.0 mmol/L or 2-hour plasma glucose ≥ 11.1 mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New diagnosis of maternal prediabetes based on postpartum 75g OGTT</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Prediabetes defined as fasting plasma glucose 6.1-6.9 mmol/L or 2-hour plasma glucose 7.8-11.0 mmol/L</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New diagnosis of diabetes based on postpartum HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Diabetes is defined as HbA1c ≥ 6.5%</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New diagnosis of prediabetes based on postpartum HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Prediabetes is defined as HbA1c 6.0-6.4%</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of testing using the device based on an acceptability questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>15-17 days postpartum; 4-6 months postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>The Acceptability Questionnaire for the Freestyle Libre Pro IQ Postpartum will be completed at two points throughout the study. Scores can range between 12 and 60, with a higher score indicating a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Glycemic variability reflected by coefficients of variation and standard deviations of blood glucose data</measure>
    <time_frame>Delivery to 2 weeks postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Blood glucose data will be collected using the Freestyle Libre Pro IQ flash glucose monitoring system</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New diagnosis of type 2 diabetes</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 2 and 5 years postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Information on new type 2 diabetes diagnoses will be obtained through administrative provincial databases</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Gestational Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Prediabetes; Complicating Pregnancy</condition>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <condition>Glucose Metabolism Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Disease</condition>
  <condition>Endocrine System Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women diagnosed with gestational diabetes</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women who have been diagnosed with gestational diabetes during the current pregnancy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Libre Freestyle Pro IQ</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will wear a flash glucose monitoring device, the Libre Freestyle Pro IQ, for two weeks following delivery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women diagnosed with gestational diabetes</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women who are currently pregnant and have been diagnosed with gestational diabetes during&#xD;
        the current pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant individuals age 18 to 45 (inclusive)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with gestational diabetes by the Diabetes Canada guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned in-hospital delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to use the study device and complete assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have access to email&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-gestational diabetes (i.e. pre-existing diabetes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned x-ray, MRI or CT within 3 weeks postpartum&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an implantable medical device (ex. pacemaker)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On medications known to affect glucose metabolism (for example glucocorticoids,&#xD;
             metformin etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On medications which may interfere with the Freestyle Libre Pro IQ accuracy (for&#xD;
             example aspirin or Vitamin C [&gt;500mg/day])&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to speak and understand English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer Yamamoto, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Calgary</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer Yamamoto, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(204) 789-3385</phone>
    <email>jennifer.yamamoto@ucalgary.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lois E Donovan, MD</last_name>
    <phone>403-955-8358</phone>
    <email>lois.donovan@albertahealthservices.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>HAPO Study Cooperative Research Group, Metzger BE, Lowe LP, Dyer AR, Trimble ER, Chaovarindr U, Coustan DR, Hadden DR, McCance DR, Hod M, McIntyre HD, Oats JJ, Persson B, Rogers MS, Sacks DA. Hyperglycemia and adverse pregnancy outcomes. N Engl J Med. 2008 May 8;358(19):1991-2002. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa0707943.</citation>
    <PMID>18463375</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sellers EA, Dean HJ, Shafer LA, Martens PJ, Phillips-Beck W, Heaman M, Prior HJ, Dart AB, McGavock J, Morris M, Torshizi AA, Ludwig S, Shen GX. Exposure to Gestational Diabetes Mellitus: Impact on the Development of Early-Onset Type 2 Diabetes in Canadian First Nations and Non-First Nations Offspring. Diabetes Care. 2016 Dec;39(12):2240-2246. Epub 2016 Oct 4.</citation>
    <PMID>27703026</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lowe WL Jr, Scholtens DM, Lowe LP, Kuang A, Nodzenski M, Talbot O, Catalano PM, Linder B, Brickman WJ, Clayton P, Deerochanawong C, Hamilton J, Josefson JL, Lashley M, Lawrence JM, Lebenthal Y, Ma R, Maresh M, McCance D, Tam WH, Sacks DA, Dyer AR, Metzger BE; HAPO Follow-up Study Cooperative Research Group. Association of Gestational Diabetes With Maternal Disorders of Glucose Metabolism and Childhood Adiposity. JAMA. 2018 Sep 11;320(10):1005-1016. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.11628.</citation>
    <PMID>30208453</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferrara A, Peng T, Kim C. Trends in postpartum diabetes screening and subsequent diabetes and impaired fasting glucose among women with histories of gestational diabetes mellitus: A report from the Translating Research Into Action for Diabetes (TRIAD) Study. Diabetes Care. 2009 Feb;32(2):269-74. doi: 10.2337/dc08-1184. Epub 2008 Nov 4.</citation>
    <PMID>18984776</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McGovern A, Butler L, Jones S, van Vlymen J, Sadek K, Munro N, Carr H, de Lusignan S. Diabetes screening after gestational diabetes in England: a quantitative retrospective cohort study. Br J Gen Pract. 2014 Jan;64(618):e17-23. doi: 10.3399/bjgp14X676410.</citation>
    <PMID>24567578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Butalia S, Donovan L, Savu A, Johnson J, Edwards A, Kaul P. Postpartum Diabetes Testing Rates after Gestational Diabetes Mellitus in Canadian Women: A Population-Based Study. Can J Diabetes. 2017 Dec;41(6):613-620. doi: 10.1016/j.jcjd.2016.12.013. Epub 2017 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>28506815</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Diabetes Canada Clinical Practice Guidelines Expert Committee, Feig DS, Berger H, Donovan L, Godbout A, Kader T, Keely E, Sanghera R. Diabetes and Pregnancy. Can J Diabetes. 2018 Apr;42 Suppl 1:S255-S282. doi: 10.1016/j.jcjd.2017.10.038. Erratum in: Can J Diabetes. 2018 Jun;42(3):337.</citation>
    <PMID>29650105</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Neiger R, Coustan DR. The role of repeat glucose tolerance tests in the diagnosis of gestational diabetes. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 1991 Oct;165(4 Pt 1):787-90.</citation>
    <PMID>1951534</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Meltzer SJ, Snyder J, Penrod JR, Nudi M, Morin L. Gestational diabetes mellitus screening and diagnosis: a prospective randomised controlled trial comparing costs of one-step and two-step methods. BJOG. 2010 Mar;117(4):407-15. doi: 10.1111/j.1471-0528.2009.02475.x. Epub 2010 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>20105163</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Calgary</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Yamamoto</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Gestational Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Prediabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Prospective Cohort Study</keyword>
  <keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>CGM</keyword>
  <keyword>Continuous Glucose Monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Flash Glucose Monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Screening</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes, Gestational</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pregnancy Complications</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glucose Metabolism Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endocrine System Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

