<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04977765</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRO00040486</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04977765</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cardiometabolic Health in Transgender Males</brief_title>
  <official_title>Defining the Cardiometabolic Profile of Transgender Boys and Men on Testosterone Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical College of Wisconsin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Advancing a Healthier Wisconsin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical College of Wisconsin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Transgender individuals are those with a gender identity opposite the sex they were assigned&#xD;
      at birth. Approximately 1% of the population is transgender, equating to ~60,000 transgender&#xD;
      Wisconsinites. A transgender boy or man is someone with a 46,XX karyotype and typical female&#xD;
      genitalia but a male gender identity and desire for more male-typical gender expression.&#xD;
      Gender-affirming testosterone (hormonal) treatment (GAHT) is the cornerstone of masculinizing&#xD;
      therapy for transgender men and boys, resulting in estrogen (E2) suppression and circulating&#xD;
      testosterone (T) levels equivalent to cisgender males. Historically, GAHT was initiated after&#xD;
      an E2-driven puberty, but the last decade has seen an explosion of referrals for GAHT in&#xD;
      transboys, many of whom are exposed to only low E2 levels before puberty is halted with&#xD;
      blocker therapy. Knowledge of risks incurred by GAHT rely on low-quality studies, precluding&#xD;
      conclusive assessment of GAHT's long-term impact on cardiometabolic outcomes. Data on&#xD;
      transboys receiving GAHT before completion of E2-driven puberty are sparser and no studies&#xD;
      have addressed mechanisms by which GAHT may affect vascular physiology. The investigators aim&#xD;
      to determine the cardiometabolic impact of GAHT in transboys/men and to determine if any&#xD;
      differences identified are mechanistically dependent on the timing of GAHT relative to&#xD;
      puberty.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Gender-affirming testosterone (hormonal) treatment (GAHT) is the cornerstone of masculinizing&#xD;
      therapy for transgender men, resulting in circulating testosterone (T) levels equivalent to&#xD;
      cismen and estrogen (E2) suppression. Historically, GAHT was initiated after an E2-driven&#xD;
      puberty, but the last decade has seen an explosion of referrals for GAHT in transboys, many&#xD;
      of whom are exposed to only low E2 levels before puberty is halted with blocker therapy.&#xD;
      Knowledge of risks incurred by GAHT rely on low quality studies, precluding conclusive&#xD;
      assessment of GAHT's long-term impact on cardiometabolic outcomes. Data on transboys&#xD;
      receiving GAHT before completion of E2-driven puberty are sparser and no studies have&#xD;
      addressed mechanisms by which GAHT may affect vascular physiology. The investigators aim to&#xD;
      determine the cardiometabolic impact of GAHT in transboys/men and to determine if any&#xD;
      differences identified are mechanistically dependent on the timing of GAHT relative to&#xD;
      puberty. The vaso-protective benefits of E2 are well-described; higher circulating E2 begins&#xD;
      in female puberty, stimulating a long-term increase in the vascular expression of the E2&#xD;
      receptor's alpha isoform (ERα). ERα activation directly stimulates nitric oxide (NO)&#xD;
      production from endothelium-derived NO synthase and is critical to maintaining a healthy&#xD;
      vascular endothelium. Pre-menopausal women have an increased capacity to produce endothelial&#xD;
      NO due to higher E2 levels and vascular ERα expression, resulting in lower cardiovascular&#xD;
      disease risk vs age-matched cismen. These data suggest a novel paradigm for the impact of&#xD;
      GAHT on vascular health in transmen that differs depending on when GAHT is initiated relative&#xD;
      to puberty. The investigators hypothesize that, in transmen who have completed E2-driven&#xD;
      puberty, GAHT will induce a regression of vascular endothelial function towards that of&#xD;
      cismen by suppressing circulating E2 and ERα expression and that similar regression will not&#xD;
      be seen in transboys initiating GAHT prior to pubertal progression. The investigators&#xD;
      propose, to our knowledge, a first-of-its-kind longitudinal study of the cardiometabolic&#xD;
      impact of 1-year of GAHT in 40 transboys and transmen as compared to cisgender controls with&#xD;
      endogenous sex hormones. The impact of GAHT initiation and continuation in transboys/men on&#xD;
      in vivo and ex vivo vascular endothelial function, estrogen-stimulated endothelial&#xD;
      vasorelaxation, and expression of vascular ERα expression will be determined by measuring&#xD;
      changes in conduit vessel endothelium-dependent vasodilation and vascular E2 receptor&#xD;
      expression and responsiveness in transboys on puberty blockers and in transmen. The&#xD;
      investigators will also determine whether GAHT suppresses the human arteriolar vascular&#xD;
      expression of ERα receptors and reduces E2-stimulated endothelial vasorelaxation in&#xD;
      transboys/men relative to ciswomen. Secondarily, The investigators will characterize the&#xD;
      metabolic, body composition and inflammatory impact of GAHT. This study will provide a novel&#xD;
      mechanistic framework for the cardiometabolic impact of GAHT and make available critical&#xD;
      information for care providers and patients on how GAHT may affect their cardiovascular risk.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vascular endothelial function after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by brachial artery ultrasound flow-mediated dilation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effects of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on in vivo endothelial function by brachial artery ultrasound flow-mediated dilation across study visits.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vascular endothelial function after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by by blood pressure.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effects of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on in vivo endothelial function by blood pressure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vascular endothelial function after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by circulating markers of endothelial activation as measured by plasma analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effects of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on in vivo endothelial function by circulating markers of endothelial activation as measured by plasma analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body composition after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by BMI</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on body composition as quantified by body mass index (BMI).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body composition after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by DXA scans.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on body composition as quantified by total body dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) scan which provides information about the amount and distribution of fat and muscle in the body.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body composition after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by the ratio of waist-to-hip circumference.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on body composition as quantified by the ratio of waist-to-hip circumference which provides information about the amount and distribution of fat and muscle in the body.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lipid profile after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will measure the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on the various components of a fasting lipid profile (triglyceride level, HDL, LDL, and total cholesterol).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in systemic inflammation after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on circulating levels of inflammatory cytokines as measured by plasma analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in glucose metabolism after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by fasting insulin level in the blood.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on fasting insulin.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in glucose metabolism after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by fasting blood glucose level.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on fasting glucose.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in glucose metabolism after one year of gender-affirming testosterone therapy as measured by HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year from baseline study visit</time_frame>
    <description>Investigators will examine the effect of gender-affirming testosterone therapy on HbA1c levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Transgender</condition>
  <condition>Transgenderism</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transgender Males</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals assigned female gender at birth but considering gender-affirming testosterone therapy. May self-identify as transgender or nonbinary etc.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cisgender Controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals assigned male or female at birth. May identify as cisgender or nonbinary etc. These individuals should not be undergoing or considering any form of hormone therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Plasma from participants will be stored and analyzed in labs on the Medical College of&#xD;
      Wisconsin campus. All samples will be stored and labeled with coded study identification&#xD;
      numbers. Only de-identified samples and data will be shared. The use of these samples will be&#xD;
      subject to Medical College of Wisconsin IRB policies and procedures. All specimens and&#xD;
      records will be held for a minimum of 10 years from the date of the last entry in the record&#xD;
      of the last subject enrolled in the study&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA FOR TRANSGENDER AND CISGENDER INDIVIDUALS&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any disease affecting glucose, sex steroid, or fat metabolism such as diabetes,&#xD;
             polycystic ovary syndrome, or clinical suspicion of insulin resistance)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any medication use that may affect glucose, sex steroid, or fat metabolism such as&#xD;
             metformin or glucocorticoids&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known cardiovascular disease such as hypertension or atherosclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Raynaud's phenomenon or other vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. BMI &gt; 40 kg/m2 for those aged ≥ 18 years or &gt; 95% percentile for age- and sex-assigned&#xD;
             at birth in those aged &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any condition that, in the investigator's opinion, may compromise study participation&#xD;
             or may confound the interpretation of the study results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR TRANSGENDER BOYS AND TRANSGENDER MEN&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Sex assigned female at birth and a male gender identity (i.e., transgender male)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Aged 12-30 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Have a care provider in the Children's Wisconsin Gender Health Clinic or&#xD;
                  Froedtert Hospital Inclusion Clinic who has determined the individual meets&#xD;
                  clinical criteria to start testosterone therapy and plans to initiate this&#xD;
                  therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Naïve to testosterone or other masculinizing medical therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Cisgender girls/women and transgender boys/men of child-bearing potential&#xD;
                  (defined as having achieved menarche (first menses), excluding those who have had&#xD;
                  a hysterectomy or are on GnRH agonist therapy (puberty blockers)) must be willing&#xD;
                  to use effective birth control (which may include abstinence)) from screening&#xD;
                  visit until final study visit&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Willing and able to give informed consent or have parent or legal guardian&#xD;
                  provide informed consent if the subject is &lt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR CISGENDER INDIVIDUALS&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Gender identity concordant with sex assigned at birth (i.e., cisgender)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged 12-30 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Not related to a transgender participant enrolled in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Naïve to any sex hormone or pubertal blocker therapy or, specific to cisgender&#xD;
             girls/women only, must be ≥ 1 year from use of oral contraceptive or other&#xD;
             contraceptive technique (intrauterine device, medroxyprogesterone injections)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing and able to give informed consent or have parent or legal guardian provide&#xD;
             informed consent if the subject is &lt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA FOR OPTIONAL NITROGLYCERIN ENDOTHELIUM-INDEPENDENT VASCULAR FUNCTION&#xD;
        STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No history of migraine headaches&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Systolic blood pressure ≥ 110 mm Hg&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No prior past adverse reaction to nitroglycerin&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Has not used a PDE5 inhibitor (i.e., sildenafil, tadalafil, vardenafil) in the past 7&#xD;
             days&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Transgender individuals must have been assigned female at birth but identify as transgender/non-binary and interested in gender-affirming testosterone therapy.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical College of Wisconsin</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Susanne Cabrera</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

