<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04979364</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>POMI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04979364</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>French Version of POMI Scale</brief_title>
  <acronym>POMI</acronym>
  <official_title>Transcultural Validation of a French Version of the Prescription Opioid Misuse Idex Scale (POMI-5F)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital, Toulouse</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      French translation and validation of the Prescription Opioid Misuse Index scale (POMI), a&#xD;
      brief questionnaire to assess opioid prescription misuse. In view of the increase in the&#xD;
      prescription of opioid analgesics for chronic non-cancer pain (CNCP), this tool is&#xD;
      particularly interesting to use during medical consultations to screen misuse in opioids user&#xD;
      patients. We conducted an observational, prospective and multicenter psychometric study with&#xD;
      a cross-cultural validation in 154 CNCP patients treated by opioid at least from 3 months, in&#xD;
      two pain clinics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic pain prevalence in the general population was estimated at 31% in the world, which&#xD;
      makes it a major public health problem, not only because of its enormous impact on patients'&#xD;
      quality of life, but also because of its significant economic impact on society, with direct&#xD;
      and indirect costs. Despite the lack of scientific evidence demonstrating their long-term&#xD;
      benefits, analgesic opioids are largely used for treating chronic non-cancer pain (CNCP) lead&#xD;
      to an increase of opioid use in recent decades in developed countries. Indeed, worldwide,&#xD;
      opioid analgesic prescription use more than doubled from 2001 to 2013, most signiﬁcantly in&#xD;
      North America and in Western and Central Europe. Between years 2004 and 2017 in France, while&#xD;
      overall analgesic opioid prescription use in the general population decreased by 8.9%, the&#xD;
      used strong opioids increased by 104%. The same finding about increase in the use strong&#xD;
      opioids was made in USA, Canada and UK. However, the use of opioid analgesics is not without&#xD;
      risk, several international studies showed an increase opioid use disorders, hospitalizations&#xD;
      and deaths related to the use of opioid analgesics. In France, rates of prescribed&#xD;
      opioid-related hospital admissions increased by 167% from 2000 to 2017 and opioid-related&#xD;
      deaths signiﬁcantly increased by 146% (1,3 à 3,2 deaths / 1,000,000 habitants from 2000 to&#xD;
      2015). A similar observation can be made in the United States, where deaths from prescription&#xD;
      opioid overdose have risen sharply in recent years, but in a much higher proportion than in&#xD;
      France (in 2016 in the U.S., more than 42,000 overdose deaths, or an annual prevalence of 133&#xD;
      deaths/1,000,000 population).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the context of CNCP, opioid analgesics are subject to increasing misuse in relation to a&#xD;
      greater number of prescriptions but also through other sources of obtaining (doctor shopping)&#xD;
      hat may contribute to the increase in risks associated with the use of opioid analgesics&#xD;
      (hospitalization, death). Few studies in France, assessed the misuse of analgesic opioids,&#xD;
      based on the evaluation of &quot;doctor shopping&quot; from healthcare databases, and particularly,&#xD;
      Chenaf et al., showed an increase of analgesic opioids shopping behavior by 34%, between 2004&#xD;
      to 0.67% in 2017. It is therefore important to be able to identify analgesic opioid misuse.&#xD;
      Actually Prescription Opioid Misuse Index (POMI) scale was validated in 2008 by American team&#xD;
      in 137 patients recruited from community substance abuse treatment programs, regional jails,&#xD;
      pain clinics and private internal medicine practices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective was the cross-cultural validation of French version of an opioid&#xD;
      analgesic misuse screening scale (POMI) in chronic pain patients in primary care. The&#xD;
      secondary objective was the assessment of the relationship between pain intensity and&#xD;
      analgesic opioid misuse.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>psychometric properties of POMI scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Once. At inclusion (TEST phase)</time_frame>
    <description>Construct validity, internal consistency, test-retest reliability, and convergent validity of POMI scale French version (POMI-5F).&#xD;
POMI scale is a self-evaluation scale with 8 items scored 0 (absence) or 1 (presence). The questionnaire is presented in 8 questions, of which 6 are used to calculate a score which is the sum of positive answers; when this score reaches 2, it's considered as positive and describe a misuse.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>psychometric properties of POMI scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Once. At 2 to 4 weeks (Re-TEST phase)</time_frame>
    <description>Construct validity, internal consistency, test-retest reliability, and convergent validity of POMI scale French version (POMI-5F).&#xD;
POMI scale is a self-evaluation scale with 8 items scored 0 (absence) or 1 (presence). The questionnaire is presented in 8 questions, of which 6 are used to calculate a score which is the sum of positive answers; when this score reaches 2, it's considered as positive and describe a misuse.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">154</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Pain</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Misuse</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with chonic non-cancer pain.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients aged 18 or more, suffered from chronic non-cancer pain for at least 6 months,&#xD;
             with at least one analgesic opioid daily for 3 months, and follow in pain clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability to read or understand questionnaires alone, cancer, and impossibility to do&#xD;
             test and retest questionnaires.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

