<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04975178</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MTBVACN3</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04975178</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy, Safety and Immunogenicity Evaluation of MTBVAC in Newborns in Sub-Saharan Africa</brief_title>
  <acronym>MTBVACN3</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomised, Double-Blind, Controlled Phase 3 Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy, Safety and Immunogenicity of MTBVAC Administered in Healthy HIV Unexposed and HIV Exposed Uninfected Newborns in Tuberculosis-Endemic Regions of Sub-Saharan Africa</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Biofabri, S.L</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>TuBerculosis Vaccine Initiative</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Cape Town</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut Pasteur de Madagascar</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Biomedical Research Center EPLS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universidad de Zaragoza</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Stellenbosch</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of KwaZulu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wits Health Consortium (Pty) Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Biofabri, S.L</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this project is to demonstrate safety, immunogenicity and improved efficacy&#xD;
      of the new live attenuated M. tuberculosis vaccine called MTBVAC in a Phase 3 efficacy trial&#xD;
      in HIV-uninfected infants born to HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected mothers as compared to&#xD;
      standard of care BCG vaccination. The proposal builds upon a group of TB vaccine development&#xD;
      partners in Europe and sub-Saharan Africa established in a previous EDCTP-supported project.&#xD;
      It creates an expanded consortium of clinical trial partners for the optimal implementation&#xD;
      of a large infant efficacy trial of MTBVAC in high TB incidence settings. New capacity for&#xD;
      efficacy trials in infants will be a valuable resource for the TB vaccine development&#xD;
      community. The proposal will create a network of institutions in three TB endemic African&#xD;
      countries with enhanced laboratory capacity to conduct TB vaccine immunology studies and to&#xD;
      bio-bank samples to discover immune correlates of vaccine-mediated protection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A new effective tuberculosis (TB) vaccine is essential to achieve World Health Organization&#xD;
      End TB goals and eliminate TB by 2050. The optimal long-term strategy would be a combination&#xD;
      of serial mass campaigns in adults, coupled with universal newborn vaccination. Newborns are&#xD;
      the only human population without prior mycobacterial exposure in TB endemic countries and we&#xD;
      hypothesize that live attenuated mycobacterial vaccines will offer better protection to this&#xD;
      naïve population compared to adults.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this project is to demonstrate safety, immunogenicity and improved efficacy&#xD;
      of the new live attenuated M. tuberculosis vaccine called MTBVAC in a Phase 3 efficacy trial&#xD;
      in HIV-uninfected infants born to HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected mothers as compared to&#xD;
      standard of care BCG vaccination. The proposal builds upon a group of TB vaccine development&#xD;
      partners in Europe and sub-Saharan Africa established in a previous EDCTP-supported project.&#xD;
      It creates an expanded consortium of clinical trial partners for the optimal implementation&#xD;
      of a large infant efficacy trial of MTBVAC in high TB incidence settings. New capacity for&#xD;
      efficacy trials in infants will be a valuable resource for the TB vaccine development&#xD;
      community. The proposal will create a network of institutions in three TB endemic African&#xD;
      countries with enhanced laboratory capacity to conduct TB vaccine immunology studies and to&#xD;
      bio-bank samples to discover immune correlates of vaccine-mediated protection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MTBVAC is a novel TB vaccine candidate based on an attenuated M. tuberculosis clinical&#xD;
      isolate of the Euro-American lineage. Attenuation is based on two independent, stable genetic&#xD;
      deletions of the genes phoP and fadD26 coding for two major virulence factors, the&#xD;
      transcription factor PhoP and the cell-wall lipids PDIM, respectively. The hypothesis is that&#xD;
      MTBVAC will provide improved protection, as individuals latently infected with live&#xD;
      M.tuberculosis have an 80% lower chance of developing TB, and as MTBVAC contains most of the&#xD;
      genes deleted from BCG and presents a wider collection of antigens to the host immune system.&#xD;
      Preclinical studies in different animal models indicated that MTBVAC is safe and is able to&#xD;
      induce an improved protection compared to BCG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1 studies showed that MTBVAC was safe and immunogenic in naïve adults and newborns, and&#xD;
      evoked an immune response that exceeded the magnitude of BCG-induced immune responses. Larger&#xD;
      dose-defining Phase 2a studies in newborns and in adults at extended dose-ranges to confirm&#xD;
      these findings will be finalised in early 2021, and allow selection of a vaccine dose to&#xD;
      progress into the proposed multi-centre efficacy trial in infants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Safety and immunogenicity in 60 HUU infants at six sites (total 360 HUU infants) will be randomised to receive BCG/MTBVAC in a 1:1 fashion. Safety and immunogenicity in 100 HEU neonates randomised to receive BCG/MTBVAC in a 1:1 fashion will also be evaluated at four South African sites. Further enrolment of HUU infants into the efficacy cohort will be initiated without waiting for favourable review by DSMB. Enrolment of HEU infants into the efficacy cohort will be initiated only after favourable unblinded review of D84 safety data by the DSMB.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>MTBVAC and BCG vaccine will be prepared, and allocation concealed by the site pharmacist. All other site staff will be blinded to vaccine allocation, throughout the follow-up period. Data pertaining to the MTBVAC vaccine and to BCG control will be collected in an observer-blinded manner. Blinding will be maintained throughout the vaccination and follow-up portions of the vaccine trial. No set of individual codes will be held at Biofabri's Headquarters. Biofabri's Headquarters will be able to access the individual randomization code from the SATVI Pharmacy randomization register. The code will be broken by the Site's Pharmacist (Study Contact for Emergency Code Break) only in the case of medical events that the investigator/physician in charge of the participant feels cannot be treated without knowing the identity of the study vaccine(s). The Site's Pharmacist is responsible for unblinding the treatment assignment in accordance with specified time frames for expedited reporting of SAEs.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevention of tuberculosis disease in healthy HIV-uninfected (HU) and HIV-exposed uninfected (HEU) neonates</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 24 months to a maximum 72 months; or until study end in South Africa.</time_frame>
    <description>Diagnosis of confirmed or unconfirmed TB disease from the time of randomization.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as defined in protocol.</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 24 months to a maximum 72 months; or until study end in South Africa.</time_frame>
    <description>Solicited injection site reaction adverse events: pain, redness, swelling, ulceration, drainage, and regional lymphadenopathy.&#xD;
Solicited systemic adverse events: fever, irritability, vomiting, diarrhea, drowsiness, poor feeding, skin rash.&#xD;
Unsolicited adverse events and serious adverse events.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity analysis in HU and HEU infants</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 24 months to a maximum 72 months; or until study end in South Africa.</time_frame>
    <description>Frequencies and co-expression patterns of CD4 and CD8 T cells in whole blood.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Biobank samples</measure>
    <time_frame>Minimum of 24 months to a maximum 72 months; or until study end in South Africa.</time_frame>
    <description>Biobank samples for (future) biomarker studies.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">6960</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MTBVAC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Both MTBVAC and BCG vaccines are administered by intradermal route in the left deltoid region. One 0.05 mL reconstituted dose of MTBVAC will be defined based on the phase IIa results.&#xD;
MTBVAC is manufactured by Biofabri. MTBVAC is formulated (1.5 - 8.5 x104 CFU/dose, 1.5 - 8.5 x105 CFU/dose or 1.5 - 8.5 x106 CFU/dose (to be selected) and presented as a lyophilised pellet in 20 dose vials (0.05 mL/dose, after reconstitution with sterile water for injection). MTBVAC vaccine will be released and distributed by BIOFABRI, and imported to the sites following approval by the local regulatory authority. MTBVAC vials should be stored in the site pharmacy between -20°C and -40ºC. A single vaccine vial will be used for each participant.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BCG</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>BCG is a live attenuated M. bovis strain developed 100 years ago and is used as a preventive vaccine against tuberculosis. It is administered at birth.&#xD;
One 0.05 mL reconstituted dose of BCG contains 2.5 x 105 CFU. The control vaccine will be the BCG vaccine available and recommended in South Africa at time of the trial.&#xD;
BCG vaccine produced by AJ Biologics (formerly Staten Serum Institute) is the only BCG vaccine (Danish strain) currently licensed for routine use in South Africa. The recommended BCG injection volume for newborn infants (0.05 mL, after reconstitution with BCG diluent) contains approximately 2.5 x 105 CFU (range 1-4 x 105 CFU). BCG vaccine vials should be stored in the site pharmacy at 2-8ºC.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MTBVAC</intervention_name>
    <description>MTBVAC is a novel TB vaccine candidate based on an attenuated M. tuberculosis clinical isolate of the Euro-American lineage. Attenuation is based on two independent, stable genetic deletions of the genes phoP and fadD26 coding for two major virulence factors, the transcription factor PhoP and the cell-wall lipids PDIM, respectively. We hypothesize that MTBVAC will provide improved protection, as individuals latently infected with live M.tuberculosis have an 80% lower chance of developing TB, and as MTBVAC contains most of the genes deleted from BCG and presents a wider collection of antigens to the host immune system. Preclinical studies in different animal models indicated that MTBVAC is safe and is able to induce an improved protection compared to BCG.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MTBVAC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BCG</intervention_name>
    <description>BCG is a live attenuated M. bovis strain developed 100 years ago and is used as a preventive vaccine against tuberculosis. It is administered at birth.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BCG</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female newborns within seven days of birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed maternal consent, including permission to access maternal antenatal,&#xD;
             postnatal, and infant medical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infant participants and their caregivers available for trial follow-up and display the&#xD;
             willingness and capacity to comply with trial procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Newborns must be in good general health during pregnancy and delivery, as assessed by&#xD;
             medical history and targeted physical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Birth weight ≥ 2450 grams.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Apgar score at 5 minutes ≥ 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A maternal HIV test result (rapid test, enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA), or&#xD;
             Polymerase chain reaction (PCR)) taken within 30 days of delivery, or within seven&#xD;
             days post-partum must be available and documented if HIV uninfected. If the mother is&#xD;
             HIV infected, then she must be on antiretroviral (ARV) therapy as per in-country&#xD;
             guidelines with a viral load of &lt;50 copies/mL (within six months of labour).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estimated gestational age ≥ 37 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mother has not participated in a clinical trial within three months prior to the&#xD;
             infant's birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mother has never participated in a TB vaccine trial before.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infant may not participate in any other clinical trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Receipt of BCG vaccination prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant antenatal, intrapartum, or postpartum complications that may affect the&#xD;
             health of the newborn.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skin condition, bruising or birth mark at the intended injection site.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Maternal HIV test (rapid test, ELISA, or PCR) result not available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV exposed Newborn's HIV PCR result positive or not available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Maternal history of TB during pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of close/household contact with a TB patient, antenatal or postnatal, whether&#xD;
             maternal, other family member or another household member who has not yet completed TB&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically suspected neonatal sepsis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any severe congenital malformation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or evidence of any systemic disease on examination, or any illness that in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator may interfere with the evaluation of the safety and&#xD;
             immunogenicity of the vaccine. Neonatal jaundice not considered clinically significant&#xD;
             is not an exclusion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>7 Days</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark Hatherill</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Cape Town, Faculty of Health Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ingrid Murillo Jelsbak</last_name>
    <phone>+34 986 33 04 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>307</phone_ext>
    <email>ingrid.murillo@biofabri.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sara Barja</last_name>
    <phone>+34 986 33 04 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>306</phone_ext>
    <email>sara.barja@biofabri.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tameris M, Mearns H, Penn-Nicholson A, Gregg Y, Bilek N, Mabwe S, Geldenhuys H, Shenje J, Luabeya AKK, Murillo I, Doce J, Aguilo N, Marinova D, Puentes E, Rodríguez E, Gonzalo-Asensio J, Fritzell B, Thole J, Martin C, Scriba TJ, Hatherill M; MTBVAC Clinical Trial Team. Live-attenuated Mycobacterium tuberculosis vaccine MTBVAC versus BCG in adults and neonates: a randomised controlled, double-blind dose-escalation trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2019 Sep;7(9):757-770. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(19)30251-6. Epub 2019 Aug 12.</citation>
    <PMID>31416768</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spertini F, Audran R, Chakour R, Karoui O, Steiner-Monard V, Thierry AC, Mayor CE, Rettby N, Jaton K, Vallotton L, Lazor-Blanchet C, Doce J, Puentes E, Marinova D, Aguilo N, Martin C. Safety of human immunisation with a live-attenuated Mycobacterium tuberculosis vaccine: a randomised, double-blind, controlled phase I trial. Lancet Respir Med. 2015 Dec;3(12):953-62. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(15)00435-X. Epub 2015 Nov 17.</citation>
    <PMID>26598141</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arbues A, Aguilo JI, Gonzalo-Asensio J, Marinova D, Uranga S, Puentes E, Fernandez C, Parra A, Cardona PJ, Vilaplana C, Ausina V, Williams A, Clark S, Malaga W, Guilhot C, Gicquel B, Martin C. Construction, characterization and preclinical evaluation of MTBVAC, the first live-attenuated M. tuberculosis-based vaccine to enter clinical trials. Vaccine. 2013 Oct 1;31(42):4867-73. doi: 10.1016/j.vaccine.2013.07.051. Epub 2013 Aug 17.</citation>
    <PMID>23965219</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

