<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04974684</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A-21-23</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04974684</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DOT HeartMate 3 Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Direct Oral Anticoagulant Therapy With the HeartMate 3 LVAD: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A prospective, single-center, randomized controlled trial of the feasibility and safety of&#xD;
      apixaban in HeartMate 3 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HeartMate 3 (HM3) Left Ventricular Assist System (LVAS) is a centrifugal, fully magnetically&#xD;
      levitated, continuous-flow pump designed to facilitate hemocompatibility by reducing shear&#xD;
      stress on blood elements and to optimize pump washout by intrinsic pulsatility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Multicenter Study of MagLev Technology in Patients Undergoing Mechanical Circulatory&#xD;
      Support Therapy with HeartMate 3 (MOMENTUM 3) trial 2-year data demonstrated an absence of&#xD;
      confirmed pump thrombosis requiring pump exchange and marked reduction in stroke rates. On&#xD;
      the backdrop of conventional anticoagulation protocols used in the study, observed bleeding&#xD;
      complication rates in HM 3 were reduced, yet there is a need for further improvement as the&#xD;
      overall intensity of conventional anti-thrombotic therapy represents a major contributor to&#xD;
      non-surgical bleeding-related outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HM3 LVAS Instructions for Use (IFU) recommend maintaining patients on Warfarin and&#xD;
      Aspirin for long-term anticoagulation therapy. Recent results of The Minimal AnticoaGulation&#xD;
      EvaluatioN To aUgment heMocompatibility (MAGENTUM 1) pilot study has demonstrated&#xD;
      substantially lower-intensity anticoagulation (INR range 1.5 - 1.9) is achievable and&#xD;
      supports the safety of lower targets with select patients implanted with the HeartMate 3&#xD;
      beyond 1 year with no thromboembolic complications or pump thrombosis. The observed outcomes&#xD;
      were similar to those with the higher intensity anticoagulation targets and further support a&#xD;
      signal of enhanced intrinsic thromboresistance of the HM3.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Direct oral anticoagulants (DOACs) are a class of drugs which directly exert therapeutic&#xD;
      effect on specific coagulation factors. Broadly, they can be categorized as direct thrombin&#xD;
      inhibitors (dabigatran) and factor Xa inhibitors (apixaban, rivaroxaban, and edoxaban) or&#xD;
      FXai. Warfarin, which inhibits vitamin K dependent synthesis of coagulation factors in a&#xD;
      manner that prevents activation of these factors, has wide inter-individual variation in&#xD;
      metabolism and a narrow therapeutic window, as well as both food-drug and drug-drug&#xD;
      interactions; the result is that patients taking warfarin require frequent monitoring of the&#xD;
      anticoagulant effect to maintain safety and efficacy. The DOAC directly enter the blood to&#xD;
      bind to the activated coagulation factor target; they have predictable pharmacokinetics,&#xD;
      little interindividual variation in metabolism, few drug-drug interactions, and no&#xD;
      interactions with foods. The large phase 3 RCT in both AF and VTE established both efficacy&#xD;
      and safety-without the need for monitoring. The FXai may provide better anticoagulation than&#xD;
      the oral direct thrombin inhibitor due to their action earlier in the coagulation cascade&#xD;
      prior to the generation of thrombin which may ameliorate the likelihood of initiation of the&#xD;
      feedback loop resulting in &gt;1000-fold increase in thrombin production. Of the studied FXai ,&#xD;
      apixaban has the lowest major bleeding complication rate and has not been shown to increase&#xD;
      GI-bleeding. It also has the least dependence on renal clearance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consequently, with the documented enhanced hemocompatibility of the HeartMate 3 and the&#xD;
      potential for reduced major bleeding with apixaban in indicated patient populations, the&#xD;
      investigators provide the rationale that patients with the HM3 are in clinical equipoise to&#xD;
      be randomized in a feasibility study of a new antithrombotic strategy testing apixaban with&#xD;
      or without aspirin compared to the current standard of care warfarin and aspirin in a&#xD;
      rigorously structured study to evaluate safety in stable patients with the HM3 device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apixaban Safety and Efficacy Data Apixaban is a DOAC that directly inhibits Factor Xa (FXai)&#xD;
      in the coagulation cascade. Its therapeutic effect is more consistent and predictable due to&#xD;
      its mechanism of action, and it is not subject to the disadvantages inherent to Vitamin K&#xD;
      antagonist (VKA) anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The rationale for Apixaban use with the HeartMate 3 There have been no studies to date that&#xD;
      have systematically evaluated the feasibility of using apixaban alone or combined with low&#xD;
      dose aspirin in HM3 patients. All the primary phase 3 clinical trials assessing DOACs have&#xD;
      focused on patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation or venous thromboembolism with or&#xD;
      without cancer. Within the literature, there are sparse reports of apixaban use with LVAD&#xD;
      patients due to recurrent bleeding or non-compliance with warfarin. These small sample size&#xD;
      studies reported encouraging low rates of thromboembolic events. In all but one instance,&#xD;
      aspirin was withheld due to the history of bleeding events. Patients in these studies either&#xD;
      had the HeartMate II or HeartWare HVAD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reduction in bleeding and thromboembolic events with HeartMate 3 compared to the HeartMate II&#xD;
      was demonstrated by the MOMENTUM 3 IDE Trial. Yet, bleeding complications remain a burdensome&#xD;
      limitation while on support and represent a significant cause of rehospitalizations and&#xD;
      morbidity. Independently, both a reduction in major bleeding events and stable&#xD;
      anticoagulation intensity constitute a compelling potential benefit of a modified&#xD;
      antithrombotic strategy with a direct oral anticoagulant. However, these apixaban associated&#xD;
      benefits remain to be validated in advanced heart failure population supported with the&#xD;
      HeartMate 3 LVAS. Therefore, the objective of this study is to assess safety and feasibility&#xD;
      of apixaban use in HM3 supported patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA COLLECTION &amp; FOLLOW-UP ASSESSMENTS The patient will be assessed at baseline. Lactate&#xD;
      dehydrogenase (LDH) will be assessed once a week for 4 weeks, then once every 2 weeks for the&#xD;
      next month and monthly thereafter; TTE ECHO follow-up will be performed at baseline, at 1&#xD;
      month and at 3 months, followed until study completion per site standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of hemocompatibility related adverse events during apixaban use with the HeartMate 3 LVAS</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation survival free of major hemocompatibility related adverse events (HRAEs). Comparison of HRAEs in apixaban and control group per protocol. Separate analysis in patients randomized to receive aspirin and no-aspirin within the apixaban group as specified in protocol.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of adverse events defined by INTERMACS definitions</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year.</time_frame>
    <description>The events evaluated are as follows:&#xD;
Stroke (ischemic/hemorrhagic)&#xD;
Pump thrombosis&#xD;
Major bleeding&#xD;
GI Bleeding&#xD;
Peripheral arterial thromboembolic events&#xD;
Transient ischemic attack&#xD;
Hemolysis&#xD;
Venous thromboembolism&#xD;
Myocardial infarction&#xD;
Right heart failure&#xD;
Cardiac arrhythmias&#xD;
Liver and kidney dysfunction&#xD;
Death due to any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>LVAD (Left Ventricular Assist Device) Thrombosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HeartMate 3</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients implanted with HeartMate 3 will be randomized in 2:1 ratio in interventional and control group. Patients in interventional group will be switched to therapy with apixaban instead of warfarin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Apixaban</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients implanted with HeartMate 3 will be randomized in 2:1 ratio in interventional and control group. Patients in interventional group will be switched to therapy with apixaban instead of warfarin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interventional group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient has been implanted with HeartMate 3 LVAS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is, at a minimum, 3 months post HeartMate 3 implant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is stable, ambulatory, and has been discharged home&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient provides written informed consent before any clinical investigation&#xD;
             related procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-compliance with anticoagulation and antiplatelet medication, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight ≤ 60 kgs. or age ≥ 80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poor kidney function with serum creatinine ≥ 221umol/L or creatinine clearance &lt; 0.042&#xD;
             mL/s, or the need for chronic renal replacement therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin &gt; 43 umol/L, shock liver, or biopsy-proven liver cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of an informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of any mechanical prosthetic valve or any ancillary circulatory assist device&#xD;
             system (other than the HM3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent history of cardioembolic stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemodynamically significant carotid arteries stenosis (documented by imaging&#xD;
             investigation not older than 12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need for antiplatelet therapy for reasons other than LVAD therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major HRAE event after HeartMate 3 index hospitalization discharge&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of hyper- or hypo- coagulable disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anti-phospholipid syndrome positive patients with documented history of&#xD;
             thrombotic/thromboembolic events&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or allergy to apixaban or aspirin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is involved in another interventional study or any study that could&#xD;
             potentially affect the functioning of the HM3 LVAD or the therapeutic effect of any of&#xD;
             the study anticoagulants (warfarin, apixaban or aspirin), or could potentially&#xD;
             confound the study results&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is currently pregnant, breastfeeding, or intending to get pregnant during&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of other anatomic or comorbid conditions, or other medical, social,&#xD;
             non-compliance or psychological conditions that, in the investigator's opinion, could&#xD;
             limit the subject's ability to participate in the clinical investigation or to comply&#xD;
             with follow-up requirements or impact the scientific soundness of the clinical&#xD;
             investigation results.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ivan Netuka</last_name>
    <phone>+420261365016</phone>
    <email>ivan.netuka@ikem.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Peter Ivak</last_name>
    <email>peter.ivak@ikem.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institute for Clinical and Experimental Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Ivan Netuka, MD, Ph.D.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chairman of the Cardiovascular Surgery Department</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HeartMate 3</keyword>
  <keyword>LVAD (Left Ventricular Assist Device)</keyword>
  <keyword>NOAC</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apixaban</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 25, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/84/NCT04974684/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

