<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01174108</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100154</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-H-0154</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01174108</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation for Severe Aplastic Anemia and Other Bone Marrow Failure Syndromes Using G-CSF Mobilized CD34+ Selected Hematopoietic Precursor Cells Co-Infused With a Reduced Dose of Non-Mobilized Donor T-cells</brief_title>
  <official_title>Allogeneic Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplantation for Severe Aplastic Anemia and Other Bone Marrow Failure Syndromes Using G-CSF Mobilized CD34+ Selected Hematopoietic Precursor Cells Co-Infused With a Reduced Dose of Non-Mobilized Donor T-Cells</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Stem cell transplants from related donors (allogenic stem cell transplants) can be used&#xD;
           to treat individuals with certain kinds of severe blood diseases or cancers, such as&#xD;
           severe anemia. Allogenic stem cell transplants encourage the growth of new bone marrow&#xD;
           to replace that of the recipient. Because stem cell transplants can have serious&#xD;
           complications, researchers are interested in developing new approaches to stem cell&#xD;
           transplants that will reduce the likelihood of these complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  By reducing the number of white blood cells included in the blood taken during the stem&#xD;
           cell collection process, and replacing them with a smaller amount of white blood cells&#xD;
           collected prior to stem cell donation, the stem cell transplant may be less likely to&#xD;
           cause severe complications for the recipient. Researchers are investigating whether&#xD;
           altering the stem cell transplant donation procedure in this manner will improve the&#xD;
           likelihood of a successful stem cell transplant with fewer complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To evaluate a new method of stem cell transplantation that may reduce the possibly of&#xD;
      severe side effects or transplant rejection in the recipient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recipient: Individuals between 4 and 80 years of age who have been diagnosed with a&#xD;
           blood disease that can be treated with allogenic stem cell transplants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Donor: Individuals between 4 and 80 years of age who are related to the recipient and&#xD;
           are eligible to donate blood. OR unrelated donors found through the National Marrow&#xD;
           Donor Program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All participants will be screened with a physical examination and medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  DONORS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Donors will undergo an initial apheresis procedure to donate white blood cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the initial donation, donors will receive injections of filgrastim to release bone&#xD;
           marrow cells into the blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After 5 days of filgrastim injections, donors will have apheresis again to donate stem&#xD;
           cells that are present in the blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  RECIPIENTS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recipients will provide an initial donation of white blood cells to be used for research&#xD;
           purposes only.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  From 7 days before the stem cell transplant, participants will be admitted to the&#xD;
           inpatient unit of the National Institutes of Health Clinical Center and will receive&#xD;
           regular doses of cyclophosphamide, fludarabine, and anti-thymocyte globulin to suppress&#xD;
           their immune system and prepare for the transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the initial chemotherapy, participants will receive the donated white blood cells&#xD;
           and stem cells as a single infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the stem cell and white blood cell transplant, participants will have regular&#xD;
           doses of cyclosporine and methotrexate to prevent rejection of the donor cells.&#xD;
           Participants will have three doses of methotrexate within the week after the transplant,&#xD;
           but will continue to take cyclosporine for up to 4 months after the transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will remain in inpatient care for up to 1 month after the transplant, and&#xD;
           will be followed with regular visits for up to 3 years with periodic visits thereafter&#xD;
           to evaluate the success of the transplant and any side effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (aHSCT) can cure patients with a variety&#xD;
      of bone marrow failure syndromes (BMFS) including severe aplastic anemia (SAA), paroxysmal&#xD;
      nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH) or myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS) associated with cytopenias.&#xD;
      Patients with BMFS have traditionally been transplanted with bone marrow (BM) as a stem cell&#xD;
      source. Although chronic graft versus host disease (cGVHD) occurs less commonly with BM&#xD;
      compared to filgrastim (G-CSF) mobilized peripheral blood stem cell (PBSC) transplants, BM&#xD;
      allografts have lower CD34+ progenitor cell numbers, which increases the risk of graft&#xD;
      rejection in heavily transfused BMFS patients to 15-20%. To overcome this risk, our group&#xD;
      developed a novel transplant approach for patients at high risk for graft rejection that&#xD;
      utilized cyclophosphamide, fludarabine and anti-thymocyte globulin (ATG) conditioning&#xD;
      followed by infusion of a CD34+ cell rich, T-cell replete G-CSF mobilized PBSC allograft.&#xD;
      Remarkably, in 56 consecutive BMFS patients who had multiple risk factors for graft rejection&#xD;
      who underwent this transplant approach, graft rejection did not occur, with all patients&#xD;
      achieving complete donor lymphohematopoietic chimerism. Unfortunately, recipients of G-CSF&#xD;
      mobilized PBSC had a higher incidence of cGVHD than has historically been observed with BM&#xD;
      transplantation (72% vs. 50% cumulative incidence of cGVHD at 1 year respectively). G-CSF&#xD;
      mobilized PBSC transplants contained approximately a 20 fold higher dose of T-cells that had&#xD;
      undergone a TH-2 type cytokine polarization, a factor which likely contributed to this high&#xD;
      incidence of cGVHD. In this protocol, we attempt to prevent graft failure and to reduce the&#xD;
      incidence of cGVHD by transplanting high numbers of CD34+ selected PBSC co-infused with a&#xD;
      reduced dose of non-mobilized donor T-cells that have not undergone a TH-2 cytokine&#xD;
      polarization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects with BMFS at high risk for graft rejection will undergo allogeneic stem cell&#xD;
      transplantation from an HLA identical sibling or match unrelated donor using the identical&#xD;
      conditioning regimen utilized in protocol 99- H-0050. Using the Miltenyi CliniMACs system,&#xD;
      recipients will receive an allograft on day 0 containing donor CD34+ cells that have been&#xD;
      positively selected and T-cell depleted following G-CSF mobilization (goal CD34+ cell dose of&#xD;
      5 x 106 CD34+ cells /kg recipient) combined with 2 x 107 cells/kg of non-mobilized CD3+&#xD;
      T-cells previously collected and cryopreserved from the same donor by apheresis prior to&#xD;
      G-CSF mobilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective: To evaluate whether administering a CD34+ selected, T-cell depleted&#xD;
      peripheral blood stem cell graft with a concomitant infusion of non-mobilized donor T-cells&#xD;
      at a dose that matches the T-cell dose that is infused in historical bone marrow transplant&#xD;
      cohorts will reduce the incidence of cGVHD at 1 year to that observed with a conventional&#xD;
      bone marrow transplant (50%) without increasing the risk of graft failure. This trial design&#xD;
      will allow the trial to stop early if it is unlikely that we have reduced the proportion of&#xD;
      one year cGVHD to 50% or if the combined event rate for failed donor engraftment or treatment&#xD;
      related mortality (TRM) at day 100 exceeds 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint of this study will be cGVHD at day 365.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary end points include transplant related mortality, engraftment, degree of donor-host&#xD;
      chimerism, incidence of acute and chronic graft versus host disease (cGVHD), transplant&#xD;
      related morbidity and overall survival. Health related quality of life will also be assessed&#xD;
      as a secondary outcome measure pre-transplant, 30 and 100 days post transplant, and every 6&#xD;
      months until 5 years post transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects with BMFS at high risk for graft rejection will undergo allogeneic stem cell&#xD;
      transplantation from an HLA identical sibling or match unrelated donor using the identical&#xD;
      conditioning regimen utilized in protocol 99-H-0050. Using the Miltenyi CliniMACs system,&#xD;
      recipients will receive an allograft on day 0 containing donor CD34+ cells that have been&#xD;
      positively selected and T-cell depleted following G-CSF mobilization (goal CD34+ cell dose of&#xD;
      5 times 10(6) CD34+ cells /kg recipient) combined with 2 times 10(7) cells/kg of&#xD;
      non-mobilized CD3+ T-cells previously collected and cryopreserved from the same donor by&#xD;
      apheresis prior to G-CSF mobilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective: To evaluate whether administering a CD34+ selected, T-cell depleted&#xD;
      peripheral blood stem cell graft with a concomitant infusion of non-mobilized donor T-cells&#xD;
      at a dose that matches the T-cell dose that is infused in historical bone marrow transplant&#xD;
      cohorts will reduce the incidence of cGVHD at 1 year to that observed with a conventional&#xD;
      bone marrow transplant (50 percent) without increasing the risk of graft failure. This trial&#xD;
      design will allow the trial to stop early if it is unlikely that we have reduced the&#xD;
      proportion of one year cGVHD to 50 percent or if the combined event rate for failed donor&#xD;
      engraftment or treatment related mortality (TRM) at day 100 exceeds 20 percent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint of this study will be cGVHD at day 365.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary end points include transplant related mortality, engraftment, degree of donor-host&#xD;
      chimerism, incidence of acute and chronic graft versus host disease (GVHD), transplant&#xD;
      related morbidity and overall survival. Health related quality of life will also be assessed&#xD;
      as a secondary outcome measure pre-transplant, 30 and 100 days post transplant and every 6&#xD;
      months until 5 years post transplant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 10, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary endpoint of this study is chronic GVHD by one year.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>chronic GVHD</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Severe Aplastic Anemia</condition>
  <condition>MDS (Myelodysplastic Syndrome)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Target doses: CD34+ cells 8 x 106/kg; CD3+ cells 2 x 107/kg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Donor</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Miltenyi CD34 Reagent System</intervention_name>
    <description>The CliniMACS CD34 Reagent System is a medical device that is used in vitro to select and enrich specific cell populations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Donor derived G-CSF mobilized PBC</intervention_name>
    <description>Cell Therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recipient:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients diagnosed with one of the following hematologic diseases which are&#xD;
                  associated with reasonable longevity, shown to be curable by allogeneic BMT but&#xD;
                  where concern for a high procedural mortality with conventional BMT may delay or&#xD;
                  prevent such treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  1) Paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH) associated with&#xD;
                       life-threatening thrombosis, and/or cytopenia, and/or transfusion dependence&#xD;
                       and/or recurrent and debilitating hemolytic crisis&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  2) Severe aplastic anemia (SAA) or pure red cell aplasia (PRCA [acquired or&#xD;
                       congenital]) associated with transfusion dependence and/or neutropenia in&#xD;
                       patients who are not candidates for, or who have failed immunosuppressive&#xD;
                       therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  3) Refractory anemia (RA) or RARS MDS patients who have associated&#xD;
                       transfusion dependence and/or neutropenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ages 4 to 80 (both inclusive), and weight &gt;18kg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Availability of HLA identical or single HLA locus mismatched family donor or&#xD;
                  10/10 matched unrelated donor at the allelic level (HLA alleles A, B, C, DR, and&#xD;
                  DQ).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  9/10 donors where all the HLA sequences have the same antigen/peptide binding&#xD;
                  domains in key exons to the patient. This can result in identical protein&#xD;
                  sequences between patient and donor. Allele mismatches in p and g groups can be&#xD;
                  considered acceptable due to the exact matching which exists in the binding&#xD;
                  domains.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Telomere Length Testing&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Germline/Inherited gene panel in patients where a suspicion for a familial bone&#xD;
                  marrow failure syndrome (BMFS) exists, hTERC and hTERT, GATA2 mutation testing&#xD;
                  will be performed on protocol 04-H-0012 or performed elsewhere prior to enrolling&#xD;
                  on 04-H-0012.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Recipient: any of the following&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major anticipated illness or organ failure incompatible with survival from PBSC&#xD;
             transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diffusion capacity of carbon monoxide (DLCO) &lt;40% predicted (patients under the age of&#xD;
             10 may be excluded from this criterion if they have difficulty performing the test&#xD;
             correctly and thus are unable to have their DLCO assessed) using DL Adj and DL/VA/Adj.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40% (evaluated by ECHO)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine greater than 2.5mg/dl or creatinine clearance less than 50 ml/min by&#xD;
             24 hr urine collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum bilirubin greater than 4 mg/dl, transaminases greater than 5 times the upper&#xD;
             limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fanconi s anemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status of 3 or more (See Bone &amp; Marrow Transplant Consortium&#xD;
             Supportive Care Guidelines for HSCT Recipients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other malignant diseases liable to relapse or progress within 5 years, with the&#xD;
             exception of a separate hematologic malignancy where allogeneic stem cell transplant&#xD;
             has been shown to be potentially curative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of an active infection not adequately responding to appropriate therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to comprehend the investigational nature of the study and provide informed&#xD;
             consent. The procedure will be explained to subjects age 8 -17 years with formal&#xD;
             consent being obtained from parents or legal guardian.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Related Donor:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Related donor deemed suitable and eligible, and willing to donate, per clinical&#xD;
             evaluations who are additionally willing to donate blood samples for research. Related&#xD;
             donors will be evaluated in accordance with existing Standard Policies and Procedures&#xD;
             for determination of eligibility and suitability for clinical donation. Note that&#xD;
             participation in this study is offered to all related donors, but study participation&#xD;
             is not required for a donor to make a stem cell donation, so it is possible that not&#xD;
             all related donors will enroll onto this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 4 and less than or equal to 80 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Related Donor: None&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA &amp; EXCLUSION CRITERIA: Unrelated Donor&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Donor eligibility will be completed per NMDP standards and in accordance with most recent&#xD;
        and stringent FDA guidelines.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard W Childs, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melissa M Spencer, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-5609</phone>
    <email>melissa.spencer@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland at Baltimore/MPRC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catonsville</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21228</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nancy Hardy, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>410-328-1230</phone>
      <email>nhardy12@umm.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Marrow Donor Program</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2010-H-0154.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 12, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 31, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 31, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 3, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS)</keyword>
  <keyword>Severe Aplastic Anemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Pure Red Cell Aplasia</keyword>
  <keyword>Paroxysmal Nocturnal Hemoglobinuria (PNH)</keyword>
  <keyword>Miltenyi CD34 Reagent System</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Aplastic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Marrow Failure Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pancytopenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

