<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01179646</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SP796</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01179646</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bioequivalence Study of Pantoprazole 40 mg DR Tablets and Protonix 40 mg Tablets</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pharmacokinetic Study to Determine the Bioequivalence of a Test 40 mg Pantoprazole Delayed-Release Tablet, Compared to a Marketed 40 mg Pantoprazole Delayed-Release Tablet (Protonix, Wyeth Pharmaceuticals) When Administered to Healthy Adult Subjects in the Fasted State</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kremers Urban Development Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kremers Urban Development Company</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study was to determine the single-dose bioequivalence of the test&#xD;
      product, a potential generic 40 mg pantoprazole delayed-release tablet formulation, compared&#xD;
      with the reference product, a pantoprazole 40 mg delayed-release tablet formulation&#xD;
      (Protonix, Wyeth Pharmaceuticals), following a single dose in the fasted state.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The 90% CI for pantoprazole ln(Cmax), ln[AUC(0-t)], and ln[AUC(0-inf)] for the comparison of&#xD;
      the test product (pantoprazole) versus the reference product (Protonix) should be within the&#xD;
      80 to 125% range required for the conclusion of bioequivalence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2004</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2004</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax (maximum observed concentration of drug substance in plasma)</measure>
    <time_frame>16 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-t (area under the concentration-time curve from time zero to time of last measurable concentration)</measure>
    <time_frame>16 hours</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-inf area under the concentration-time curve from time zero to infinity)</measure>
    <time_frame>16 hoyurs</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Protonix</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Protonix 40 mg DR Tablet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pantoprazole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pantoprazole 40 mg DR Tablet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pantoprazole 40 mg DR Tablet vs. Protonix 40 mg DR Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>Single dose crossover BE study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pantoprazole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Protonix</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Protonix 40 mg DR Tablet (Wyeth Pharmaceuticals)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non tobacco/nicotine-using (6 months minimum) healthy males and females between 19 and&#xD;
             50 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight from 15% below or 15% above, inclusive, the ideal weight for height and&#xD;
             estimated frame, as adapted from the 1983 Metropolitan Life Table.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects were surgically sterile, at least two years postmenopausal, or if&#xD;
             sexually active, had a partner who had been vasectomized for at least 6 months, or&#xD;
             agreed to utilize one of the following forms of contraception: barrier (condom with&#xD;
             spermicide or diaphragm with spermicide), IUD, or hormonal (oral, implant, transdermal&#xD;
             patch, or injection) for the following specified times.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects using hormonal contraceptives were on a stable dose for 3 months prior to dosing,&#xD;
        or they agreed to also use a barrier method of birth control from screening through&#xD;
        completion of the study. Subjects having an intrauterine device (IUD) must have had the IUD&#xD;
        in place for at least 2 months prior to dosing, or they agreed to also use a barrier method&#xD;
        of birth control from screening through completion of the study. For other forms of birth&#xD;
        control, the subject had used the method at least 2 weeks prior to screening and agreed to&#xD;
        use the method through completion of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Voluntary consent to participate in this study as demonstrated by signing the informed&#xD;
             consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons of Asian origin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who were pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinically significant gastrointestinal, renal, hepatic, neurologic,&#xD;
             hematologic, endocrine, oncologic, pulmonary, immunologic, psychiatric, or&#xD;
             cardiovascular disease, or any other condition that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator, could jeopardize the safety of the subject or impact the validity of the&#xD;
             study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity, allergic or adverse response to pantoprazole or related&#xD;
             drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive results from HIV antibody screen, hepatitis B surface antigen screen, and/or&#xD;
             hepatitis C antibody screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in a previous clinical trial within 30 days prior to study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Donation of one pint or more of whole blood within 56 days prior to study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Donation of 2 units of red blood cells within 112 days prior to study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Donation of plasma with 7 days prior to study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Difficulty in swallowing medication or any gastrointestinal disease that could affect&#xD;
             the drug absorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal diet or substantial changes in eating habits within 30 days prior to study&#xD;
             initiation. Examples included, but were not limited to, vegetarian, fasting, or liquid&#xD;
             supplement, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with any known enzyme-altering agents (barbiturates, phenothiazines, or&#xD;
             cimetidine, etc.) within 30 days prior to study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any prescription medication (except hormonal contraceptives for females) within&#xD;
             14 days prior to study initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any over-the-counter (OTC) medication, including mega-dose vitamins,&#xD;
             analgesics, herbal/nutritional supplements, and antacids, within 7 days prior to study&#xD;
             initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive urine screen for alcohol or drugs of abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to eat the food as provided in the study menu.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &lt;12.0 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of alcohol or drug abuse within 2 years prior to dosing.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alan Marion, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MDS Pharma Services</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MDS Pharma Services</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lincoln</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68502</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 10, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 11, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 10, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 10, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">August 11, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Alan S. Marion, MD, PhD</name_title>
    <organization>MDS Pharma Services (US) Inc.</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bioequivalency</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pantoprazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>August 12, 2010</submitted>
    <returned>September 8, 2010</returned>
    <submitted>September 8, 2010</submitted>
    <returned>September 29, 2010</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

