<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01179009</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201202157</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01179009</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment Resistant Depression (Pilot)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Safe Ketamine-Based Therapy for Treatment Resistant Depression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Florida Atlantic University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Treatment resistant depression (TRD) is a major public health problem. Current therapeutic&#xD;
      options for this patient population remain limited. With all available treatments, only a&#xD;
      sub-set of those patients who achieve an antidepressant response are likely to achieve&#xD;
      treatment-induced remission. The need for antidepressant medication that can provide both&#xD;
      rapid and long lasting relief of TRD symptoms is widely recognized. There is new evidence&#xD;
      that drugs that block NMDA glutamate receptors (NMDA antagonists) are promising candidates&#xD;
      for meeting this need. Existing studies in TRD have used only a low-dose, brief infusion of&#xD;
      ketamine that would not be expected to re-sensitize the NMDA receptor; in agreement with this&#xD;
      theory, these prior studies have found only temporary improvements of depression. Our key&#xD;
      hypothesis is that a higher-dose, longer-term ketamine infusion, such as that used in chronic&#xD;
      pain studies, would provide a more robust and lasting improvement from depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Accordingly, we will be test whether a 100-hour ketamine infusion would be more effective&#xD;
      than the standard 40-minute ketamine infusion currently used in other TRD studies. We will&#xD;
      randomize subjects to one of 2 arms: (1) 100-hour (+/- 4 hours) ketamine infusion plus&#xD;
      clonidine for the entire infusion (2) 40-minute ketamine infusion (plus clonidine) following&#xD;
      a 100+/- hour saline infusion. All subjects will receive clonidine, an alpha-2 agonist, to&#xD;
      minimize side effects of ketamine (namely, brief/mild psychotic and cognitive symptoms).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A subset of patients with TRD will also receive a 100-hour (+/- 4-hours) ketamine infusion&#xD;
      with two head MRIs pre-infusion and one head MRI post-infusion and/or weekly maintenance IM&#xD;
      injections of either ketamine or active CNS placebo, lorazepam for up to 16 weeks. Little&#xD;
      research has been done on the mechanism of ketamine's putative antidepressant action. There&#xD;
      is now a consensus that, in the early stages of the novel treatment development for&#xD;
      depression, clinical studies should be paired with mechanistic studies (neuroimaging) to&#xD;
      understand the underlying mechanism and validate this as a treatment target. Ketamine is&#xD;
      thought to have an antidepressant effect by increasing synaptic connections and therefore&#xD;
      increasing connectivity in critical cognitive/emotional circuits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This experiment is a pilot study involving up to 20 healthy males or females between the ages&#xD;
      of 18-65 to test whether a 100-hour ketamine infusion plus clonidine would be more effective,&#xD;
      with longer lasting results, then the standard 40-minute ketamine infusion (plus clonidine).&#xD;
      Each of the 2 arms, will be evaluated using a between subject, double-blind, randomized&#xD;
      design. An additional subset of 20 non-randomized patients, separate from the original&#xD;
      randomized clinical trial (RTC), will receive an MRI pre and post ketamine infusion and/or&#xD;
      weekly maintenance IM injections of either ketamine or active CNS placebo, lorazepam for up&#xD;
      to 16 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. a. Controlled up to 100-hour IV ketamine infusion b. clonidine safener PO prior to&#xD;
           infusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. a. Controlled 40-minute IV ketamine infusion b. clonidine safener PO prior to infusion&#xD;
           c. up to 100-hour(+/-)IV placebo (saline) infusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. a. Controlled up to 100-hour IV ketamine infusion b. clonidine safener PO prior to&#xD;
           infusion c. MRI pre and post ketamine infusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. a.Controlled up to 100-hour IV ketamine infusion b. clonidine safener PO prior to&#xD;
           infusion c. responders after up to 100-hour IV ketamine infusion receive IM injections&#xD;
           of ketamine or lorazepam In both conditions and the neuroimaging subset, participants&#xD;
           will be admitted to the Washington University School of Medicine Clinical Research Unit&#xD;
           at Barnes-Jewish Hospital for approximately 108-hours (Monday morning-Friday evening).&#xD;
           Pulse, blood pressure, pulse-oximetry, and an electrocardiogram strip will be routinely&#xD;
           monitored. Serial labs and clinical/safety ratings will be done pre-, during, and&#xD;
           post-infusion, with the last assessments being used to assure that subjects have&#xD;
           returned to their &quot;baseline&quot; prior to discharge from the research unit. Participants&#xD;
           will continue to see their primary psychiatrist throughout the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in (1) Clinical Global Interview (CGI) scores and (2) Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRS) scores</measure>
    <time_frame>approximately 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Primary Aim 1: To evaluate the efficacy and tolerability of a single safener for the prevention of ketamine-induced psychotomimetic effects in healthy humans.&#xD;
Primary Aim 2: To evaluate the effect of a standardized IV ketamine plus optimal safener combination treatment on change in the severity of depression in patients with TRD.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Disorder, Treatment-Resistant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 100-hour infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100-hour infusion of ketamine plus a safener (clonidine)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 40-minute infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>40-minute ketamine infusion following a 100-hours +/- placebo (saline) infusion. Participants will also receive a safener (clonidine)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine IM injections</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>One-2 weeks after the end of the 96-hour ketamine infusion, subjects assigned to the ketamine maintenance arm will return for ketamine maintenance injections (0.5-5 mg/kg, IM).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lorazepam IM Injections</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects randomized to the lorazepam control arm will also return for IM lorazepam maintenance injections 2 mg IM (range 0.5 - 4).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Controlled IV ketamine infusion (0.00225mg/kg-min. [18% (0.0125 mg/kg-min.). A subset of participants will receive ketamine maintenance injections (0.5-5 mg/kg, IM) for up to 16 weeks after 100-hour infusion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 100-hour infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 40-minute infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine IM injections</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ketalar</other_name>
    <other_name>Ketalin</other_name>
    <other_name>Ketalor</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clonidine</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive an approximately 5-day pretreatment of clonidine (max. dose 1mg/day divided doses) prior to and throughout the ketamine infusion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 100-hour infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 40-minute infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine IM injections</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>lorazepam IM Injections</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Catapares</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>IV saline (i.e. placebo ketamine)</description>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 40-minute infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>lorazepam IM Injections</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>saline</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Scopolamine Transdermal Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Some participants will receive a scopolamine transdermal patch prior to and throughout their infusion/injections visits.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine 100-hour infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ketamine IM injections</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>lorazepam IM Injections</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Transderm scop, Scopace, Maldemar</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>lorazepam Injection</intervention_name>
    <description>A subset of participants will receive lorazepam IM maintenance injections for up to 16 weeks after 100-hour infusion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>lorazepam IM Injections</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ativan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. males and females aged 18-65 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Diagnostic and Statistical Manual (DSM) IV diagnosis of Major Depressive Disorder,&#xD;
             recurrent, severe;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. depression must be considered treatment refractory as defined by Montgomery Asberg&#xD;
             Depression Rating Scale (MADRS) score of 22 or above which is consistent with other&#xD;
             studies;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. on a stable dose of permitted antidepressant medication or no medication pre-infusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. not currently psychotic and no history of psychosis within the previous 12 months;&#xD;
             psychosis reported in the distant past may not be exclusionary if brief, per PI's&#xD;
             judgment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. no history of significant clinical or intolerable side effects or complications from&#xD;
             clonidine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. if a female of child-bearing potential: not pregnant or breast feeding and agrees to&#xD;
             use birth control during the time of pre-dosing and infusions; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. confirmed bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, or schizoaffective disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. current or recent substance abuse/dependence (or any lifetime recreational ketamine or&#xD;
             PCP use);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. any severe Axis II personality disorder or schizophrenia spectrum disorder that, in&#xD;
             the PI's judgment, could confound diagnosis or adherence to treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. the presence of any abnormal laboratory findings or serious medical disorder or&#xD;
             condition that may, in the judgment of the PI, confound the assessment of relevant&#xD;
             biologic measures or diagnoses including: clinically significant organ system&#xD;
             dysfunction; significant and uncontrolled endocrine disease, including diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus; hypothyroidism; cardiovascular disease; coagulopathy; significant anemia;&#xD;
             significant acute infection; glaucoma; dehydration; epilepsy; any diagnosed cardiac&#xD;
             condition causing documented hemodynamic compromise or dysfunction of the SA or AV&#xD;
             node; any diagnosed respiratory condition causing documented or clinically recognized&#xD;
             hypoxia (e.g., chronic obstructive or restrictive pulmonary disease); after&#xD;
             evaluation, anyone determined to have a potentially compromised airway that could be&#xD;
             difficult to intubate; fever; BMI less than 14.5; or any medical condition known to&#xD;
             interfere with cognitive performance; medication-related exclusions include memantine,&#xD;
             or any medication that could be considered contraindicated ketamine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. current treatment with any medication contraindicated with ketamine or clonidine;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. lifetime illegal use of PCP or ketamine; no clinical use of ketamine for past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. meets DSM-IV criteria for Mental Retardation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. currently hospitalized;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. acutely suicidal or homicidal (i.e., in imminent danger with plan, urges and intent to&#xD;
             harm oneself or others) including any prior serious attempts (e.g., those requiring&#xD;
             hospitalization) at the PI's discretion;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. is pregnant or breast-feeding; unwilling to use birth control if female of child&#xD;
             bearing potential&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. unable to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. For participants in the neuroimaging subset: history of claustrophobia, serious head&#xD;
             injuries, seizures disorder, developmental delays, pacemaker, metal implants,&#xD;
             permanent metal piercings or anything else that would preclude having an MRI.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eric Lenze, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John W Newcomer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nuri B Farber, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 2, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 9, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 10, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>depression</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Treatment-Resistant</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Clonidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scopolamine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lorazepam</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Butylscopolammonium Bromide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

