<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03588650</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HLX20-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03588650</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 1 Study of HLX20, a Human Monoclonal Antibody Targeting PD-L1Protein in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <acronym>HLX20</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Study of HLX20, a Human Monoclonal Antibody Targeting Programmed Death Ligand 1 (PD-L1) Protein in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shanghai Henlius Biotech</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shanghai Henlius Biotech</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, dose escalation, first-in-human study of HLX20, an anti-PD-L1&#xD;
      monoclonal antibody, in patients with metastatic or recurrent solid tumors who have failed&#xD;
      standard therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tumor microenvironment plays an important role in the interaction of immune cells with cancer&#xD;
      . The identification of programmed cell death receptor 1 (PD-1) and programmed death ligand-1&#xD;
      (PD-L1) have provided the scientific rationale and supports the clinical development of&#xD;
      agents targeting this pathway. Currently, PD-1 and PD-L1 inhibitory pathway blockade has&#xD;
      demonstrated impressive activity against a spectrum of multiple tumor types, including&#xD;
      Hodgkin's lymphoma, melanoma, bladder cancer, lung cancer, renal cell carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HLX20 is a novel anti-PD-L1 monoclonal antibody. In the nonclinical pharmacology studies,&#xD;
      HLX20 has demonstrated anti-tumor activities in xenogenic animal models comparable to&#xD;
      currently available anti-PD-L1 monoclonal antibodies. HLX20 binds to PD-1 and PD-L1&#xD;
      inhibitory pathway and human PD-L1 at high affinity, and mouse PD-L1 at much lower affinity.&#xD;
      HLX20 does not cause hemolysis to human red blood cells and has no local irritation to human&#xD;
      tissues. (The results of pharmacokinetic (PK)/toxicokinetic studies in cynomolgus studies&#xD;
      have been described in detail in the Investigator's Brochure.)The no-observable adverse&#xD;
      effect level (NOAEL) is set at 100 mg/kg every 2 weeks for 13 weeks in cynomolgus studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on these results, the initial dose 1 mg/kg every 2 weeks was chosen for this study&#xD;
      .This dose level is approximately 30-fold lower than the human equivalent dose of NOAEL from&#xD;
      preclinical toxicology studies. An adaptive Bayesian dose-finding design will be used to&#xD;
      identify the MTD (maximum tolerated dose). The target toxicity rate for the MTD is set at 0.3&#xD;
      and the maximum sample size is 30.The safety profiles at different dose levels, PK&#xD;
      parameters, biomarkers, pharmacodynamic markers, immunogenicity as well as the preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy of the drug, will also be investigated in this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 7, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose of HLX20 in solid tumors patients</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The target toxicity rate in this study for the MTD is set at 0.3 ( 30% DLT) identified by an adaptive Bayesian dose-finding design .</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum serum concentration (Cmax) of HLX20.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimum serum concentration (Cmin) of HLX20.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under serum concentration-time curve within one dosing interval (AUC0-tau) of HLX20.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination half-life (T1/2) of HLX20 in different cohorts</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clearance rate (CL) of HLX20</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Volume of distribution at steady state (Vss) of HLX20.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The presence and percentage of anti-HLX20 antibody</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with complete response/partial response/stable disease divided by the total number of patients treated</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR).</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with confirmed complete or partial response, divided by the total number of treated patients with measurable disease at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Receptor occupancy of PD-L1 on human T-cells.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HLX20, in patients with solid tumors</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each cycle of treatment consists of 4 weeks. Patients who enroll into this study will receive an infusion of assigned dose of HLX20 once every two weeks. No intra-patient dose escalation is allowed. The proposed dose escalation sequence is 1, 3, 10 and 20 mg/kg, starting from 1 mg/kg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HLX20</intervention_name>
    <description>a Human Monoclonal Antibody Targeting Programmed Death Ligand-1 (PD-L1) Protein</description>
    <arm_group_label>HLX20, in patients with solid tumors</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or females of 18 years of age or older (or per local regulations).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have histologically-proven measurable, or evaluable advanced (systemically or locally&#xD;
             progressive), or metastatic solid tumors or the locally advanced disease is not&#xD;
             amenable to local therapy, who have failed, or are intolerant to standard therapy or&#xD;
             for whom no standard therapy is available. (For patients with hepatocellular&#xD;
             carcinoma, the diagnosis needs to be supported by dynamic computed tomography&#xD;
             [CT]/magnetic resonance imaging, if pathological confirmation is not attainable).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of ≤ 2 at the time of&#xD;
             study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to comprehend and provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. A life expectancy longer than 3 months in the opinion of the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate hematologic functions, as defined by: absolute neutrophil counts&#xD;
&#xD;
             ≥ 1500/mm3; a hemoglobin level ≥ 10 g/dL; a platelet count ≥ 100,000/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate hepatic function defined by: a total bilirubin level ≤ 1.5 × of upper limit&#xD;
             of normal (ULN); aspartate transaminase and alanine transaminase levels ≤ 2.5 × ULN or&#xD;
             ≤ 5 × ULN in known hepatic metastases or with primary hepatocellular carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate renal function, as defined by the creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/minute (as&#xD;
             calculated by the Cockcroft-Gault formula).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate cardiac function defined as left ventricular ejection fraction ≥ 50% by&#xD;
             cardiac ultrasound or multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan. A recent MUGA scan is&#xD;
             acceptable if performed within 8 weeks of the first infusion of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Females of child-bearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test upon entry into&#xD;
             this study and must be willing to use highly effective birth control upon enrollment,&#xD;
             during the Treatment Phase and for 180 days following the last dose of study drug. A&#xD;
             female is considered of child-bearing potential following menarche and until becoming&#xD;
             postmenopausal (no menstrual period for a minimum of 12 months) unless permanently&#xD;
             sterile (undergone a hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, or bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. If male, must be surgically sterile or willing to use highly effective birth control&#xD;
             upon enrollment, during the Treatment Phase, and for 180 days following the last dose&#xD;
             of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of prior major surgery, prior cytotoxic chemotherapy, or prior therapy with&#xD;
             investigational agents, medical device, or local radiotherapy should be at least 28&#xD;
             days prior to Screening and at least 42 days from the last infusion of immune check&#xD;
             point inhibitors (including anti-programmed cell death receptor-1 [PD-1] or&#xD;
             anti-PD-L1) before the first infusion of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Child-Pugh score of A (patients with hepatocellular carcinoma only).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Able to be followed up as required by the study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Persistent ≥ Grade 2 toxicities from prior therapies, with the exception of alopecia&#xD;
             of any grade, Grade ≤ 2 peripheral neuropathy, and laboratory values listed per the&#xD;
             inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Concurrent unstable or uncontrolled medical conditions, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active systemic infections;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Poorly controlled hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥ 160 mmHg or diastolic&#xD;
                  blood pressure ≥ 100 mmHg), or poor compliance with antihypertensive agents;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant arrhythmia, unstable angina pectoris, congestive heart&#xD;
                  failure (Class III or IV of New York Heart Association) or acute myocardial&#xD;
                  infarction within 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled diabetes or poor compliance with hypoglycemic agents;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The presence of chronically unhealed wound or ulcers;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other chronic diseases, which, in the opinion of the Investigator, could&#xD;
                  compromise safety of the patient or the integrity of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Newly-diagnosed or symptomatic brain metastases (patients with a history of brain&#xD;
             metastases must have received definitive surgery or radiotherapy, be clinically&#xD;
             stable, and not be taking steroids for brain edema). Anticonvulsants are allowed.&#xD;
             Patients with history of leptomeningeal disease will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any concurrent malignancy other than basal cell carcinoma or carcinoma in situ of the&#xD;
             cervix. (Patients with a previous malignancy but without evidence of disease for ≥ 3&#xD;
             years are allowed to participate).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Females who are pregnant, lactating, or intend to become pregnant during their&#xD;
             participation in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known history of human immunodeficiency virus infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders (including&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, diverticulitis with the exception of diverticulosis,&#xD;
             celiac disease, irritable bowel disease, Wegner syndrome) within the past 2 years.&#xD;
             Patients with well controlled vitiligo, alopecia, and Grave's disease, hypothyroidism&#xD;
             (eg, following Hashimoto syndrome) stable on hormone replacement, or psoriasis not&#xD;
             requiring systemic treatment (within the past 3 years), or patients with controlled&#xD;
             Type 1 diabetes mellitus who are on a stable insulin regimen are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days before the first&#xD;
             dose. The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids or local steroid injections (eg,&#xD;
                  intra-articular injection), OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of&#xD;
                  prednisone or equivalent, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (eg, CT scan&#xD;
                  premedication).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of primary immunodeficiency or allogeneic transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Active hepatitis B (HBsAg reactive). Active hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection, defined&#xD;
             as having a positive HCV antibody test followed by a positive HCV RNA test at&#xD;
             Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of interstitial lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Receipt of live attenuated vaccines within 30 days prior to the first dose of IP.&#xD;
             Patients, if enrolled, should not receive live or live attenuated vaccines during the&#xD;
             study and for 30 days after the last dose of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The patient is the Investigator, sub-investigator or anyone directly involved in the&#xD;
             conduct of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. History or current evidence of any condition or disease that could confound the&#xD;
             results of the study or, in the opinion of Investigator, is not in the best interest&#xD;
             of the patient to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rosita Hsieh, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+886-2-27927927</phone>
    <phone_ext>103</phone_ext>
    <email>rhsieh@henlix.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Eugene Liu, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+886-2-27927927</phone>
    <phone_ext>106</phone_ext>
    <email>eliu@henlix.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kinghorn cancer centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Darlinghurst</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2010</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amy Prawira, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>61 2 93555655</phone>
      <email>amy.prawira@svha.org.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Macquarie University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Darlinghurst</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2109</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dhanusha Sabanathan, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>61 98122956</phone>
      <email>clinicaltrials@mq.edu.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sunshine Coast University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brisbane</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <zip>4000</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gold Coast Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southport</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <zip>4215</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jasotha Sanmugarajah, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>61 7 56872658</phone>
      <email>Jasotha.Sanmugarajah@health.qld.gov.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CMAX Clinical research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Adelaide</city>
        <state>South Australia</state>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ganessan Kichenadasse, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>61 8 7088 7900</phone>
      <email>Ganessan.kichenadasse@sa.gov.au</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cabrini Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3144</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 22, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 4, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 17, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 4, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

