<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01674673</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2011-10-130</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01674673</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Long-term Observational Study on the Efficacy of SSRIs or Combined Treatment(SSRIs+ CBT) in Panic Disorder Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Long-term Observational Study on the Efficacy of SSRIs Pharmacotherapy or Combined Treatment(SSRIs Pharmacotherapy + CBT) in Panic Disorder Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Samsung Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Samsung Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is known that the treatment of panic disorder with medication and psychotherapy are both&#xD;
      effective. Representative as a treatment for panic disorder, Selective serotonin reuptake&#xD;
      inhibitors (SSRIs) are recommended as first-line treatment of panic disorder. In general, the&#xD;
      initial reaction rate of panic disorder medication known to be frequently stopped early&#xD;
      recurrence 70-80% It's too early, it is recommended that the duration of drug treatment for&#xD;
      at least one year to be long-lasting. But whether it is appropriate for the duration of drug&#xD;
      treatment to maintain a certain extent remains controversial, and maintain the medication for&#xD;
      more than one year, even if the long-term effects known to be approximately 50% less than&#xD;
      beyond being negative when remission based. Meanwhile, the typical method for the treatment&#xD;
      of panic disorder psychology, cognitive behavioral therapy (Cognitive behavioral therapy) and&#xD;
      looked comparable to the effect of the drug in the treatment of the known, especially in&#xD;
      recent years when the combined treatment with medication can increase the long-term treatment&#xD;
      of sexual reported that there's has been the subject of attention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      But prospectively compare the long-term effects of these two treatments, research, especially&#xD;
      the research about the long-term effects of the combined treatment with the drug treatment of&#xD;
      panic disorder is very low, and almost nil is Researchers, drug treatment and the effect of&#xD;
      the combined treatment in patients with panic disorder over two years prospective study to&#xD;
      compare the plans were. And verification, the researchers performed only through this study&#xD;
      by comparing the long-term effects of the combined treatment with medication combined&#xD;
      treatment of medication to be more effective than if the reaction to the long-term treatment&#xD;
      of panic disorder that can affect the clinical and biological factors navigate to evaluate&#xD;
      them. In addition, long-term observational study, panic disorder patients' subjective quality&#xD;
      of life actually improved to some extent on the map together proven to.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Panic disorder SSRI medication and long-term effects of the combined treatment on the&#xD;
      Hamilton Rating Scale more effective treatment compared with the Scale for Anxiety (HAM-A),&#xD;
      Clinical Psychology, I try to find the law. Drug and combination therapy of panic disorder&#xD;
      from affecting the long-term effects on clinical (demographic and economic Factors), and to&#xD;
      check for navigation and biological factors. - Improved quality of life to some extent due to&#xD;
      the long-term treatment of patients with panic disorder, if you want to check&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3 Expected Effects Panic disorder in a comparative study of the long-term effects of the&#xD;
      combined treatment with SSRI medication until now very rare, and most of the research to&#xD;
      target Westerners, Asians to study is almost wholly lacking. Also to investigate the nature&#xD;
      of the clinical course of panic disorder, long-term study also little or no sleep. Elapsed&#xD;
      for the treatment of long-term treatment of panic disorder and its impact on various clinical&#xD;
      variables to be able to figure out if, through the analysis of the results of this study, the&#xD;
      future could be a very useful background material, used in the development of clinical care&#xD;
      guidelines is expected. Leading researchers in various studies for panic disorder at home and&#xD;
      abroad, and also, therefore, the results obtained in this research is very useful in the&#xD;
      pathogenesis and in the treatment of panic disorder is expected. The results of this study&#xD;
      will be introduced in the Domestic Society and International Society, will finally be&#xD;
      published in major journals of SCI related.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3 Research plan 3.1 Research information and how to&#xD;
&#xD;
      - The selection of subjects Diagnosis by the DSM-IV diagnostic criteria for major panic&#xD;
      attacks in patients with disabilities will be conducted by a clinical psychologist or&#xD;
      psychiatrist: Mini International Neuropsychiatric Interview Plus (MINI-plus) of structured&#xD;
      skilled diagnostic tool.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the case of patients who were taking medication Airlines sulfur existing at least 2 weeks&#xD;
      (hydrochloric acid flu Jade Satin scheduled to participate in a study of the existing 4&#xD;
      weeks) and stop taking the drug. All other prescription non-drug (herbal medicine), forbids&#xD;
      smoking within 24 hours before the test, caffeine drink, drinking is prohibited in the state&#xD;
      to proceed with a test is scheduled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment conditions Randomization Randomization table belonging goes: medication alone group&#xD;
      and the combined treatment group on either side Will be determined by the SSRIs Tx group -&gt;&#xD;
      Korean panic disorder treatment algorithm (Korean Medication Algorithm for Panic Disorder&#xD;
      2008: Initial Treatment Strategies. J. C. Yang et al., 2008) according to the treatment by&#xD;
      applying Standardized treatment is expected to be performed. Single use only, benzodiazepine&#xD;
      (alprazolam) and tapering zolpidem use, but only occasionally, within 3 months of treatment,&#xD;
      so that Should, in principle, (using the PRN as alprazolam available).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Combined Tx group SSRIs Tx group, and the same drug treatment to be carried out once a&#xD;
           week underwent 10 sessions of CBT, and, after 3 Once a month booster session is&#xD;
           scheduled to be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
           - Therapists&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Treatment conducted by a psychiatrist skilled in both groups, but CBT case of a&#xD;
           qualified clinical psychology Scholars will participate as an adjunct therapy in the&#xD;
           treatment session.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Assessment Is scheduled to visit (24 months) to assess the clinical manifestations:&#xD;
                a total of 11 times.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 1: Screening &amp; Baseline Visit 2,3,4: every visit per month. / CBT once a week about 3&#xD;
      months, 10 sessions of treatment Visit 5-11: every 3 months to visit / CBT Booster session in&#xD;
      three months, once implemented&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visit 1 (Screening &amp; Baseline)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  MINI-plus diagnostic tool&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Obtaining research consent&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Determine whether severe medical or psychiatric diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Demographic data survey (In the future, when compared to the quality of life,&#xD;
                according to the therapeutic, marital status, educational And income levels&#xD;
                yuksujun compensation, and demographic and economic variables according to the&#xD;
                comparison of the response to treatment in order) Age of onset (early onset and&#xD;
                late-onset separated) survey&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Clinical data (Baseline severity and panic frequency) survey&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Duration of disease survey A comorbidity (need to MINI-plus disease confirmed)&#xD;
                     Whether other drugs: Prescription&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Alcohol and substance combination presence Past medication or CBT, such as&#xD;
                     whether to perform&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Hamilton Rating Scale for Anxiety (HAM-A), Hamilton Rating Scale for&#xD;
                     Depression (HAM-D), Clinical Global Impression-Severity (CGI-S), PDSS (Panic&#xD;
                     Disorder Severity Scale), Evaluate the PSR (Psychiatric status ratings)&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  As a self-assessment item MMPI-II, Anxiety Sensitivity Index-Revised (ASI-R),&#xD;
                     Albany Panic and Phobic Questionnaire (APPQ), WHOQOL-BREF, Stress Response&#xD;
                     Inventory (SRI) measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Clinical Response Remission rate Response rate and survey (No panic attack and PDSS&#xD;
                scores &lt;5 on standards)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Pharmacological Tx Drug administration and dosage, drug side effects, Compliance&#xD;
                Survey&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Anxiety-related biomarkers measured&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  CBC and lipid battery tests blood samples&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Heart rate variability (HRV), Biofeedback (EMG, EDR, measuring peripheral skin&#xD;
                     temperature)&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Cytokine (IL-1b, 2,6, TNF-alpha, IFN-r, IL-12 / IL-4, 10) measurements → blood&#xD;
                     samples&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Genetic factor survey → blood samples&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Serotonin related genes (5-HTTLPR &amp; serotonin 2A receptor genetic polymorphism&#xD;
                     gene)&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  COMT, BDNF, DRD2, MAOA genetic polymorphism gene&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Personality factor Psychiatrist skilled clinical interview of DSM-IV Axis II&#xD;
                diagnosis enforcing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visit 2, 3, 4 (every 1 month, after 1, 2, and 3 Month)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Clinicians additional item (Clinical Global Impression-Improvement (CGI-I) rating)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Item self-assessment (MMPI-II)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Clinical Response&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Pharmacological Tx History&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Anxiety-related biomarkers measured (Visit 4, 3-month period)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Visit 5-11 (every 3 months, after 6, 9 12, 15, 18, 21, 24 Month)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  visit 2,3,4 same as the one measuring anxiety-related biomarker for 6 months, 12&#xD;
                months, 18 months, 24 months, and only at the point&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Statistical analyses Methods of treatment: comparison between the two&#xD;
                     treatment groups for baseline anxiety severity, and status as a covariate Will&#xD;
                     be analyzed under analysis of covariance (ANCOVA) model using For comparison:&#xD;
                     two treatments according to the degree of improvement between the groups&#xD;
                     (remitters) the Cochran- It is planned to use the Mantel-Haenszel test.&#xD;
                     Personality or reaction and make a difference, according to the genetic factor&#xD;
                     gene to gene on gene interaction, and gene to environment interaction multiple&#xD;
                     regression or MDR (multidimensional reduction) using the statistical program&#xD;
                     is expected to be analyzed.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Plan for the subject's right to privacy and information protection Effect from&#xD;
                     September 30, 2011, in accordance with the Privacy Act, personal information&#xD;
                     collected purposes, the subject's right to privacy and information protection&#xD;
                     for subject identification is not possible to encrypt your name and personal&#xD;
                     number of participants in the study, and you want to collect personal items of&#xD;
                     information, the right description of the subjects for the duration of the&#xD;
                     protection of personal information and use, and is expected to obtain this&#xD;
                     consent. Information obtained from the study to the Clinical Trials Committee&#xD;
                     of the Food and Drug Administration to be used only for the purpose of&#xD;
                     analysis and clinical research information to connect to, and comply with the&#xD;
                     relevant provisions. The results of this trial will be published if the&#xD;
                     subject's identity will remain secret, and all relevant data will be managed&#xD;
                     under the supervision of the Principal Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2 Subjects plan Panic disorder patients 20 years of age or older to visit the Samsung Seoul&#xD;
      Hospital, and the Department of Mental Health, a foreign patients, patients who agreed to&#xD;
      participate in this study will be of. Plan the patient-specific total of 110 patients on each&#xD;
      drug treatment group and combined treatment group, 55 patients recruited by the first year of&#xD;
      study commences 2 years F / U to enforce the number of subjects. Which G * Power 3.0.10&#xD;
      version program (Erdfelder, E., Faul, F., &amp; Buchner, A. (1996)), using the power 80%,&#xD;
      significance level of 5%, effect size 0.6, and the case and control groups equal number&#xD;
      allocation to treatment in panic disorder seems common rate, the percentage of Asian American&#xD;
      about 20% and Samsung Seoul Hospital, Department of Mental Health, panic disorder patients&#xD;
      for many years to visit when you consider that approximately 2,300 (initial 200 patients, at&#xD;
      least), the appropriate is suggested by the number of subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject selection criteria&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Outpatients with panic disorder at the SMC&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PD patients who agree to participate in the clinical study&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PD patients who are over 20 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject exclusion criteria&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PD patients who have either severe medical illnesses or other psychiatric illnesses&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PD patients who are pregnant, or lactating PD patients who have suicidal idea&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.3 Subjects for Risk / Benefit Risk: every 3, 6, 12, 18, and 24 months after treatment with&#xD;
      at the time, be conducted sampling method is typically performed venous blood 60 ml (6&#xD;
      times). Accordingly, the subcutaneous blood or mild pain on the puncture site hematoma and&#xD;
      bruising and discomfort of the byeolun.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the possible side effects be used to study aviation sulfur drugs, selective&#xD;
      serotonin reuptake inhibitors, such as nausea, vomiting, dry mouth, dizziness, diarrhea,&#xD;
      insomnia, somnolence, ejaculation delay or erectile impairment sexual interference and can&#xD;
      be.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suspended for the duration of existing drugs, on recurrence gonghwangjeung and cause a&#xD;
      worsening of the subjects were taking the existing air sulfur drugs, if may be.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interests: while participating in a clinical trial for two years, the state of mental health,&#xD;
      and balance the autonomic nervous system, the degree and temperament / personality traits in&#xD;
      the individual subjects to learn. Blood through the analysis of the primary results of a&#xD;
      blood test before and after treatment may also be associated with various psychological&#xD;
      tests, can receive free of charge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4 Annual Research Plan (3-year study performed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  1st year (2012): Patient recruitment and conduct research&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  2nd year (2013): Studies performed&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  3rd year (2014): conduct research and data analysis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PDSS</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Panic Disorder</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      whole blood&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Panic disorder patients 20 years of age or older to visit the Samsung Seoul Hospital, and&#xD;
        the Department of Mental Health, a foreign patients, patients who agreed to participate in&#xD;
        this study will be of. Plan the patient-specific total of 100 patients on each drug&#xD;
        treatment group and combined treatment group, 55 patients recruited by the first year of&#xD;
        study commences 1 years F / U to enforce the number of subjects.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Outpatients with panic disorder at the SMC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PD patients who agree to participate in the clinical study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PD patients who are over 20 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PD patients who have either severe medical illnesses or other psychiatric illnesses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PD patients who are pregnant, or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PD patients who have suicidal idea&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>BumHee BH Yu, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Samsung Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bum-Hee Yu, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0234101385</phone>
    <email>bh.yu@samsung.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samsung Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>000000</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bum-Hee Yu, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0234103583</phone>
      <email>bh.yu@samsung.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 24, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 29, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 26, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 26, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 30, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>panic disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>SSRIs pharmacotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Behavioral therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Panic Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

