<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01676077</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>85750</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01676077</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Outcome Study for Dysferlinopathy</brief_title>
  <acronym>Jain COS</acronym>
  <official_title>International Clinical Outcome Study for Dysferlinopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Newcastle-upon-Tyne Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jain Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Newcastle-upon-Tyne Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The &quot;Clinical Outcome Study for Dysferlinopathy&quot; is being performed in centres in Europe (UK-&#xD;
      Newcastle; Spain- Barcelona, Sevilla; Germany- Berlin, Munich; Italy- Padova; France- Paris,&#xD;
      Marseille), USA (Charlotte, NC; Columbus, OH; Washington, DC; St.Louis, MO, Stanford CA),&#xD;
      Japan (Tokyo) and Australia (Sydney). Oversight and funding for this study is being provided&#xD;
      by the Jain Foundation, a non-profit foundation dedicated to finding therapies for&#xD;
      dysferlinopathies(LGMD2b/Miyoshi). The aim of this &quot;Clinical Outcome Study&quot; is to determine&#xD;
      the clinical outcome measures required for future clinical trials, characterize the disease&#xD;
      progression of dysferlinopathy and collect biological samples for the identification of&#xD;
      disease markers that are needed to non-invasively monitor the disease during clinical trials.&#xD;
      Without this information, effective clinical trials cannot be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is recruiting a large number of genetically confirmed dysferlinopathy patients&#xD;
      aged 10 years or older, who are ambulant or non-ambulant. Participants will be assessed at 6&#xD;
      visits over 3 years via medical, physiotherapy, and MRI/MRS assessments, as well as standard&#xD;
      blood tests. Optionally, the participants can donate blood samples and a skin sample for use&#xD;
      in the identification of disease markers and other approved research.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Dysferlinopathy represents a rare group of muscular dystrophies, presenting a particular&#xD;
      challenge for the definition of natural history and &quot;trial readiness&quot;. In the early days&#xD;
      after the cloning of the dysferlin gene, several papers described the clinical phenotype over&#xD;
      time of collections of patients leading to the recognition of the &quot;core&quot; phenotypes of&#xD;
      Miyoshi Myopathy (MM), LGMD2B and the rarer distal myopathy with anterior tibial involvement.&#xD;
      Most of these papers dealt with inbred populations with a limited number of mutations&#xD;
      represented. Subsequent studies have reported larger numbers of patients with outbred&#xD;
      mutations and extended the clinical spectrum to include onset as young as early childhood and&#xD;
      as late as old age, with a large group of patients in whom a clear distinction in their&#xD;
      pattern of muscle involvement into Miyoshi or LGMD was not possible, with involvement of both&#xD;
      the proximal and distal musculature in most patients, especially as the disease progresses. A&#xD;
      limitation of all of these studies however is that with few exceptions, again mainly in&#xD;
      inbred groups, long-term follow-up data are not presented and data on clinical progression&#xD;
      are collected in different ways making precise comparisons between their conclusions&#xD;
      difficult. Nonetheless, the studies overall are in agreement that dysferlinopathy is a&#xD;
      chronically progressive condition sometimes with periods where there is a plateauing of&#xD;
      muscle function, with variable age at wheelchair dependency and probably a low risk of&#xD;
      cardiac and respiratory complications compared to other types of muscular dystrophy.&#xD;
      Intriguing suggestions from these publications which require more systematic study include&#xD;
      the definition of a particularly good level of sporting prowess before the onset of symptoms&#xD;
      and the description of a subacute onset with muscle pain and swelling, both features, if&#xD;
      better understood, that potentially could help in our understanding of the pathogenesis of&#xD;
      the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, two as yet unpublished studies have addressed the topic of charting the natural&#xD;
      history of dysferlinopathy more systematically. In a study of 9 genetically confirmed LGMD2B&#xD;
      and MM patients studied over 18 months, Isabel Illa and colleagues found a significant&#xD;
      decline in muscle strength in a set of muscle groups measured by manual muscle testing, and&#xD;
      in knee flexion measured by quantitative muscle testing, accompanied by a detectable&#xD;
      deterioration on MRI imaging in biceps femori and tibialis posterior. Maggie Walter and&#xD;
      colleagues assessed the natural course of disease and efficacy of deflazacort treatment in 25&#xD;
      patients (between 25 and 63 years of age) with genetically confirmed dysferlinopathy in a&#xD;
      double-blind, cross-over trial. During the first year of the study, they assessed the natural&#xD;
      course of disease in 6-month intervals, evaluating MRC scores, quantitative strength&#xD;
      measurement by hand-held dynamometry (Citec, Groningen, Netherlands), and torque measurement&#xD;
      (M3 diagnose system, Fa. Schnell, Germany), Neuromuscular Symptoms Score (NSS), Timed&#xD;
      Function Tests (getting up from lying and sitting position, climbing 4 stairs, running 10m),&#xD;
      Vignos Scale, Hammersmith Motor Ability Score, and Global Assessment CGI Scale, quality of&#xD;
      life SF-36 scale and laboratory parameters (sodium, potassium, creatinine, urea, GOT, GPT,&#xD;
      gamma-GT, CK, blood count, ESR, CRP). Medication (placebo or deflazacort in a cross-over&#xD;
      design) was only started in the 2nd year of the study. All patients showed a decline in&#xD;
      muscle strength over one year, which was reflected in the tests performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is reassuring that from these data we can conclude that it is likely that there will be&#xD;
      changes detectable with time in dysferlinopathy that could inform the design of future&#xD;
      clinical trials, but the optimal measurements have yet to be defined and mapped in a much&#xD;
      larger group of dysferlinopathy patients representing the entire clinical spectrum of this&#xD;
      diverse disease group. Extrapolating from the requirements for studies in other types of&#xD;
      muscular dystrophies, including the regulatory advice for establishing pivotal trials of&#xD;
      therapies in these disorders, these measures would need to include not only measures of&#xD;
      muscle strength, but also of function and some degree of patient reported outcomes. The&#xD;
      unpublished results of Isabel Illa and colleagues, as well as another small study of MRI in&#xD;
      dysferlinopathy, also show some hope for the use of MRI as a measure of change in muscle over&#xD;
      time which might be applicable as an outcome measure. Up until now, muscle MRI has been seen&#xD;
      more as a tool for delineating the pattern of muscles involved than for monitoring change -&#xD;
      the use of MRI for monitoring disease progression in a non-invasive manner is however&#xD;
      attracting a lot of current interest, though more study is needed especially in respect of&#xD;
      functional correlates and patient relevance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The frequency of dysferlinopathy provides a further challenge to the collection of natural&#xD;
      history data. The relative frequency of different forms of muscular dystrophy depends to a&#xD;
      certain extent on the population studied. Dysferlinopathy appears to be a more common cause&#xD;
      of LGMD in Southern European populations than in Northern European ones. Founder mutations&#xD;
      exist in only a few small communities. There is little doubt that dysferlinopathy is&#xD;
      under-diagnosed and, in fact, the clinical diagnostic process by which dysferlinopathy is&#xD;
      diagnosed is also variable. Most laboratories still rely on the suggestion of the diagnosis&#xD;
      by muscle immunocytochemistry or (more reliably) immunoblotting. Some laboratories carry out&#xD;
      protein testing on monocytes as an alternative screening methodology. The gold standard for&#xD;
      dysferlinopathy diagnosis has however become DNA testing, with sequencing carried out in a&#xD;
      small number of commercial laboratories as well as a series of diagnostic laboratories in&#xD;
      Europe and the USA. The Jain Foundation (www.jain-foundation.org) can help guide those who&#xD;
      are unsure about their diagnosis through the process of getting a genetic analysis. Please&#xD;
      contact Sarah Shira at the Jain Foundation for help with diagnosis at +1 425 882 1492&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the perspective of different approaches to therapy in dysferlinopathy, a clearer&#xD;
      definition of the natural history of the disease and the delineation of suitable outcome&#xD;
      measures for clinical trials needs to be prioritised. The current protocol builds on existing&#xD;
      national and international networks to bring together a critical mass to address the&#xD;
      following specific aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Define the natural history of dysferlinopathy in a large unselected patient group with&#xD;
           respect to age and nature of onset, progression and presence of complications via&#xD;
           existing and expanded registries and databases&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Study a selection of possible outcome measures for dysferlinopathy trials over a three&#xD;
           year period in a multicentre evaluation of 150 patients based in centres of excellence&#xD;
           for muscular dystrophy diagnosis and management&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Extend the existing registry activities coordinated by the Jain Foundation to ensure a&#xD;
           comprehensive patient registry for dysferlinopathy, within the TREAT-NMD international&#xD;
           registry framework.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Dysferlinopathy</condition>
  <condition>LGMD2B</condition>
  <condition>Miyoshi Myopathy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with a genetically confirmed dysferlinopathy</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Serum, Plasma, DNA, RNA, Skin fibroblasts&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A diagnosis of Limb Girdle Muscular Dystrophy type 2B (LGMD2B), Miyoshi myopathy, or any&#xD;
        other clinical diagnosis associated with dysferlinopathies&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Confirmed diagnosis of dysferlinopathy proven by a) two (predicted) pathogenic dysferlin&#xD;
        mutations, b) one (predicted) pathogenic dysferlin mutation and absent dysferlin protein on&#xD;
        muscle immunoblot, or c) one (predicted) pathogenic dysferlin mutation and dysferlin&#xD;
        protein level ≤20% of normal level determined by blood monocyte testing. Mutations will be&#xD;
        checked for pathogenicity via the UMD bioinformatics tools.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Contact Sarah Shira at the Jain Foundation for help with diagnosis at +1 425 882 1492&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ambulant with or without aids; or full-time wheelchair user, i.e. non-ambulant; with&#xD;
             the ratio 2:1 between recruited ambulant and recruited non-ambulant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All ages ≥ 10 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to perform assessments (there will be different assessments for ambulant and&#xD;
             non-ambulant patients).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to attend scheduled investigations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent to participate in the clinical outcome study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Funds are available to cover necessary hotel stays and travel costs to the study&#xD;
        centres for the participant and a helper (if needed).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known current or planned medical or other interventions that might interfere with the&#xD;
             possibility to undertake the planned tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other concomitant pathology that in the view of the investigator would jeopardise the&#xD;
             ability to take part in the protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Volker Straub</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Newcastle University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anna Mayhew</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Newcastle University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>944305</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neurology &amp; Pathology, Washington University, School of Medicine in St Louis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Carolinas Medical Center, Neuroscience &amp; Spine Institute, Dept of Neurology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28207</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Neuromuscular Center at the Research Institute of Nationwide Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43230</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut de Myologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75013</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Neurosciences, University of Padova</name>
      <address>
        <city>Padova</city>
        <zip>35128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Center of Neurology and Psychiatry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kodaira</city>
        <state>Tokyo</state>
        <zip>187-8551</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Sant Pau, Neurology Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Virgen del Rocio, IBiS, Neurology Department</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sevilla</city>
        <zip>41013</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Genetic Medicine, Newcastle University, International Centre for Life</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newcastle upon Tyne</city>
        <zip>NE1 3BZ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.Jain-foundation.org</url>
    <description>This study is fully funded by the Jain Foundation, a non-profit foundation whose mission is to cure muscular dystrophies caused by dysferlin protein deficiency.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.dysferlinoutcomestudy.org</url>
    <description>All information for this study can be found on the study website (www.dysferlinoutcomestudy.org), including contact details and participating sites</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 30, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>LGMD2B</keyword>
  <keyword>Miyoshi Myopathy</keyword>
  <keyword>Dysferlin</keyword>
  <keyword>Dysferlinopathy</keyword>
  <keyword>Limb Girdle muscular dystrophy type 2b</keyword>
  <keyword>Muscular Dystrophy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Muscular Dystrophies, Limb-Girdle</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

