<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02171416</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Cures</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2012-005726-30</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02171416</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cold Contact Urticaria Treatment With Rilonacept</brief_title>
  <acronym>Cures</acronym>
  <official_title>A Single-center, Double-blind Placebo-controlled Parallel Group Phase II Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Rilonacept in Subjects With Cold Contact Urticaria (CCU)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Regeneron Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cold contact urticaria (CCU) is a frequent form of physical urticaria that is characterized&#xD;
      by the development of wheal and flare type skin reactions due to the release of histamine and&#xD;
      other proinflammatory mast cell mediators following exposure of the skin to cold. Typically,&#xD;
      symptoms occur within minutes after cold contact, including exposure to cold air, liquids or&#xD;
      objects and are limited to cold exposed skin areas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators postulate that there is an overlap between acquired cold urticaria and&#xD;
      cold-induced autoinflammatory syndromes, and that cold urticaria patients unresponsive to&#xD;
      antihistamines will benefit from IL-1 targeting treatment strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will evaluate the efficacy and safety of the IL-1 transfusion protein rilonacept&#xD;
      in patients with cold contact urticaria who could not be successfully treated with first-line&#xD;
      medication such as antihistamines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a double-blind placebo-controlled parallel group phase II study of the efficacy and&#xD;
      safety of rilonacept in subjects with CCU. A total of 20 patients will be included by the&#xD;
      Urticaria specialty clinics of ACC. The total duration of the study course for each patient&#xD;
      is 14 weeks and is divided in:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Screening period (2 weeks, days -14-0)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Placebo-controlled double-blind phase (Part A, 6 weeks, days 0-42)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Open label phase (Part B, 6 weeks, days 42-84) All eligible patients will be randomized&#xD;
           (1:1 randomization) to one of two groups: 1) Rilonacept 160mg/week or 2) Placebo, and&#xD;
           will receive the respective dose subcutaneously. Following the placebo-controlled&#xD;
           double-blind phase patients will enter the open-label phase and receive rilonacept&#xD;
           open-label treatment (160mg or 320mg depending on treatment response during part A).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the effect of rilonacept on the clinical signs and symptoms of CCU</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in symptom development (critical temperature thresholds (CTT) in CCU patients from baseline to day 42 in the rilonacept group as compared to the placebo group</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the safety of rilonacept in subjects with CCU</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>This includes physical examination, routine safety laboratory assessments, vital signs and adverse event reporting</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the patient's quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Dermatology Life Quality Index (DLQI) from baseline to day 42 in the rilonacept group as compared to the placebo group and from baseline to the open-label treatment with rilonacept</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in mast cell mediator release</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measured in the blood of CCU patients during the challenge with cold water at day 42 in the rilonacept group as compared to the placebo group and during the open-label treatment in the rilonacept 160 mg group as compared to the 320 mg group</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Cold Contact Urticaria</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo s.c every 7 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rilonacept 160mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rilonacept s.c every 7 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rilonacept</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Arcalyst</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Rilonacept 160mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult ( &gt; 18 years of age)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Outpatients with CCU for more than six weeks. Urticaria symptoms must comprise wheal&#xD;
             and itch and be resistant to conventional antihistamine treatment in standard doses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a positive cold stimulation test at 4°C (assessed by TEMPtest 3.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent signed and dated. Able to read, understand and willing to sign the&#xD;
             informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to read, understand and complete study-related questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing, committed and able to return for all clinic visits and complete all&#xD;
             study-related procedures, including willingness to self-administer SC injections or to&#xD;
             have SC injections administered by a qualified person&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In women, negative pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reliable method of contraception for both women of childbearing potential as well as&#xD;
             men, during the course of the study. A highly effective method of birth control is&#xD;
             defined as those which result in a low failure rate (i.e. less than 1% per year) when&#xD;
             used consistently and correctly such as implants, injectables, combined oral&#xD;
             contraceptives, some IUDs, sexual abstinence or vasectomised partner.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects are considered eligible according to the following tuberculosis (TB)&#xD;
             screening criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of latent or active TB prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No signs or symptoms suggestive of active TB&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No recent close contacts with a person with active TB&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A negative QuantiFERON-TB test on day -14 (screening visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with a live (attenuated) virus vaccine during the month prior to day 0&#xD;
             (Randomization).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of serious chronic or active infection(s) eg. listeriosis within six weeks&#xD;
             prior to the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of acute or latent Tuberculosis as defined by the local guidelines/local&#xD;
             medical practice&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of acute tuberculosis despite the proper treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant concomitant illness such as, but not limited to, cardiac, renal,&#xD;
             neurological, endocrinological, metabolic, lymphatic or hematological disease that&#xD;
             would adversely affect the subject's participation or evaluation in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active systemic inflammatory condition including, but not limited to, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosis, polymyalgia rheumatica, vasculitis, or&#xD;
             myositis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of fibromyalgia or chronic fatigue syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of current HIV, Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis C infection by clinical or&#xD;
             serological history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of malignancies including malignant hematological disorders other than a&#xD;
             successfully treated non-metastatic cutaneous, basal, or squamous cell carcinoma&#xD;
             and/or in situ cervical cancer within five years of the Screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe respiratory disease, including, but not limited to severe bronchiectasis,&#xD;
             chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, bullous lung disease, uncontrolled asthma, or&#xD;
             pulmonary fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of any of the following laboratory abnormalities at enrollment visit:&#xD;
             creatinine &gt;1.5 x Upper Limit of Normal (ULN), WBC &lt;3.6 x 103/mm3; platelet count&#xD;
             &lt;150,000 mm3; ALT or AST &gt;2.0 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous ineffective treatment with IL1 inhibitor or other biologic agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to CHO cell derived therapeutics or proteins or any components&#xD;
             of rilonacept.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would interfere with&#xD;
             participation in the study or place the subject at risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present History of substance abuse (drug or alcohol) or any other factor (e.g.,&#xD;
             serious psychiatric condition) that could limit the subject's ability to comply with&#xD;
             study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lactating females or pregnant females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrollment in another investigational treatment or device study or use of an&#xD;
             investigational agent, or no completion of less than 4 weeks or 5 half-lives,&#xD;
             whichever is longer, since end of another investigational device or drug trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects for whom there is concern about compliance with the protocol procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are detained officially or legally to an official institute.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karoline Krause, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Berlin Charité ; Dermatology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>10117</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsmedizin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mainz</city>
        <zip>55131</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 13, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 20, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 24, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 16, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 16, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 17, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Karoline Krause</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PD MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urticaria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rilonacept</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

