<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03277495</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-0948</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1U01DA045524-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03277495</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Predictors and Consequences of Combustible Cigarette Smokers' Switch to Standardized Research E-Cigarettes</brief_title>
  <official_title>Predictors and Consequences of Combustible Cigarette Smokers' Switch to Standardized Research E-Cigarettes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois at Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Chicago</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary goal of this study is to examine whether cigarette smokers can reduce their use&#xD;
      of conventional, combustible cigarettes by switching to a Standardized Research E-Cigarette&#xD;
      (SREC); whether participants can maintain these reductions and use of SRECs over a 12-week&#xD;
      period; and whether there are changes in subjective and objective measures of health, appeal&#xD;
      and acceptability of the products used during this time frame.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will enroll 180 conventional cigarette smokers who report smoking at least&#xD;
      7 cigarettes/day. Following completion of baseline questionnaires and a week of ecological&#xD;
      momentary assessments (EMA) tracking participants usual smoking behavior, participants will&#xD;
      be stratified (by sex and by whether they use menthol cigarettes) and randomly assigned with&#xD;
      a 2:1 allocation ratio to one of two conditions: 1) nicotine SREC (N = 120); and 2) placebo&#xD;
      SREC (N = 60). Both staff and participants will be blind to assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Counseling at Week 2. Participants in both conditions will receive brief behavioral&#xD;
      counseling on reducing their combustible cigarette use by substitution with SREC. Staff will&#xD;
      work with participants to set individual goals for reduction during this first week, with the&#xD;
      goal of achieving at least 75% reduction in the number of combustible cigarettes smoked by&#xD;
      the end of the week, and all are encouraged to reduce further. Participants will also be told&#xD;
      not to use any other combustible tobacco products. During the week, participants will&#xD;
      complete a daily text or web report on number of cigarettes smoked and SREC cartridges used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 3 Visit. Participants will bring back all used and unused cartridges for adherence&#xD;
      counts, complete a brief questionnaire about subjective reactions and potential adverse&#xD;
      effects, and provide breath CO. Participants will meet with study staff to review their&#xD;
      progress with switching to SREC and receive continued behavioral counseling to substitute&#xD;
      SREC for cigarettes. Participants will receive SREC refill cartridges and will start a second&#xD;
      7-day EMA protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 4 Visit. EMA debriefing to check for compliance and any problem reports; return of used&#xD;
      and unused cartridges, complete assessments; review of progress with switching to SREC.&#xD;
      Participants will receive a 2 week supply of SREC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weeks 5-13. Participants return to the study office every 2 weeks to return cartridges,&#xD;
      receive a new supply, and provide breath CO. During the week, participants will continue&#xD;
      daily use reports via web/text.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 14 (End-of-Treatment). Participants return to the study office to complete a full&#xD;
      assessment battery. They will be encouraged to continue to stay off/reduce all combustible&#xD;
      cigarettes, but will not receive additional SREC refills from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 18 (One Month Follow-up). Participants complete a final survey.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will be stratified by sex and use of menthol cigarettes and randomly assigned with a 2:1 allocation ratio to one of two conditions: 1) nicotine SREC (N = 120); and 2) placebo SREC (N = 60).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Combustible cigarette use</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks (end of treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>number of cigarettes smoked per week</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Abstinence</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks (end of treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of participants who achieve total abstinence from combustible cigarettes (defined as no cigarette smoking in the past 7 days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of cigarettes smoked</measure>
    <time_frame>18-weeks (end of trial)</time_frame>
    <description>The total number of cigarettes smoked in the 7 days prior to the last assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>CO level</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>in ppm</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Blood Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>systolic blood pressure and diastolic blood pressure in mm hg</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Heart Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>beats per minute</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>in pounds</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cotinine</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary cotinine levels (ng/mL)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>self-report of respiratory symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The St. George's Respiratory Questionnaire (SGRQ)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>nicotine dependence</measure>
    <time_frame>12-weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fagerstrom Test for Nicotine Dependence</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">180</enrollment>
  <condition>Tobacco Use</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>nicotine SREC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The liquid in the e-cigarette refills contains nicotine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>placebo SREC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The liquid in the e-cigarette refills does not contain nicotine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Brief behavioral counseling</intervention_name>
    <description>Staff will engage in behavioral counseling to identify strategies for reducing combustible cigarette use. All participants in the trial receive this intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>nicotine SREC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>placebo SREC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nicotine present in the SREC device and refills</intervention_name>
    <description>Nicotine is present in the liquid in the SREC device and all refills. Two-thirds of the sample will receive nicotine in their SREC; one-third will not (placebo)</description>
    <arm_group_label>nicotine SREC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. men and women 18 years of age or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. daily smoking rate of 7 cigarettes/day or greater for at least one year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. interested in reducing cigarette use;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. willing to try e-cigarettes;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. able to attend in-person assessments over the next 5 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. English speaking; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. breath CO of 10ppm or greater (assessed at baseline visit). Women who are of&#xD;
             child-bearing age cannot be pregnant and must agree to use an approved form of birth&#xD;
             control during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. current use of any smoking cessation medication or participation in a smoking&#xD;
             cessation program or study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. current daily ENDS user;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. pregnancy if female; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. no two members of the same household may participate in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robin Mermelstein, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kathleen Diviak, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>312-996-2327</phone>
    <email>kdiviak@uic.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 7, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 7, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 11, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Illinois at Chicago</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Robin Mermelstein</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Distinguished Professor and Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Within two years after the final data collection is completed, the investigators will create a completely de-identified data set will that obfuscate any variable that might potentially be used to identify an individual study participant. Data collection instruments, codebooks, and other data documentation will be made available in conjunction with this dataset in a standard format that is readable across a variety of applications and operating system platforms.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will become available no later than two years after the final data collection is completed. There is no time frame identified for stopping the sharing of the data.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>A data sharing agreement will be required for release of any data. Individuals requesting a copy of study data will need to submit a detailed research plan that includes the purpose of the proposed research, the variables required, the duration of the analysis phase, IRB approval with FWA information, investigator training in human subjects and other approvals specific to the individual datasets. They will also be required to submit a Data Protection Plan or Institutional Privacy Policy, describing the computing environment in which data will be managed and analyzed and how physical access to computing equipment will be controlled. Data will only be released once all IRB approvals and Human Subjects concerns have been addressed.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

