<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01505725</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999910456</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-DA-N456</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01505725</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nicotine Reinforcement and Smoking-Cue Reactivity: Association With Genetic Polymorphisms</brief_title>
  <official_title>Nicotine Reinforcement and Smoking-Cue Reactivity: Association With Genetic Polymorphisms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Researchers have been studying behavioral components of nicotine addiction by looking at&#xD;
      how drugs have a reinforcing effect, connecting the stimulation provided by the drug&#xD;
      (nicotine) to the behavior that produces it (smoking). Based on previous studies, researchers&#xD;
      are interested in learning more about how nicotine affects current smokers' responses to&#xD;
      psychological tests and smoking-related cues, and in studying whether certain kinds of&#xD;
      genetic background may affect smokers' responses to these kinds of studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the effect of nicotine versus denicotinized cigarettes during specific&#xD;
           psychological tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the effects of smoking cues versus neutral cues on craving, mood, and&#xD;
           autonomic response.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To study the effect of genes on nicotine reinforcement and smoking-cue reactivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Individuals between 18 and 64 years of age who are current smokers (at least 10 cigarettes&#xD;
      per day for at least 1 year) and are not currently interested in reducing their smoking or&#xD;
      seeking treatment for tobacco dependence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pilot session:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will practice smoking using the measuring equipment that will be used in&#xD;
           the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After successful practice, participants will read or listen to music for 1 hour, during&#xD;
           which they are not allowed to smoke.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the 1-hour period, participants will sample study cigarettes that have different&#xD;
           levels of nicotine, and will be asked to guess whether the cigarettes are normal study&#xD;
           cigarettes or denicotinized cigarettes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Baseline session:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood, urine, and breath samples will be taken at the start of the session.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will smoke part of an initial cigarette, and then will read or listen to&#xD;
           music for 1 hour, during which they are not allowed to smoke.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the 1-hour period, participants will give another breath sample and will complete&#xD;
           questionnaires about mood and concentration levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Trial sessions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will smoke study cigarettes, and will be asked to either respond to&#xD;
           questions about perceived nicotine levels in the cigarettes or press a lever for the&#xD;
           chance to be rewarded with additional puffs of the cigarette. After the session,&#xD;
           participants will give another breath sample and will complete questionnaires about mood&#xD;
           and concentration levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will also participate in cue-reactivity sessions to test the body's&#xD;
           physiological response to smoking cues (a pack of cigarettes) and neutral cues (a pack&#xD;
           of unsharpened pencils). After the session, participants will complete questionnaires on&#xD;
           mood and concentration 15, 30, 45, and 60 minutes after the session.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the conclusion of the last experimental session, participants will discuss the study&#xD;
           with researchers, and may receive a referral list of smoking treatment programs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives: 1) to compare the reinforcing efficacy of nicotine versus denicotinized&#xD;
      cigarettes using a forced choice and an operant response procedure, 2) to compare the effects&#xD;
      of smoking cues versus neutral cues on craving, mood, and autonomic responsivity, and 3) to&#xD;
      explore potential associations between several genetic polymorphisms and the phenotypic&#xD;
      measures of nicotine reinforcement and smoking-cue reactivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: 175 adult smokers (35 for pilot study I, 60 for pilot stufy II and 80 for&#xD;
      main study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: Placebo-controlled, within-subjects design. Pilot studies will entail 1-2 sessions.&#xD;
      Main study will entail one baseline/adaptation session and 5-10 experimental sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Behavioral Measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      During forced-choice sessions, primary measure is the percentage of nicotine cigarette puffs&#xD;
      chosen and taken during choice trials. During operant response sessions, primary measures&#xD;
      include breakpoint (final ratio completed), total number of responses, and number of&#xD;
      cigarette puffs earned and taken. During cue-reactivity sessions, primary measures include&#xD;
      craving, mood, and autonomic responsivity (heart rate, blood pressure, skin conductance, and&#xD;
      skin temperature).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Genetic Measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following genetic polymorphisms will be assayed: 1) C/T rs2023239 variant of the CB1R&#xD;
      gene, 2) the Ser/Gly rs6280 variant of DRD3 gene, and 3) variants of the CYP2A6 gene.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary study measures include baseline smoking history, FTND, TCQ-SF, mood form, CO, and&#xD;
      urinary cotinine and 3-hydroxycotinine. The ratio of 3-hydroxycotinine/cotinine is a&#xD;
      phenotypic biomarker of the rate of nicotine metabolism, which has been shown to be&#xD;
      associated with CYP2A6 genotype, level of nicotine dependence, various smoking behaviors, and&#xD;
      treatment outcome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 16, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date>November 29, 2013</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Choice of nicotine cigarettes; cue-elicited craving</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>smoking history measures; variants of several genes related to nicotine additions</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">92</enrollment>
  <condition>Nicotine Dependence</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. 18-64 year old males and females&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. smoking at least 10 cigarettes per day for at least 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. urinary cotinine level greater than or equal to 100 ng/ml (NicAlert reading&#xD;
                  greater than or equal to 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. medically and psychologically healthy as determined by screening criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. definite plan to reduce or quit tobacco use in the next 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. treatment for tobacco dependence in the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. use of nicotine replacement products, bupropion, or varenicline in the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. consumption of more than 15 alcoholic drinks per week during the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. use of any illicit drug more than twice per week during the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. current use of any medication that would interfere with the protocol in the opinion of&#xD;
             MAI&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. under the influence of a drug or alcohol at experimental sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. pregnant, nursing, or become pregnant during the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stephen J Heishman, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute on Drug Abuse, Biomedical Research Center (BRC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bickel WK, Hughes JR, DeGrandpre RJ, Higgins ST, Rizzuto P. Behavioral economics of drug self-administration. IV. The effects of response requirement on the consumption of and interaction between concurrently available coffee and cigarettes. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1992;107(2-3):211-6.</citation>
    <PMID>1615122</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cappelleri JC, Bushmakin AG, Baker CL, Merikle E, Olufade AO, Gilbert DG. Confirmatory factor analyses and reliability of the modified cigarette evaluation questionnaire. Addict Behav. 2007 May;32(5):912-23. Epub 2006 Jul 27.</citation>
    <PMID>16875787</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carter BL, Tiffany ST. Meta-analysis of cue-reactivity in addiction research. Addiction. 1999 Mar;94(3):327-40.</citation>
    <PMID>10605857</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 29, 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 6, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 4, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 4, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Nicotine Reinforcement</keyword>
  <keyword>Tobacco Craving</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavior Genetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Smoking</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

