<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01508091</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FONDECYT 1110035</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01508091</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Calorie Restriction Retards the Aging Process</brief_title>
  <official_title>Calorie Restriction Retards the Aging Process by Inducing Sirtuins and Uncoupling Protein 3, Thereby Reducing the Production of Reactive Oxygen Species.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Chile</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Calorie restriction is the only experimental manipulation that prolongs longevity in&#xD;
      experimental animals. The life prolonging effects of calorie restriction are related to a&#xD;
      lower incidence of tumors and less inflammation, but more importantly, a lower generation of&#xD;
      reactive oxygen species (ROS). This effect is related to the overexpression of two groups of&#xD;
      enzymes. One is a group of (NAD+)-dependent deacetylases called sirtuins whose main actions&#xD;
      are to increase free fatty acid flow from adipose tissue, improve insulin secretion and&#xD;
      promote mitochondrial biogenesis in muscle. The other group corresponds to uncoupling&#xD;
      proteins (UCP), specially UCP 3 that reduces the mitochondrial production of ROS. On the&#xD;
      other hand, an effect of calorie restriction that is always reported, is a decrease in&#xD;
      resting energy expenditure. A reduction in the activity of UCP1 in brown adipose tissue could&#xD;
      be a mechanisms to explain this effect. However sirtuins apparently increase the expression&#xD;
      of UCP1.Recently PET CT scans have emerged as a non invasive methodology to recognize brown&#xD;
      adipose tissue activity and indirectly, UCP1 activity. Also measurement of telomere length in&#xD;
      peripheral blood mononuclear cells has consolidated as a good marker of aging. Two possible&#xD;
      models of calorie restriction can be studied in humans. One is a retrospective model in which&#xD;
      adults are separated in those that have maintained a stable weight during adulthood in a&#xD;
      manner analogous to the weight clamp model of calorie restriction in non human primates. This&#xD;
      model is only reliable if there are objective records of the weight that the studied subjects&#xD;
      had 20 or more years ago. In the retrospective part of this project the investigators propose&#xD;
      to study adults whose weight was recorded previously. The investigators pretend to compare&#xD;
      telomere length and expression of SIRT1 and 6 in PBMC, plasma 8 isoprostanes and carotid&#xD;
      intima media thickness between weight maintainers and weight gainers. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesis is that weight maintainers will have a better aging profile than weight gainers.&#xD;
      In the prospective part of the project the investigators will study a human model of calorie&#xD;
      restriction prescribing a 25% reduction in calorie intake during 3 months and comparing&#xD;
      groups according to weight loss. At baseline and the end of the study period, UCP3 and SIRT1&#xD;
      expression in muscle biopsies, SIRT1 and 6 expression in PBMC and brown adipose activity,&#xD;
      assessed by 18fluorodeoxyglucose uptake using PET/CT will measured. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesis is that individuals subjected to calorie restriction will experience an increase&#xD;
      in the expression of UCP3, SIRT1 and SIRT6 and a reduction in brown adipose tissue activity.&#xD;
      Simultaneously, these subjects will experience a reduction in oxidative stress markers in&#xD;
      muscle and plasma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      HYPOTHESIS: Calorie restriction delays the ageing process and thus telomere erosion, due to a&#xD;
      reduction of oxidative stress, via expression modulation of uncoupling proteins and sirtuins.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RETROSPECTIVE STUDY:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 1000 adults aged 40 to 55 years, that had participated in nutritional&#xD;
      assessments studies during which their body weight was recorded, and had a body mass index&#xD;
      (BMI) of less than 30 kg/m2 at that time will be considered eligible. Other sources of&#xD;
      subject recruitment will be health records from armed forces personnel and our institutional&#xD;
      data base. Those that accept and sign a written informed consent, will be subjected to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A complete clinical history, recording past and present diseases, medication use,&#xD;
           history of smoking, drinking and illicit drug use.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A dietary questionnaire to assess nutrient intake&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. A complete clinical examination including the measurement of body weight, height, blood&#xD;
           pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. A physical activity questionnaire previously validated by us 1&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Measurement of body composition by DEXA&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Withdrawal of a 10 hours fasting blood sample of 30 ml to measure&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Packed red cell volume, blood glucose, creatinine, serum lipids, TSH, thyroid&#xD;
                hormones and insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Telomere length in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Sirt1 and 6 gene expression in PBMC.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Plasma 8- isoprostanes&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Measurement of carotid intima media thickness by ultrasound, performed by a trained&#xD;
           professional using previously reported protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once evaluated, subjects will be classified as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Weight maintainers if their actual weight is, at the most within 10% of the weight&#xD;
           recorded at least 10 years before&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Weight gainers, if their actual weight is over 20% of the weight previously recorded&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following will be excluded from further analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Subjects with a history of chronic debilitating diseases such as renal failure, cancer,&#xD;
           autoimmune diseases,hypothyroidism, diabetes mellitus or AIDS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Subjects engaged in extremely high physical activity (more than 10 hour per week of&#xD;
           sports or work requiring extreme physical activity such as shoveling or hard manual&#xD;
           work.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Subjects with a history of drug abuse or alcoholism&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Subjects using anorexigenic or anabolic drugs, or chronic users of non steroidal&#xD;
           anti-inflammatory drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Subjects smoking more than 5 cigarettes per day (91 packs per year)&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Overly malnourished subjects, defined as a body mass index below 18 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROSPECTIVE STUDY:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To study the effects of a three month period of calorie restriction in normal volunteers on&#xD;
      the expression of expression of SIRT1 and UCP3 in muscle, SIRT6 in PBMC, brown adipose tissue&#xD;
      activity and the accumulation of markers of oxidative damage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific goals:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To develop a prospective model of calorie restriction in normal human volunteers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To study changes associated with calorie restriction on:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Serum markers of inflammation and free fatty acids during fasting.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The uptake of 18fluorodexoyglucose by brown adipose tissue measured by PET-CT&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The expression of mRNA of UCP3 and SIRT1 in muscle biopsies.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The expression of mRNA for SIRT1 and 6 in muscle and peripheral blood mononuclear&#xD;
                cells&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The accumulation of 4 hydroxynonenal and 8 hydroxyguanosine in muscle, as markers&#xD;
                of oxidative damage&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The production of ROS by peripheral neutrophils as an overall measure of the&#xD;
                capacity to generate free radicals&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Insulin sensitivity, measured using formula derived from glucose tolerance.&#xD;
                METHODOLOGY Premenopausal women, aged 25 to 40 years, with a BMI between 27 and 32&#xD;
                kg/m2, interested in losing weight, will be studied. Inclusion criteria will be:&#xD;
                complete high school, stable weight (± 2 kg) in the last six months, and absence of&#xD;
                diabetes, medication intake that could influence energy expenditure such as beta&#xD;
                blockers (except oral contraceptives) and lack of engagement in competitive or&#xD;
                exhausting physical activities. Women will be required to use an effective&#xD;
                contraceptive method, and a pregnancy test will be performed every month while the&#xD;
                study lasts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After signing an informed consent form, total energy expenditure will be measured through&#xD;
      calorimetry and actigraphy or doubly labeled water. Subjects will be considered to be in&#xD;
      energy balance, taking into account that weight is stable (the lack of weight change will be&#xD;
      assessed during the two weeks required for inclusion studies). Therefore, it can be assured&#xD;
      that energy intake at that moment is equal to total energy expenditure .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Afterwards, subjects subjected to a 25% restriction of their measured total energy&#xD;
      expenditure (this level of restriction has been well tolerated by volunteers, even during one&#xD;
      year). Restriction will be balanced, using a mediterranean type diet, maintaining a&#xD;
      proportion of 50% carbohydrates, 25-30% of lipids, 25% of proteins and a provision of 100% of&#xD;
      micronutrient requirements. Patients will attend to dietician reinforcement every week. To&#xD;
      ease the restriction period, one extra meal will be allowed once a week. According to weight&#xD;
      change, volunteers will be considered as energy restricted (group 1) is they loose at least 3&#xD;
      kg or 5 % weight during the study period. Instead those subjects that do not reach these&#xD;
      goals will be considered as the control group (Group 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention will last three months and will be carried out during a period in which&#xD;
      temperature remains relatively stable and is lower, in Santiago Chile, to avoid an effect of&#xD;
      climate on brown adipose tissue activity. The ideal will be between May and August. Both&#xD;
      groups will be evaluated on a weekly basis by a nutritionist to assess compliance with the&#xD;
      diet, reinforce indications and be weighed. Subjects will receive a monthly monetary&#xD;
      remuneration in order to permit the purchase of specific foods and brands prescribed. Each&#xD;
      subject will be educated about healthy dietary and physical activity lifestyle. Eventual&#xD;
      changes in physical activity which will be ascertained using portable actigraphs&#xD;
      (Actiheart®).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Apart from weight change, volunteers will be considered as calorie restricted if triglyceride&#xD;
      levels decrease at least 15% and T3 levels are reduced by at least 8 ng/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline, and the end of the three month intervention period in which controls should be&#xD;
      in zero energy balance and adherent subjects in negative energy balance, the following&#xD;
      determinations will be carried out:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Measurement of routine clinical laboratory parameters to discard concomitant diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Measurement of fasting serum free fatty acids.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Measurement of ultrasensitive C reactive protein and carboxymethyllisine (CML) as an&#xD;
           inflammation marker and glycotoxin respectively, using commercial ELISA kits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Measurement of triglyceride and T3 levels to assess compliance with calorie restriction.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Glucose tolerance curve to measure glucose and insulin and calculate insulin sensitivity&#xD;
           using Matsuda formula&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Measurement of oxidative burst of peripheral neutrophils by Fluorescence Activated Cell&#xD;
           Sorting (FACS) as an expression of ROS production capacity of the organism&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Measurement of SIRT1 and 6 gene expression in PBMC by RT-PCR according to the technique&#xD;
           reported by Crujeiras et al&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. PET CT to measure 18fluorodeoxyglucose uptake by supraclavicular fat in thermoneutral&#xD;
           conditions and after immersing one foot in water at 8°C during five minutes, according&#xD;
           to Virtanen et al.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Vastus lateralis muscle biopsy, performed by a physician using a Bard needle using a&#xD;
           technique previously reported buy our group (this is a safe and simple procedure but the&#xD;
           biopsy sample obtained is small, therefore the analyses that can be performed are&#xD;
           limited), to measure:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  mRNA for UCP3 by RT-PCR , using the technique reported by Millet et al in biopsies&#xD;
                obtained in a similar way in humans.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  mRNA for SIRT1 by RT-PCR using the technique reported by Heilbronn et al.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Immunohistochemical expression of 8 hydroxyguanosine and 4 hydroxynonenal as&#xD;
                oxidation markers, using methods previously reported by us.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Body composition measurement by double energy X ray absorptiometry (DEXA).&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Resting energy expenditure measurement in and open-circuit indirect calorimeter (model&#xD;
           2900, Sensor Medics Corp., Yerba Linda, CA, USA).&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Actigraphy using Actiheart actigraphs to assess eventual changes in spontaneous physical&#xD;
           activity induced by calorie restriction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Telomere length will not be measured in the prospective protocol, considering that not&#xD;
      changes will be detected in the short study period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>May 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>UCP3 mRNA expression in vastus lateralis after energy restriction</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The main outcome measure will be UCP3 mRNA expression in vastus lateralis, which will be measured before and after the 3 month intervention period. This enzyme is the last link in the chain of events that occur after calorie restriction. Millet et al reported a value for UCP3 mRNA of 15 ± 1.5 amol/ìg total RNA in 18 subjects. Expecting a 60% increase over baseline in the expression of the enzyme, 17 subjects per group are required to obtain results with an á of 0.05 and a power of 0.8. Considering attrition rates, we must study 24 subjects per group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brown adipose tissue (BAT) activity, indicating UCP1 expression after calorie restriction</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Active BAT and its activation with cold exposure in humans, was demonstrated measuring 18 fluorodeoxyglucose uptake using PET-CT and colocalized the areas of 18F-FDG uptake to the expression of UCP1 thus for practical purposes it is a non invasive and reliable method to detect the presence of the tissue and the activity of UPC1, whic is downregulated by energy restriction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Calorie restricted</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 % calorie restriction respect measured total energy expenditure, using a Mediterranean diet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>energy restricted mediterranean-type diet</intervention_name>
    <description>Prescription of diet 25 % lower than actual total energy expenditure in overweight or moderately obese premenopausal women</description>
    <arm_group_label>Calorie restricted</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Calorie restriction</other_name>
    <other_name>Energy restriction</other_name>
    <other_name>Mediterranean diet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>25 % calorie restriction</intervention_name>
    <description>25 % calorie restriction respect total energy expenditure</description>
    <arm_group_label>Calorie restricted</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  overweight or obese premenopausal women aged 25 - 40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetes,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic diseases,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  extreme physical exercise,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  drugs affecting energy expenditure&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maria Pia de la Maza, MD</last_name>
    <phone>5629781502</phone>
    <email>mpmaza@inta.uchile.cl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Daniel Carlos Bunout, MD</last_name>
    <phone>5629781495</phone>
    <email>dbunout@inta.uchile.cl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica Alemana de Santiago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago</city>
        <state>Region Metropolitana</state>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pablo Lavados, MD</last_name>
      <email>plavados@alemana.cl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Claudio Mizon, MD</last_name>
      <phone>56996321586</phone>
      <email>cmizon@alemana.cl</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Claudio Mizon, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Chile</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 10, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 11, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 23, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Chile</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>MARIA PIA DE LA MAZA</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>ageing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>November 11, 2014</submitted>
    <returned>November 17, 2014</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

