<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04015622</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PROTRACT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04015622</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PROstate Cancer TReatment Optimization Via Analysis of Circulating Tumour DNA</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROTRACT</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized Phase II Trial Comparing Biomarker Directed Therapy Versus Clinician's Choice of Enzalutamide or Docetaxel in Patients With Advanced Prostate Cancer Post Abiraterone</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>British Columbia Cancer Agency</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>British Columbia Cancer Agency</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the strategy in treatment selection using ctDNA&#xD;
      fraction as a predictive biomarker to direct treatment decision (ctDNA fraction &lt;2% receives&#xD;
      enzalutamide, and ctDNA fraction ≥2% receives docetaxel) versus clinician's choice of&#xD;
      enzalutamide or docetaxel, in subjects with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer&#xD;
      post abiraterone setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, open-label, phase II trial with 1:1 randomization to either Arm A&#xD;
      biomarker directed therapy (patients with ctDNA fraction &lt;2% receive enzalutamide, and ctDNA&#xD;
      fraction ≥2% receive docetaxel), versus Arm B clinician's choice of enzalutamide or&#xD;
      docetaxel, in subjects with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer post abiraterone.&#xD;
      At time of progression, patient will cross-over to the other therapy (e.g., enzalutamide to&#xD;
      docetaxel, and docetaxel to enzalutamide).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is defined as the time between the date of starting trial treatment to any of the following: clinical, PSA, radiographic progression, or death from any cause on first-line therapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the objective response as per RECIST 1.1 in patients treated with biomarker directed therapy vs. clinician's choice.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PSA response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>PSA response rate is defined as the proportion of patients with a PSA decline (defined as a ≥30%, ≥50% and other declines in PSA from baseline) in mCRPC patients treated with biomarker directed therapy vs. clinician's choice.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Second progression free survival (PFS2)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>PFS2 is defined as the time elapsed between the date of treatment commencement and the first documented evidence of any disease progression or death from any cause from cross-over second-line therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>OS is defined as time from treatment commencement to death of any cause of mCRPC patients treated with biomarker directed therapy vs. clinician's choice.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical benefit rate (CBR)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>CBR is defined as PSA or measurable radiological response of any duration or stable disease for ≥ 12 weeks (no symptomatic progression, PSA progression, or objective disease progression).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of specific ctDNA-based genomic alterations to treatment response</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Among mCRPC patients receiving enzalutamide and docetaxel</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer (mCRPC)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A: Biomarker directed Therapy (BT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ctDNA fraction &lt;2% receives enzalutamide, and ctDNA fraction ≥2% receives docetaxel until disease progression, then cross-over to the other therapy (e.g., enzalutamide to docetaxel, or docetaxel to enzalutamide).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B: Clinician's Choice (CC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Enzalutamide or docetaxel until disease progression, then cross-over to the other therapy (e.g., enzalutamide to docetaxel, or docetaxel to enzalutamide).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Enzalutamide</intervention_name>
    <description>Enzalutamide 160 mg PO OD</description>
    <arm_group_label>A: Biomarker directed Therapy (BT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B: Clinician's Choice (CC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Xtandi</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Docetaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>Docetaxel 75 mg/m2 IV every 3 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>A: Biomarker directed Therapy (BT)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>B: Clinician's Choice (CC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Taxotere</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must meet ALL of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Willing and able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Adult males ≥ 18 years age&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of histologically confirmed adenocarcinoma of the prostate without evidence of&#xD;
             neuroendocrine or small cell differentiation. If histology is not available, patients&#xD;
             must have metastatic disease typical of prostate cancer (i.e., involving bone or&#xD;
             pelvic lymph nodes or para-aortic lymph nodes) AND a serum concentration of PSA that&#xD;
             is rising and &gt;20ng/mL at the time prostate cancer was diagnosed clinically&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Consent to analysis of archival tissue collected at diagnosis is mandatory&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Prior surgical orchiectomy or if on LHRH agonist/antagonist then testosterone &lt; 1.7&#xD;
             nmol/L at screening visit (patients must maintain LHRH agonist/antagonist therapy for&#xD;
             duration of study treatment if not surgically castrated)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Evidence of metastatic disease on bone scan or CT scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Evidence of biochemical or imaging progression in the setting of surgical or medical&#xD;
             castration while on abiraterone. Progressive disease for study entry is defined by one&#xD;
             of the following three criteria as per PCWG317:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. PSA progression: minimum of two rising PSA values from a baseline measurement of&#xD;
                  one week interval. Minimum PSA at screening visit is 1.0 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Soft tissue or visceral disease progression: an increase ≥20% in the sum of the&#xD;
                  diameter (short axis for nodal lesions and long axis for non-nodal lesions) from&#xD;
                  the smallest sum of the diameter since treatment started, or appearance of any&#xD;
                  new lesions (see Appendix B for definition of measurable disease as per RECIST&#xD;
                  1.1 criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Bone progression: ≥ 2 new lesions on bone scan confirmed on subsequent bone scan&#xD;
                  at least 8 weeks apart (2+2 rule as per PCWG317)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. ECOG performance status 0-2 (see Appendix C)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Prior treatment with abiraterone, in either castration-sensitive or&#xD;
             castration-resistant setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Eligible for treatment with either enzalutamide or docetaxel as per standard of care&#xD;
             guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Adequate organ function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 109/L, platelet count ≥ 100 x 109/L and&#xD;
                  hemoglobin ≥ 90 g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Creatinine clearance ≥ 30 ml/min (calculated by Cockcroft-Gault formula, see&#xD;
                  Appendix D)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) except for patients with&#xD;
                  known Gilbert's syndrome (direct bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤ 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Able to swallow study drug and comply with study requirements including provision of&#xD;
             peripheral blood samples at specified time points for correlative studies&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Recovery from all prior treatment-related toxicity to grade ≤ 2 (as per CTCAE 5.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must NOT meet any of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Severe concurrent illness or co-morbid disease that would make the subject unsuitable&#xD;
             for enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior therapy with enzalutamide or other experimental anti-androgens (e.g. ARN-509,&#xD;
             TOK-001)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior systemic chemotherapy with docetaxel or cabazitaxel&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active concurrent malignancy (with the exception of non-melanomatous skin cancer, or&#xD;
             other solid tumours curatively treated with no evidence of disease for ≥3 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Wide-field radiotherapy or radioisotopes such as Strontium-89, or Radium-223 ≤ 28 days&#xD;
             prior to starting study drug (limited-field palliative radiotherapy for up to 5&#xD;
             fractions prior to starting study drug is permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Brain metastases or active epidural disease (treated epidural disease is permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Contraindication to prednisone therapy including poorly controlled diabetes mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of seizure or seizure disorder, or history of any cerebrovascular event within&#xD;
             6 months of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Uncontrolled hypertension Grade ≥3 (i.e. systolic blood pressure ≥160 mmHg or&#xD;
             diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Gastrointestinal disorder affecting absorption&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Major surgery within 4 weeks of starting study treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Khalaf, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>British Columbia Cancer Agency</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Daniel Khalaf, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6048776000</phone>
    <phone_ext>672418</phone_ext>
    <email>daniel.khalaf@bccancer.bc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kim N Chi, MD</last_name>
    <phone>6048776000</phone>
    <phone_ext>672734</phone_ext>
    <email>kchi@bccancer.bc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BC Cancer - Kelowna (Sindi Ahluwalia Hawkins Centre)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kelowna</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V1Y 5L3</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daygen Finch, MD</last_name>
      <phone>2507123900</phone>
      <email>DFinch-02@bccancer.bc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daygen Finch, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BC Cancer - Surrey Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Surrey</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V3V 1Z2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Krista Noonan, MD</last_name>
      <phone>6049304064</phone>
      <email>KNoonan2@bccancer.bc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Krista Noonan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BC Cancer - Vancouver Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V5Z 4E6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kim N Chi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>6048776000</phone>
      <phone_ext>672734</phone_ext>
      <email>kchi@bccancer.bc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kim N. Chi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>BC Cancer - Victoria Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Victoria</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V8R 6V5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joanna Vergidis, MD</last_name>
      <phone>2505195572</phone>
      <email>JVergidis@bccancer.bc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joanna Vergidis, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fizazi K, Tran N, Fein L, Matsubara N, Rodriguez-Antolin A, Alekseev BY, Özgüroğlu M, Ye D, Feyerabend S, Protheroe A, De Porre P, Kheoh T, Park YC, Todd MB, Chi KN; LATITUDE Investigators. Abiraterone plus Prednisone in Metastatic, Castration-Sensitive Prostate Cancer. N Engl J Med. 2017 Jul 27;377(4):352-360. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1704174. Epub 2017 Jun 4.</citation>
    <PMID>28578607</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>James ND, de Bono JS, Spears MR, Clarke NW, Mason MD, Dearnaley DP, Ritchie AWS, Amos CL, Gilson C, Jones RJ, Matheson D, Millman R, Attard G, Chowdhury S, Cross WR, Gillessen S, Parker CC, Russell JM, Berthold DR, Brawley C, Adab F, Aung S, Birtle AJ, Bowen J, Brock S, Chakraborti P, Ferguson C, Gale J, Gray E, Hingorani M, Hoskin PJ, Lester JF, Malik ZI, McKinna F, McPhail N, Money-Kyrle J, O'Sullivan J, Parikh O, Protheroe A, Robinson A, Srihari NN, Thomas C, Wagstaff J, Wylie J, Zarkar A, Parmar MKB, Sydes MR; STAMPEDE Investigators. Abiraterone for Prostate Cancer Not Previously Treated with Hormone Therapy. N Engl J Med. 2017 Jul 27;377(4):338-351. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1702900. Epub 2017 Jun 3.</citation>
    <PMID>28578639</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Attard G, Parker C, Eeles RA, Schröder F, Tomlins SA, Tannock I, Drake CG, de Bono JS. Prostate cancer. Lancet. 2016 Jan 2;387(10013):70-82. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(14)61947-4. Epub 2015 Jun 11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26074382</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lorente D, Mateo J, Perez-Lopez R, de Bono JS, Attard G. Sequencing of agents in castration-resistant prostate cancer. Lancet Oncol. 2015 Jun;16(6):e279-92. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(15)70033-1. Epub 2015 May 27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26065613</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wyatt AW, Gleave ME. Targeting the adaptive molecular landscape of castration-resistant prostate cancer. EMBO Mol Med. 2015 Jul;7(7):878-94. doi: 10.15252/emmm.201303701. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25896606</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Robinson D, Van Allen EM, Wu YM, Schultz N, Lonigro RJ, Mosquera JM, Montgomery B, Taplin ME, Pritchard CC, Attard G, Beltran H, Abida W, Bradley RK, Vinson J, Cao X, Vats P, Kunju LP, Hussain M, Feng FY, Tomlins SA, Cooney KA, Smith DC, Brennan C, Siddiqui J, Mehra R, Chen Y, Rathkopf DE, Morris MJ, Solomon SB, Durack JC, Reuter VE, Gopalan A, Gao J, Loda M, Lis RT, Bowden M, Balk SP, Gaviola G, Sougnez C, Gupta M, Yu EY, Mostaghel EA, Cheng HH, Mulcahy H, True LD, Plymate SR, Dvinge H, Ferraldeschi R, Flohr P, Miranda S, Zafeiriou Z, Tunariu N, Mateo J, Perez-Lopez R, Demichelis F, Robinson BD, Schiffman M, Nanus DM, Tagawa ST, Sigaras A, Eng KW, Elemento O, Sboner A, Heath EI, Scher HI, Pienta KJ, Kantoff P, de Bono JS, Rubin MA, Nelson PS, Garraway LA, Sawyers CL, Chinnaiyan AM. Integrative clinical genomics of advanced prostate cancer. Cell. 2015 May 21;161(5):1215-1228. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2015.05.001. Erratum in: Cell. 2015 Jul 16;162(2):454.</citation>
    <PMID>26000489</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chedgy EC, Annala M, Beja K, Warner EW, Gleave ME, Chi KN, Wyatt AW. Moving Toward Personalized Care: Liquid Biopsy Predicts Response to Cisplatin in an Unusual Case of BRCA2-Null Neuroendocrine Prostate Cancer. Clin Genitourin Cancer. 2016 Apr;14(2):e233-6. doi: 10.1016/j.clgc.2015.12.023. Epub 2015 Dec 24.</citation>
    <PMID>26797585</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lallous N, Volik SV, Awrey S, Leblanc E, Tse R, Murillo J, Singh K, Azad AA, Wyatt AW, LeBihan S, Chi KN, Gleave ME, Rennie PS, Collins CC, Cherkasov A. Functional analysis of androgen receptor mutations that confer anti-androgen resistance identified in circulating cell-free DNA from prostate cancer patients. Genome Biol. 2016 Jan 26;17:10. doi: 10.1186/s13059-015-0864-1.</citation>
    <PMID>26813233</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wyatt AW, Azad AA, Volik SV, Annala M, Beja K, McConeghy B, Haegert A, Warner EW, Mo F, Brahmbhatt S, Shukin R, Le Bihan S, Gleave ME, Nykter M, Collins CC, Chi KN. Genomic Alterations in Cell-Free DNA and Enzalutamide Resistance in Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer. JAMA Oncol. 2016 Dec 1;2(12):1598-1606. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2016.0494.</citation>
    <PMID>27148695</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Azad AA, Volik SV, Wyatt AW, Haegert A, Le Bihan S, Bell RH, Anderson SA, McConeghy B, Shukin R, Bazov J, Youngren J, Paris P, Thomas G, Small EJ, Wang Y, Gleave ME, Collins CC, Chi KN. Androgen Receptor Gene Aberrations in Circulating Cell-Free DNA: Biomarkers of Therapeutic Resistance in Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2015 May 15;21(10):2315-24. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-14-2666. Epub 2015 Feb 23.</citation>
    <PMID>25712683</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Annala M, Struss WJ, Warner EW, Beja K, Vandekerkhove G, Wong A, Khalaf D, Seppälä IL, So A, Lo G, Aggarwal R, Small EJ, Nykter M, Gleave ME, Chi KN, Wyatt AW. Treatment Outcomes and Tumor Loss of Heterozygosity in Germline DNA Repair-deficient Prostate Cancer. Eur Urol. 2017 Jul;72(1):34-42. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2017.02.023. Epub 2017 Mar 1.</citation>
    <PMID>28259476</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Quigley D, Alumkal JJ, Wyatt AW, Kothari V, Foye A, Lloyd P, Aggarwal R, Kim W, Lu E, Schwartzman J, Beja K, Annala M, Das R, Diolaiti M, Pritchard C, Thomas G, Tomlins S, Knudsen K, Lord CJ, Ryan C, Youngren J, Beer TM, Ashworth A, Small EJ, Feng FY. Analysis of Circulating Cell-Free DNA Identifies Multiclonal Heterogeneity of BRCA2 Reversion Mutations Associated with Resistance to PARP Inhibitors. Cancer Discov. 2017 Sep;7(9):999-1005. doi: 10.1158/2159-8290.CD-17-0146. Epub 2017 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>28450426</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wyatt AW, Annala M, Aggarwal R, Beja K, Feng F, Youngren J, Foye A, Lloyd P, Nykter M, Beer TM, Alumkal JJ, Thomas GV, Reiter RE, Rettig MB, Evans CP, Gao AC, Chi KN, Small EJ, Gleave ME. Concordance of Circulating Tumor DNA and Matched Metastatic Tissue Biopsy in Prostate Cancer. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2017 Dec 1;109(12). doi: 10.1093/jnci/djx118.</citation>
    <PMID>29206995</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Annala M, Vandekerkhove G, Khalaf D, Taavitsainen S, Beja K, Warner EW, Sunderland K, Kollmannsberger C, Eigl BJ, Finch D, Oja CD, Vergidis J, Zulfiqar M, Azad AA, Nykter M, Gleave ME, Wyatt AW, Chi KN. Circulating Tumor DNA Genomics Correlate with Resistance to Abiraterone and Enzalutamide in Prostate Cancer. Cancer Discov. 2018 Apr;8(4):444-457. doi: 10.1158/2159-8290.CD-17-0937. Epub 2018 Jan 24.</citation>
    <PMID>29367197</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beltran H, Wyatt AW, Chedgy EC, Donoghue A, Annala M, Warner EW, Beja K, Sigouros M, Mo F, Fazli L, Collins CC, Eastham J, Morris M, Taplin ME, Sboner A, Halabi S, Gleave ME. Impact of Therapy on Genomics and Transcriptomics in High-Risk Prostate Cancer Treated with Neoadjuvant Docetaxel and Androgen Deprivation Therapy. Clin Cancer Res. 2017 Nov 15;23(22):6802-6811. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-17-1034. Epub 2017 Aug 25.</citation>
    <PMID>28842510</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khalaf DJ, Annala M, Taavitsainen S, Finch DL, Oja C, Vergidis J, Zulfiqar M, Sunderland K, Azad AA, Kollmannsberger CK, Eigl BJ, Noonan K, Wadhwa D, Attwell A, Keith B, Ellard SL, Le L, Gleave ME, Wyatt AW, Chi KN. Optimal sequencing of enzalutamide and abiraterone acetate plus prednisone in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer: a multicentre, randomised, open-label, phase 2, crossover trial. Lancet Oncol. 2019 Dec;20(12):1730-1739. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(19)30688-6. Epub 2019 Nov 11.</citation>
    <PMID>31727538</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khalaf D, Annala M, Finch DL, et al. Phase 2 randomized cross-over trial of abiraterone + prednisone (ABI+P) vs enzalutamide (ENZ) for patients (pts) with metastatic castration resistant prostate cancer (mCPRC): Results for 2nd-line therapy. J Clin Oncol [Internet] 2018;36(15_suppl):5015.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Scher HI, Morris MJ, Stadler WM, Higano C, Basch E, Fizazi K, Antonarakis ES, Beer TM, Carducci MA, Chi KN, Corn PG, de Bono JS, Dreicer R, George DJ, Heath EI, Hussain M, Kelly WK, Liu G, Logothetis C, Nanus D, Stein MN, Rathkopf DE, Slovin SF, Ryan CJ, Sartor O, Small EJ, Smith MR, Sternberg CN, Taplin ME, Wilding G, Nelson PS, Schwartz LH, Halabi S, Kantoff PW, Armstrong AJ; Prostate Cancer Clinical Trials Working Group 3. Trial Design and Objectives for Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer: Updated Recommendations From the Prostate Cancer Clinical Trials Working Group 3. J Clin Oncol. 2016 Apr 20;34(12):1402-18. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2015.64.2702. Epub 2016 Feb 22.</citation>
    <PMID>26903579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sridhar SS, Freedland SJ, Gleave ME, Higano C, Mulders P, Parker C, Sartor O, Saad F. Castration-resistant prostate cancer: from new pathophysiology to new treatment. Eur Urol. 2014 Feb;65(2):289-99. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2013.08.008. Epub 2013 Aug 11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23957948</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beer TM, Armstrong AJ, Rathkopf DE, Loriot Y, Sternberg CN, Higano CS, Iversen P, Bhattacharya S, Carles J, Chowdhury S, Davis ID, de Bono JS, Evans CP, Fizazi K, Joshua AM, Kim CS, Kimura G, Mainwaring P, Mansbach H, Miller K, Noonberg SB, Perabo F, Phung D, Saad F, Scher HI, Taplin ME, Venner PM, Tombal B; PREVAIL Investigators. Enzalutamide in metastatic prostate cancer before chemotherapy. N Engl J Med. 2014 Jul 31;371(5):424-33. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1405095. Epub 2014 Jun 1.</citation>
    <PMID>24881730</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Bono JS, Logothetis CJ, Molina A, Fizazi K, North S, Chu L, Chi KN, Jones RJ, Goodman OB Jr, Saad F, Staffurth JN, Mainwaring P, Harland S, Flaig TW, Hutson TE, Cheng T, Patterson H, Hainsworth JD, Ryan CJ, Sternberg CN, Ellard SL, Fléchon A, Saleh M, Scholz M, Efstathiou E, Zivi A, Bianchini D, Loriot Y, Chieffo N, Kheoh T, Haqq CM, Scher HI; COU-AA-301 Investigators. Abiraterone and increased survival in metastatic prostate cancer. N Engl J Med. 2011 May 26;364(21):1995-2005. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1014618.</citation>
    <PMID>21612468</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ryan CJ, Smith MR, de Bono JS, Molina A, Logothetis CJ, de Souza P, Fizazi K, Mainwaring P, Piulats JM, Ng S, Carles J, Mulders PF, Basch E, Small EJ, Saad F, Schrijvers D, Van Poppel H, Mukherjee SD, Suttmann H, Gerritsen WR, Flaig TW, George DJ, Yu EY, Efstathiou E, Pantuck A, Winquist E, Higano CS, Taplin ME, Park Y, Kheoh T, Griffin T, Scher HI, Rathkopf DE; COU-AA-302 Investigators. Abiraterone in metastatic prostate cancer without previous chemotherapy. N Engl J Med. 2013 Jan 10;368(2):138-48. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1209096. Epub 2012 Dec 10. Erratum in: N Engl J Med. 2013 Feb 7;368(6):584.</citation>
    <PMID>23228172</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Scher HI, Fizazi K, Saad F, Taplin ME, Sternberg CN, Miller K, de Wit R, Mulders P, Chi KN, Shore ND, Armstrong AJ, Flaig TW, Fléchon A, Mainwaring P, Fleming M, Hainsworth JD, Hirmand M, Selby B, Seely L, de Bono JS; AFFIRM Investigators. Increased survival with enzalutamide in prostate cancer after chemotherapy. N Engl J Med. 2012 Sep 27;367(13):1187-97. Epub 2012 Aug 15.</citation>
    <PMID>22894553</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Azad AA, Eigl BJ, Leibowitz-Amit R, Lester R, Kollmannsberger C, Murray N, Clayton R, Heng DY, Joshua AM, Chi KN. Outcomes with abiraterone acetate in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer patients who have poor performance status. Eur Urol. 2015 Mar;67(3):441-7. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2014.01.030. Epub 2014 Jan 31.</citation>
    <PMID>24508071</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Noonan KL, North S, Bitting RL, Armstrong AJ, Ellard SL, Chi KN. Clinical activity of abiraterone acetate in patients with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer progressing after enzalutamide. Ann Oncol. 2013 Jul;24(7):1802-1807. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdt138. Epub 2013 Apr 12.</citation>
    <PMID>23585511</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu YM, Cieślik M, Lonigro RJ, Vats P, Reimers MA, Cao X, Ning Y, Wang L, Kunju LP, de Sarkar N, Heath EI, Chou J, Feng FY, Nelson PS, de Bono JS, Zou W, Montgomery B, Alva A; PCF/SU2C International Prostate Cancer Dream Team, Robinson DR, Chinnaiyan AM. Inactivation of CDK12 Delineates a Distinct Immunogenic Class of Advanced Prostate Cancer. Cell. 2018 Jun 14;173(7):1770-1782.e14. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2018.04.034.</citation>
    <PMID>29906450</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Takeda DY, Spisák S, Seo JH, Bell C, O'Connor E, Korthauer K, Ribli D, Csabai I, Solymosi N, Szállási Z, Stillman DR, Cejas P, Qiu X, Long HW, Tisza V, Nuzzo PV, Rohanizadegan M, Pomerantz MM, Hahn WC, Freedman ML. A Somatically Acquired Enhancer of the Androgen Receptor Is a Noncoding Driver in Advanced Prostate Cancer. Cell. 2018 Jul 12;174(2):422-432.e13. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2018.05.037. Epub 2018 Jun 14.</citation>
    <PMID>29909987</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Viswanathan SR, Ha G, Hoff AM, Wala JA, Carrot-Zhang J, Whelan CW, Haradhvala NJ, Freeman SS, Reed SC, Rhoades J, Polak P, Cipicchio M, Wankowicz SA, Wong A, Kamath T, Zhang Z, Gydush GJ, Rotem D; PCF/SU2C International Prostate Cancer Dream Team, Love JC, Getz G, Gabriel S, Zhang CZ, Dehm SM, Nelson PS, Van Allen EM, Choudhury AD, Adalsteinsson VA, Beroukhim R, Taplin ME, Meyerson M. Structural Alterations Driving Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer Revealed by Linked-Read Genome Sequencing. Cell. 2018 Jul 12;174(2):433-447.e19. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2018.05.036. Epub 2018 Jun 18.</citation>
    <PMID>29909985</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Henzler C, Li Y, Yang R, McBride T, Ho Y, Sprenger C, Liu G, Coleman I, Lakely B, Li R, Ma S, Landman SR, Kumar V, Hwang TH, Raj GV, Higano CS, Morrissey C, Nelson PS, Plymate SR, Dehm SM. Truncation and constitutive activation of the androgen receptor by diverse genomic rearrangements in prostate cancer. Nat Commun. 2016 Nov 29;7:13668. doi: 10.1038/ncomms13668.</citation>
    <PMID>27897170</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tannock IF, de Wit R, Berry WR, Horti J, Pluzanska A, Chi KN, Oudard S, Théodore C, James ND, Turesson I, Rosenthal MA, Eisenberger MA; TAX 327 Investigators. Docetaxel plus prednisone or mitoxantrone plus prednisone for advanced prostate cancer. N Engl J Med. 2004 Oct 7;351(15):1502-12.</citation>
    <PMID>15470213</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Bono JS, Oudard S, Ozguroglu M, Hansen S, Machiels JP, Kocak I, Gravis G, Bodrogi I, Mackenzie MJ, Shen L, Roessner M, Gupta S, Sartor AO; TROPIC Investigators. Prednisone plus cabazitaxel or mitoxantrone for metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer progressing after docetaxel treatment: a randomised open-label trial. Lancet. 2010 Oct 2;376(9747):1147-54. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61389-X.</citation>
    <PMID>20888992</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baca SC, Prandi D, Lawrence MS, Mosquera JM, Romanel A, Drier Y, Park K, Kitabayashi N, MacDonald TY, Ghandi M, Van Allen E, Kryukov GV, Sboner A, Theurillat JP, Soong TD, Nickerson E, Auclair D, Tewari A, Beltran H, Onofrio RC, Boysen G, Guiducci C, Barbieri CE, Cibulskis K, Sivachenko A, Carter SL, Saksena G, Voet D, Ramos AH, Winckler W, Cipicchio M, Ardlie K, Kantoff PW, Berger MF, Gabriel SB, Golub TR, Meyerson M, Lander ES, Elemento O, Getz G, Demichelis F, Rubin MA, Garraway LA. Punctuated evolution of prostate cancer genomes. Cell. 2013 Apr 25;153(3):666-77. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2013.03.021.</citation>
    <PMID>23622249</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barbieri CE, Baca SC, Lawrence MS, Demichelis F, Blattner M, Theurillat JP, White TA, Stojanov P, Van Allen E, Stransky N, Nickerson E, Chae SS, Boysen G, Auclair D, Onofrio RC, Park K, Kitabayashi N, MacDonald TY, Sheikh K, Vuong T, Guiducci C, Cibulskis K, Sivachenko A, Carter SL, Saksena G, Voet D, Hussain WM, Ramos AH, Winckler W, Redman MC, Ardlie K, Tewari AK, Mosquera JM, Rupp N, Wild PJ, Moch H, Morrissey C, Nelson PS, Kantoff PW, Gabriel SB, Golub TR, Meyerson M, Lander ES, Getz G, Rubin MA, Garraway LA. Exome sequencing identifies recurrent SPOP, FOXA1 and MED12 mutations in prostate cancer. Nat Genet. 2012 May 20;44(6):685-9. doi: 10.1038/ng.2279.</citation>
    <PMID>22610119</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berger MF, Lawrence MS, Demichelis F, Drier Y, Cibulskis K, Sivachenko AY, Sboner A, Esgueva R, Pflueger D, Sougnez C, Onofrio R, Carter SL, Park K, Habegger L, Ambrogio L, Fennell T, Parkin M, Saksena G, Voet D, Ramos AH, Pugh TJ, Wilkinson J, Fisher S, Winckler W, Mahan S, Ardlie K, Baldwin J, Simons JW, Kitabayashi N, MacDonald TY, Kantoff PW, Chin L, Gabriel SB, Gerstein MB, Golub TR, Meyerson M, Tewari A, Lander ES, Getz G, Rubin MA, Garraway LA. The genomic complexity of primary human prostate cancer. Nature. 2011 Feb 10;470(7333):214-20. doi: 10.1038/nature09744.</citation>
    <PMID>21307934</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wyatt AW, Mo F, Wang K, McConeghy B, Brahmbhatt S, Jong L, Mitchell DM, Johnston RL, Haegert A, Li E, Liew J, Yeung J, Shrestha R, Lapuk AV, McPherson A, Shukin R, Bell RH, Anderson S, Bishop J, Hurtado-Coll A, Xiao H, Chinnaiyan AM, Mehra R, Lin D, Wang Y, Fazli L, Gleave ME, Volik SV, Collins CC. Heterogeneity in the inter-tumor transcriptome of high risk prostate cancer. Genome Biol. 2014 Aug 26;15(8):426. doi: 10.1186/s13059-014-0426-y.</citation>
    <PMID>25155515</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beltran H, Eng K, Mosquera JM, Sigaras A, Romanel A, Rennert H, Kossai M, Pauli C, Faltas B, Fontugne J, Park K, Banfelder J, Prandi D, Madhukar N, Zhang T, Padilla J, Greco N, McNary TJ, Herrscher E, Wilkes D, MacDonald TY, Xue H, Vacic V, Emde AK, Oschwald D, Tan AY, Chen Z, Collins C, Gleave ME, Wang Y, Chakravarty D, Schiffman M, Kim R, Campagne F, Robinson BD, Nanus DM, Tagawa ST, Xiang JZ, Smogorzewska A, Demichelis F, Rickman DS, Sboner A, Elemento O, Rubin MA. Whole-Exome Sequencing of Metastatic Cancer and Biomarkers of Treatment Response. JAMA Oncol. 2015 Jul;1(4):466-74. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2015.1313.</citation>
    <PMID>26181256</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Beltran H, Prandi D, Mosquera JM, Benelli M, Puca L, Cyrta J, Marotz C, Giannopoulou E, Chakravarthi BV, Varambally S, Tomlins SA, Nanus DM, Tagawa ST, Van Allen EM, Elemento O, Sboner A, Garraway LA, Rubin MA, Demichelis F. Divergent clonal evolution of castration-resistant neuroendocrine prostate cancer. Nat Med. 2016 Mar;22(3):298-305. doi: 10.1038/nm.4045. Epub 2016 Feb 8.</citation>
    <PMID>26855148</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gundem G, Van Loo P, Kremeyer B, Alexandrov LB, Tubio JMC, Papaemmanuil E, Brewer DS, Kallio HML, Högnäs G, Annala M, Kivinummi K, Goody V, Latimer C, O'Meara S, Dawson KJ, Isaacs W, Emmert-Buck MR, Nykter M, Foster C, Kote-Jarai Z, Easton D, Whitaker HC; ICGC Prostate Group, Neal DE, Cooper CS, Eeles RA, Visakorpi T, Campbell PJ, McDermott U, Wedge DC, Bova GS. The evolutionary history of lethal metastatic prostate cancer. Nature. 2015 Apr 16;520(7547):353-357. doi: 10.1038/nature14347. Epub 2015 Apr 1. Erratum in: Nature. 2020 Aug;584(7820):E18.</citation>
    <PMID>25830880</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hong MK, Macintyre G, Wedge DC, Van Loo P, Patel K, Lunke S, Alexandrov LB, Sloggett C, Cmero M, Marass F, Tsui D, Mangiola S, Lonie A, Naeem H, Sapre N, Phal PM, Kurganovs N, Chin X, Kerger M, Warren AY, Neal D, Gnanapragasam V, Rosenfeld N, Pedersen JS, Ryan A, Haviv I, Costello AJ, Corcoran NM, Hovens CM. Tracking the origins and drivers of subclonal metastatic expansion in prostate cancer. Nat Commun. 2015 Apr 1;6:6605. doi: 10.1038/ncomms7605.</citation>
    <PMID>25827447</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lorente D, Omlin A, Zafeiriou Z, Nava-Rodrigues D, Pérez-López R, Pezaro C, Mehra N, Sheridan E, Figueiredo I, Riisnaes R, Miranda S, Crespo M, Flohr P, Mateo J, Altavilla A, Ferraldeschi R, Bianchini D, Attard G, Tunariu N, de Bono J. Castration-Resistant Prostate Cancer Tissue Acquisition From Bone Metastases for Molecular Analyses. Clin Genitourin Cancer. 2016 Dec;14(6):485-493. doi: 10.1016/j.clgc.2016.04.016. Epub 2016 May 5.</citation>
    <PMID>27246360</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ross RW, Halabi S, Ou SS, Rajeshkumar BR, Woda BA, Vogelzang NJ, Small EJ, Taplin ME, Kantoff PW; Cancer and Leukemia Group B. Predictors of prostate cancer tissue acquisition by an undirected core bone marrow biopsy in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer--a Cancer and Leukemia Group B study. Clin Cancer Res. 2005 Nov 15;11(22):8109-13.</citation>
    <PMID>16299243</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Efstathiou E, Titus M, Wen S, Hoang A, Karlou M, Ashe R, Tu SM, Aparicio A, Troncoso P, Mohler J, Logothetis CJ. Molecular characterization of enzalutamide-treated bone metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. Eur Urol. 2015 Jan;67(1):53-60. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2014.05.005. Epub 2014 May 29.</citation>
    <PMID>24882673</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McKay RR, Zukotynski KA, Werner L, Voznesensky O, Wu JS, Smith SE, Jiang Z, Melnick K, Yuan X, Kantoff PW, Montgomery B, Balk SP, Taplin ME. Imaging, procedural and clinical variables associated with tumor yield on bone biopsy in metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 2014 Dec;17(4):325-31. doi: 10.1038/pcan.2014.28. Epub 2014 Aug 5.</citation>
    <PMID>25091040</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spritzer CE, Afonso PD, Vinson EN, Turnbull JD, Morris KK, Foye A, Madden JF, Roy Choudhury K, Febbo PG, George DJ. Bone marrow biopsy: RNA isolation with expression profiling in men with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer--factors affecting diagnostic success. Radiology. 2013 Dec;269(3):816-23. doi: 10.1148/radiol.13121782. Epub 2013 Oct 28.</citation>
    <PMID>23925271</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vandekerkhove G, Chi KN, Wyatt AW. Clinical utility of emerging liquid biomarkers in advanced prostate cancer. Cancer Genet. 2018 Dec;228-229:151-158. doi: 10.1016/j.cancergen.2017.08.003. Epub 2017 Aug 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28958406</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Carreira S, Romanel A, Goodall J, Grist E, Ferraldeschi R, Miranda S, Prandi D, Lorente D, Frenel JS, Pezaro C, Omlin A, Rodrigues DN, Flohr P, Tunariu N, S de Bono J, Demichelis F, Attard G. Tumor clone dynamics in lethal prostate cancer. Sci Transl Med. 2014 Sep 17;6(254):254ra125. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.3009448.</citation>
    <PMID>25232177</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Antonarakis ES, Lu C, Wang H, Luber B, Nakazawa M, Roeser JC, Chen Y, Mohammad TA, Chen Y, Fedor HL, Lotan TL, Zheng Q, De Marzo AM, Isaacs JT, Isaacs WB, Nadal R, Paller CJ, Denmeade SR, Carducci MA, Eisenberger MA, Luo J. AR-V7 and resistance to enzalutamide and abiraterone in prostate cancer. N Engl J Med. 2014 Sep 11;371(11):1028-38. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1315815. Epub 2014 Sep 3.</citation>
    <PMID>25184630</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dijkstra S, Mulders PF, Schalken JA. Clinical use of novel urine and blood based prostate cancer biomarkers: a review. Clin Biochem. 2014 Jul;47(10-11):889-96. doi: 10.1016/j.clinbiochem.2013.10.023. Epub 2013 Oct 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24177197</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Quek SI, Wong OM, Chen A, Borges GT, Ellis WJ, Salvanha DM, Vêncio RZ, Weaver B, Ench YM, Leach RJ, Thompson IM, Liu AY. Processing of voided urine for prostate cancer RNA biomarker analysis. Prostate. 2015 Dec;75(16):1886-95. doi: 10.1002/pros.23066. Epub 2015 Aug 26.</citation>
    <PMID>26306723</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ulz P, Belic J, Graf R, Auer M, Lafer I, Fischereder K, Webersinke G, Pummer K, Augustin H, Pichler M, Hoefler G, Bauernhofer T, Geigl JB, Heitzer E, Speicher MR. Whole-genome plasma sequencing reveals focal amplifications as a driving force in metastatic prostate cancer. Nat Commun. 2016 Jun 22;7:12008. doi: 10.1038/ncomms12008.</citation>
    <PMID>27328849</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Romanel A, Gasi Tandefelt D, Conteduca V, Jayaram A, Casiraghi N, Wetterskog D, Salvi S, Amadori D, Zafeiriou Z, Rescigno P, Bianchini D, Gurioli G, Casadio V, Carreira S, Goodall J, Wingate A, Ferraldeschi R, Tunariu N, Flohr P, De Giorgi U, de Bono JS, Demichelis F, Attard G. Plasma AR and abiraterone-resistant prostate cancer. Sci Transl Med. 2015 Nov 4;7(312):312re10. doi: 10.1126/scitranslmed.aac9511.</citation>
    <PMID>26537258</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heitzer E, Ulz P, Belic J, Gutschi S, Quehenberger F, Fischereder K, Benezeder T, Auer M, Pischler C, Mannweiler S, Pichler M, Eisner F, Haeusler M, Riethdorf S, Pantel K, Samonigg H, Hoefler G, Augustin H, Geigl JB, Speicher MR. Tumor-associated copy number changes in the circulation of patients with prostate cancer identified through whole-genome sequencing. Genome Med. 2013 Apr 5;5(4):30. doi: 10.1186/gm434. eCollection 2013.</citation>
    <PMID>23561577</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Volik S, Alcaide M, Morin RD, Collins C. Cell-free DNA (cfDNA): Clinical Significance and Utility in Cancer Shaped By Emerging Technologies. Mol Cancer Res. 2016 Oct;14(10):898-908. Epub 2016 Jul 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27422709</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Bono JS, Smith MR, Saad F, Rathkopf DE, Mulders PFA, Small EJ, Shore ND, Fizazi K, De Porre P, Kheoh T, Li J, Todd MB, Ryan CJ, Flaig TW. Subsequent Chemotherapy and Treatment Patterns After Abiraterone Acetate in Patients with Metastatic Castration-resistant Prostate Cancer: Post Hoc Analysis of COU-AA-302. Eur Urol. 2017 Apr;71(4):656-664. doi: 10.1016/j.eururo.2016.06.033. Epub 2016 Jul 9.</citation>
    <PMID>27402060</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tran C, Ouk S, Clegg NJ, Chen Y, Watson PA, Arora V, Wongvipat J, Smith-Jones PM, Yoo D, Kwon A, Wasielewska T, Welsbie D, Chen CD, Higano CS, Beer TM, Hung DT, Scher HI, Jung ME, Sawyers CL. Development of a second-generation antiandrogen for treatment of advanced prostate cancer. Science. 2009 May 8;324(5928):787-90. doi: 10.1126/science.1168175. Epub 2009 Apr 9.</citation>
    <PMID>19359544</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 9, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 9, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 11, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>circulating tumor DNA</keyword>
  <keyword>Enzalutamide</keyword>
  <keyword>Docetaxel</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Docetaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

