<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04019158</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NMSK - Lheureux 02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04019158</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of iVR Treadmill on Gait in PD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Immersive Virtual Reality on Treadmill to Ecologically Assess Parkinson's Disease Patients' Gait</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc- Université Catholique de Louvain</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc- Université Catholique de Louvain</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Parkinson's Disease (PD) patients suffer from gait impairments responsible for falls and bad&#xD;
      quality of life: reduced speed and stride length, randomness in stride duration variability&#xD;
      (reduced Long-Range Autocorrelations (LRA)). This pilot study will compare the&#xD;
      spatio-temporal walking parameters and LRA of PD patients tested under three conditions:&#xD;
      walking over ground, walking on a treadmill and walking on a treadmill in virtual reality.&#xD;
      The aim is to determine the effect on gait of an optical flow recreated in virtual reality,&#xD;
      by means of a virtual reality headset, on a treadmill.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. BACKGROUND Parkinson's disease (PD) is the second most common degenerative neurological&#xD;
           disease. PD induces gait disorders that lead to increased risk of falls. These falls&#xD;
           seriously affect patients' quality of life and generate significant health care costs.&#xD;
           Unfortunately, gait disorders do not respond well to drug treatments and their&#xD;
           management is mainly based on rehabilitation treatment. The rehabilitation approach&#xD;
           comprises two steps: a functional assessment of locomotor capacities followed by&#xD;
           completion of a therapeutic physical exercise program.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Like heart rate, stride duration varies in the short and long term according to a&#xD;
           complex dynamic of temporal variations. These variations present long-range&#xD;
           autocorrelations (LRA): the stride duration does not vary randomly but in a structured&#xD;
           way. The study of LRA is based on complex mathematical methods requiring recording of&#xD;
           512 consecutive gait cycles. LRA are altered in PD patients whose gait rhythm is&#xD;
           excessively random. Alteration of LRA is correlated with neurological impairments (Hoehn&#xD;
           &amp; Yahr scale and UPDRS) and patients' locomotor stability (ABC scale &amp; BESTest).&#xD;
           Measurement of LRA would be the first available objective and quantitative biomarker of&#xD;
           stability and risk of falling in patients with PD.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Guidelines concerning rehabilitation programs for PD patients are based on education&#xD;
           (prevention of falls and inactivity,...), physical exercises, functional training&#xD;
           (double task, complex tasks,...), learning, adaptation strategies (cueing) and action&#xD;
           observation. The combination between immersive virtual reality (iVR), using an iVR&#xD;
           headset, and treadmill walking will be developped.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Treadmill walking has shown long-term effectiveness on PD patients' gait and quality of&#xD;
           life. A study carried out recently has shown that a single treadmill session reduces the&#xD;
           stride duration variability during the intervention. Although the treadmill seems to&#xD;
           improve patients' gait, it lacks an essential ecological component that allows humans to&#xD;
           stabilize gait: an optical flow, an environment that scrolls during walking. iVR allows&#xD;
           to give patients a visual flow when walking on treadmill as if they were walking&#xD;
           overground and patients could benefit from it. The purpose of this pilot study is to&#xD;
           compare the spatio-temporal gait parameters and gait variability parameters obtained&#xD;
           during three Walking conditions: over ground walking, treadmill walking, treadmill&#xD;
           walking with a VR headset.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.1 Participants : 10 patients suffering from idiopathic Parkinson's Disease will be&#xD;
      recruited from the local community and from the Neurology and the Physical and Rehabilitation&#xD;
      Medicine outpatient clinics of the Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc (Woluwe-Saint-Lambert,&#xD;
      Belgium).&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2 Functional assessment: Before the expermientations starts, all participants will undergo&#xD;
      a non harmful assessment including clinical tests and questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
      PD patients: Age, height, weight, sex, most affected side, Movement Disorder Society-Unified&#xD;
      Parkinson Disease Rating Scale (MDS-UPDRS), Mini Balance Evaluation Systems Test&#xD;
      (Mini-BESTest), Simplified version of the Activities-specific Balance Confidence Scale&#xD;
      (ABC-Scale), modified Hoehn &amp; Yahr scale, Mini Mental State Examination (MMSE).&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3 Procedure : Every participants will walk in three conditions in a randomized order. Each&#xD;
      condition lasted ±15 minutes in order to get 512 gait cycles mandatory to assess the presence&#xD;
      of LRA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first condition consists in Over ground Walking (OW). Participants will be asked to walk&#xD;
      on an rectangular track with rounded corner of 63.2 meters in CUSL at their comfortable&#xD;
      walking speed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second condition is Treadmill Walking (TW). Patients will walk on the treadmill at their&#xD;
      comfortable walking speed assessed before the condition with a 10 Meter Walk Test. During&#xD;
      this condition, patients will wear a non weight-bearing safety harness (Petzl, Volt, France).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The last condition consists in walking on a treadmill, at the same speed as during TW,&#xD;
      patients still wearing the non weight-bearing harness, while wearing a VR headset (VRTW). The&#xD;
      VR headset (HTC, Vive, Taïwan) consists of a kind of mask that the person comes to put on his&#xD;
      face. Two Fresnel lenses are in front of the person's eyes and the person looks at a display&#xD;
      that allows stereoscopic 3D through these lenses. The patient is then immersed in an&#xD;
      immersive virtual environment, cut off from the outside world. For this experiment, a VR&#xD;
      environment has been created by means of Unity software and using C# code. While walking on&#xD;
      the treadmill, the participants will see a quiet hallway surrounding them. The participants&#xD;
      will perceive an optic flow while walking on the treadmill. The speed of the optic flow&#xD;
      perceived inside the headset by the patient will be matched with the speed of the treadmill&#xD;
      to create the illusion of walking on an actual hallway. A cybersickness questionnaire&#xD;
      (Simulator Sickness Questionnaire, SSQ) will be completed before and just after VRTW. Indeed,&#xD;
      the use of a VR headset can cause dizziness, nausea, headaches and other symptoms in some&#xD;
      patients. We want to evaluate whether or not the use of an optical flow displayed in VR on a&#xD;
      treadmill leads to cybersickness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4 Data acquisition: Two Inertial Measurement Units (IMU) (IMeasureU Research, VICON, USA)&#xD;
      will be taped on patients' both lateral malleoli. IMUs will be taped on the leg on the side&#xD;
      most affected by the disease. This system allowed to record ankle accelerations at 500 Hz.&#xD;
      The data will then be put on a computer and each peak of acceleration, corresponding to each&#xD;
      heel strike, will be detected by software internally developed to determine all stride&#xD;
      durations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5 Gait assessment: Data will be extracted from 512 consecutive gait cycles which is&#xD;
      required to measure gait variability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.1 Spatiotemporal gait variables:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mean gait speed, gait cadence and stride length will be measured as follow:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mean gait speed (m.s-1) = Total walking distance (m)/ Acquisition duration (s) Gait cadence&#xD;
      (#steps.min-1) = Total number of steps (#)/Acquisition duration (min) Step length (m) = Gait&#xD;
      speed (m/s)*60/Gait cadence (steps/min)&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.2 Stride duration variability : Stride duration variability can be assessed 2 ways: in&#xD;
      terms of magnitude or in terms of organization (how stride duration evolves across&#xD;
      consecutive gait cycles).&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.2.1 Magnitude of the stride duration variability : To determine the effect of the RAS on&#xD;
      the magnitude of the stride duration variability during 512 gait cycles, the mean, the&#xD;
      standard deviation (SD) and the coefficient of variation (CV = [SD/mean] * 100) will be&#xD;
      assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.2.2 Temporal organization of the stride duration variability (LRA) : Temporal&#xD;
      organization of stride duration variability will be assessed by LRA computation using the&#xD;
      evenly spaced averaged version of the Detrended Fluctuation Analysis (DFA) to obtain α&#xD;
      exponent. The presence of LRA can be shown with α exponent values between 0.5 and 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be treated by the mean of CVI Labwindows (C++).&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.6 Statistical analyses : Statistical analyses will be conducted using Sigmaplot 13. If the&#xD;
      normality test is passed, a one-way repeated measures ANOVA will be applied to determine the&#xD;
      effect of the various walking condition on spatiotemporal gait parameters (gait speed, gait&#xD;
      cadence, stride length) and on linear and nonlinear measures of stride duration variability&#xD;
      (CV, SD, H and α exponents). When a significant difference between groups is detected with&#xD;
      the ANOVA, a post hoc test will be performed to compare each mean with the other means to&#xD;
      isolate the groups from each other.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A paired t-test will also be conducted to determine a possible change in score on the SSQ&#xD;
      questionnaire after TW and after VRTW.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 10, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 19, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 19, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Long-Range Autocorrelations</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline in long-range autocorrelations during each intervention condition (3 x 10 min walking)</time_frame>
    <description>Long-Range Autocorrelations</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean gait speed</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline in mean gait speed during each intervention condition (3 x 10 min walking)</time_frame>
    <description>Total walking distance (m)/ Acquisition duration (s)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Step length</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline in step length during each intervention condition (3 x 10 min walking)</time_frame>
    <description>Gait speed (m/s)*60/Gait cadence (steps/min)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gait cadence</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline in gait cadence during each intervention condition (3 x 10 min walking)</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of steps (#)/Acquisition duration (min)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Coefficient of variation of stride duration</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline in coefficient of variation during each intervention condition (3 x 10 min walking)</time_frame>
    <description>[SD/mean stride duration] * 100</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Simulator Sickness Questionnaire (SSQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline in SSQ after the VRW condition</time_frame>
    <description>It is a questionnaire about symptoms that may appear when using virtual reality headsets</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <condition>Virtual Reality</condition>
  <condition>Gait Disorders, Neurologic</condition>
  <condition>Long Range Autocorrelations</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Parkinson's Disease patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Parkinson's Disease patients will walk in three conditions for +- 15 minutes per condition: walking over ground, walking on a treadmill, walking on a treadmill in virtual reality</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Virtual reality headset</intervention_name>
    <description>All participants will walk in the three conditions described earlier in this form</description>
    <arm_group_label>Parkinson's Disease patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        PD patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  idiopathic PD diagnosis made by an experienced neurologist according to United Kingdom&#xD;
             Brain Bank criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mild to moderate motor disorders according to modified Hoehn &amp; Yahr scale (stages&#xD;
             I-III)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ability to walk for a minimum of 512 gait cycles (±15 minutes) in a row without&#xD;
             walking aids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no other pathology interacting with gait or provoking dizziness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no uncorrected vision disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a minimum of 24/30 on the Mini-Mental State Examination (MMSE)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        PD Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  other neurological or orthopedic pathologies that could interact with their motor&#xD;
             capacities and gait performance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pathology that could provoke vertigo or nausea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncorrected vision disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindications to physical exercise&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thierry Lejeune, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cliniques universitaires Saint-Luc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cliniques Universitaires Saint Luc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussel</city>
        <zip>1200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 9, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 12, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 15, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 4, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 4, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Parkinson's Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Virtual reality</keyword>
  <keyword>Gait</keyword>
  <keyword>Variability</keyword>
  <keyword>Fractal</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gait Disorders, Neurologic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

