<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04458636</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17/LO/1135</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04458636</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Stratified TreAtment to Reduce Risk in COPD</brief_title>
  <acronym>STARR2</acronym>
  <official_title>Delivering Personalised Care in the Management of Exacerbations of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease: A Multi-centre Randomised Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute for Health Research, United Kingdom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the efficacy of blood-eosinophil directed corticosteroid therapy using&#xD;
      near-patient testing, compared to current standard practice during an exacerbation of COPD in&#xD;
      a multi-centre randomised placebo controlled trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study design: Double-blind placebo controlled randomised clinical trial Study setting:&#xD;
      Primary care GP practices Participants: Adults ≥40 years with COPD Sample size: 228 Study&#xD;
      duration: 12 months data collection Primary objective: To evaluate the efficacy of&#xD;
      blood-eosinophil directed corticosteroid therapy using near-patient testing, compared to&#xD;
      current standard practice during an exacerbation of COPD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objective: To evaluate quality of life, symptoms, lung function and healthcare&#xD;
      utilisation in a blood-eosinophil directed corticosteroid therapy arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory objective: To evaluate stability of eosinophil counts and mediator levels&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) affects adults and is largely caused by&#xD;
      cigarette smoke in the developed world. It is predicted to be the 3rd leading cause of death&#xD;
      by 2020 affecting over 250 million people worldwide. COPD is characterised by progressive&#xD;
      airflow obstruction punctuated by frequent periods of worsening in respiratory symptoms and&#xD;
      function associated with a significant impact on quality of life. These episodes are termed&#xD;
      exacerbations and current treatment strategies rely on oral corticosteroids (prednisolone)&#xD;
      and antibiotics but this is in a &quot;one size fits all&quot; approach. However there is little&#xD;
      evidence supporting this strategy and both treatments can potentially cause harm. In addition&#xD;
      to this, previous findings have shown that eosinophil counts within blood samples from COPD&#xD;
      patients can be used as a biomarker to determine treatment with oral steroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of near-patient testing in primary care will characterise patients with COPD and&#xD;
      inform to guide effective and personalised treatment with reductions in treatment failure&#xD;
      rates, improvements in health and reductions in adverse events associated with inappropriate&#xD;
      and excessive corticosteroid and antibiotic therapy. Currently available systems include the&#xD;
      HemoCue ® 5-point differential cell count system which accurately and rapidly (within 2&#xD;
      minutes) determine the eosinophil count finger-prick sampling. This diagnostic is currently&#xD;
      used in neonatology, Emergency Departments (ED) and at Mount Everest Base Camp 28-30. It is&#xD;
      thus conceivable that this could be used in primary care to deliver a randomised control&#xD;
      trial to demonstrate that stratified medicine approaches in the management of COPD&#xD;
      exacerbations are superior to standard therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is believed that personalising this treatment approach during an exacerbation of COPD, to&#xD;
      direct whether corticosteroids is necessary for all patients, depending on the results of the&#xD;
      eosinophil count from near-patient testing, is superior to current standard treatment&#xD;
      strategies in the primary care setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment target for STARR 2 is 228 participants with COPD from GP surgeries within the&#xD;
      Thames Valley and South Midlands. A participant's involvement is 12 months and involves up to&#xD;
      5 visits. These visits consist of CRF completion, questionnaires, breathing tests, urine&#xD;
      testing, blood samples and spirometry. The trial drugs are only taken for 14 days during an&#xD;
      exacerbation but participants can be re-randomised for up to 4 times in the study when they&#xD;
      exacerbate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: At exacerbation randomised to 'standard therapy' or 'blood eosinophil directed&#xD;
      therapy'. Standard therapy will be prednisolone and antibiotic therapy. Blood eosinophil&#xD;
      directed therapy will be prednisolone and/or antibiotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigational medicinal product: Prednisolone or placebo equivalent. The IMP is part of&#xD;
      current clinical practice. Prednisolone is an anti-inflammatory and given in short durations&#xD;
      (≤2 weeks duration) orally for its systemic action at the onset of an exacerbation in COPD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation duration: Study entry at stable state or during an exacerbation. Randomisation&#xD;
      at exacerbation. IMP treatment period 14 days. Post treatment follow-up visits at days 14, 30&#xD;
      and 90. Stable state and randomisation visit duration maximum 60 minutes. Follow-up visits at&#xD;
      days 14, 30, and 90 maximum duration 30 minutes. Participants may be re-randomised and&#xD;
      followed up if they have further exacerbations after the 30 day visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection: Demographic and exacerbation clinical data including duration of symptoms,&#xD;
      past medical history, medication history and exacerbation history is collected. Blood&#xD;
      eosinophil tests is collected by pin-prick testing using the HemoCue ®; lung function using&#xD;
      spirometry and FeNO; and symptoms and quality of life using questionnaires. Serum is&#xD;
      collected at visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study schedule:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study assessments will be performed within primary care by the research study team. The&#xD;
      following assessments may occur at the study visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility check: Inclusion and exclusion criteria will be checked against the participant's&#xD;
      medical notes and with the participant during the visit. This responsibility will be&#xD;
      delegated by the PI to a member of the research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demographic history: Participant demographics including age, smoking history and past COPD&#xD;
      medical history will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medication history: Full medication history will be collected, including the use of as&#xD;
      required and over the counter medication. Any drug allergy will be documented and dates of&#xD;
      flu vaccination, S. pneumoniae and H. influenzae B vaccinations will be recorded from medical&#xD;
      records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Past medical history: Full medical history will be collected from the participant and from&#xD;
      the medical notes. COPD diagnosis history: The age of onset and age of diagnosis of COPD&#xD;
      symptoms will be recorded from the participant and from the medical records.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Past exacerbation history: The frequency of exacerbations, including those requiring&#xD;
      hospitalisation in the previous 12 months will be captured from participant recollection and&#xD;
      from the medical records. Medication prescribed at each exacerbation event (if available)&#xD;
      from medical records will be captured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exacerbation history: The current history of the exacerbation, including duration of symptoms&#xD;
      and treatment history will collected by questioning. The severity of the exacerbation will be&#xD;
      recorded according to Anthonisen criteria14 with increased symptoms of breathlessness, sputum&#xD;
      production and sputum purulence will be used as per GOLD31 definition. The Anthonisen&#xD;
      criteria for exacerbation as follows: Type 1 - Three major symptoms; Type 2 - two major&#xD;
      symptoms; Type 3 - One major and one minor symptom. The major symptoms are i) Increased&#xD;
      breathlessness; ii) increased sputum production; or iii) increased sputum purulence. The&#xD;
      minor symptoms are iv) Upper respiratory tract infection in the previous 5 days; v) fever&#xD;
      without apparent cause; vi) increased wheeze; vii) increased cough; viii) increase in&#xD;
      respiratory or heart rate 20% above baseline. Questionnaires: Patient reported outcome&#xD;
      measures (PRO's) will be sought to specifically test symptoms, health status, quality of life&#xD;
      and any associated depression and anxiety. This will include the Medical Research Council&#xD;
      dyspnoea scale (MRC); Visual analogue score (VAS) 32; COPD Assessment Tool (CAT) 33; the&#xD;
      Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS)34 and the EuroQol 5D35. Participants will be&#xD;
      asked to complete a daily diary (using the VAS tool, for the duration of 30 days) for&#xD;
      assessment of symptoms and recovery following treatment. Instructions to use these&#xD;
      questionnaires will be given to all participants. Each of these questionnaires are validated&#xD;
      to be self-completed for ease of use. All research staff undertaking any assessments and&#xD;
      procedures will be trained to use the equipment and perform the questionnaires to determine&#xD;
      patient reported outcomes. Near-patient point of care testing procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 5 drops of blood (up to a maximum of 10 drops) will be taken for measurement of&#xD;
      peripheral blood eosinophil counts, glucose and CRP levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A urine sample for testing of glycosuria will be performed immediately. All samples will be&#xD;
      discarded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lung Function: Spirometry will be performed to determine the forced expiratory volume in 1&#xD;
      second (FEV1) and the forced vital capacity (FVC) according to standard ATS/ERS criteria36.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Venous blood sampling: Using a fully sterile technique, a blood test will be performed to&#xD;
      measure inflammation. All participants consenting to trial sample collection will have a&#xD;
      maximum of 20mLs of blood taken at each visit. Collected blood will be centrifuged&#xD;
      immediately and serum/plasma will be aliquoted into fully anonymised barcoded tubes.&#xD;
      Anonymised samples will be then be securely transported to the John Radcliffe Hospital and&#xD;
      stored at the Respiratory Medicine Laboratory (John Radcliffe Hospital), under the HTA&#xD;
      licence, at -80˚c for exploratory outcome analysis and for future use subject to ethical&#xD;
      approval. There will be separate instructions detailing the sample handling process for this&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 2, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of treatment non-responders defined as those needing re-treatment, hospitalisation or death at 30 and 90 days</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of treatment non-responders, defined as those needing re-treatment, hospitalisation or death</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COPD assessment test (CAT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14, 30 and 90</time_frame>
    <description>CAT questionnaire. A higher score (max score of 40) reflects worse COPD symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life - change from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14, 30 and 90</time_frame>
    <description>European Quality of Life-5 dimension-3 level (EQ 5D 3L) questionnaire. A higher number on each of the 5 dimension reflects worse quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual analogue scale (VAS) for cough, wheeze, sputum volume, sputum purulence and breathlessness</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14, 30 and 90</time_frame>
    <description>Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) symptom score (scale of 0 to 100 - 100 being the worst). Separate scale for 5 items: cough, wheeze, sputum volume, sputum purulence and breathlessness. Results will be represented as a sum of all 5 scores at each time point.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lung function</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14, 30 and 90</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in FEV1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exacerbations</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of moderate and severe exacerbations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">203</enrollment>
  <condition>COPD Exacerbation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Blinded prednisolone 30mg orally once per day for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Biomarker care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Blinded prednisolone 30mg orally once per day for 14 days if peripheral eosinophil count is equal or greater than 2%. Placebo equivalent if peripheral blood eosinophil count is &lt;2%.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prednisolone</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral</description>
    <arm_group_label>Biomarker care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female, aged 40 years or above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with COPD (primary or secondary care diagnosis) with spirometric&#xD;
             confirmation of airflow obstruction (FEV1/FVC ratio &lt;0.7).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of at least 1 exacerbation in the previous 12 months, requiring systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids and/or antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or ex-smoker with at least a 10 pack year smoking history&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the research staff, is able and willing to comply with all trial&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of atopic childhood asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current history of primary lung malignancy or current active pulmonary TB&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically relevant disease or disorder (past or present) which in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator may either put the subject at risk because of participating in the study&#xD;
             or may influence the results of the study or the subject's ability to participate in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically relevant lung disease, other than COPD considered by the investigator&#xD;
             to be the primary diagnosis. For example mild-to-moderate bronchiectasis is acceptable&#xD;
             in addition to COPD unless the bronchiectasis is considered to be the primary&#xD;
             diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An alternative cause for the increase in symptoms of COPD that are unrelated to an&#xD;
             exacerbation such as i) suspicion or clinical evidence of pneumonia; ii) high&#xD;
             probability and suspicion of pulmonary embolism; iii) suspicion or clinical evidence&#xD;
             of a pneumothorax; iv) primary ischaemic event - ST or Non ST elevation myocardial&#xD;
             infarct and left ventricular failure [i.e. not an exacerbation of COPD]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known allergy to the IMP (prednisolone), NIMP (doxycycline) or to any of the&#xD;
             constituents of the placebo&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on maintenance corticosteroids (prednisolone, hydrocortisone,&#xD;
             fludrocortisone)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known adrenal insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled in another CTIMP trial and receiving an intervention as part of the&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and breast-feeding women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mona Bafadhel, MBChB, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nuffield Department of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.ndm.ox.ac.uk/principal-investigators/researcher/mona-bafadhel</url>
    <description>Website address for CI</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 17, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 17, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Oxford</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mona Bafadhel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>eosinophils</keyword>
  <keyword>oral corticosteroids</keyword>
  <keyword>primary care</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prednisolone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>upon request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

