<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02794818</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00005088</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02794818</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Penn State ProduceRx Feasibility Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Penn State ProduceRx Feasibility Study: Developing a &quot;Prescription Produce&quot; Model That Can Impact Long-term Health Outcomes for Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To provide &quot;prescriptions&quot; for weekly Community Supported Agriculture (CSA) boxes of fruits&#xD;
      and vegetables to patients, accompanied by nutritional education (e.g. printed newsletters&#xD;
      and YouTube videos), and evaluate benefits for participants by exploring commitment to the&#xD;
      program, opinions about healthy eating, retention of nutrition and food preparation&#xD;
      knowledge, overall takeaway from the program, as well as self-assessment of health status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To establish the overall feasibility of an effective &quot;prescription produce&quot; program for&#xD;
      at-risk and underserved patients - called &quot;ProduceRx&quot; - by utilizing produce from regional&#xD;
      farms in addition to the resources of the Penn State Health System and an interdisciplinary&#xD;
      team of healthcare workers (dietitians, dietetic interns, and medical students).&#xD;
&#xD;
      To provide a proof-of-concept for this model (i.e. ProduceRx + interdisciplinary approach to&#xD;
      health education) for other healthcare institutions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participating prescribers within the Penn State Health system will identify potential&#xD;
      patients for ProduceRx based on the &quot;high-risk&quot; or &quot;underserved&quot; requirements. For the&#xD;
      initial pilot starting on August 1, 2016, the following four physicians have agreed to&#xD;
      participate with the program/study: Dr. Ann Rogers, Dr. Marsha Novick, Dr. Peter Lewis, and&#xD;
      Dr. Laurie Nelson, whose specialties are general surgery and minimally invasive bariatric&#xD;
      surgery, adolescent and bariatric medicine, family medicine, and internal medicine,&#xD;
      respectively. Additionally, Lisa Hardy, a nurse practitioner at Dr. Ann Rogers' bariatric&#xD;
      clinic, and Christine Bruce, a physician assistant at Dr. Laurie Nelson's internal medicine&#xD;
      clinic will serve as the fifth and sixth prescribers. Prescribers will be provided with&#xD;
      ProduceRx prescription pads that they will use to write &quot;prescriptions&quot; for their patients to&#xD;
      the program. The prescription pads will be coded with a unique identifying code at the bottom&#xD;
      that will allow researchers to keep track of data associated with that prescription (i.e.&#xD;
      patient compliance with the program, difference in patient outcomes with different providers,&#xD;
      etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited by the abovementioned physicians based on the physicians'&#xD;
      interpretation of the two qualifications for the program: &quot;high-risk&quot; or &quot;underserved.&quot;&#xD;
      Recruiting materials such as informational brochures and advertisement signs (both electronic&#xD;
      and printed) will be utilized to help these providers explain the program to qualifying&#xD;
      patients without sacrificing time in the office. If selected patients elect to participate in&#xD;
      the program, they will visit the ProduceRx website at https://sites.psu.edu/producerx and&#xD;
      register for the program. Initial registration will feature an informed consent form to&#xD;
      participate in research associated with this program. Patients will have the option of&#xD;
      consenting or declining to consent to participation in this research. For those that consent,&#xD;
      they will complete their initial survey through REDCap before bring routed to the&#xD;
      participating farm's weekly ordering platform. Those patients who decline to consent will be&#xD;
      automatically routed to the participating farm's ordering platform to order their first&#xD;
      weekly box.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The survey will be a modified version of the CDC's Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System&#xD;
      Questionnaire (BRFSS). This survey will assess patients' demographic characteristics, as well&#xD;
      as health characteristics and behaviors. Demographic variables include age, race/ethnicity,&#xD;
      education level, and employment status. Health characteristics include self-reported medical&#xD;
      conditions, and height and weight (for calculation of body mass index). The survey will ask&#xD;
      participants to self-report fruit and vegetable consumption and perceived barriers to&#xD;
      consumption. Level of physical activity will also be monitored throughout the program to see&#xD;
      if it is affected by changes in nutrition. Additionally, investigators will measure&#xD;
      compliance of patients with the program; compliance will be defined as the number of weeks&#xD;
      that patients voluntarily participate (purchase weekly boxes of produce) throughout the&#xD;
      program from the time that they register with the program until the end of the pilot in&#xD;
      December 2016.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During subsequent weeks, patients will visit the farm's website directly to order their&#xD;
      weekly produce boxes. Participants will be asked to complete a post-program questionnaire at&#xD;
      the end of the pilot in December 2016. Meanwhile, the main ProduceRx website will function as&#xD;
      a platform for nutritional education delivery (delivered by medical students, registered&#xD;
      dietitians, dietetic interns, as well as opportunities for other healthcare workers and&#xD;
      community members), with links to the program's YouTube cooking/nutrition videos and postings&#xD;
      of electronic versions of the printed newsletters. The website will also feature a calendar&#xD;
      of upcoming local events, such as nature hikes, outdoor walks, free cooking classes, and&#xD;
      farmers' markets, in order to facilitate an overall healthy lifestyle outside of the actual&#xD;
      program. Additionally, the website will feature a comments section for participants to ask&#xD;
      questions and communicate with one another. This comments section will be monitored to ensure&#xD;
      appropriate commenting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the program, a focus group will be held at Penn State Hershey Medical Center&#xD;
      (PSHMC) to evaluate the functionality/feasibility of the pilot, including logistical&#xD;
      convenience, how much produce was utilized each week, and what challenges participants faced&#xD;
      integrating the produce and educational content into their daily lives. The focus group will&#xD;
      ideally last from 45 to 90 minutes and will be moderated by Sarayna Schock, an MSII and PI on&#xD;
      this study. A semi-structured interview guide will be used and responses will be recorded to&#xD;
      adequately capture all feedback. These focus group responses will be recorded and transcribed&#xD;
      by research volunteers and analyzed by an interdisciplinary research team to identify&#xD;
      emergent themes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To ease the burden of time constraints already imposed on physicians, participating&#xD;
      healthcare providers will be surveyed via email at the end of the pilot to evaluate their&#xD;
      perceived program efficacy, the benefit of the program to their patients, and elicit program&#xD;
      feedback. A semi-structured survey created with REDCap will be used to solicit specific&#xD;
      responses, in addition to open feedback.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified CDC BRFSS Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>18-week study period</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaire items will assess participants' demographic characteristics, health characteristics, and behaviors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Dietary Modification</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participating Patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participating patients will receive a prescription for weekly CSA produce boxes with nutritional education</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participating Providers</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participating providers will be surveyed at the end of the pilot to evaluate their perceived program efficacy, the benefit of the program to their patients, and elicit program feedback.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Produce boxes with nutritional education</intervention_name>
    <description>CSA produce boxes &quot;prescribed&quot; to study participants with free online nutritional education included</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participating Patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients determined to be &quot;underserved&quot; or &quot;at-risk&quot; within the Penn State Health System&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals (ages 18-75) who are currently patients in the Penn State Hershey Health&#xD;
             system in the departments of Family and Community Medicine, General Pediatrics,&#xD;
             Internal Medicine, General Surgery and Minimally Invasive Surgery/Bariatric,&#xD;
             Endocrinology, and Cardiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Individuals at risk for developing chronic illness and metabolic disease as identified&#xD;
             by PCP, care coordinator, or a participating physician from an abovementioned&#xD;
             specialty.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals willing to participate in the program and complete a pre-program survey&#xD;
             and a post-program survey in December 2016.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Individuals with access to transportation to and from the CSA drop-off sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Individuals willing/able to pay the $10 subsidized &quot;copay&quot; for the weekly box of&#xD;
             produce (federal food stamps in the form of SNAP/EBT vouchers will be accepted by&#xD;
             Strites Orchard as a means of payment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Individuals that speak English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Individuals with difficulty obtaining fresh produce or lack of knowledge regarding&#xD;
             healthy cooking methods and nutrition, as determined by PCP or a participating&#xD;
             physician from an abovementioned specialty.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Prescribers (physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants) in the Penn&#xD;
             State Hershey Health system in the departments of Family and Community Medicine,&#xD;
             General Pediatrics, Internal Medicine, General Surgery and Minimally Invasive&#xD;
             Surgery/Bariatric, Endocrinology, and Cardiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals outside of immediate areas of Strites Orchard's CSA drop-off sites (which&#xD;
             include the following: Bosler Avenue, Lemoyne; Koch Lane Harrisburg (Paxtonia);&#xD;
             Allendale, Camp Hill; Strites Orchard, Harrisburg; Dogwood Lane, Dillsburg; East&#xD;
             Willow Street, Elizabethtown; Hampden Summit; Linglestown Rd., Harrisburg; St. Johns&#xD;
             Drive, Camp Hill; Shetland Dr., Hummelstown; West Areba Ave., Hershey; Wickerberry&#xD;
             Lane, Palmyra; W. Green St., Mechanicsburg; Brisban St. Harrisburg (Paxtang); Cattell&#xD;
             St., Middletown; and N. 2nd St., Harrisburg.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Individuals unaffiliated with the Penn State Hershey Health System.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals who already have sufficient fruits and vegetables in their diet as&#xD;
             determined by the participating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Non-English speaking participants.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Penn State Milton Hershey Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hershey</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17033</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://sites.psu.edu/producerx</url>
    <description>Main ProduceRx program website</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kraschnewski JL, George DR, Rovniak LS, Monroe DL, Fiordalis E, Bates E. Characterizing customers at medical center farmers' markets. J Community Health. 2014 Aug;39(4):727-31. doi: 10.1007/s10900-014-9818-x.</citation>
    <PMID>24421001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 25, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 4, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 9, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 20, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Milton S. Hershey Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sarayna Schock</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MSII</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

