<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01148004</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100124</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-CC-0124</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01148004</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Influence of Ritonavir, Alone and in Combination With Lopinavir, on Fenofibric Acid Pharmacokinetics in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Influence of Ritonavir, Alone and in Combination With Lopinavir, on Fenofibric Acid Pharmacokinetics in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Patients infected with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) are often treated with&#xD;
      protease inhibitors that help fight HIV infection. However, these medications often increase&#xD;
      blood cholesterol levels, particularly triglycerides and low-density lipoproteins, and can&#xD;
      lead to heart disease and other problems. Patients may take drugs known as fibrates (such as&#xD;
      gemfibrozil (Lopid )) to lower triglyceride levels, but even with maximum approved doses&#xD;
      patients often cannot reach goal triglyceride levels. Research suggests that fibrates and&#xD;
      certain HIV medications, such as ritonavir and lopinavir/ritonavir, may interact and decrease&#xD;
      the effectiveness of the fibrate treatment. More research is needed to determine the best&#xD;
      drug to lower triglyceride levels in HIV patients who are receiving protease inhibitor&#xD;
      therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To evaluate the drug-drug interaction between fenofibrate and protease inhibitors&#xD;
      lopinavir/ritonavir and ritonavir.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Healthy individuals between 18 and 60 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This study will require a screening visit and 18 study visits. The screening visit will&#xD;
           take 3 to 4 hours, and can occur 7 to 30 days before starting the study. The rest of the&#xD;
           study, not including the screening visit, is 48 days. Three of the visits will take&#xD;
           about 12 hours, and the remaining 15 visits will take about 1 hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For study days 1 to 7, participants will take fenofibrate alone. Participants will keep&#xD;
           a daily record of medication doses and any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For study days 8 to 27, participants will take fenofibrate and ritonavir. Participants&#xD;
           will keep a daily record of medication doses and any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For study days 29 to 48, participants will take fenofibrate and lopinavir/ritonavir.&#xD;
           Participants will keep a daily record of medication doses and any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will have regular study visits to provide blood samples for research and&#xD;
           monitoring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Highly active antiretroviral therapy (HAART) has enhanced the life expectancy of human&#xD;
      immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infected patients, making HIV a manageable chronic disease for&#xD;
      many patients. Patients with HIV are prone to lipid abnormalities secondary to HIV infection&#xD;
      and antiretroviral therapy, particularly HIV protease inhibitors (PI). PI containing regimens&#xD;
      that contain boosting doses of ritonavir (RTV) (i.e., 100 200 mg once or twice daily) often&#xD;
      cause significant increases in total cholesterol, low density lipoprotein cholesterol, and&#xD;
      triglycerides. Therapy for isolated hypertriglyceridemia includes fibric acid derivatives,&#xD;
      such as gemfibrozil (GFZ) or fenofibrate; however, despite treatment with these agents,&#xD;
      triglyceride levels often remain elevated in HIV infected patients treated with HAART. Many&#xD;
      factors likely contribute to the incomplete effectiveness of fibrates in these patients. One&#xD;
      possible contributing factor may be a clinically significant interaction between HAART and&#xD;
      fibrates. We recently reported a mean 41 percent decrease in GFZ area under the curve when&#xD;
      administered with the PI combination lopinavir/ritonavir (LPV/r). To determine whether a&#xD;
      similar interaction exists with fenofibrate, this study will characterize the impact of RTV&#xD;
      and LPV/r on the pharmacokinetic (PK) profile of fenofibrate (Tricor formulation), after a&#xD;
      single 145 mg oral dose, administered to healthy volunteers. In a single sequence study&#xD;
      design, 13 subjects will receive a single 145 mg dose of fenofibrate on three occasions:&#xD;
      before and after 14 days of RTV 100 mg twice daily, and after 14 days of LPV/r 400/100 mg&#xD;
      twice daily. With the exclusion of the screening period, the total duration of the study will&#xD;
      be 48 days. Fenofibric acid (FFA) PK will be determined for all 3 sampling periods and&#xD;
      compared. Results from this study will inform us about a potentially clinically relevant drug&#xD;
      drug interaction between fenofibrate and RTV boosted PI combinations. This information may&#xD;
      therefore assist clinicians in choosing triglyceride lowering therapy for their HIV infected&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 13, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 29, 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 29, 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fenofibratae pharmacokinetic parameter values</measure>
    <time_frame>48 days from study day 1 (after screening has been completed)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">25</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <condition>Fenofibrate</condition>
  <condition>Protease Inhibitors</condition>
  <condition>Hypertriglyceridemia</condition>
  <condition>Glucuronosyltransferase</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fenofibrate</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ritonavir</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lopinavir/Ritonavir</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A subject will be considered eligible for this study only if all of the following criteria&#xD;
        are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between the ages of 18 and 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy according to medical history and physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory values: normal liver function tests (ALT less than or equal to 41 units/L,&#xD;
             AST less than or equal to 34 units/L, total bilirubin less than or equal to 1.0 mg/dL,&#xD;
             and direct bilirubin less than or equal to 0.2 mg/dL); serum creatinine less than or&#xD;
             equal to ULN; hemoglobin greater than or equal to 12 g/dL (for both males and females)&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. For patients with a history of Gilbert's Syndrome, patients with a total bilirubin&#xD;
             that is greater than 1.0 mg/dL will be considered eligible for study participation if&#xD;
             direct bilirubin is within normal limits (direct bilirubin &lt; 0.2 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal ECG with no history of cardiac arrhythmias or conduction abnormalities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of child bearing potential who are able and willing to prevent pregnancy by&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  a. practicing abstinence or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  b. using non hormonal effective methods of birth control, such as condoms or&#xD;
&#xD;
        diaphragms during the study period and for 1 month after study completion&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A subject will be ineligible for this study if 1 or more of the following criteria are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant routine therapy with any prescription, over the counter, herbal, or&#xD;
             holistic medications, including hormonal contraceptives by any route and any&#xD;
             investigational drugs for 30 days prior to study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Concomitant therapy (chronic or intermittent) with any prescription, over the&#xD;
                  counter, or herbal drugs will not be allowed during the study duration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intermittent use of acetaminophen, non-steroidal anti-inflammatory medications&#xD;
                  (i.e., ibuprofen), and loperamide will be allowed to be taken according to each&#xD;
                  manufacturer s recommendations during the study, but will not be allowed on the&#xD;
                  days of PK blood sampling&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A daily multivitamin with minerals will be allowed during the study, according to&#xD;
                  the subject s wishes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to obtain venous access for blood sample collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence or history of any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diabetes mellitus (clinical diagnosis based on current guidelines)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pulmonary disease (e.g. uncontrolled asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
                  disease, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac disease (e.g. heart failure, history of arrhythmia, or abnormal ECG&#xD;
                  results during screening, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hypertension (systolic blood pressure greater than 145 mmHG or diastolic blood&#xD;
                  pressure greater than 90 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal disease (chronic or acute renal failure or insufficiency)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatitis (as assessed by patient interview) or hepatic impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pancreatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bleeding disorders (e.g. hemophilia, gastrointestinal or intracranial bleeding)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Seizure disorders, with the exception of childhood febrile seizures in the past&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Schizophrenia or other psychiatric illnesses that may interfere with the subject&#xD;
                  s ability to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any condition that may interfere with the interpretation of the study results or&#xD;
                  not be in the best interest of the subject in the opinion of the investigators&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive serum or urine pregnancy test or breastfeeding female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of persistent diarrhea or malabsorption that would interfere with the&#xD;
             subject s ability to absorb drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug or alcohol abuse that may impair safety or adherence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of intolerance or allergic reaction to LPV/r, RTV, or fenofibrate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting total cholesterol greater than 240 mg/dL or fasting triglycerides greater than&#xD;
             400 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting glucose greater than 100 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of tobacco products, including cigarettes and chewing tobacco&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Scott R Penzak, Pharm.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Penzak SR, Chuck SK. Management of protease inhibitor-associated hyperlipidemia. Am J Cardiovasc Drugs. 2002;2(2):91-106. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>14727985</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grunfeld C, Tien P. Difficulties in understanding the metabolic complications of acquired immune deficiency syndrome. Clin Infect Dis. 2003;37 Suppl 2:S43-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12942373</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sax PE. Strategies for management and treatment of dyslipidemia in HIV/AIDS. AIDS Care. 2006 Feb;18(2):149-57. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16338773</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 29, 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 18, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 18, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 22, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 6, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 6, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypertriglyceridemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Protease Inhibitors</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>HV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertriglyceridemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ritonavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lopinavir</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fenofibrate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

