<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01145196</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100140</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-EI-0140</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01145196</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Genotype-Phenotype Study of Patients With Plaquenil -Induced Retinal Toxicity, With Evaluation of the ABCA4 Gene</brief_title>
  <official_title>Genotype - Phenotype Study of Patients With Plaquenil-induced Retinal Toxicity, With Evaluation of the ABCA4 Gene</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Eye Institute (NEI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Plaquenil (hydroxychloroquine) is an anti-inflammatory drug that is used to treat some&#xD;
      autoimmune diseases such as lupus and rheumatoid arthritis. This drug can damage the retina&#xD;
      by causing a condition called plaquenil-induced retinal toxicity, which may lead to vision&#xD;
      loss. However, most people taking plaquenil do not develop this problem. Researchers are&#xD;
      interested in studying whether differences in a person s genes explain why some people&#xD;
      develop plaquenil-induced retinal toxicity while others do not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To investigate possible correlations between certain genes or genetic mutations and&#xD;
      plaquenil-induced retinal toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals at least 18 years of age who have previously used plaquenil.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Both individuals who have and have not developed plaquenil-induced retinal toxicity will&#xD;
           be eligible for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study requires one or two visits to the National Eye Institute or an outpatient&#xD;
           study clinic over a maximum 2-year period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will provide a personal and family medical history, and will have a full&#xD;
           eye examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will also provide blood samples for testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  No treatment will be provided as part of this protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to investigate whether there is a correlation between genetic&#xD;
      mutations, beginning with an analysis of ABCA4, and Plaquenil -induced retinal toxicity and&#xD;
      to describe the phenotype of Plaquenil -induced retinal toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY POPULATION:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will enroll 100 patients, 18 years of age or older, found to have Plaquenil&#xD;
      -induced retinal toxicity. 200 volunteers with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), rheumatoid&#xD;
      arthritis (RA), or Sj(SqrRoot)(Delta)gren s syndrome and history of Plaquenil use, but&#xD;
      without evidence of retinal toxicity, will also be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is an observational study with 1-2 outpatient visits to the NEI clinic or review of&#xD;
      medical records for off-site participants. All participants will provide a blood sample for&#xD;
      genetic analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOME MEASURES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical examination and blood samples will be used for genetic testing and mutation&#xD;
      identification. The primary outcome of this study is to identify genetic mutations, starting&#xD;
      with those in ABCA4 gene, associated with retinal toxicity in participants with a history of&#xD;
      Plaquenil use. Secondary objectives i clude determining the utility of testing metrics in&#xD;
      evaluating the presence of retinal toxicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 23, 2010</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The outcome of this study is to identify genetic mutations, starting with those in ABCA4 gene, associated with retinal toxicity in participants with a history of plaquenil use.</measure>
    <time_frame>annually for five years</time_frame>
    <description>The outcome of this study is to identify genetic mutations, starting with those in ABCA4 gene, associated with retinal toxicity in participants with a history of plaquenil use.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The secondary outcome of this study is to determine the utility of various testing metrics in evaluating the presence of retinal toxicity.</measure>
    <time_frame>annually for five years</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary outcome of this study is to determine the utility of various testing metrics in evaluating the presence of retinal toxicity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Genotype</condition>
  <condition>Retinal Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Affected</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants affected by Paquenil induced retinal toxicity</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Unaffected</arm_group_label>
    <description>control participants without Plaquenil induced retinal toxicity</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study will enroll 100 patients, 18 years of age or older, found to have Plaquenil&#xD;
        -induced retinal toxicity. 200 volunteers with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE),&#xD;
        rheumatoid arthritis (RA), or Sjogren's syndrome and history of Plaquenil use, but without&#xD;
        evidence of retinal toxicity, will also be recruited.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Affected participants must be 18 years of age or older and have:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), rheumatoid arthritis (RA) or&#xD;
                  Sj(SqrRoot)(Delta)gren s syndrome, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of Plaquenil use, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Evidence of Plaquenil -induced retinal toxicity, based on clinical findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Unaffected volunteers must be 18 years of age or older and have:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), rheumatoid arthritis (RA) or&#xD;
                  Sj(SqrRoot)(Delta)gren s syndrome, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of Plaquenil use, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No retinal disease upon examination within the last six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. All participants must be able to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Provide their own consent, and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Safely provide a blood sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
        &lt;TAB&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Participants with other known (genetic) retinal disease including but not limited to:&#xD;
        Stargardt s disease and cone or cone-rod dystrophy whose diagnosis preceded their Plaquenil&#xD;
        use. Participants with no known previous genetic diagnosis but with clinical findings&#xD;
        associated with a genetic diagnosis, such as parafoveal or macular flecks which are&#xD;
        associated with Stargardt s disease or fundus flavimaculatus, will also be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Catherine A Cukras, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Eye Institute (NEI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anne M Alvarez, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-0097</phone>
    <email>annemarie.alvarez@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Catherine A Cukras, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-5061</phone>
    <email>cukrasc@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2010-EI-0140.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Levy GD, Munz SJ, Paschal J, Cohen HB, Pince KJ, Peterson T. Incidence of hydroxychloroquine retinopathy in 1,207 patients in a large multicenter outpatient practice. Arthritis Rheum. 1997 Aug;40(8):1482-6.</citation>
    <PMID>9259429</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>HOBBS HE, SORSBY A, FREEDMAN A. Retinopathy following chloroquine therapy. Lancet. 1959 Oct 3;2(7101):478-80.</citation>
    <PMID>14402143</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Webster AR, Héon E, Lotery AJ, Vandenburgh K, Casavant TL, Oh KT, Beck G, Fishman GA, Lam BL, Levin A, Heckenlively JR, Jacobson SG, Weleber RG, Sheffield VC, Stone EM. An analysis of allelic variation in the ABCA4 gene. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 2001 May;42(6):1179-89.</citation>
    <PMID>11328725</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 23, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 15, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 15, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 16, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Retinal Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Plaquenil-Induced</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

