<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04177758</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19092704</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04177758</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating Vitamin D3 Supplement on Post-Op Outcomes</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Tripled-Blinded, Randomized Controlled Trial Evaluating Vitamin D3 Supplementation on Post-Operative Functional and Clinical Outcomes Following Total Knee Arthroplasty</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rush University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rush University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to determine if vitamin D supplementation is associated with&#xD;
      differences in short-term recovery in patients following total knee arthroplasty compared to&#xD;
      patients who do not receive supplementation. If so, vitamin D supplementation has the&#xD;
      potential to become widely incorporated into the routine care for patients undergoing knee&#xD;
      replacements.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients will be enrolled from the clinics of Dr. Denis Nam and Dr. Craig Della Valle, two&#xD;
      fellowship-trained orthopedic surgeons in the division of Adult Reconstruction at Midwest&#xD;
      Orthopedics at Rush University Medical Center. Study staff will screen the clinic schedule of&#xD;
      each surgeon and will discuss the purposes of the investigation at the time of their visit.&#xD;
      If the patient is willing to participate in the investigation, verbal and written consent&#xD;
      will be obtained by the study staff. At the time of consenting, patients will also be asked&#xD;
      to perform a TUG test and will be asked to complete the questions that comprise the&#xD;
      functional component of the KSS score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be tripled-blinded, thus, the patients, clinicians, and research staff&#xD;
      involved will be unaware of patient allocation during this study. Each patient will receive a&#xD;
      study ID, and a computer randomization system will be used to allocate patients to receive&#xD;
      either vitamin D3 or placebo based on their study ID. Only members of the Rush pharmacy staff&#xD;
      will possess the list matching the study ID to the study group assignment, ensuring that the&#xD;
      study remains triple-blinded and that study coordinators are unaware of a patient's&#xD;
      assignment when he or she picks up the study medication from the pharmacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients randomized to the experimental arm of the study will receive 50,000IU of vitamin D3&#xD;
      following surgery and asked to take the medication orally following surgery. Vitamin D3 was&#xD;
      selected over vitamin D2 as the former is less expensive and is more effective at raising&#xD;
      serum 25-OH vitamin D levels than the latter. The regimen of 50,000IU given once was selected&#xD;
      as this regimen has been previously used without side effects in previous studies and has&#xD;
      been shown to be as effective as other regimens that utilize more frequent dosing with&#xD;
      smaller doses. Patients randomized to the control arm will receive placebo tablets and&#xD;
      advised to consume their medication similar to the treatment arm. Both groups of patients&#xD;
      will receive their medications from the pharmacy at Rush Medical Center, which will be&#xD;
      responsible for providing patients with the appropriate regimen. All patients will receive&#xD;
      the same postoperative multimodal analgesic regimen that is normally administered to patients&#xD;
      undergoing THA and TKA at Rush University Medical Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In accordance with current standard post-operative care, patients will be asked to follow-up&#xD;
      with their surgeon in clinic at 3 weeks and 6 weeks following surgery. At these&#xD;
      post-operative visits, patients will be asked to repeat the TUG test and the 17-questions of&#xD;
      the functional component of the KSS score.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 8, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knee Society Score (KSS), functional component (2012)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks post operative score</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the functional component of the 2012 version of the knee society score from the time of consenting to 3 weeks following surgery. Range 0-100</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knee Society Score (KSS), functional component (2012)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks post operative score</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in the functional component of the 2012 version of the knee society score from the time of consenting to 6 weeks following surgery. Range 0-100</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timed up and go test</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks following surgery</time_frame>
    <description>A timed up and go (TUG) test before surgery at time of consenting and at 3 weeks following surgery. The TUG test consists of measuring the time it takes for an individual to rise from a seated position in a chair, walk to a mark 3 meters away, turn around, come back, and sit in the same chair from which they started. Patients will be asked to perform the test twice at each of the aforementioned encounters. The use of any assistive devices such as cane or a walker) will also be noted.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timed up and go test</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks following surgery</time_frame>
    <description>A timed up and go (TUG) test before surgery at time of consenting and at 6 weeks following surgery. The TUG test consists of measuring the time it takes for an individual to rise from a seated position in a chair, walk to a mark 3 meters away, turn around, come back, and sit in the same chair from which they started. Patients will be asked to perform the test twice at each of the aforementioned encounters. The use of any assistive devices such as cane or a walker) will also be noted.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks following surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of any of the Knee Society's Standardized List of Complications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">142</enrollment>
  <condition>Knee Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients randomized to the control arm will receive placebo tablets and advised to consume their medication similar to the treatment arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients randomized to the experimental arm of the study will receive 50,000IU of vitamin D3 following surgery and asked to take the medication orally following surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin D</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients randomized to the experimental arm of the study will receive 50,000IU of vitamin D3 following surgery and asked to take the medication orally following surgery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients randomized to the control will receive a placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient undergoing primary total knee arthroplasty for osteoarthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to undergo randomization and return for all scheduled visits&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 80 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) Score ≥ 4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other supplemental vitamin D or Calcium use including their analogs: ergocalciferol,&#xD;
             calcitriol, dihydrotachysterol, and paricalcitol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malabsorption syndromes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to take medications orally&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal impairment defined as a glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &lt; 30 mL/minute or&#xD;
             creatinine &gt;1.3 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypercalcemia defined as albumin-corrected hypercalcemia &gt;12 mg/dL&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Denis Nam, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rush University Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rush University medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 22, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 22, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 26, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis, Knee</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin D</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

