<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04173546</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>69HCL18_0974</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04173546</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Identification of Psychoactive Substance Users in Young Adults (16 to 25 Years Old) Visiting the Emergency Department</brief_title>
  <acronym>DRUGS</acronym>
  <official_title>Systematic Screening and Identification of Psychoactive Substances Users in Young Adults (16 to 25 Years Old) Visiting the Emergency Department</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospices Civils de Lyon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospices Civils de Lyon</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Adolescence is a time for great physical and psychological change and it's often at that&#xD;
      period of life that first use of psychoactive substances occurs. Although addiction is rare&#xD;
      in teenagers, psychoactive substances abuse can have serious long-term health consequences on&#xD;
      them. This is therefore a priority for all healthcare providers to identify early use and&#xD;
      abuse of drugs in the youth's population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The addictive process underlies environmental, genetic and individual causes. That is why it&#xD;
      is somehow possible to identify individuals at risk based on some common sociological,&#xD;
      cultural and environmental risk factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the acute consequences of psychoactive substances abuses, Emergency Departments are&#xD;
      main checkpoints for the screening of young drug users. Indeed, one patient out of five&#xD;
      admitted in an Emergency Department shows a positive blood alcohol concentration regardless&#xD;
      of the reason for their admission. This rate is twice as high as in the overall population.&#xD;
      Hence, Emergency Departments are at the front-line for screening, caring, referral and&#xD;
      transfer of psychoactive substances users. That is why the Emergency Department is the best&#xD;
      place for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2004, the special consultations of young consumers were founded in order to deal with&#xD;
      these special cases where dependence is not yet established or installed and care has to be&#xD;
      adapted to the age. Offering help to this age range represents a real challenge since only&#xD;
      20% of the teenagers come to visit this special consultations on their own initiative. The&#xD;
      rest of teenagers are either obliged by their parents or sentenced by a court. The&#xD;
      investigators assume that the repetition of care offered to the teenagers by repeated&#xD;
      emergency admissions could trigger their own desire to overcome their drug use disorders and&#xD;
      visit the Addictionology Department.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Consumption questionnaire and urinary strips to detect psychoactive substances users</measure>
    <time_frame>Follow-up time: 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the prevalence of psychoactive substances use among young adults, aged 16 to 25, visiting the Emergency Department.&#xD;
This evaluation will be twofold:&#xD;
declarative through a consumption questionnaire (response by Yes or No without score) (whole life, past three months and previous month)&#xD;
analytical by means of a urinary screening for recent consumptions (from a few days to a few weeks according to the products) of seven psychoactive substances (Alcohol, tobacco, cannabis, ecstasy, amphetamines, cocaine, morphinics).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">459</enrollment>
  <condition>Psychiatric Emergency</condition>
  <condition>Drug Use</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Urinary strips will determine the recent consumptions (from a few days to a few weeks&#xD;
      according to the products) of seven psychoactive substances (alcohol, tobacco, cannabis,&#xD;
      ecstasy, amphetamines, cocaine, morphinics). The detection of some substances in urine works&#xD;
      via measurement of the decomposition products from metabolism: cotinine for tobacco, ethyl&#xD;
      glucuronide for alcohol, benzoylecgonine for cocaine. Regarding ecstasy, amphetamines,&#xD;
      cannabis and morphinics, the detection is done directly in urines. There are seven reading&#xD;
      windows (one for each substance) on the Drug Screen: if a colored strip appears in the&#xD;
      reading window it means that the detection is negative, otherwise if there is no strip it is&#xD;
      considered as positive&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Young people aged 16-25 inclusive, admitted to the Medical and Psychiatric Emergency&#xD;
        Department (Building N) of the Edouard Herriot Hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients aged 16 to 25 admitted at the Medical and Psychiatric Emergency&#xD;
             Department.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For adults: those who will agree to participate in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Minors from the age of 16: those who will agree to participate and want to&#xD;
             exercise their rights by themselves or for whom one parent or legal guardian agrees&#xD;
             for their participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient who doesn't understand French&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient under legal protection measures or guardianship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  confused person (GSC &lt; 15)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aurélie BERGER-VERGIAT, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Service Addictologie et Psychiatrie des urgences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Edouard Herriot</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <zip>69003</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 19, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

