<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04178785</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0038-19-WOMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04178785</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remifentanil Versus Fentanyl During Laparoscopic Hysterectomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Remifentanil Versus Fentanyl During Laparoscopic Hysterectomy- a Randomized Control Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Wolfson Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Wolfson Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction- During laparoscopic procedures surgical field exposure is one of the crucial&#xD;
      aspects for a successful surgery. Exposure can be optimized by pneumoperitoneum, positioning&#xD;
      of the patient and muscle relaxation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The European Association for Endoscopic Surgery has recommended using the lowest&#xD;
      intraperitoneal pressure allowing adequate exposure of the operative field rather than using&#xD;
      a routine pressure. A way to lower intraabdominal pressure during laparoscopic procedures is&#xD;
      to employ a deeper level of neuromuscular blockade.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intravenous (IV) opioids such as fentanyl and remifentanil are commonly used to provide&#xD;
      analgesia and supplement sedation during general anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In terms of analgesia, management of intraoperative stress, remifentanil exhibits similar&#xD;
      effects to fentanyl in adult healthy volunteers and surgical patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In clinical practice, if the surgeon asks for relaxation toward the end of the surgery, then&#xD;
      many anesthesiologists will increase the dose of the IV opioids. In our experience the use of&#xD;
      remifentanil achieves a better muscle relaxation and surgical space exposure with a lower&#xD;
      intraabdominal pressure and less need for a neuromuscular blockage as compared to fentanyl.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, the investigators aimed to compare the use of fentanyl versus remifentanil during&#xD;
      laparoscopic hysterectomy. Because surgical complications due to inadequate exposure are a&#xD;
      rare event, the typical way to study this issue is to use surgeon's satisfaction score.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study design- Prospective, single-center single blind randomized controlled trial. Patients&#xD;
      electively admitted for laparoscopic hysterectomy will be approached for requirement. After&#xD;
      obtaining a written informed consent, patients will be randomly assigned either to the study&#xD;
      group (Remifentanil group) or to the control group (Fentanyl group) in a 1:1 ratio. A blocked&#xD;
      randomization scheme will be created using a computer-generated list of random numbers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      study protocol-&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. anesthesia is induced and maintained with propofol&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Ventilation is performed with volume/pressure control mode with a tidal volume of 6-8&#xD;
           ml/kg, a frequency of 10-12/min and a positive end-expiratory pressure of 5 cm H2O&#xD;
           aiming at normocapnia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Tracheal intubation is performed 2 min after administration of the muscle relaxant&#xD;
           0.6-1.2 mg/kg rocuronium.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Patients in the study group will receive 0.2 mcg/kg/min Remifentanil&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Fentanyl at the dose of 100mcg will be administered to all the patients in the control&#xD;
           group&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The gynecologist, surgical staff and patients will be blinded to group allocation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. During surgery additional muscle relaxant will be given only when asked by the&#xD;
           gynecologist and will be mentioned in the anesthesiologic chart&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. The investigator managed the insufflation of the abdomen to 12 mmHg pneumoperitoneum.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Patients will be placed in the lithotomy position in a 30-degree head-down body&#xD;
           position.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Antibiotic prophylaxis is given for all patients&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. The gynecologists will evaluate the surgical conditions before a colpotomy is made in a&#xD;
           circumferential fashion around the cervix and toward the end of the surgery on&#xD;
           four-point rating scale (1: excellent, 2: good, 3: acceptable 4: poor)&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. The gynecologists will also rate surgical space conditions on a numeric rating scale&#xD;
           (NRS), where NRS 0 indicated optimal surgical space conditions and NRS 100 indicated&#xD;
           unacceptable surgical space conditions and an intervention is needed to secure&#xD;
           acceptable surgical space6&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 22, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 22, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical space conditions with modification of a 4-point scale. AT TIME OF COLPOTOMY</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>grade 1 (optimal) = optimal surgical space conditions;&#xD;
grade 2 (good) = nonoptimal conditions, but an intervention was not considered;&#xD;
grade 3 (acceptable) = an intervention was considered to improve surgical space;&#xD;
grade 4 (poor) = inadequate conditions and an intervention was necessary to ensure acceptable surgical space.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgical space conditions with modification of a 4-point scale. AT THE END OF SURGERY</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>1. grade 1 (optimal) = optimal surgical space conditions;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>surgical space conditions on a numeric rating scale (NRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>where NRS 0 indicated optimal surgical space conditions and NRS 100 indicated unacceptable surgical space conditions and an intervention is needed to secure acceptable surgical space</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">76</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>REMIFENATIL</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prospective, single-center single blind randomized controlled trial. Patients electively admitted for laparoscopic hysterectomy will be approached for requirement. After obtaining a written informed consent, patients will be randomly assigned either to the study group (Remifentanil group) or to the control group (Fentanyl group) in a 1:1 ratio. A blocked randomization scheme will be created using a computer-generated list of random numbers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FENTANYL</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prospective, single-center single blind randomized controlled trial. Patients electively admitted for laparoscopic hysterectomy will be approached for requirement. After obtaining a written informed consent, patients will be randomly assigned either to the study group (Remifentanil group) or to the control group (Fentanyl group) in a 1:1 ratio. A blocked randomization scheme will be created using a computer-generated list of random numbers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remifentanil</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients electively admitted for laparoscopic hysterectomy will be approached for requirement. After obtaining a written informed consent, patients will be randomly assigned either to the study group (Remifentanil group) or to the control group (Fentanyl group) in a 1:1 ratio.</description>
    <arm_group_label>REMIFENATIL</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt;18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  scheduled for laparoscopic hysterectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known allergy to medications that are included in the trial, severe renal disease or&#xD;
             impaired liver function&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>MIchal De Wolf</last_name>
    <phone>9725028346</phone>
    <email>michald@wmc.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wolfson medical center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Holon</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hadas Miremberg, MD</last_name>
      <phone>972526741740</phone>
      <email>dasile2@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 22, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 22, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 26, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 22, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 22, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 26, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>laparoscopic</keyword>
  <keyword>remifentanil</keyword>
  <keyword>fentanyl</keyword>
  <keyword>hysterectomy</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Remifentanil</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

