<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02710071</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>110342</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02710071</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of OSA Associated Hypertension With Nebivolol or Hydrochlorothiazide</brief_title>
  <acronym>nebhctz</acronym>
  <official_title>A Blinded Crossover Study of the 24 Hour Blood Pressure Response to Treatment of Obstructive Sleep Apnea Associated Hypertension With Nebivolol or Hydrochlorothiazide</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients who have obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) frequently stop breathing while they sleep.&#xD;
      They often develop high blood pressure. We are not sure what drug is best to treat the high&#xD;
      blood pressure. This study will give the patients nebivolol or hydrochlorothiazide (HCTZ) for&#xD;
      6 weeks after 2 weeks of placebo. The blood pressure response will be evaluated by 24 hour&#xD;
      monitoring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a blinded crossover study measuring the antihypertensive efficacy of nebivolol vs&#xD;
      HCTZ in up to 34 subjects. Subjects with an apnea-hypopnea index (AHI) &gt; 10 and hypertension&#xD;
      can enter the study. Hypertension is defined as a systolic blood pressure (SBP) &gt; 140 or a&#xD;
      diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &gt; 90 on the average of three seated blood pressure&#xD;
      measurements or a history of medical therapy for hypertension. Subjects who have tried and&#xD;
      abandoned continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) therapy for sleep apnea are eligible for&#xD;
      this study. All others will be advised that CPAP is preferred treatment for sleep apnea and&#xD;
      are eligible only if they decline CPAP or use it for too short a time at night to be&#xD;
      effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then patients will have their antihypertensive drugs tapered off and receive single blind&#xD;
      placebo for two weeks. After that, all subjects receive nebivolol or HCTZ for six weeks with&#xD;
      a full evaluation at that time. Subjects are crossed over to HCTZ 12.5 mg for 2 weeks&#xD;
      followed by HCTZ 25 mg for 4 more weeks. Nebivolol 5 mg will be taken daily at bedtime for 2&#xD;
      weeks and then as a dose of 10 mg for the remaining 4 weeks. Subjects will receive a&#xD;
      telephone call at the time of increased dosage as a reminder. Blood, urine and 24-hour blood&#xD;
      pressure measurements, hemodynamic measurements, questionnaires and drug accountability are&#xD;
      measured in the same manner toward at the the end of placebo and each drug treatment. The&#xD;
      entire study will take 14 weeks, although each study period may be lengthened by one week if&#xD;
      necessary for the convenience of the subject's personal schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will provide blood pressure readings from their home monitor or in clinic and will&#xD;
      not have the dose increased if they have systolic blood pressure below 105 mm Hg or side&#xD;
      effects suggesting that an increased dose might worsen side effects&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of each treatment period, subjects will undergo noninvasive hemodynamic testing.&#xD;
      Ultrasound will be used to measure aortic diameter and blood velocity in the ascending aorta&#xD;
      in order to better estimate cardiac output. Then, finger plethysmography will be used to&#xD;
      acquire beat-to-beat finger blood pressure and pulse rate. Beat-to-beat derived hemodynamic&#xD;
      variables will be calculated by a model flow algorithm (e.g. brachial artery flow, stroke&#xD;
      volume, cardiac output, ejection time, blood pressure rate of change, peripheral resistance).&#xD;
      Applanation tonometry will be used to obtain pulse wave velocity and central arterial&#xD;
      pressure. ECG will be recorded with standard ECG leads to determine heart rate variability in&#xD;
      both time and frequency domains. Spontaneous baroreflex will be determined from beat-to-beat&#xD;
      changes in blood pressure and pulse pressure interval. Forearm reactive hyperemia will be&#xD;
      used to quantify endothelial dysfunction during 4 minutes of post-ischemic change. Subjects&#xD;
      will then complete an Epworth Sleepiness Scale questionnaire (ESS) and a Functional Outcomes&#xD;
      of Sleep Questionnaire (FOSQ) to find whether they are drowsy in the daytime and if they feel&#xD;
      that they are compromised by not having adequate rest. Any adverse event will be recorded.&#xD;
      They are asked about any concurrent medication over the prior period, including prescription&#xD;
      medication, over the counter medication, and caffeine intake. Medication compliance is&#xD;
      evaluated by pill count. Those who fail to return their pill bottle are requested to bring it&#xD;
      in. Finally, a 24-hour ambulatory blood pressure monitor (ABPM) will be attached to&#xD;
      automatically collect blood pressure and heart rate values every 15 minutes during the wake&#xD;
      period and every 30 minutes during the sleep period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>24-h, Wake and Sleep Period Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of 2 weeks of placebo therapy, at the end of 6 weeks of Nebivolol therapy and at the end of 6 weeks of hydrochlorothiazide therapy.</time_frame>
    <description>24-h Systolic Blood Pressure is the average of all 24-h Ambulatory Systolic Blood Pressure recordings. The Wake Period Systolic Blood Pressure is the average of all Systolic Blood Pressures recorded every 15 minutes during the wake period. The Sleep Period Systolic Blood pressure is the average of all Systolic Blood Pressures recorded every 30 minutes during the sleep period.&#xD;
24-h Diastolic Blood Pressure is the average of all 24-h Ambulatory Diastolic Blood Pressure recordings. The Wake Period Diastolic Blood Pressure is the average of all Diastolic Blood Pressures recorded every 15 minutes during the wake period. The Sleep Period Diastolic Blood pressure is the average of all Diastolic Blood Pressures recorded every 30 minutes during the sleep period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">41</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo, Nebivolol, Hydrochlorothyazide</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sequence: Placebo, Then Nebivolol 5mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks,Then Hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo, Hydrochlorothyazide, Nebivolol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sequence: Placebo, Then Hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg for 4 weeks, Then Nebivolol 5mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nebivolol</intervention_name>
    <description>Nebivolol 5mg then nebivolol 10 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo, Hydrochlorothyazide, Nebivolol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo, Nebivolol, Hydrochlorothyazide</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Bystolic</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hydrochlorothiazide</intervention_name>
    <description>Hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 mg then hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo, Hydrochlorothyazide, Nebivolol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo, Nebivolol, Hydrochlorothyazide</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Hydrodiuril</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients ranging from 20 - 80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) of 20-38 to include the typical obese OSA patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension with blood pressures &gt; 140/90 but less than 180/105 mmHg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Apnea-hypopnea index above 10&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving sleep medicines (including heavy alcohol use) or drugs with adverse&#xD;
             interactions with study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who have premenstrual syndrome, or those who are pregnant or capable of&#xD;
             pregnancy and unwilling to use effective non-hormonal contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shift workers or have symptoms of narcolepsy, restless legs syndrome or insomnia, in&#xD;
             order to minimize confounding effects of other sleep disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have apneas which are primarily central&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have sleep fragmentation caused by syndromes such as chronic pain or movement&#xD;
             disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have diseases such as asthma or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease that compromises&#xD;
             respiration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have known coronary or cerebral vascular disease, history of arrhythmias,&#xD;
             cardiomyopathy, history of psychosis, current alcohol or drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have any contraindications to any study materials, such as heart block.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have secondary hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have creatinine levels above 2.5 mg %, more than 1+ proteinuria by dipstick, hematuria&#xD;
             or electrolyte disorders.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael G. Ziegler, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Professor of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ziegler MG, Milic M, Sun P. Antihypertensive therapy for patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Curr Opin Nephrol Hypertens. 2011 Jan;20(1):50-5. doi: 10.1097/MNH.0b013e3283402eb5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21326007</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 7, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 16, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>July 15, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>September 22, 2020</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 22, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 22, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael G. Ziegler</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hydrochlorothiazide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nebivolol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <pre_assignment_details>41 of 405 participants were randomized. Of those not randomized, 364 did not meet inclusion criteria</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Placebo, Then Nebivolol, Then Hydrochlorothyazide</title>
          <description>The participants first received Placebo for 2 weeks. They then received nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks. They then received hydrochlorothyazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothyazide 25 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Placebo, Then Hydrochlorothiazide, Then Nebivolol</title>
          <description>The participants first received Placebo for 2 weeks. They then received hydrochlorothyazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothyazide 25 mg for 4 weeks. They then received nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Placebo (2 Weeks).</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="21"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="20"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="21"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="20"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
        <period>
          <title>First Intervention (6 Weeks).</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="21"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="20"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="18"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="16"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="3"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="4"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Withdrawal by Subject</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="3"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="4"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
        <period>
          <title>Second Intervention (6 Weeks).</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="18"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="16"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="17"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="14"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Withdrawal by Subject</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <population>In the study arm 1 (&quot;Placebo, Then Nebivolol, Then Hydrochlorothiazide&quot;): 21 participant first received baseline Placebo for 2 weeks. In the study arm 2 (&quot;Placebo, Then Hydrochlorothiazide, Then Nebivolol&quot; ): 20 participants first received baseline Placebo for 2 weeks.</population>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Placebo, Then Nebivolol, Then Hydrochlorothiazide</title>
          <description>The participants first received Placebo for 2 weeks. They then received nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks. They then received hydrochlorothyazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothyazide 25 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Placebo, Then Hydrochlorothiazide, Then Nebivolol</title>
          <description>The participants first received Placebo for 2 weeks. They then received hydrochlorothyazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothyazide 25 mg for 4 weeks. They then received nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="21"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="20"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="41"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>&lt;=18 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Between 18 and 65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="18"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="19"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="37"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>&gt;=65 years</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="50" spread="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="54" spread="11"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="52" spread="11"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="6"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="17"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="18"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="35"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="21"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="20"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="41"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>24-h Ambulatory Diastolic Blood Pressure</title>
          <units>mmHg</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>24-h diastolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="86" spread="11"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="79" spread="11"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="82" spread="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Wake diastolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="89" spread="11"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="83" spread="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="86" spread="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Sleep diastolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="78" spread="11"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="74" spread="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="76" spread="10"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>24-h, Wake and Sleep Period Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressure</title>
        <description>24-h Systolic Blood Pressure is the average of all 24-h Ambulatory Systolic Blood Pressure recordings. The Wake Period Systolic Blood Pressure is the average of all Systolic Blood Pressures recorded every 15 minutes during the wake period. The Sleep Period Systolic Blood pressure is the average of all Systolic Blood Pressures recorded every 30 minutes during the sleep period.&#xD;
24-h Diastolic Blood Pressure is the average of all 24-h Ambulatory Diastolic Blood Pressure recordings. The Wake Period Diastolic Blood Pressure is the average of all Diastolic Blood Pressures recorded every 15 minutes during the wake period. The Sleep Period Diastolic Blood pressure is the average of all Diastolic Blood Pressures recorded every 30 minutes during the sleep period.</description>
        <time_frame>At the end of 2 weeks of placebo therapy, at the end of 6 weeks of Nebivolol therapy and at the end of 6 weeks of hydrochlorothiazide therapy.</time_frame>
        <population>The overall Number of Analyzed Participants for primary outcome (27) differs from the Overall Number of Placebo (baseline) Participants (41) because 14 participants were excluded from the analysis due to either low quality of acquired data or due to missing data. Data Analysis was performed for the same 27 participants and for the each test period.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Placebo</title>
            <description>Placebo for 2 weeks.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Nebivolol</title>
            <description>Nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O3">
            <title>Hydrochlorothiazide</title>
            <description>Hydrochlorothiazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothiazide 25 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>24-h, Wake and Sleep Period Systolic and Diastolic Blood Pressure</title>
          <description>24-h Systolic Blood Pressure is the average of all 24-h Ambulatory Systolic Blood Pressure recordings. The Wake Period Systolic Blood Pressure is the average of all Systolic Blood Pressures recorded every 15 minutes during the wake period. The Sleep Period Systolic Blood pressure is the average of all Systolic Blood Pressures recorded every 30 minutes during the sleep period.&#xD;
24-h Diastolic Blood Pressure is the average of all 24-h Ambulatory Diastolic Blood Pressure recordings. The Wake Period Diastolic Blood Pressure is the average of all Diastolic Blood Pressures recorded every 15 minutes during the wake period. The Sleep Period Diastolic Blood pressure is the average of all Diastolic Blood Pressures recorded every 30 minutes during the sleep period.</description>
          <population>The overall Number of Analyzed Participants for primary outcome (27) differs from the Overall Number of Placebo (baseline) Participants (41) because 14 participants were excluded from the analysis due to either low quality of acquired data or due to missing data. Data Analysis was performed for the same 27 participants and for the each test period.</population>
          <units>mmHg</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Error</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="27"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="27"/>
                <count group_id="O3" value="27"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>24-h systolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="137" spread="3.1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="130" spread="2.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="133" spread="2.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>24-h diastolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="82" spread="1.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="77" spread="1.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="80" spread="1.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Wake systolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="141" spread="3.1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="135" spread="2.5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="138" spread="3.1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Wake diastolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="86" spread="1.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="81" spread="1.7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="85" spread="2.1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Sleep systolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="129" spread="3.2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="123" spread="2.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="127" spread="3.0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Sleep diastolic blood pressure</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="76" spread="2.0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="71" spread="2.02"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O3" value="75" spread="2.15"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>16 weeks.</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Placebo, Then Nebivolol, Then Hydrochlorothyazide</title>
          <description>Participants first received Placebo for 2 weeks. They then received nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks. They then received hydrochlorothyazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothyazide 25 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Placebo, Then Hydrochlorothyazide, Then Nebivolol</title>
          <description>Participants first received Placebo for 2 weeks. They then received hydrochlorothyazide 12.5 mg for 2 weeks followed by hydrochlorothyazide 25 mg for 4 weeks. They then received nebivolol 5 mg for 2 weeks followed by nebivolol 10 mg for 4 weeks.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="21"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="20"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="21"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="20"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="21"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="20"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Michael G. Ziegler, M.D.</name_or_title>
      <organization>University of California San Diego</organization>
      <phone>619 543 2885</phone>
      <email>mziegler@ucsd.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

