<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03700801</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2018-NFMDXK-003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03700801</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Efficacy, Weight Control, and Safety in Newly-diagnosed Type 2 Diabetes With Different Antidiabetic Therapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Multicenter Prospective Cohort Study of the Hypoglycemic Efficacy, Weight Control, and Safety in Newly-diagnosed Type 2 Diabetes: Triple Combination Therapy Using Metformin, Saxagliptin Plus Dapagliflozin Versus Premixed Insulin</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zhujiang Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Sixth Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Third Affiliated Hospital, Sun Yat-Sen University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Peking University Shenzhen Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dongguan Kanghua Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>First People's Hospital, Shunde China</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The First Affiliated Hospital of Guangdong Pharmaceutical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Fifth Affiliated Hospital of Zunyi Medical College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Shenzhen Sixth People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Zhujiang Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study Hypothesis：Compared with premixed insulin, triple oral combination therapy has similar&#xD;
      hypoglycemic effect, better weight control and lower incidence of hypoglycemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective: Comparing whether the hypoglycemic efficacy of the triple oral combination&#xD;
      therapy is not inferior than that of the premixed insulin in the treatment of newly-diagnosed&#xD;
      type 2 diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objective: Comparing the effects on body weight and the risk of inducing&#xD;
      hypoglycemia between triple oral combination therapy and premixed insulin, and exploring the&#xD;
      effects of these two therapies on weight control and safety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Study Endpoint: The absolute change in baseline of HAb1c after 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Study Endpoint: fasting blood glucose, 2-hour postprandial blood glucose, fasting&#xD;
      C-peptide, 2-hour postprandial C-peptide, body weight, proportion of patients with&#xD;
      hypoglycemia, etc.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Overview of research design：Newly diagnosed T2DM patients who meet the inclusion/exclusion&#xD;
      criteria will be divided into a triple oral combination group (study group) or a premixed&#xD;
      insulin treatment group (control group). Blood glucose of these two groups will be recorded&#xD;
      during 12 weeks of treatment. And the change of the following effected indexes after 12 weeks&#xD;
      of treatment will be recorded: HbA1c, fasting / 2-hour postprandial c-peptide. Also, weight,&#xD;
      times of hypoglycemia and the occurrence of adverse events will be recorded during the whole&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Details during implementation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Grouping：&#xD;
&#xD;
           In the cohort study, patients are divided into two groups, with the study group as the&#xD;
           triple drug group and the control group as the premixed insulin treatment group. The&#xD;
           grouping method is as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Non-randomized grouping method was performed in this study. After signing the informed&#xD;
           consent, the participants were assigned a corresponding number according to the order in&#xD;
           which they were included in the study. For example, if the patient was the first to be&#xD;
           included in the cohort, his number was taken as No. 1; if the patient was the second to&#xD;
           be included in the cohort, his number was taken as No. 2, and so on. Then patients were&#xD;
           assigned to corresponding group based on their assigned numbers. If the assigned numbers&#xD;
           were odd, they were arranged in triple combination therapy group; if not, they were&#xD;
           arranged in premixed Insulin group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Drugs treatment and dose adjustment:&#xD;
&#xD;
           The use of saxagliptin: the initial dose is 5mg / time,1 time/day, before breakfast; if&#xD;
           the blood glucose dose not reach the standard when metformin and dapagliflozin have been&#xD;
           used up to the above-mentioned maximum amount, then adjust the dose in the order of&#xD;
           &quot;7.5mg / time, 1 time/day, taken before morning;10mg / time, 1 time/day, taken before&#xD;
           breakfast&quot; every 2 weeks; If the patient's blood glucose still fails to reach the&#xD;
           standard with the initial dose of the above-mentioned triple combination in 2 weeks, the&#xD;
           drug is adjusted to the maximum dose in the order of &quot;metformin-daglipide-saxagliptin&quot;.&#xD;
           If the blood glucose still fails to reach the standard, it is recommended that the&#xD;
           patients quit the study and then switch to other hypoglycemic therapy; if hypoglycemia&#xD;
           occurs during the incremental adjustment of the drug, and the effects of insufficient&#xD;
           diet and excessive exercise are excluded, it is recommended to maintain the therapeutic&#xD;
           dose before the dose of drug increased. If the patient has symptoms of hypoglycemia&#xD;
           (dizziness, fatigue, hand tremor, palpitations, etc.) when taking the initial dose of&#xD;
           the above-mentioned triple drug, it is considering to be the result of insufficient&#xD;
           eating or excessive exercise, then patients need temporarily eating to correct&#xD;
           hypoglycemia and investigators emphasize again to the patient the education in diet,&#xD;
           sports, etc. If the patient's diet is normal and the factors of excessive exercise are&#xD;
           excluded, adjust the drug treatment plan by firstly halving the dose of dapagliflozin,&#xD;
           and closely monitor the patient's blood glucose for the next week: if the blood glucose&#xD;
           does not reach the standard, continue to use the original triple therapy (metformin&#xD;
           0.5g/time 2 times/day or 3 times/day + saxagliptin 5 mg/time 1 time/day + dapagliflozin&#xD;
           10 mg/time 1 time/day); if the blood glucose reaches the standard and no hypoglycemia&#xD;
           symptoms occurs, maintain the existing plan (Metformin 0.5g / time 2 times/day or 3&#xD;
           times/day + saxagliptin 5mg/time 1 time/day + dapagliflozin 5mg/time 1 time/day), and&#xD;
           monitor blood glucose every week for not less than 2 days; If hypoglycemia still occurs,&#xD;
           the dose of saxagliptin should be reduced by half (metformin 0.5g /time 2 /day or 3 /day&#xD;
           + saxagliptin 2.5mg/time 1 /day + dapagliflozin 5mg/time 1 /day). If hypoglycemia still&#xD;
           occurs, reduce the dose of metformin to 0.5g /time 1 /day. If hypoglycemia still occurs,&#xD;
           then the patient will withdraw from the test, the medication is used according to the&#xD;
           actual situation of the patient and the patient's glucose is continue to be monitored to&#xD;
           ensure the glucose level of the patient reach the standard smoothly.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Insulin aspart 30: The initial total dose is 0.3U-0.5U/Kg, 2 times/day, subcutaneous&#xD;
           injection before breakfast and dinner, adjusted according to the blood glucose level&#xD;
           detected by the blood glucose meter. The target of insulin aspart 30 is that fasting&#xD;
           fingertip blood glucose (FBG) &lt;7mmol/L, postprandial fingertip blood glucose (PBG)&#xD;
           &lt;10mmol/L after three meals, if the blood glucose still not reach the standard (the&#xD;
           blood glucose measured in the specified monitoring time is not within the above range&#xD;
           two days in a row), then the clinical physicians adjust the insulin treatment therapy&#xD;
           based on the patient's blood glucose level, including increasing or decreasing the dose&#xD;
           of insulin aspart 30.&#xD;
&#xD;
           During the above-mentioned premixed insulin treatment, if hypoglycemia symptoms&#xD;
           (dizziness, fatigue, hand tremor, palpitations, etc.) occur caused by insufficient&#xD;
           eating or excessive exercise, then patients need temporarily eating to correct&#xD;
           hypoglycemia and investigators emphasize the diet and sport again to the patient. If the&#xD;
           patient's diet is normal and the factors of excessive exercise are excluded, then the&#xD;
           premixed insulin dose is lowered by 2-4 IU/time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Blood glucose monitoring:&#xD;
&#xD;
           The patient prepares the blood glucose meter and test paper at home, and the researchers&#xD;
           will explain to them how to use the device and give them adequate training.&#xD;
           Self-monitoring of blood glucose will be carried out by patients themselves at home. The&#xD;
           frequency of blood glucose monitoring is set as follows: monitoring frequency is once a&#xD;
           day for the first week; twice a day for the second week; once every three days for the&#xD;
           third and fourth weeks. After that, if blood glucose reaches the standard and remains&#xD;
           stable, it is recommended for patients to monitor blood glucose at least one day a week;&#xD;
           If blood glucose can't reach the standard or is unstable, the frequency of monitoring is&#xD;
           at least once every three days for recommendation.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Glycemic control standard refers to fasting fingertip blood glucose (FBG) &lt;7mmol/L and&#xD;
           postprandial fingertip blood glucose (PBG) &lt;10mmol/L, without presenting of hypoglycemia&#xD;
           (blood sugar &lt;3mmol/L) and associated symptoms (dizziness, fatigue, tremor,&#xD;
           palpitations, etc.) Detection time for fingertip blood glucose: fasting, 2 hours after&#xD;
           breakfast, before bedtime.&#xD;
&#xD;
           During each telephone follow-up, the researcher will record the patient's blood glucose,&#xD;
           adverse events, and guide the patient to handle hypoglycemia, such as measure the blood&#xD;
           glucose, eat cookies and candy rapidly, and record them in a log, whenever hypoglycemia&#xD;
           symptoms appear&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Follow-up At lease four times of visit：The first visit would last relatively longer with&#xD;
           around 4 days to screen and confirm appropriate volunteers. And the next three visits,&#xD;
           four weeks a day are mainly to assess the health for subjects. Additionally, subjects&#xD;
           are required to have a HbA1c test in the first and last visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Telephone follow-up: During the study period, the investigators will conduct a weekly&#xD;
      telephone follow-up of the subjects to find out their medication records, blood glucose&#xD;
      levels and adverse events, and to adjust their medication dosage in time in case of adverse&#xD;
      events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>According to two different therapies, patients were divided into the study group (triple combination therapy group) and control group (premixed insulin treatment group). Each group included 65 cases.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in HbA1c after 12 weeks of intervention.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>fasting/2-hour postprandial blood glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in fasting/2-hour postprandial blood glucose after 12 weeks of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fasting/2-hour postprandial c-peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in fasting/2-hour postprandial c-peptide after 12 weeks of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in weight after 12 weeks of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of hypoglycemia in two groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Triple combination therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>triple combination therapy group: Triple oral hypoglycemic therapy based on metformin 0.5mg twice a day, dapagliflozin 10mg per day plus saxagliptin 5mg per day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Premixed insulin therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>premixed insulin therapy group: The initial total dose is 0.3U-0.5U/Kg, twice a day, subcutaneous injection before breakfast and dinner, adjusted according to the blood glucose level detected by the blood glucose meter</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Triple combination therapy group</intervention_name>
    <description>Triple oral hypoglycemic therapy based on metformin, dapagliflozin plus saxagliptin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Triple combination therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Metformin, Dapagliflozin and Saxagliptin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Premixed insulin therapy group</intervention_name>
    <description>Subcutaneous injection therapy with insulin aspart 30 in patients with T2DM</description>
    <arm_group_label>Premixed insulin therapy group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Insulin aspart 30</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The newly-diagnosed type 2 diabetes mellitus according to the 1999 WHO guideline on&#xD;
             diagnosing type 2 diabetes mellitus; 9%≤HbA1c≤12%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age: 18-65 years old, Men or women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Voluntarily taking the triple combination therapy using metformin, saxagliptin plus&#xD;
             dapagliflozin or premixed insulin therapy, without taking any other hypoglycemic&#xD;
             therapy before;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. 18.5kg/m2≦BMI≦32 kg/m2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Voluntarily participating in our study and insisting on monitoring blood glucose at&#xD;
             least one day a week, finishing re-examination after three month with the informed&#xD;
             consent signed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Type 1 diabetes mellitus, or islet dysfunction (fasting C-peptide &lt;0.1nmol/L&#xD;
             (0.3ng/ml), peak value &lt;0.17nmol/L (0.5ng/ml))&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with acute complication：ketoacidosis / hyperglycemic hyperosmolar status /&#xD;
             lactic acidosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with proliferative diabetic retinopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with severe infection or urinary tract infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with clinically significant hepatobiliary disorders, including but not&#xD;
             limited to chronic active hepatitis and / or severe liver dysfunction. ALT or AST&gt; 3&#xD;
             times the normal upper limit (ULN) or serum total bilirubin (TB)&gt; 34.2 μmol / L (&gt; 2&#xD;
             mg / dL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with the following nephrotic history or kidney disease-related&#xD;
             characteristics：&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. history of unstable or acute kidney disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with moderate / severe renal injury or end-stage renal disease (eGFR &lt;60&#xD;
                  mL / min / 1.73 m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. urinary albumin: creatinine ratio&gt; 1800 mg / g;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. the serum (Cr) ≥133 μmol / L (≥1.50 mg / dL) in male subjects; the serum&#xD;
                  Cr≥124μmol / L (&gt; 1.40 mg / dL) in female subjects;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. congenital renal glucosuria;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Poor control of Severe hypertension, SBP ≥ 160 mmHg and / or DBP ≥ 100 mmHg; SBP &lt;96&#xD;
             mmHg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with myocardial infarction / unstable angina / severe arrhythmia / heart&#xD;
             failure in the past 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Hb≤110g/L in female subjects and Hb≤120g/L in male subjects;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Pregnant women or women who are planning to be pregnant during the study, women who&#xD;
             are currently in lactation, or who having not adopted highly effective,&#xD;
             medical-approved birth control methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Gastrointestinal diseases or surgical history, including Roemheld syndrome, severe&#xD;
             hernia, intestinal obstruction, intestinal ulcers, gastrointestinal anastomosis, bowel&#xD;
             resection, weight loss surgery or banding surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Taking any drugs that affect blood sugar or body weight, history of alcohol or drug&#xD;
             abuse over the past 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients who have received organ transplants or who have been definitely diagnosed as&#xD;
             immunodeficiency syndrome with immune disfunction;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. With a history of hypersensitivity or contraindication to metformin, saxagliptin,&#xD;
             dapagliflozin or other drugs to be used in the researched.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patients that might not follow this program, or with severe physical/mental illness&#xD;
             that may affect the effectiveness or safety, based on the judgement of investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jia Sun</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Endocrinology, Zhujiang Hospital, Southern Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jia Sun</last_name>
    <phone>+ 86 206 1643 195</phone>
    <email>sunjia@smu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Peili Wu</last_name>
    <phone>+8615626251212</phone>
    <email>plgeer@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 7, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Triple Combination Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Premixed Insulin</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypoglycemic efficacy</keyword>
  <keyword>Weight control</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin Aspart</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dapagliflozin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Saxagliptin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The related data will be published in academic journals</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

