<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03709030</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>13946</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03709030</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Early MRI in Acute GallstonE Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>E-MAGED</acronym>
  <official_title>Determining the Utility of Direct Access Magnetic Resonance Cholangiopancreatography (MRCP) in the Assessment of Suspected Acute Gallstone Disease Presentations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Perspectum</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Perspectum</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This pilot study aims to determine the utility of direct Magnetic Resonance&#xD;
      Cholangiopancreatography (MRCP) in the assessment of suspected acute gallstone disease&#xD;
      presentations. This will take the form of a randomized controlled trial, the design of which&#xD;
      is based on recent internal audit data which indicated that a high proportion of patients&#xD;
      ultimately require MRCP prior to diagnosis, treatment and discharge, and suggested that early&#xD;
      scan may improve overall costs and outcomes. Patients with symptoms and signs suggestive of&#xD;
      suspected gallstone disease and deranged liver function tests/amylase (i.e. suggestive of a&#xD;
      potentially obstructive gallstone disease), will be enrolled across the full range of&#xD;
      'front-door' locations for surgical presentations within the hospital (Emergency Department,&#xD;
      Surgical Emergency Unit, Ambulatory Assessment Unit), and randomized to one of two diagnostic&#xD;
      pathways which are both existing variations in current clinical care:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. MRCP is used as the first mode of imaging;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. following a standard care model (ultrasound then MRCP if deemed appropriate). An&#xD;
           assessment will then be undertaken of the cost-effectiveness of early MRCP versus&#xD;
           standard care, using the primary outcome measure of cost to diagnostic scan report&#xD;
           calculated using hospital episode statistics (HES), with secondary outcome measures to&#xD;
           assess the overall utility which include length of stay, time to diagnosis, overall cost&#xD;
           of admission using HES, in-hospital complications, Patient Reported Outcome Measures&#xD;
           (PROMs), readmission and re-attendance rates (ED/GP), and service/radiology costs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute biliary disease comprises a significant proportion of surgical presentations in&#xD;
      Accident and Emergency departments (A&amp;E), as well as of emergency surgical admissions to&#xD;
      secondary care. Historically, this patient group first undergoes an abdominal ultrasound to&#xD;
      confirm the presence of gallstones and look at ancillary features that may suggest&#xD;
      cholecystitis or the presence of bile duct stones. The vast majority of patients who have&#xD;
      abnormal liver biochemistry then proceed to Magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography&#xD;
      (MRCP), because the ultrasound scan is unable to clarify matters sufficiently to satisfy&#xD;
      clinical need. There is often considerable delay in carrying out two sequential imaging&#xD;
      investigations for each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A number of studies have raised questions regarding the utility of ultrasound in acute&#xD;
      biliary disease. The prevalence of Common Bile Duct (CBD) stones in patients with&#xD;
      cholelithiasis is significant at 5-15%. CBD diameter, often used in US reporting as a marker&#xD;
      of the presence of choledocholithiasis, may not correspond to the presence of a CBD stone -&#xD;
      in one study, only 37% of patients with CBD stones had CBD dilatation on ultrasound.&#xD;
      Ultrasound is a user-dependent technology, where the seniority of the scanner can influence&#xD;
      the reliability of the report, and a 2013 study by Barlow et al. suggested that ultrasound&#xD;
      findings in the context of deranged LFTs are often inaccurate in predicting CBD stones in&#xD;
      gallstone pancreatitis, suggesting that MRCP be used to improve diagnosis. A 2015&#xD;
      retrospective study led by Qiu et al. found the sensitivity of peri-operative ultrasound for&#xD;
      CBD stones to be very low at 44.95% and supported the use of MRCP as a diagnostic test if CBD&#xD;
      stones were suspected. They also suggested the potential for economic benefits of using MRCP&#xD;
      over US in patients with potential choledocholithiasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MRCP has been shown to be more cost-effective than US in selecting patients for Endoscopic&#xD;
      Retrograde Cholangio-Pancreatography (ERCP) with suspected CBD stones, has a comparable&#xD;
      accuracy to ERCP 6, and has been shown to reduce the number of unnecessary ERCPs performed in&#xD;
      gallstone patients 7. Epelboym (2013) and Nebiker (2009) however disagree, characterising the&#xD;
      use of MRCP in such patients as expensive and inefficient, and support the use of ultrasound&#xD;
      as the primary diagnostic modality 8,9.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a recent paper, Milburn et al conducted a retrospective study examining the patient&#xD;
      journeys corresponding to 234 inpatient MRCP scans over a 2-year period. They found that&#xD;
      increasing access to MRCP led to further interventions in 22% of cases due to an increased&#xD;
      detection of complications and alternate pathologies (e.g. malignancy), and therefore&#xD;
      increased overall length of stay. The median duration from request to scan was 2 days, with a&#xD;
      further 1 day to scan report (therefore 3 days overall from request to report). They&#xD;
      suggested improved access and timely reporting of MRCP could potentially reduce length of&#xD;
      stay, though it may also increase the number of interventions 10. Clearly, there is a need to&#xD;
      examine whether proceeding directly with MRCP (without preceding ultrasound) would prove to&#xD;
      be cost-effective for these patients, and with a growing body of evidence as to the utility&#xD;
      of early diagnosis to hasten the patient journey and improve treatment outcomes, further&#xD;
      research is needed to determine whether the use of direct MRCP may be beneficial in this&#xD;
      regard.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A recent audit of patients seen in the John Radcliffe Hospital ED over a period of six weeks&#xD;
      revealed 46 patients admitted with gallstone disease, an incidence of approximately 1&#xD;
      admission per day. This correlates well with local audit of surgical admissions, which gives&#xD;
      a referral rate of approximately 2 patients a day with 45% of patients referred from ED and&#xD;
      55% being referred from primary care. Despite the broad range of pathologies encountered in&#xD;
      the ED and the considerable overlap in presentation, the diagnostic accuracy of emergency&#xD;
      physicians with respect to gallstone disease was high, with the suggested specificity of an&#xD;
      ED cholecystitis diagnosis calculated at around 85%, based largely on clinical findings and&#xD;
      blood tests without radiological confirmation. This suggests that ED clinicians may be able&#xD;
      to identify patients whose presenting symptoms are likely to be secondary to acute gallstone&#xD;
      disease with a reasonable degree of accuracy on a clinical basis alone. Subsequent analysis&#xD;
      of the continued inpatient diagnostic pathways suggested that whilst ultrasound remains the&#xD;
      initial diagnostic radiological modality in the majority of patients with such presentations,&#xD;
      approximately 59% (27/46) of patients undergo cross-sectional imaging during their admission,&#xD;
      with around 48% (22/46) undergoing inpatient MRCP. Whilst access times to MRCP have improved&#xD;
      in recent years, this pathway nevertheless may potentially result in an unnecessarily&#xD;
      extended time to definitive diagnosis, and potentially unnecessary radiological expenditure.&#xD;
      This raises the possibility that using MRCP as the initial diagnostic test in such patients&#xD;
      may improve pathway efficiency, reduce length of stay and radiological burden, and hence&#xD;
      reduce admission costs, notwithstanding the potential for improved diagnostic accuracy and&#xD;
      detection of pathology such as common bile duct stones and/or pancreatitis. It may also&#xD;
      improve patient satisfaction and clinical outcomes (e.g. earlier access to ERCP and stone&#xD;
      removal in biliary obstruction patients). This can be assessed in a prospective randomised&#xD;
      study to assess utility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This pilot study aims to determine the utility of direct Magnetic Resonance&#xD;
      Cholangiopancreatography (MRCP) in the assessment of suspected acute gallstone disease&#xD;
      presentations. This will take the form of a randomized controlled trial, the design of which&#xD;
      is based on recent internal audit data which indicated that a high proportion of patients&#xD;
      ultimately require MRCP prior to diagnosis, treatment and discharge, and suggested that early&#xD;
      scan may improve overall costs and outcomes. Patients with symptoms and signs suggestive of&#xD;
      suspected gallstone disease and deranged liver function tests/amylase (i.e. suggestive of a&#xD;
      potentially obstructive gallstone disease), will be enrolled across the full range of&#xD;
      'front-door' locations for surgical presentations within the hospital (Emergency Department,&#xD;
      Surgical Emergency Unit, Ambulatory Assessment Unit), and randomized to one of two diagnostic&#xD;
      pathways which are both existing variations in current clinical care:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. MRCP is used as the first mode of imaging;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. following a standard care model (ultrasound then MRCP if deemed appropriate). An&#xD;
           assessment will then be undertaken of the cost-effectiveness of early MRCP versus&#xD;
           standard care, using the primary outcome measure of cost to diagnostic scan report&#xD;
           calculated using hospital episode statistics (HES), with secondary outcome measures to&#xD;
           assess the overall utility which include length of stay, time to diagnosis, overall cost&#xD;
           of admission using HES, in-hospital complications, Patient Reported Outcome Measures&#xD;
           (PROMs), readmission and re-attendance rates, and service/radiology costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to standard MRCP scan processing by the radiology department, data obtained&#xD;
      through this study will be processed using the new quantitative MRCP+ technology (provided by&#xD;
      Perspectum Diagnostics) to assess its diagnostic efficacy in detecting biliary tree&#xD;
      dilatation, stones or strictures. Perspectum Diagnostics' quantitative MRCP technology is a&#xD;
      software package which allows previously acquired MRCP data to be enhanced and quantitatively&#xD;
      characterised using advanced image processing techniques (MRCP+). Conventional MRCP scans can&#xD;
      be difficult to interpret since the 2D representation suffers from occlusion problems and a&#xD;
      lack of depth information. This new technology can enhance the data without the need for&#xD;
      contrast agent, enabling the visualization of smaller ducts. Quantitative characterisation of&#xD;
      the biliary tree computes biliary tube diameter at each point along the duct, along with&#xD;
      information about the cross-section orientation and branching topology. Combining true 3D&#xD;
      rendering of the enhanced data with quantitative characterization facilitates clear mapping&#xD;
      of the biliary tree, which can potentially improve surgical planning, facilitate detection of&#xD;
      strictures, dilatations and gallstones in suspected biliary colic presentations and&#xD;
      objectively stratify patients. As yet however this application of the MRCP+ has not been&#xD;
      fully assessed in clinical practice, and this subsequent part of the study would aim to&#xD;
      address this and provide data to enable assessment of its diagnostic utility.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 17, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomised Controlled Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost to diagnosis</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Total cost of admission up to the final diagnostic scan report</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall cost of admission</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean total cost of hospital admission for patients undergoing direct MRCP</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean length of hospital admission for patients undergoing direct MRCP</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to final diagnostic scan report</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean time to final diagnostic scan report for patients undergoing direct MRCP</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital complications</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage rate of patient-reported significant 30-day complications throughout study duration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>readmission and re-attendance rates</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage rate of readmission/re-attendance throughout study duration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Cholecystitis; Acute, Choledocholithiasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with suspected acute gallstone disease and deranged liver function tests/amylase will be investigated with abdominal ultrasound as first line imaging, as per standard care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Direct MRCP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with suspected acute gallstone disease and deranged liver function tests/amylase will be investigated with magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography (MRCP) as first-line imaging</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography (MRCP)</intervention_name>
    <description>magnetic resonance imaging of liver, gall bladder, pancreas</description>
    <arm_group_label>Direct MRCP</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or Female, aged 16 years or above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected gallstone/biliary disease presenting with acute abdominal pain AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one of the following blood test results to reflect abnormal liver function;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin &gt; 23 IU/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine Aminotransferase &gt; 50 IU/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate Aminotransferase &gt;46 IU/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Gamma Glutamyl Transpeptidase &gt; 44 IU/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Amylase &gt; 138 IU/L&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous diagnosis of chronic pancreatitis/hepatitis or chronic alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with contraindications to MR imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable disease as per judgment of the investigator which would render the patient&#xD;
             unsuitable for MR imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If not suitable for study intervention on admission - e.g. requiring immediate&#xD;
             ERCP/surgery, or ICU admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous enrolment in the study (i.e. on repeat attendance to hospital)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Already admitted to hospital for more than 16 hours&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex Novak, BSc MBChB</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oxford University Hospitals NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <state>Oxfordshire</state>
        <zip>OX3 9DU</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 12, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 17, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cholecystitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gallstones</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholelithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecystolithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Choledocholithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecystitis, Acute</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

