<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03701789</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BAREBONE2018</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03701789</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Baricitinib Treatment on Peripheral Bone in RA</brief_title>
  <acronym>BAREBONE</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Bone Quality in Patients With Rheumatoid Arthritis Treated With Baricitinib: Single Centre, Mode of Action Study (BARE BONE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Erlangen-Nürnberg Medical School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Erlangen-Nürnberg Medical School</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA) suffer systemic and peripheral bone loss. In this&#xD;
      study we aim to test the efficacy of in-label treatment with Baricitinib on the volumetric&#xD;
      bone mineral density in patients with RA over 52 weeks. Inclusion of RA patients comprises&#xD;
      pathologic volumetric bone mineral density measured by (High Resolution peripheral&#xD;
      quantitative Computed Tomomgraphy) HR-pQCT maging of finger joints.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Systemic and local bone loss is a pathognomonic feature of rheumatoid arthritis and can be&#xD;
      seen in a very early phase of the disease. Understanding the pathogenesis of rheumatoid&#xD;
      arthritis (RA) has advanced substantially in recent years. The mode of action of&#xD;
      immunosuppressive medication on pro-inflammatory cytokines, different cell types or&#xD;
      activation of cells is intensively studied and understood. In contrary, little is known on&#xD;
      how these medications influence bone damage in peripheral joints in terms of bone density,&#xD;
      bone microstructure, bone quality or erosions. This is due to different reasons. One factor&#xD;
      is the lack of suitable, user-independent imaging tools for outcome measurements. For&#xD;
      example, using conventional X-ray of the hand and fingers, no information can be obtained&#xD;
      about the volumetric density, microarchitecture, bone quality or volumetric erosion size.&#xD;
      Applying Dual-energy Xray absorptiometry (DXA) of peripheral joints, does also not provide&#xD;
      information about the volumetric bone density and no accurate difference can be obtained&#xD;
      regarding cortical or trabecular density parameters. Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) as an&#xD;
      outcome measure in RA enables good the detection and partly quantification of erosions,&#xD;
      however no information about bone density can be quantified. HR-pQCT (high resolution&#xD;
      peripheral quantitative computed tomography) imaging allows in detail (82 micrometer&#xD;
      isotropic voxelsize) evaluation of density, microstructure parameters as well as&#xD;
      quantification of erosions in peripheral joints. Furthermore, HR-pQCT data allows the&#xD;
      biomechanical analysis of the bone and therefore statements on the bone quality can be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Modulating inhibitors targeting the Janus Kinase (JAK) - Signal Transducer and Activator of&#xD;
      Transcription (STAT) pathway, effect pro-inflammatory cytokines and have been approved for&#xD;
      therapy in RA patients. Analysis of the inhibition of the JAK-STAT pathway in rheumatoid&#xD;
      arthritis synovium showed decreased phosphorylation of STAT1. Also pro-inflammatory&#xD;
      activation of STAT1 and downstream targets were inhibited by JAK inhibition. More&#xD;
      interesting, STAT1-/- mice have higher bone density due to Runx2 activation but are otherwise&#xD;
      are indistinguishable from wildtype mice . Furthermore, inhibition of STAT1 accelerates bone&#xD;
      repair after trauma, a similar process in our observation in rheumatoid arthritis joints. On&#xD;
      the other hand, JAK1 deficient mice showed reduced body mass peri-natal which has been&#xD;
      speculated to indicate bone growth delays. Focusing on bone loss, JAK inhibition&#xD;
      (tofacitinib) suppressed osteoclast mediated bone destruction via reduction of T cell derived&#xD;
      RANKL. In vitro we observed that osteoclast (OC) differentiation was not influenced by JAK&#xD;
      inhibition in regard to OC numbers and transcription factor expression. Interestingly, in&#xD;
      osteoblast cultures, JAK inhibition induced Runx2, Col1a and Osterix. In co-culture assays&#xD;
      with osteoblasts and OC precursors JAK inhibition led to decreased OC differentiation.Thus&#xD;
      JAK inhibition mediated OC function is not only influenced by T cell but also osteoblast&#xD;
      derived RANKL and therefore interferes in the balance of bone turnover by activating&#xD;
      osteoblasts.Using HR-pQCT measurements of fingers of RA patients treated with tofacitinib in&#xD;
      a small sample size we detected an astonishing gain of volumetric bone mineral density (mg&#xD;
      Hydroxylapatite/mm³). Furthermore, we noticed a decrease of the intra-articular cortical&#xD;
      porosity and a positive change of erosion size. In these cases, volumetric bone density in&#xD;
      metacarpal joints improved up to 20 %. In our experience, regarding other immunosuppressive&#xD;
      medication for example anti-TNF Inhibition, no comparable effect was observed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The longitudinal setup of this mode of action study is used to determine the effect of&#xD;
      baricitinib on the change of the volumetric bone mineral density in RA patients with&#xD;
      pathologic vBMD measured by HR-pQCT technique over 52 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 11, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 11, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 11, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in volumetric bone mineral density (vBMD) in metacarpal and radial bone between baseline and week 52 in patients with rheumatoid arthritis treated with baricitinib as determined by HR-pQCT</measure>
    <time_frame>52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>HR-pQCT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Rheumatoid Arthritis</condition>
  <condition>Bone Density</condition>
  <condition>Finger Joints</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>In-label treatment with Baricitinib</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Baricitinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Effect of Baricitinib on vBMD measured by HR-pQCT</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with Rheumatoid Arthritis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Oliumiant</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Main inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients eligible for inclusion in this study have to fulfil all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject must be able to understand and communicate with the investigator and comply&#xD;
             with the requirements of the study, must give a written and signed and dated informed&#xD;
             consent before any study assessment is performed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or non-pregnant, non-lactating female subjects aged between 18 - 74&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must oblige to use a highly effective method of birth&#xD;
             control until at least 4 weeks after the last IMP administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of RA according to the ACR/EULAR criteria and with symptoms for at least 3&#xD;
             months with moderate to severe RA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pathologic volumetric bone density, microstructure or presence of erosions detected by&#xD;
             HR-pQCT and or MRI measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with at least one DMARD (e.g. methotrexate) without sufficient&#xD;
             clinical response or stopped due to toxicities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fulfil criteria for baricitinib treatment according to its SmPC&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing pregnancy status or breast-feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chest X-ray or chest MRI with evidence of ongoing infectious or malignant&#xD;
                  process, obtained within 3 months or according to local guidelines, prior to&#xD;
                  screening and evaluated by a qualified physician&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Contraindication for baricitinib treatment according to its SmPC&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current treatment with bDMARDs or other JAK-inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine clearance &lt; 60ml/min (calculated analogue MDRD)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Current treatment with OAT3 inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History or evidence of ongoing alcohol or drug abuse, within the last six months&#xD;
                  before inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participation in an interventional clinical trial with an IMP within the last 4&#xD;
                  weeks&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>74 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Arnd Kleyer, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine 3, Rheumatology and Immunology Universital Hospital Erlangen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitiy Hospital Erlangen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Erlangen</city>
        <state>Bavaria</state>
        <zip>91052</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 4, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 10, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Arthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arthritis, Rheumatoid</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

