<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00417781</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9361700470</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NHRI-EX94-9407PC</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NHRI-EX95-9407PC</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NHRI-EX96-9607PC</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NHRI-EX97-9707PC</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NHRI-EX98-9507PC</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00417781</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Follow-up, Family Study on Attention-deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Follow-up, Family Study on Attention-deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Health Research Institutes, Taiwan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD), characterized by inattention,&#xD;
      hyperactivity and impulsivity, is an early onset, common (5-10% worldwide; 7.5% in Taiwan),&#xD;
      clinically heterogeneous, impairing disorder. Despite the abundance of research on ADHD, the&#xD;
      vast majority of samples have been limited to Caucasians; there is limited information about&#xD;
      the expressions, patterns, correlates, and outcomes for ADHD in the Taiwanese population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. to investigate the neuropsychological functioning, and psychiatric, academic, and social&#xD;
           outcomes of ADHD at adolescence;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. to examine the psychopathology and neuropsychological functioning among parents and&#xD;
           siblings of ADHD probands;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. to determine the components of ADHD and neuropsychological functioning with the greatest&#xD;
           familial recurrence risks; and&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. to validate the classification of ADHD and comorbid subtypes of ADHD using psychosocial,&#xD;
           familial, neuropsychological and longitudinal data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects and Methods: This 5-year proposal consists of two parts: (1) a 3 year-retrospective&#xD;
      cohort study and family study design; and (2) a 2 year-prospective cohort study design.&#xD;
      Several Chinese version of rating scales will be prepared in the first 6 months. The sample&#xD;
      will consist of probands with (n=180) and without (n=90) ADHD, ages 11-16, recruited from the&#xD;
      Children's Mental Health Center, NTUH and an epidemiological study. The ADHD diagnosis has&#xD;
      been made 3-6 years ago prior to recruitment. Probands and their parents will be assessed&#xD;
      using the following measures (n=810) in the first 3 years. Only probands will be reassessed&#xD;
      in the last 2 years. The measures will include a psychiatric interview using K-SADS-E and&#xD;
      self-reports covering the individual and familial/environmental domains; and&#xD;
      neuropsychological tests (WISC-III, CPT, WCST, CANTAB). The informants include probands and&#xD;
      their parents and teachers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long-term Objectives: The long-term objectives are to identify the endophenotypes that are&#xD;
      close to the biological expression of genes underlying ADHD, to determine the familial&#xD;
      aggregation and its specificity regarding the components of ADHD, and neuropsychological&#xD;
      deficit, and to identify the impact of ADHD on academic, psychiatric, family, and social&#xD;
      outcomes; and to identify a cohort of families with ADHD for future neuroimaging,&#xD;
      neurophysiological, and molecular genetic studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      (A) Specific Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ultimate goals of this family study are to identify the endophenotypes that are closer to&#xD;
      the biological expression of genes underlying ADHD, to identify patterns of familial&#xD;
      aggregation with regards to ADHD and neuropsychological function, to examine the impact of&#xD;
      ADHD on family functioning and parental psychosocial adjustment, and to characterize the&#xD;
      long-term outcome of ADHD at adolescence in a Taiwanese sample. We propose to replicate&#xD;
      previous studies on ADHD using a novel approach (an ambispective follow-up, bottom-up family&#xD;
      study design using a mixed clinical and epidemiological sample) to validate the findings of&#xD;
      previous studies in terms of the correlates, patterns, expression, outcome, and familial&#xD;
      aggregation for ADHD and to attempt to determine whether neurological, and neuropsychological&#xD;
      dysfunctioning also run in ADHD probands. With the accomplishment of these goals, this study&#xD;
      will resolve controversies over inconsistent findings in previous studies and contribute to&#xD;
      the literature on the validity of ADHD and ADHD comorbid subtypes using family data. The&#xD;
      specific aims of this study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Follow-up component:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. to explore the potential risk factors for the developing ADHD;&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. to investigate the expression and patterns of ADHD at adolescence in terms of&#xD;
                symptoms, neuropsychological, neurological, familial, school and social functions;&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. to examine the symptoms continuity and the determinants of persistent ADHD&#xD;
                symptoms;&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. to identify the symptomatic, academic, and social outcomes of ADHD at early and&#xD;
                late adolescence, including the use of tobacco, betel nut, alcohol and drug; and&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. to validate the comorbid subtypes of ADHD using psychopathological,&#xD;
                neuropsychological, behavioral, familial and social correlates.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Family study component:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. to examine the psychopathology and neuropsychological functioning among parents and&#xD;
                probably siblings of ADHD probands in comparison with those of control probands;&#xD;
                and&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. to identify the most familial correlated components of ADHD symptoms and&#xD;
                neuropsychological measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. Specific Hypotheses&#xD;
&#xD;
      The major research questions for the current proposal generated from prior research by our&#xD;
      group and others are listed below. Under each question, specific hypotheses are provided:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. What are the major adolescent and young adult outcomes for children with ADHD? (Outcome&#xD;
           of ADHD)&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Children with ADHD will be more likely to have comorbid psychiatric disorders such&#xD;
                as oppositional defiant disorder, conduct disorder, depression, and substance use&#xD;
                such as initial use of nicotine, betel nut, and alcohol at adolescence and&#xD;
                depression, substance abuse, and antisocial personality disorder at young&#xD;
                adulthood.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Academic underachievement, impaired functioning in several social domains,&#xD;
                interpersonal difficulties, and low self-esteem will be apparent at adolescence and&#xD;
                young adulthood.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. What are the correlates and endophenotype of ADHD? (Validity of ADHD)&#xD;
&#xD;
           a. Adolescents with ADHD will have more prenatal exposure to alcohol and nicotine,&#xD;
           family dysfunction, parent-child conflict, sleep-related problems, somatic complaints,&#xD;
           and neurological and neuropsychological dysfunctioning than those without ADHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. What are the specific components of ADHD that are familial?&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. We hypothesize that parents of children with ADHD are at higher risks for ADHD and&#xD;
                inattention will demonstrate more apparent family aggregation than hyperactivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. We also anticipate that deficit in executive function such as impaired working&#xD;
                memory, impulsivity, and problem-solving difficulties will be familial among&#xD;
                individuals with ADHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. In addition, associations between risk factors, and correlates that have not been&#xD;
                addressed previously are also investigated post hoc. These analyses will be&#xD;
                corrected for multiple comparisons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance and Background (deleted here) (E) Research Design and Methods This is a 5-year&#xD;
      project with the first three years of a retrospective cohort study and family study designs&#xD;
      and the last two years of a prospective follow-up cohort study design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A.1: The First Three-Year Study (2005.1~2007.12):&#xD;
&#xD;
      The major tasks of the first 3-year of this study consisted of three parts: (1) 6&#xD;
      months-development of several rating scales for adolescent and adult subjects, K-SADS-E&#xD;
      interview training, pilot study of the Cambridge Neuropsychological Test Automated Batteries,&#xD;
      and recruitment of subjects; (2) 2 years and 3 months-completion of recruitment and&#xD;
      assessments of 180 ADHD families and 90 control families (n=810); and (3) 3 months-data&#xD;
      management and analyses for the adolescent outcome and family aggregation of these 270&#xD;
      families and preparation for the follow-up study in the young adulthood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A.1.1: Preparation phase-the first 6 months (2005.1~2005.6)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Reliability and validity of instruments The Chinese version of the Conners Parent Rating&#xD;
           Scale-Revised Short Form (CPRS-R: S), Conners Teacher Rating Scale-Revised Short Form&#xD;
           (CTRS-R: S), Adult ADHD rating scale (ASRS), and Adult Self-Report Inventory (ASRI) will&#xD;
           be prepared with culture-relevant colloquial expressions by the experienced child&#xD;
           psychiatrists and professional translators.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. K-SADS-E and SAICA semi-structural interview training The interviewers will be trained&#xD;
           to conduct the K-SADS-E interviews for parent report on themselves and probands, and&#xD;
           proband report on themselves by the PI and staff child psychiatrists. (The details of&#xD;
           training courses will be provided upon request).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Training for administration and pilot study of neuropsychological tests including the&#xD;
           Cambridge Neuropsychological Test Automated Batteries (CANTAB), CPT, and WSCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A.1.2: Follow-up Studies for Children with ADHD-2 years and 3 months (2005.7~2007.9)&#xD;
&#xD;
      a. Description of Subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. 1: Selection of Subjects The sample will consist of two groups: one exposed group&#xD;
           including aged 12 to 15 adolescents with ADHD and one unexposed group including&#xD;
           adolescents without ADHD. Their parents will be recruited in the family study. Their&#xD;
           psychiatric diagnoses were made 3-6 years ago either at a clinical setting or in an&#xD;
           epidemiological study. Recruitment will stop when we will have approximately 180&#xD;
           probands with ADHD and 90 control probands.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Inclusion Criteria The inclusion criteria for the exposed group are (1) that&#xD;
                subjects either had the clinical diagnosis of DSM-IV ADHD, which was made by a&#xD;
                full-time child psychiatrist at the first visit and following visits or by a child&#xD;
                psychiatrist using the K-SADS-E as the second-stage case ascertainment at an&#xD;
                epidemiological study; (2) the diagnoses of ADHD were made 3-6 years ago; (3) their&#xD;
                ages range from 12 to 15 when we conduct study; (4) subjects have at least one&#xD;
                sibling aged 6-18 and live with at least one biological parent; and (5) subjects&#xD;
                and their family consent to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
                The inclusion criteria for the unexposed group are (1) that subjects were assessed&#xD;
                either at a clinical setting or in an epidemiological study same as to those in the&#xD;
                exposed group 6 years ago; (2) their ages range from 12 to 15 when we conduct&#xD;
                study; (3) subjects have at least one sibling aged 6-18 and live with at least one&#xD;
                biological parent; and (4) subjects and their family consent to participate in this&#xD;
                study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Exclusion Criteria The subjects, including those who in the exposed and unexposed&#xD;
                groups, will be excluded from the study if they currently meet criteria or have a&#xD;
                history of the following condition as defined by DSM-IV: Schizophrenia,&#xD;
                Schizoaffective Disorder, Organic Psychosis, Mental Retardation, or Pervasive&#xD;
                Developmental Disorder. Moreover, the subjects will be excluded from the unexposed&#xD;
                group if have a history of the following condition as defined by DSM-IV: ADHD, ODD,&#xD;
                or CD in addition to the above exclusion criteria. a.2: Source of Subjects Half of&#xD;
                the subjects will be recruited from the Department of Psychiatry, National Taiwan&#xD;
                University Hospital and half from the community in Taipei city based on the&#xD;
                diagnoses in a epidemiology survey for ADHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Procedures A letter and telephone contact with explanation of the purpose and procedure&#xD;
           of this study and reassurance of confidentiality will be done before the recruitment of&#xD;
           subjects, followed by face-to-face explanation and written informed consent. The&#xD;
           subjects and their parents will be interviewed separately to provide information about&#xD;
           the subjects' family composition, prenatal, developmental, and medical history,&#xD;
           psychiatric diagnoses, and social functioning. CANTAB and other neuropsychological tests&#xD;
           will be administered to probands and their parents. We will implement a quality control&#xD;
           procedure consisting of verification of the interviews of 20% of the sample. These&#xD;
           subjects will have their interview verified with audiotape, which will be reviewed by a&#xD;
           blinded rater. The child and parent self-reported questionnaires will be administered&#xD;
           either before or after child and parent interviews. We will interview 270 families (# N&#xD;
           of assessments = 810). For the second-part of follow-up study at late adolescence&#xD;
           (2008.1~2009.9), we will try to obtain corresponding information such as the addresses,&#xD;
           telephone numbers, and email addresses of their relatives or friends close to them in&#xD;
           order to decrease the loss of follow-up rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A.1.3: Data Analysis and Manuscript Preparation for the first part of study-Adolescent&#xD;
      Outcome (2007.10~2007.12) The research team will concentrate on data management and analysis&#xD;
      of the information gathered in the first three years to understand the adolescent outcome and&#xD;
      endophenotype of ADHD. We will also try to prepare several manuscripts for publication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A.3: Interviews and Psychiatric Diagnosis: Interviewers will be supervised by staff child&#xD;
      psychiatrists. We developed a formal training package including an overview of the study and&#xD;
      its methods, the diagnostic instruments, and detailed descriptions of the instruments and&#xD;
      interview procedures. DVD of psychiatric interviews with adolescents and adults with ADHD and&#xD;
      other major diagnostic categories are available for training and developing inter-rater&#xD;
      reliability. The quality control of interview will be carried out continuously.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The PI got her training in best estimate for diagnoses in her doctoral study at Yale. The&#xD;
      best estimate diagnosis, based upon all available information (interviews, questionnaires,&#xD;
      family histories, and medical records), will be made by the PI who will be blind to the&#xD;
      diagnostic status of the proband and who will not be involved in direct interviews of any of&#xD;
      the probands or parents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. Measures B.1: Interviews for Psychiatric Diagnostic Information and Social functioning&#xD;
      using the Chinese K-SADS-E for making diagnosis of probands and their siblings and parents;&#xD;
      and the Social Adjustment Inventory for Children and Adolescents B.1.2: Self-reported&#xD;
      measures The assessments will cover individual and familial/environmental vulnerability&#xD;
      factors. They include measures of symptomatology, temperament/personality, psychopathology,&#xD;
      competence, pubertal status, sleep patterns as well as familial and school functioning (Table&#xD;
      1). Chinese versions of these self-reported scales will be available including CBCL,&#xD;
      CTRS-R:S, CPRS-R:S, EPQ-JR, PDS, MES, DOTS, SAICA-C, PBI-C, FACS-C, ASRI, and DAS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long-term Objectives: The long-term objectives are to identify the endophenotypes that are&#xD;
      close to the biological expression of genes underlying ADHD, to determine the familial&#xD;
      aggregation and its specificity regarding the components of ADHD, and neuropsychological&#xD;
      deficit, and to identify the impact of ADHD on academic, psychiatric, family, and social&#xD;
      outcomes; and to identify a cohort of families with ADHD for future neuroimaging,&#xD;
      neurophysiological, and molecular genetic studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2009</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1800</enrollment>
  <condition>Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Community-based sample &amp; children with ADHD and their families&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Community-based sample for the development of several Chinese versions of instruments:&#xD;
             SNAP-IV, SDQ, ASRI, and ASRS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ADHD follow-up family studies (ADHD group): (1) that subjects either had the clinical&#xD;
             diagnosis of DSM-IV ADHD, which was made by a full-time child psychiatrist at the&#xD;
             first visit and following visits or by a child psychiatrist using the K-SADS-E as the&#xD;
             second-stage case ascertainment at an epidemiological study; (2) the diagnoses of ADHD&#xD;
             were made 3-6 years ago; (3) their ages range from 12 to 15 when we conduct study; (4)&#xD;
             subjects have at least one sibling aged 6-18 and live with at least one biological&#xD;
             parent; and (5) subjects and their family consent to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  (control group)(1) that subjects were assessed either at a clinical setting or in an&#xD;
             epidemiological study same as to those in the exposed group 6 years ago; (2) their&#xD;
             ages range from 12 to 15 when we conduct study; (3) subjects have at least one sibling&#xD;
             aged 6-18 and live with at least one biological parent; and (4) subjects and their&#xD;
             family consent to participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subjects, including those who in the exposed and unexposed groups, will be&#xD;
             excluded from the study if they currently meet criteria or have a history of the&#xD;
             following condition as defined by DSM-IV: Schizophrenia, Schizoaffective Disorder,&#xD;
             Organic Psychosis, Mental Retardation, or Pervasive Developmental Disorder. Moreover,&#xD;
             the subjects will be excluded from the unexposed group if have a history of the&#xD;
             following condition as defined by DSM-IV: ADHD, ODD, or CD in addition to the above&#xD;
             exclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan Shur-Fen Gau, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Taiwan University Hospital &amp; College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan Univeristy Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>10002</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 31, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 3, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 4, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 14, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ADHD, adolescence, family study, endophenotype, outcome</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperkinesis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

