<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00415584</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>05-09-244</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00415584</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cinacalcet to Treat Hypercalcemia in Renal Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cinacalcet for Treatment of Persistent Secondary Hyperparathyroidism in Renal Transplant Recipients: Effect on Renal Function, Serum Calcium and Bone Histomorphometry</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Montefiore Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Montefiore Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Secondary hyperparathyroidism can persist following successful renal transplantation and can&#xD;
      cause high blood calcium, kidney dysfunction or failure and excessive bone loss among other&#xD;
      problems. If the condition does not resolve, surgery is frequently required to remove the&#xD;
      parathyroid glands, with all the inherent risks of surgery. Cinacalcet, a medicine used to&#xD;
      treat secondary hyperparathyroidism in patients with kidney disease, may be effective in&#xD;
      treating this condition in the renal transplant recipient. We will study the effect of&#xD;
      cinacalcet on calcium, bone and renal function in a 6 month treatment protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Secondary Hyperparathyroidism in the renal transplant recipient can cause abnormal bone and&#xD;
      mineral metabolism, resulting in hypercalcemia that is detrimental to renal function, causing&#xD;
      renal dysfunction and calcinosis. These patients often require parathyroidectomy to correct&#xD;
      the hypercalcemia. Surgery is not without significant risk to the patient. Risks include&#xD;
      vocal cord paralysis, protracted hypocalcemia, cardiac arrhythmias, muscle cramps. In&#xD;
      addition, parathyroidectomy has been associated with subsequent renal impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cinacalcet is a calcimimetic agent that is very effective in the treatment of secondary&#xD;
      hyperparathyroidism in patients with renal failure as well as in hypercalcemia of parathyroid&#xD;
      cancer. There have been reports of short term Cinacalcet use in renal transplant recipients.&#xD;
      Serum calcium was improved in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, little is known about the effect of cinacalcet on bone activity and turnover. It is&#xD;
      not known whether Cinacalcet causes low turnover bone activity with adynamic bone disease. It&#xD;
      is known that low turnover bone disease in renal patients can by itself cause hypercalcemia&#xD;
      as the bone becomes static and unable to respond to everyday calcium loads.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have shown that adynamic bone can develop in renal transplant recipients under a variety&#xD;
      of conditions. It is not known what effect, if any, cinacalcet has on the bone activity of&#xD;
      renal transplant recipients with persistent secondary hyperparathyroidism.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study is to determine the effect of Cinacalcet on serum calcium, renal&#xD;
      function and bone histology in renal transplant recipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a prospective, open-label study. Stable adult renal transplant recipients who are at&#xD;
      least 3 months post renal transplant, are hypercalcemic and have persistent&#xD;
      hyperparathyroidism with inappropriately elevated Parathyroid hormone will be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol procedures will include baseline and 6 month measurements of bone mineral density,&#xD;
      bone biochemical parameters, glomerular filtration rate, anterior iliac crest bone biopsy.&#xD;
      Subjects will start cinacalcet after the first biopsy. The medication will be titrated to&#xD;
      normalize serum calcium. Medication will be supplied by the study. Serum electrolytes will be&#xD;
      monitored as indicated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    low enrollment&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>January 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>normalization of serum calcium</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>changes in renal function</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>changes in bone mineral density</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>changes in bone turnover</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Secondary Hyperparathyroidism</condition>
  <condition>Hypercalcemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cinacalcet HCl</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cinacalcet HCl</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Cinacalcet HCl</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  renal transplant recipient at least 3 months post transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hypercalcemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hyperparathyroidism&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  allergic to cinacalcet, tetracycline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  on medication that utilize same liver system as cinacalcet Hcl&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maria Coco, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Montefiore Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bronx</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10467</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 25, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>hypercalcemia</keyword>
  <keyword>transplant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypercalcemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperparathyroidism, Secondary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cinacalcet</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

