<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02479516</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APP242122</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02479516</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Community Health Assessment Program in the Philippines</brief_title>
  <acronym>CHAP-P</acronym>
  <official_title>Community Health Assessment Program in the Philippines</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>McMaster University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ateneo de Zamboanga University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>McMaster University</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators are adopting an intervention which has been tested in Canada to the&#xD;
      Philippine setting. The program will be called Community Health Assessment Program in the&#xD;
      Philippines (CHAPP). The main goal of CHAPP is to decrease diabetes and its complications by&#xD;
      implementing a community-based program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The CHAPP intervention will be modified so that it will be applicable to the Philippine&#xD;
      setting and other Low and Middle Income Countries. The initial plan for the program is that&#xD;
      trained volunteers or health workers will be running the CHAPP sessions 2-hours a week in a&#xD;
      community location for residents in the community. During the CHAPP session, volunteers will&#xD;
      administer a questionnaire and do basic measures (assessing the weight, height, blood&#xD;
      pressure, waist measurement). The questions can be entered into a laptop/tablet/cell-phone or&#xD;
      written into a paper questionnaire depending on the abilities of the volunteer to use&#xD;
      computers. Based on the data gathered, the volunteers will identify residents who have a high&#xD;
      risk of developing diabetes (including long term complications of diabetes such as&#xD;
      hypertension), educate them regarding what to do to avoid having diabetes (by doing exercise,&#xD;
      improving their diet, and avoiding unhealthy lifestyle), and refer them to local health care&#xD;
      when needed. Residents who have high risk of developing diabetes will be referred to have&#xD;
      their blood sugar checked. Residents who have diabetes or complications of diabetes will be&#xD;
      checked to see if they are being treated properly; if not they will be referred to the local&#xD;
      doctor for treatment and medication. All the information regarding the CHAPP sessions will be&#xD;
      sent to the Local Public Health Office or other designated local health centre so that they&#xD;
      will be able to educate, monitor, and attend to residents who have diabetes or who have high&#xD;
      risk of developing diabetes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary research question: What is the effect of CHAPP on diabetes awareness, detection and&#xD;
      management in rural communities in Zamboanga Peninsula, Philippines?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Project Description:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This 5-year program will be carried out sequentially as an embedded mixed methods research&#xD;
      project.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives of the research:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify optimal ways to adapt elements of the CHAP model to fit local conditions&#xD;
           (sociocultural, economic and environmental) and focussing on the prevention and&#xD;
           management of diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the effectiveness, generalizability, and cost-effectiveness of the CHAPP&#xD;
           intervention for use in rural communities in LMICs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To foster uptake of findings from the CHAPP program to other organizations and groups in&#xD;
           the Philippines and other LMICs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1: Adaptation of CHAPP to the sociocultural and economic setting Design: Qualitative&#xD;
      inquiry to modify and incorporate the CHAP intervention model to best fit the local setting&#xD;
      in Zamboanga Peninsula.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants: Department of Health Personnel; Provincial Health Office Personnel; Municipal&#xD;
      Mayor and barangay (local term for a small village) officials; Municipal Health Officers,&#xD;
      Public Health Nurses and Midwives; Local Lead Organization representatives; CHAPP target&#xD;
      participants (residents 40 years and older).Three municipalities will be selected from each&#xD;
      province for the KII.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Instruments: Interview guides for use in individual and group interviews, document&#xD;
      abstraction forms (to be developed once key documents have been identified).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Gathering Procedure: Document review, Key Informant Interviews (KII), Focus Group&#xD;
      Discussions (FGDs), and directed exercises (free listing, pile sort and taxonomy building).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis and outcome: Thematic Framework Analysis (CITE).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 2: Pilot project of CHAPP in selected rural communities Design: 6-month prospective&#xD;
      pilot project. The CHAPP intervention protocol developed in phase 1 will be pilot tested in&#xD;
      selected municipalities in the Zamboanga Peninsula.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To pilot test feasibility of the CHAPP The setting and study population: Two&#xD;
      eligible communities Region IX. Target participants are permanent resident of qualified&#xD;
      municipalities 40 years and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Community Participant Sampling: Cluster random sample of 400 residents 40 years of age and&#xD;
      older will be generated for each pilot Municipality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other participants: CHAPP Local Lead Organizations (LLO) and volunteers, selected CHAPP&#xD;
      participants, health workers (doctor, nurse, midwife).&#xD;
&#xD;
      CHAPP intervention: The proposed CHAPP intervention will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diabetes risk assessment (modified FINRISK and assessment of lifestyle risk behaviours)&#xD;
           sessions be at least every 2 weeks in accessible community locations, manned by trained&#xD;
           volunteers of LLO&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Volunteers educate CHAPP participants regarding their diabetes risk factors and ways to&#xD;
           practice healthy lifestyle (including referral to local resources/activities) using&#xD;
           diabetes education materials adapted for local context&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Use of an accepted process have participant data transmitted to a central web database&#xD;
           system through a combination of cell-phone and computer-based technology&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have participant assessment result forwarded to the Municipal Health Officer (doctor)&#xD;
           for follow-up and screening Data Gathering Procedures: Participant survey (risk profile,&#xD;
           physical activity, diet), data collected during CHAPP sessions, Community Process&#xD;
           Evaluation Data Analysis and Outcomes: Ease of conduct, difficulties encounters,&#xD;
           revisions needed&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 3: Effectiveness of CHAPP Design: Stepped-Wedge cluster RCT Objective: To determine if&#xD;
      CHAPP program will significantly improve behaviours related to the prevention and treatment&#xD;
      (physical activity, diet, medication use for diabetic patients) of diabetes among residents&#xD;
      40 years of age and older compared to usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization: The CHAPP will be implemented in 20 communities will be randomly selected,&#xD;
      stratified by district and population size and randomly assigned to 1 of 4 wedges (5&#xD;
      communities per wedge).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant sampling: A cluster random sample of 400 residents 40 years of age and older will&#xD;
      be generated for each of the 20 Municipalities at the onset.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: The CHAPP intervention will be implemented during intervention periods of&#xD;
      selected communities. During control periods, communities will follow usual practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Instruments: Same research instruments will be used as in Phase 2 Primary outcome:&#xD;
      For the general population, outcomes that will be assessed are physical activity measured by&#xD;
      the International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ), Diet measured by the portions of&#xD;
      the diet survey lines from the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS)&#xD;
      questionnaire. For diagnosed diabetics, outcome will also include medication compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes: Hospital admission rates and mortality rates due to diabetes and&#xD;
      diabetes-related illness (based on International Classification of Disease-9 codes), number&#xD;
      of newly diagnosed residents with diabetes, and changes in the BP and BMI of CHAPP&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection: All data collection procedures will be similar to Phase 2 or may be modified&#xD;
      based on the results of the pilot study and advice from the Advisory Committee.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis: The primary analysis will be to compare communities receiving the CHAPP&#xD;
      intervention to those receiving regular care according to the stepped wedge schedule.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>November 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elevated HBA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood Pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Health Behaviour questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHAPP intervention communities</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CHAPP intervention: The proposed CHAPP intervention will include:&#xD;
Diabetes risk assessment (modified FINRISK and assessment of lifestyle risk behaviours) sessions be at least every 2 weeks in accessible community locations, manned by trained volunteers of LLO&#xD;
Volunteers educate CHAPP participants regarding their diabetes risk factors and ways to practice healthy lifestyle (including referral to local resources/activities) using diabetes education materials adapted for local context&#xD;
Use of an accepted process have participant data transmitted to a central web database system through a combination of cell-phone and computer-based technology&#xD;
Have participant assessment result forwarded to the Municipal Health Officer (doctor) for follow-up and screening</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Delayed Intervention communities</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Community Health Assessment Program Philippines (CHAP-P)</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>CHAPP intervention communities</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resident of the intervention community&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <link>
    <url>http://chapprogram.ca/</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 19, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 24, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 19, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 19, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 24, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes screening</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Promotion</keyword>
  <keyword>Low and Middle Income Countries</keyword>
  <keyword>CHAP</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

