<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02476955</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>7075-001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>ARQ 092-102</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02476955</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open-label Phase 1b Study of ARQ 092 in Combination With Anastrozole</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label Phase 1b Study of ARQ 092 in Combination With Other Antineoplastic Agents in Subjects With Selected Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ArQule, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Merck Sharp and Dohme, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ArQule, Inc. (a wholly owned subsidiary of Merck Sharp and Dohme, a subsidiary of Merck &amp; Co., Inc.)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An Open-label Phase 1b Study of ARQ 092 in Combination with other Antineoplastic Agents in&#xD;
      Subjects with Selected Solid Tumors&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label Phase 1b, dose escalation study of oral ARQ 092 administered in&#xD;
      combination with carboplatin plus paclitaxel (Carboplatin Plus Paclitaxel Arm) or in&#xD;
      combination with paclitaxel alone (Paclitaxel Arm), in subjects with advanced, inoperable&#xD;
      metastatic and/or recurrent solid tumors, or in combination with anastrozole (Anastrozole&#xD;
      Arm) in subjects with ovarian or endometrial cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment in the Carboplatin plus Paclitaxel Arm and Paclitaxel Alone Arm is now closed.&#xD;
      Enrollment in the Expansion Cohort for the Anastrozole Arm continues for patients with&#xD;
      Endometrial cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 9, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 7, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 7, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of treatment emergent adverse events (TEAEs) as assessed by the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 4.03</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at each scheduled visit up to treatment discontinuation + 30 days with an estimated treatment duration of 3 to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of adverse events will be assessed as a measure of the safety and tolerability profile of ARQ 092</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR) based on central review of tumor measurement using Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and every 2 cycles (8 weeks) after the first dose of ARQ 092 during the first 6 cycles (24 weeks) of treatment, and every 3 cycles (12 weeks) thereafter or as clinically indicated, and at the End of Treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>ORR will be assessed as a measure of efficacy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS) based on central review of tumor measurement using Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and every 2 cycles (8 weeks) after the first dose of ARQ 092 during the first 6 cycles (24 weeks) of treatment, and every 3 cycles (12 weeks) thereafter or as clinically indicated, and at the End of Treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>PFS will be assessed as a measure of efficacy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DoR) based on central review of tumor measurement</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and every 2 cycles (8 weeks) after the first dose of ARQ 092 during the first 6 cycles (24 weeks) of treatment, and every 3 cycles (12 weeks) thereafter or as clinically indicated, and at the End of Treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>DoR will be assessed as a measure of efficacy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak plasma concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>During Cycle 1, Day 1 and Cycle 2, Day 1 of treatment (t=0, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 hours post ARQ 092 dose). And at Cycle 1, Day 8, Day 15, and Day 22 (t = pre-dose ARQ 092 dose).</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration vs. time curve (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>During Cycle 1, Day 1 and Cycle 2, Day 1 of treatment (t=0, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 hours post ARQ 092 dose). And at Cycle 1, Day 8, Day 15, and Day 22 (t = pre-dose ARQ 092 dose).</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Half-life of ARQ 092</measure>
    <time_frame>During Cycle 1, Day 1 and Cycle 2, Day 1 of treatment (t=0, 2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 hours post ARQ 092 dose). And at Cycle 1, Day 8, Day 15, and Day 22 (t = pre-dose ARQ 092 dose).</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">41</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ARQ 092 + anastrozole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ARQ 092 will be administered orally at 150 milligrams (mg) every day (QD), 5 days on/9 days off of a 28 day cycle in combination with anastrozole which will be administered orally at 1 mg QD continuously. The combination treatment will continue until progression of disease (clinical or radiological), unacceptable toxicity, or another of the discontinuation criteria is documented.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ARQ 092 + carboplatin + paclitaxel (Closed)</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will receive ARQ 092 orally at dose levels specified for their respective dose cohorts plus carboplatin (AUC6, intravenously, Day 1) plus paclitaxel (175 mg/m2, intravenously, Day 1) on a 21-day schedule.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ARQ 092 + anastrozole</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>cis-Diammine</other_name>
    <other_name>Paraplatin</other_name>
    <other_name>Taxol</other_name>
    <other_name>Abraxane</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ARQ 092 + paclitaxel (Closed)</intervention_name>
    <description>ARQ 092 will be administered orally at 200 mg twice a day (BID) weekly (Cohort 1P) of a 28-day cycle in combination with an intravenous (IV) infusion of paclitaxel (80 mg/m2). ARQ 092 will be administered once a week on Day 1, Day 8, Day 15, and Day 22 of each 28-day cycle; paclitaxel will be administered once a week on Day 1, Day 8, and Day 15 for three consecutive weeks followed by one week off of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ARQ 092 + anastrozole</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Taxol</other_name>
    <other_name>Abraxane</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ARQ 092 + anastrozole</intervention_name>
    <description>ARQ 092 will be administered orally at 150 mg QD, 5 days on/9 days of a 28 day cycle in combination with anastrozole which will be administered orally at 1 mg QD continuously.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ARQ 092 + anastrozole</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Arimidex</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signed written informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically or cytologically confirmed locally advanced, inoperable, or metastatic&#xD;
             tumors:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects with endometrial cancer with:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Documented/locally determined AKT1, PIK3CA, or PIK3R1 mutations with or&#xD;
                       without PTEN deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  ER+ status&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Female subjects of child-bearing potential must have a negative serum or urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test within 72 hours prior to administration of the first dose of study&#xD;
             drug. &quot;Women of childbearing potential&quot; is defined as sexually mature women who have&#xD;
             not undergone hysterectomy and/or bilateral oophorectomy, or who have not been&#xD;
             naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive months prior to administration of&#xD;
             the first dose of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Measurable or evaluable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects must agree to provide requested amount of archival and/or fresh tissue biopsy&#xD;
             samples at baseline for mutational analysis by the Sponsor's central laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Life expectancy ≥ 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Failure to respond to or refractory to approved/standard therapy; or for whom standard&#xD;
             therapy does not exist, or is not tolerable; or for whom approved/standard therapy is&#xD;
             not considered to be sufficient or appropriate by the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Adequate organ function as indicated by the following laboratory values. All&#xD;
             laboratory tests must be obtained within 7 days prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematological&#xD;
&#xD;
                  - Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.0 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
                  - Platelet count (Plt) ≥ 100 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
                  - Hemoglobin (Hb) ≥ 8 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 60 mL/min /1.73 m2 for subjects with serum&#xD;
                       creatinine levels &gt; 1.5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatic&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Direct bilirubin ≤ ULN for subjects with total bilirubin levels &gt; 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  AST and ALT ≤ 3 x ULN or ≤ 5 x ULN for subjects with known liver metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Metabolic - Glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c) ≤ 8%&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. If a subject is currently receiving bisphosphonates or denosumab, the subject must&#xD;
             have received the bisphosphonates or denosumab for at least four weeks before starting&#xD;
             study treatment. Initiation of bisphosphonates or denosumab during the study may be&#xD;
             allowed provided the subject completes the first cycle of treatment without any DLT&#xD;
             and the Investigator rules out tumor progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Male or female subjects of child-bearing potential must agree to use double-barrier&#xD;
             contraceptive measures, oral contraception, or avoidance of intercourse during and&#xD;
             after the study (3 months after the last dose of ARQ 092 or anastrozole, whichever is&#xD;
             longer)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Anti-cancer therapy, such as chemotherapy, immunotherapy, targeted and&#xD;
             hormonal/endocrine therapy, or investigational agents within five half-lives or two&#xD;
             weeks (whichever is shorter) for oral drugs, five half-lives or four weeks (whichever&#xD;
             is shorter) for intravenous drugs, and six weeks for nitrosoureas, mitomycin C, or&#xD;
             bevacizumab prior to administration of the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  To be eligible for study treatment, toxicity from prior treatment must recover to&#xD;
                  Grade ≤ 1, except for alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Concurrent systemic high-dose corticosteroids when used intermittently in an&#xD;
                  antiemetic regimen for central nervous system (CNS) metastases management or as a&#xD;
                  part of the premedication regimen are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prior hormonal therapy (including, but not limited to, tamoxifen, megestrol&#xD;
                  acetate, fulvestrant, and GnRH analogs) for the treatment of recurrent/advanced&#xD;
                  endometrial cancer are not allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Radiation therapy within four weeks prior to administration of the first dose of study&#xD;
             drug&#xD;
&#xD;
             • To be eligible for study treatment, radiation therapy-related toxicity must recover&#xD;
             to Grade ≤ 1 prior to administration of the first dose of study drug. Concurrent&#xD;
             palliative radiotherapy for local pain-control may be allowed, provided the subject&#xD;
             does not meet criteria of progressive disease and treated lesions will not be included&#xD;
             in the target/non-target lesion assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Major surgical procedure within four weeks prior to administration of the first dose&#xD;
             of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
             • To be eligible for study treatment, all surgical wounds must be fully healed and any&#xD;
             surgery-related adverse events (AE) must recover to Grade ≤ 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous treatment with AKT inhibitors (e.g., MK-2206, GSK2141795, AZD5363)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Contraindications to treatment with anastrozole defined by the Investigator based on&#xD;
             institutional Standard of Care (SOC), scientific evidence, expert medical judgment, or&#xD;
             published literature&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of allergic reaction attributed to compound(s) of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition as ARQ 092 or anastrozole&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Unable or unwilling to swallow ARQ 092 or anastrozole&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known active Central Nervous System (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis&#xD;
&#xD;
             • To be eligible for the study treatment, subjects must have stable disease ≥ 3&#xD;
             months, confirmed by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) or computed tomography (CT)&#xD;
             scan, and have CNS metastases well controlled by low-dose steroids, anti-epileptics,&#xD;
             or other symptom-relieving medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of myocardial infarction (MI) or congestive heart failure defined as Class II&#xD;
             to IV per the New York Heart Association (NYHA) classification within 6 months of the&#xD;
             first dose of ARQ 092 (MI that occurred &gt; 6 months prior to the first dose of ARQ 092&#xD;
             will be permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of Type 1 or 2 diabetes mellitus requiring regular medication (other than oral&#xD;
             hypoglycemic agents including metformin) or fasting glucose ≥ 160 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Significant gastrointestinal disorder(s), that could in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator, interfere with the absorption, metabolism, or excretion of ARQ 092&#xD;
             (e.g., Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis, extensive gastric resection)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Previous malignancy within 2 years of the first dose of study drugs, except tumors&#xD;
             totally resected and/or not requiring therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Concurrent uncontrolled illness not related to cancer, including but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
             • Ongoing or active infection, including human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis&#xD;
             B (HBV) (hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg] positive; subjects with documented&#xD;
             laboratory evidence of HBV clearance may be enrolled) or hepatitis C (HCV) (positive&#xD;
             HCV antibody), or bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Psychiatric illness, substance abuse, and/or social situation that would limit&#xD;
             compliance with study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Blood transfusion within 5 days of the blood draw being used to confirm eligibility&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Oklahoma Health Sciences Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oklahoma City</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>73104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 10, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 17, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 22, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ARQ 092</keyword>
  <keyword>Carboplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Paclitaxel</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT inhibitor in combination therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Targeted therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Molecular therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI)</keyword>
  <keyword>Receptor tyrosine kinase (RTK)</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase 1 - Phase I</keyword>
  <keyword>Solid tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>Metastatic solid tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>Recurrent solid tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>Ovarian cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Endometrial cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Cervical cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Triple-negative breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT kinases</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT pathway</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT signaling</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT pan inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>PI3K/AKT/mTOR signaling pathway</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT1</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT2</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT3</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase I Clinical Trial</keyword>
  <keyword>Clinical oncology</keyword>
  <keyword>Tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT1 inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT2 inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT3 inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT1 mutation</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT2 mutation</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT3 mutation</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT1 amplification</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT2 amplification</keyword>
  <keyword>AKT3 amplification</keyword>
  <keyword>Anastrozole</keyword>
  <keyword>Estrogen receptor positive</keyword>
  <keyword>PIK3CA mutation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Albumin-Bound Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anastrozole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>http://engagezone.msd.com/doc/ProcedureAccessClinicalTrialData.pdf</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>http://engagezone.msd.com/ds_documentation.php</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

