<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04236128</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18-0200-E</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04236128</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Home to Stay Mobile App for Colorectal Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Home To Stay: An Integrated Monitoring System Using a Mobile App to Reduce Readmissions Following Colorectal Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mount Sinai Hospital, Canada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mount Sinai Hospital, Canada</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Colorectal surgery includes surgery for colorectal cancer, inflammatory bowel&#xD;
      disease and other benign diseases such as diverticulitis. In Canada, approximately 21,000&#xD;
      colorectal surgeries are performed each year. Patients undergoing colorectal surgery face&#xD;
      high rates of unplanned hospital visits including readmission to hospital and Emergency Room&#xD;
      (ER) visits. These unplanned hospital visits lead to significant distress and anxiety for&#xD;
      patients and increased health care costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Aims: The goal is to evaluate the use of an integrated discharge monitoring system&#xD;
      with a mobile application (app) to support colorectal surgery patients at home following&#xD;
      discharge from hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: The study will include 3 hospitals across Canada. Patients will be assigned to&#xD;
      either a control group or intervention group. Control group patients will receive standard&#xD;
      follow up care after going home following surgery. Intervention group patients will be&#xD;
      enrolled in an integrated discharge monitoring system using an app to monitor their progress&#xD;
      at home following discharge after surgery. The main outcomes are to measure the number of&#xD;
      patients with unplanned hospital visits within 30 days of discharge following surgery, the&#xD;
      quality of patient recovery and confidence managing one's own health care. Patients are&#xD;
      eligible if they are being discharge home after having elective colorectal surgery, are 18&#xD;
      years or older and speak and understand English or French. At the end of the study, the&#xD;
      outcomes between the control group and intervention group will be compared to look for&#xD;
      important differences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected Outcomes: It is expected that the results of this study will show that the&#xD;
      integrated discharge monitoring system will lead to a significant improvement in the quality&#xD;
      of patient recovery and self-confidence with one's own health care, as well as significantly&#xD;
      reduce the number of unplanned hospital visits for patients undergoing colorectal surgery in&#xD;
      Canada.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Patients undergoing colorectal surgery are vulnerable during their transition&#xD;
      from hospital to home and face high rates of unplanned hospital visits including readmission&#xD;
      to hospital and ER visits. Not only does this lead to significant distress for patients but&#xD;
      also translates into significant health care costs. At a patient engagement meeting with&#xD;
      patients from across Canada led by our group, one of the main themes that emerged was the&#xD;
      patients' sense of abandonment upon discharge from hospital following surgery. Based on this&#xD;
      feedback, our investigative team developed and pilot tested an integrated discharge&#xD;
      monitoring system using a mobile application (app) to support patients following discharge&#xD;
      from hospital after colorectal surgery. The results of this pilot work provided compelling&#xD;
      data to suggest that this integrated discharge monitoring system was feasible, highly rated&#xD;
      by patients and may lead to a considerable decrease in 30-day unplanned hospital visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Aims: Therefore, the aim of this study is to conduct a 3 year, randomized controlled&#xD;
      trial (RCT) to evaluate the effectiveness of an integrated discharge monitoring system to&#xD;
      support colorectal surgery patients at home following discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: A RCT will be implemented at 3 high volume colorectal surgery centres across Canada.&#xD;
      The intervention is an integrated discharge monitoring system using an app that has been&#xD;
      developed and pilot tested in partnership with SeamlessMD. The inclusion criteria for the&#xD;
      study are: any patient being discharged home following elective colorectal surgery, 18 years&#xD;
      or older and able to speak and understand English or French. The primary outcome for the&#xD;
      study is 30-day unplanned hospital visits and the secondary outcomes include patient quality&#xD;
      of recovery and self-efficacy with one's own health care. A sample size of 670 patients is&#xD;
      planned and will provide an 80% power to detect a 30% reduction in 30-day unplanned hospital&#xD;
      visits, assuming a baseline 30-day unplanned hospital visit rate of 27%, 0.05 Type 1 error&#xD;
      rate and an 80% power.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected Outcomes: It is expected that the results of this trial will show that the&#xD;
      integrated discharge monitoring system leads to a significant improvement in patient&#xD;
      satisfaction in terms of quality of recovery and self-efficacy as well as a significant&#xD;
      reduction in 30-day unplanned hospital visits and health care costs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>30-day unplanned hospital visit rate</measure>
    <time_frame>30 Days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who are either readmitted to any hospital or present to the ER at any hospital in the first 30 post-operative days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient quality of recovery</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Recovery 15 (QoR-15) questionnaire administered to patients in both groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient self-efficacy to manage one's own health care</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after hospital discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Activation Measure (PAM-13) administered to patients in both groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">670</enrollment>
  <condition>Colorectal Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention group will receive the same usual care as the control group plus be enrolled in the integrated discharge monitoring system.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will receive usual follow up care that is currently provided at the 3 participating centres.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mobile App</intervention_name>
    <description>The app will be provided to patients in hospital on post-operative day 3. On the day of discharge, the patient will be emailed a &quot;Daily Health Check&quot; and receive subsequent &quot;Daily Health Check&quot; emails on Day 1-14, 21 and 30 days following discharge. The &quot;Daily Health Check&quot; is a tailored questionnaire to elicit their symptoms and status of post-operative recovery. After the patient has completed the &quot;Daily Health Check&quot;, a &quot;Daily Health Check Summary&quot; is emailed to the patient that summarizes their responses and provides appropriate action recommendations based on their responses ranging from: (i) suggestions for educational modules, (ii) expect a call from your health care team in the next 24 hours, (iii) call your surgeon's office today or (iv) go to the nearest emergency room. The patient's &quot;Daily Health Check&quot; responses are displayed in real time on a secure website that automatically &quot;red flags&quot; extreme responses to alert the health care team to contact the patient by telephone.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any patient who is being discharged to home after undergoing elective colorectal&#xD;
             surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to speak and understand English or French&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  provides informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  post-operative admission less than 3 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  requiring discharge to rehabilitation centre to recover prior to being able to go home&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erin Kennedy</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MOUNT SINAI HOSPITAL</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Selina Research Coordinator</last_name>
    <phone>416-586-4800</phone>
    <email>selina.schmocker@sinaihealth.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Selina Research Coordinator</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 17, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mount Sinai Hospital, Canada</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Erin Kennedy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Colorectal Surgeon (Principal Investigator)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

