<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04239937</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SJ-800</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04239937</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Insulin Resistance in Stress-metabolic Medical Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Insulin Resistance in Stress-metabolic Medical Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Slagelse Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Slagelse Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An observational study on the insulin resistance in sepsis and septic shock patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This observational study is inspired by the short-term insulin resistance and hyperglycemia&#xD;
      that have been demonstrated in post-operative patients in response to tissue injury by Van&#xD;
      den Berghe et al 2001. This short-term insulin resistance and hyperglycemia have also been&#xD;
      observed in acutely ill patients (Van den Berghe et al 2006). The underlying mechanism for&#xD;
      why acute ill patients have short-term insulin resistance is still unclear, but it is&#xD;
      believed that the basic mechanism is increased glucose regeneration and gluconeogenesis,&#xD;
      which is the consequence of stress metabolism. Hyperglycemia can occur as a result of insulin&#xD;
      resistance and is associated with an increased risk of multiple complications, which is why&#xD;
      it is important to detect and treat (Van den Berghe et al 2001). This also means that the&#xD;
      more insulin-resistant the patient has been prior to the acute condition, the greater the&#xD;
      risk of elevated blood glucose concentrations. PRS Review Comments identify apparent errors,&#xD;
      deficiencies, or inconsistencies in the submitted information. Any comments provided should&#xD;
      not be considered comprehensive. Advisory comments noted in a previous version of a study&#xD;
      record may apply to subsequent versions, even if not repeated. It is the responsibility of&#xD;
      the data provider to ensure that the record is consistent with the ClinicalTrials.gov Review&#xD;
      Criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to clarify the degree of insulin resistance in medical patients who&#xD;
      are not diagnosed with diabetes. Further it will be clarified how long these patients remain&#xD;
      insulin resistant after discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The acute medical patients diagnosed with sepsis or septic shock will be observed during&#xD;
      hospitalization and after discharge. Sepsis is defined as life-threatening organ dysfunction&#xD;
      caused by dysregulated host response to infection. Because the entire body is affected by an&#xD;
      infection, it is expected that this group of patients have a high level of stress metabolism,&#xD;
      insulin resistance and increased gluconeogenesis. The hypothesis is that acute medical&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with sepsis or septic shock have a level of insulin resistance (days to&#xD;
      weeks) and thus an increased risk of hyperglycemia. Insulin resistance is expected to&#xD;
      decrease as the patient's condition improves.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with elevated infection levels (CRP and leukocyte count) who are simultaneously&#xD;
      diagnosed with sepsis, has peripheral insulin resistance due to stress metabolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pancreas will try to compensate for the peripheral insulin resistance by increasing its&#xD;
      secretion of insulin to the bloodstream. C-peptide is excreted in equimolar amounts to&#xD;
      insulin, thereby C-peptide becomes an expression of peripheral insulin resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is assumed that the insulin resistance gradually decreases after discharge and further as&#xD;
      the patient's condition improves (CRP and leukocyte counts).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study design is a prospective follow-up study. The difference in C-peptide will be&#xD;
      observed over a time period of 28 days as an expression of the participant's insulin&#xD;
      secretion. Futher, the participants' blood glucose will also be observed continuously to find&#xD;
      the correlation between the degree of insulin resistance and glucose concentration. In&#xD;
      addition, measure the correlation between the degree of infection and the increase in&#xD;
      C-peptide concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is the change in C-peptide (the difference between the maximum&#xD;
      concentration and the concentration after 28 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The area under the curve for blood glucose level measured over 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Correlation of infection level (CRP/leukocyte count) and increase in C-peptide&#xD;
           concentration (dose-response).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Correlation between infection rate and insulin resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients admitted to the hospital with sepsis or septic shock can be recruited. Patients will&#xD;
      be followed for 28 days from admission. The patients will be applied to a continuous flash&#xD;
      glucose monitor (FGM) on the first day. Follow-up will be performed by blood sampling of&#xD;
      C-peptide, leukocyte count, and CRP. HbA1c will also be measured for the exclusion of&#xD;
      diabetes. Blood sampling will be taken both during hospitalization and after discharge.&#xD;
      C-peptide will be measured every second day during hospitalization and leukocyte count and&#xD;
      CRP will be measured every day during hospitalization. Reading of FGM will be performed on&#xD;
      the 14. and on the 28. day where blood sampling of C-peptide, leukocyte count, and CRP also&#xD;
      will be measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 18, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 27, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 27, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>C-peptide</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in C-peptide over time</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood glucose level</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The area under the curve for blood glucose level measured over 28 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infection level and C-peptide concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of infection level (CRP/leukocyte count) and increase in C-peptide concentration (dose-response).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between infection rate and insulin resistance.</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between infection rate and insulin resistance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Septic Shock</condition>
  <condition>Sepsis</condition>
  <condition>Insulin Resistance</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Sepsis or septic shock patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with sepsis or septic shock who are admitted to the emergency ward and&#xD;
             subsequently transferred to an intensive, intermediate or medical ward at Slagelse&#xD;
             Hospital. Patients are diagnosed with sepsis or septic shock based on screening using&#xD;
             Sequential (sepsis-related) Organ Failure Assessment (SOFA) or Quick SOFA (qSOFA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be of legal age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with diabetes (T1DM or T2DM)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with terminal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are already participating in a trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who do not understand and speak danish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are demented&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postoperative patients &lt;1 month after surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are going through dialysis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah Duncan</last_name>
    <phone>0045 61705065</phone>
    <email>duncans@duncans.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Peter Gæde</last_name>
    <email>phgo@regionsjaelland.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Slagelse Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Slagelse</city>
        <zip>4200</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sarah Duncan</last_name>
      <phone>004561705065</phone>
      <email>duncans@duncans.dk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Peter Gæde</last_name>
      <email>phgo@regionsjaelland.dk</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>November 13, 2020</submitted>
    <returned>December 8, 2020</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

