<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04100811</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MIR-P001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04100811</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Identification of Clinically Insignificant or Significant Prostate Cancer With the miR Scientific Sentinel™ Platform</brief_title>
  <official_title>Validating the miR Scientific Sentinel™ Platform (Sentinel PCC4 Assay) in Men Undergoing Core Needle Biopsy Due to Suspicion of Prostate Cancer for Distinguishing Between no Cancer, Low-, Intermediate- and High-Risk Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>miR Scientific LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>miR Scientific LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this non-interventional study, men being seen by urologists in the course of their normal&#xD;
      practice that present with clinical suspicion of prostate cancer (based on DRE, elevated&#xD;
      Prostate Specific Antigen (PSA), and/or family medical history of prostate cancer, among&#xD;
      other reasons) and who meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria will be asked to consent to the&#xD;
      clinical study and provide a 40-60 mL urine sample, without prior DRE, along with relevant&#xD;
      de-identified clinical data, at the time of the initial consultation, prior to core-needle&#xD;
      biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The miR Scientific Sentinel® Prostate Cancer Classifier Platform (Sentinel® PCC4 Test) is a&#xD;
      new molecular test that interrogates 442 small non-coding RNAs (sncRNA) extracted from&#xD;
      urinary exosomes. Using the expression levels of 442 sncRNAs isolated from urine exosomes,&#xD;
      the Sentinel® PCC4 Test provides an initial classification of disease status as either no&#xD;
      molecular evidence of prostate cancer (NMEPC), or molecular evidence (MEPC) of low-,&#xD;
      intermediate- or high-risk of aggressive prostate cancer. This study is designed to validate&#xD;
      the classification algorithm and finalize the performance characteristics of the Test using&#xD;
      risk-group labeling based on pathological grading from core-needle biopsy data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The miR Scientific Sentinel® Prostate Cancer Classifier Platform (Sentinel® PCC4 Test) is a&#xD;
      new molecular test that interrogates 442 small non-coding RNAs extracted from urinary&#xD;
      exosomes. The Sentinel® PCC4 Test provides urologists with an early, non-invasive and precise&#xD;
      indication of disease status in men presenting with clinical suspicion of prostate cancer.&#xD;
      The test provides an initial classification of disease status as either no molecular evidence&#xD;
      of prostate cancer (NMEPC), or molecular evidence (MEPC) of low-, intermediate- or high-risk&#xD;
      of aggressive prostate cancer. The current standard of care (SOC) assesses the risk of&#xD;
      prostate cancer based on information that includes a suspicious DRE, and &quot;elevated&quot; serum PSA&#xD;
      (commonly greater than 3ng/mL based on the current NCCN guidelines, but in clinical practice&#xD;
      can frequently be less than or greater than 3ng/mL, depending on the practice). The estimated&#xD;
      sensitivity (44%) and specificity (68%) of the current SOC means that a significant portion&#xD;
      of prostate cancer cases are not identified, and many biopsies with resulting co-morbidities&#xD;
      are unnecessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who enroll in this study will receive the current SOC and have a TRUS- or MRI-guided&#xD;
      fusion core needle biopsy. Biopsies will be read by pathologists associated with each&#xD;
      participating clinical institution at which the biopsy was performed. The Gleason score,&#xD;
      tumor staging, and anatomic location for each positive core will be collected at each site,&#xD;
      and barcoded urine samples will be couriered overnight to the miR Scientific laboratories for&#xD;
      Sentinel® PCC4 Test analysis. To minimize the potential for inter-observer variability, the&#xD;
      pathology of the core needle biopsies for each patient will also be reviewed by an&#xD;
      independent central pathologist, not associated with miR Scientific.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After assessing the pathology, anatomic contribution and additional clinical data&#xD;
      (particularly DRE and serum PSA levels) that inform Grade Group assessment and the NCCN risk&#xD;
      assessment, the final risk group assessment for both Primary Study Objective #1 and Primary&#xD;
      Study Objective #2 will be determined by the pathologist. The final risk group determination&#xD;
      for each patient will be used individually to represent the risk status provided by the&#xD;
      current SOC for comparison to the molecular classifications provided by the Sentinel® PCC4&#xD;
      Test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The performance of the Sentinel® PCC4 Test to classify the disease status of a future patient&#xD;
      (with unknown true disease status) as either no molecular evidence of prostate cancer or, for&#xD;
      patients with molecular evidence of prostate cancer, as having low-risk, intermediate-risk or&#xD;
      high-risk of aggressive prostate cancer will be established for both Primary Study&#xD;
      Objectives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Study Objective #1: To establish the performance characteristics of the Sentinel®&#xD;
      Prostate Cancer Classifier Platform (Sentinel® PCC4 Test) using pathological grading (Grade&#xD;
      Grouping based on Gleason score as proposed by Epstein and colleagues in 2013) as the&#xD;
      comparative basis for assessing the prostate health of men aged 45-75 years presenting with&#xD;
      suspicion of prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The performance characteristics of the Sentinel® PCC4 Test as described via the Primary Study&#xD;
      Objectives will be assessed in comparison to core needle biopsy report using pathology&#xD;
      Gleason score grading (Grade Group) risk classifiers where GG1 is indicative or low-risk, GG2&#xD;
      as intermediate risk and GG3-5 as high-risk of aggressive prostate cancer. The sensitivity,&#xD;
      specificity, positive and negative predictive values of the Sentinel® PCC4 Test for&#xD;
      risk-classification in concordance with the GG-risk assessment will be established.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Study Objective #2: To establish the performance characteristics of the Sentinel®&#xD;
      PCC4 Test when using the modified risk assessment criteria recently recommended by the&#xD;
      National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) as the basis for assessing the prostate health&#xD;
      of men aged 45-75 years presenting with suspicion of prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the pathological grade of the tumor, the NCCN risk assessment incorporates&#xD;
      additional clinical measures associated with tumor progression, including number of positive&#xD;
      cores, percent tumor involvement per core, tumor stage (anatomical location of positive&#xD;
      cores), serum PSA and PSA density. The same molecular expression data from the Sentine® PCC4&#xD;
      Test will be used to evaluate both Primary Objectives for each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Methodology: This study will enroll patients visiting urology clinics for initial&#xD;
      clinical workup based on any clinical suspicion of prostate cancer. The study will evaluate&#xD;
      the properties of the Sentinel® PCC4 Test that is based on use of a proprietary&#xD;
      classification system to identify patients with no molecular evidence of prostate cancer and&#xD;
      to initially classify the risk of prostate cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For a given two-group comparison, the proprietary Classification Algorithm controls&#xD;
      sensitivity for a patient with unknown true disease status at or above a pre-specified level,&#xD;
      denoted 1-α; for example, the value that has been assumed in this design is α=0.05. Note that&#xD;
      the value of α represents the false-negative rate of the test for the given two-group&#xD;
      comparison.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The initial nominal labeling of clinical groups will be done separately when using the&#xD;
      Gleason Grade group (Primary Study Objective #1) and recent NCCN definitions (Primary Study&#xD;
      Objective #2) as described in detail above. Cross-validation will be used in the training&#xD;
      dataset to determine the classification cut-offs for a given two-group comparison in the&#xD;
      Sentinel® PCC4 Test. A general description of this procedure is as follows. For each&#xD;
      participant in the training dataset (current participant), a two-group classification for&#xD;
      this current participant will be determined based on the remaining members of the training&#xD;
      dataset using only the current participant's sncRNA sequence; the accuracy of this&#xD;
      determination will be assessed by comparison of the group classification determined to the&#xD;
      actual label given to the current participant (either Grade Group or NCCN group). That is,&#xD;
      the disease status label of the current participant in the training dataset will be blinded,&#xD;
      thereby mimicking the setting for classification of a future patient. This procedure is then&#xD;
      repeated separately for each subject in the training dataset. The tuning parameters and&#xD;
      cutoff boundary used for each of the two-group classifications comprising the Sentinel® PCC4&#xD;
      Test are then calculated so that the empirical sensitivity over participants in the training&#xD;
      dataset is at least 1-α.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With these cut-offs and classification rules determined using the training dataset for the&#xD;
      Sentinel® PCC4 Test, the Sentinel® PCC4 classifications for each member of the validation&#xD;
      dataset will be determined using only information generated from their expression levels of&#xD;
      the sncRNA sequences; the corresponding results will be stored in a date-stamped, locked file&#xD;
      as described above. The clinical risk group for each member of the validation dataset as&#xD;
      determined by the central pathologist will also be stored in a locked and date-stamped file.&#xD;
      When both files are completed, they will be released to the miR Scientific team and the&#xD;
      performance characteristics of the Sentinel® PCC4 Test established in the validation dataset;&#xD;
      note that these error rates refer to the classification of a future patient with unknown&#xD;
      disease status.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Validate the performance characteristics of the miR Sentinel® PCC4 Test to classify subjects into low-risk, intermediate-risk, high-risk, or no molecular evidence of prostate cancer using risk-group labeling based on pathological grading</measure>
    <time_frame>Urine samples will be collected from participants at the time of entry and processed within 72 hours upon receipt for the miR Sentinel PCC4 Assay interrogation.</time_frame>
    <description>The Sentinel® PCC4 Test is a urine exosome-based test that provides a molecular assessment of prostate cancer risk, for the diagnosis and prognosis that can be used for the management of prostate cancer. The test measures the levels of 442 small non-coding RNAs (sncRNAs) that include a mix of microRNAs (miRNAs) and small nucleolar RNA (snoRNAs). Because the false-negative rate of core-needle biopsy is generally thought to be in the range of at least 10-15%, the maximum achievable apparent specificity for diagnosing prostate cancer when using core needle biopsy pathology as the basis to assess prostate health may be at most 85-90%. We expect that with 1500 subjects enrolled, 630 (42%) will be biopsy negative with no pathological evidence of prostate cancer (NPEPC); 420 (28%) will be GG1; 195 (13%) will be GG2 and 255 (17%) will be GG3-GG5.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Validate the performance characteristics of the miR Sentinel® PCC4 Test to classify subjects into low-risk, intermediate-risk, high-risk, or no molecular evidence of prostate cancer using risk-group labeling based on NCCN risk assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Urine samples will be collected from participants at the time of entry and processed within 72 hours upon receipt for the miR Sentinel PCC4 Assay interrogation.</time_frame>
    <description>In addition to the pathological grade of the tumor, the NCCN risk assessment incorporates additional clinical measures associated with tumor progression, including number of positive cores, percent tumor involvement per core, tumor stage (anatomical location of positive cores), serum PSA and PSA density. The same molecular expression data from the Sentine® PCC4 Test will be used to evaluate b for each patient.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">4000</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Urine for Sentinel™ PCC4 Assay&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Up to 4000 male participants will be enrolled from multi clinical sites in the U.S. and&#xD;
        Canada. Participants will be men ages 45 and above with a core needle biopsy as part of&#xD;
        routine clinical workup for diagnosis of prostate cancer.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males ≥ 45 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Males with clinical suspicion of prostate cancer, including but not limited to&#xD;
             elevated PSA level, suspicious DRE, family history of prostate cancer, and/or germline&#xD;
             mutation, who as a result undergo TRUS- or MRI-guided core-needle biopsy and PSA&#xD;
             recording (for NCCN group label).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Signed informed consent prior to initiation of any study-related procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient provided a voided urine sample within 30 days prior to biopsy being&#xD;
             performed and prior to DRE (if any). This collection must be ≥ 1 hour after the last&#xD;
             urination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Persons previously diagnosed with prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Persons who have previously undergone a 12 core or fusion biopsy in the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Persons who have had a DRE within 72 hours of the urine collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Persons incapable of providing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Persons presenting with clinical symptoms of urinary tract infection, including&#xD;
             prostatitis at the time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Persons with prior history of invasive treatment for benign prostatic hyperplasia&#xD;
             within 3-6 months of study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients treated with a 5-alpha-reductase inhibitor, Saw Palmetto for BPH or male&#xD;
             pattern baldness within 3 months of the urine collection.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Only males get prostate cancer</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carl A Olsson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Integrated Medical Professionals</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chief Scientific Officier, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>(518) 763-3779</phone>
    <email>martin.tenniswood@mirscientific.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Director of Research, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>(518) 772-7792</phone>
    <email>winnie.wang@mirscientific.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Georgia Urology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30328</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniel Canter, MD</last_name>
      <phone>404-292-3727</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urology of Greater Atlanta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockbridge</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30281</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>James M Libby, MD</last_name>
      <phone>770-474-5281</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Integrated Medical Professionals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Farmingdale</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11735</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carl A Olsson, MD</last_name>
      <phone>516-456-9731</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 19, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 20, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

