<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04946370</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-08022500</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04946370</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maximizing Responses to Anti-PD1 Immunotherapy With PSMA-targeted Alpha Therapy in mCRPC</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Trial of Pembrolizumab and Androgen-receptor Pathway Inhibitor With or Without 225Ac-J591 for Progressive Metastatic Castration Resistant Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I/II study investigating the combination of 225Ac-J591 (a drug that can&#xD;
      deliver radiation to prostate cancer cells) with pembrolizumab (immunotherapy, a drug that&#xD;
      increases the immune system's ability to destroy cancer cells). This study will assess&#xD;
      whether 225Ac-J591 + pembrolizumab + androgen receptor pathway inhibitor (ARPI) is more&#xD;
      effective against prostate cancer than pembrolizumab + ARPI alone.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial is for men with progressive metastatic castration-resistant prostate&#xD;
      cancer (mCRPC). The primary objectives of the study are to determine the optimal dose of&#xD;
      225Ac-J591 when combined with pembrolizumab (phase I) and then to assess whether the&#xD;
      combination of 225Ac-J591, pembrolizumab, and androgen receptor pathway inhibitor (ARPI) is&#xD;
      more effective against prostate cancer than pembrolizumab and ARPI alone. 225Ac-J591 is a&#xD;
      radionuclide conjugate involving Actinium-225 linked to J591, an antibody that recognizes&#xD;
      prostate-specific membrane antigen (PSMA) on the surface of cancer cells; 225Ac-J591 is able&#xD;
      to deliver powerful radiation to cancer cells. Pembrolizumab is a drug that strengthens the&#xD;
      body's immune response to cancer cells. In the phase I portion of the study, two cohorts of&#xD;
      up to 6 patients each will receive combined therapy: ARPI (standard dosing schedule),&#xD;
      pembrolizumab (400 mg every 6 weeks), 225Ac-J591 (single dose, either 65 or 90 KBq/kg).&#xD;
      Following a minimum of 12 weeks of safety follow-up, the study team will determine which&#xD;
      225Ac-J591 dose is better. In the phase II portion, patients will be randomized to&#xD;
      pembrolizumab + ARPI with or without 225Ac-J591. The primary endpoint for phase II will be&#xD;
      response - a composite of PSA, circulating tumor cell (CTC) count, and imaging changes.&#xD;
      Patients who achieve at least one of the criteria will be considered responders. Imaging (CT&#xD;
      scan, bone scan) will occur every 12 weeks. Additionally, participants will undergo&#xD;
      68Ga-PSMA-11 PET/CT scan prior to therapy and at 12 weeks. Patients are able to receive&#xD;
      pembrolizumab every 6 weeks for maximum 18 cycles (approximately 2 years).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>In the phase I portion of the study, patients will receive 225Ac-J591 at either 65 or 90 KBq/kg, in addition to pembrolizumab and ARPI. In the subsequent phase II portion of the study, patients will be randomized to receive 225Ac-J591 (at the dose determined in phase I) + ARPI and pembrolizumab or ARPI and pembrolizumab alone in a 1:1 ratio. Randomization will take into account prior receipt of ARPI, baseline PSMA imaging intensity, and presence of visceral metastasis.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients with dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) following treatment with pembrolizumab and 225Ac-J591</measure>
    <time_frame>From visit 1 through 12 weeks on study</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome for phase I; DLTs will be measured by utilizing the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0. There will be 12 weeks of safety follow-up following visit 1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determination of optimal dose of 225Ac-J591 for phase II</measure>
    <time_frame>From visit 1 through 12 weeks on study</time_frame>
    <description>Primary outcome for phase I; following 12 weeks of safety follow-up, the study team will make a determination of the 225Ac-J591 dose for phase II (either 65 or 90 KBq/kg).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in composite response rate of pembrolizumab and ARPI with or without 225Ac-J591</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be collected at the time of visit 1 and up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome for phase II will be response, a composite of: PSA decline greater than 50% of baseline, measurable disease response by imaging criteria, conversion of circulating tumor cell count to favorable or undetectable.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in overall survival following treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Survival will be collected from Day 1 and up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival will be captured through in-clinic or telephone contact with subjects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in biochemical progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be collected at the time of visit 1 and up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>PSA progression will be defined as a rise of &gt; 25% above either the pretreatment level or the nadir PSA level (whichever is lowest). PSA must increase by &gt; 2 ng/ml to be considered progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in radiographic progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Patients will undergo imaging at screening and then every 12 weeks, for up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>Response evaluation criteria in solid tumors RECIST (Version 1.1) criteria with prostate cancer working group 3 (PCWG3) modifications will be used.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportion with 1-year progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be collected at the time of visit 1 through 1 year on study</time_frame>
    <description>By imaging (RECIST 1.1 criteria with prostate cancer working group 3 modifications) or biochemical (PSA) criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportion with &gt;30% PSA decline</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be collected at the time of visit 1 and up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline (pre-treatment) PSA levels will be compared to PSA nadir on study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportion with &gt;50% PSA decline</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be collected at the time of visit 1 and up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline (pre-treatment) PSA levels will be compared to PSA nadir on study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportion with &gt;90% PSA decline</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be collected at the time of visit 1 and up to 100 months</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline (pre-treatment) PSA levels will be compared to PSA nadir on study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">76</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + 225Ac-J591 + ARPI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive one dose of 225Ac-J591 (single dose, either 65 or 90 Kbq/kg) in combination with pembrolizumab (400mg every 6 weeks) and ARPI (standard dose schedule, examples of ARPI include enzalutamide and apalutamide).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + ARPI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive pembrolizumab (400mg every 6 weeks) and ARPI (standard dose schedule) without 225Ac-J591.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>225Ac-J591</intervention_name>
    <description>Alpha-emitter Actinium-225 conjugated to the anti-PSMA antibody J591.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + 225Ac-J591 + ARPI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab will be administered intravenously, 400mg every 6 weeks. Patients may receive maximum 18 cycles of therapy, approximately 2 years.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + 225Ac-J591 + ARPI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + ARPI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Androgen receptor pathway inhibitor</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive an oral androgen receptor pathway inhibitor (ARPI). Examples include enzalutamide and apalutamide. Dosing will be the standard dosing, as described by the package insert.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + 225Ac-J591 + ARPI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + ARPI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>68Ga-PSMA-11</intervention_name>
    <description>[185 ±74 MBq or 5 ±2 mCi] intravenous during screening and 12 weeks. Imaging agent for PSMA PET/CT.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + 225Ac-J591 + ARPI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab + ARPI</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>68Ga-PSMA-HBED-CC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants who are at least 18 years of age on the day of signing informed&#xD;
             consent with histologically confirmed diagnosis of prostate adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A male participant must agree to use a contraception during the treatment period and&#xD;
             for at least 4 months after the last dose of study treatment and refrain from donating&#xD;
             sperm during this period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented progressive metastatic CRPC based on Prostate Cancer Working Group 3&#xD;
             (PCWG3) criteria, which includes at least one of the following criteria: PSA&#xD;
             progression, Objective radiographic progression in soft tissue, New bone lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status of 0-1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have serum testosterone &lt; 50 ng/dL. Subjects must continue primary androgen&#xD;
             deprivation with an LHRH/GnRH analogue (agonist/antagonist) if they have not undergone&#xD;
             orchiectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have previously been treated with at least one of the following in any disease state:&#xD;
             Androgen receptor signaling inhibitor (such as enzalutamide), CYP 17 inhibitor (such&#xD;
             as abiraterone acetate). These drugs may have been initiated in the metastatic hormone&#xD;
             sensitive or non-metastatic (M0) CRPC setting provided they meet criteria for&#xD;
             progressive mCRPC at study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have normal organ and marrow function as defined: Absolute neutrophil&#xD;
             count &gt;2,000 cells/mm3, Hemoglobin ≥9 g/dL, Platelet count &gt;150,000 x 109/mcL, Serum&#xD;
             creatinine &lt;1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) or calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 50&#xD;
             mL/min/1.73 m2 by Cockcroft-Gault, Serum total bilirubin &lt;1.5 x ULN (unless due to&#xD;
             Gilbert's syndrome in which case direct bilirubin must be normal), Serum AST and ALT&#xD;
             &lt;3 x ULN in absence of liver metastases; &lt; 5x ULN if due to liver metastases (in both&#xD;
             circumstances bilirubin must meet entry criteria), Serum internalized normalized ratio&#xD;
             (INR) OR prothrombin time (PT) AND activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) must&#xD;
             be &lt;1.5 x ULN unless participant is receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or&#xD;
             aPTT is within therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior receipt of chemotherapy for castration-resistant prostate cancer. Prior receipt&#xD;
             of docetaxel chemotherapy in the hormone sensitive setting or for localized disease is&#xD;
             acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior therapy with an anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, or anti PD L2 agent or with&#xD;
             an agent directed to another stimulatory or co-inhibitory T-cell receptor (eg, CTLA-4,&#xD;
             OX 40, CD137).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years&#xD;
             (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             drugs). Replacement therapy (eg., thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid&#xD;
             replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a&#xD;
             form of systemic treatment and is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior bone-seeking beta-emitting radioisotopes (e.g. Sm-153, Sr-89) or investigational&#xD;
             PSMA-targeted therapy; prior radium-223 is allowed provided last dose administered &gt;12&#xD;
             weeks prior to C1D1 on this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of a second malignancy, unless potentially curative treatment has been&#xD;
             completed with no evidence of malignancy for 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of myelodysplastic syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of Hepatitis B (defined as Hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg]&#xD;
             reactive) or known active Hepatitis C virus (defined as HCV RNA [qualitative] is&#xD;
             detected) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving chronic systemic steroid therapy&#xD;
             (in dosing exceeding 10 mg daily of prednisone equivalent) or any other form of&#xD;
             immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational&#xD;
             agent or has used an investigational device within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior systemic anti-cancer therapy including investigational agents&#xD;
             within 4 weeks or &lt;5 half-lives prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known active CNS metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis. Participants with&#xD;
             previously treated brain metastases may participate provided they are radiologically&#xD;
             stable, i.e. without evidence of progression for at least 4 weeks by repeat imaging&#xD;
             (note that the repeat imaging should be performed during study screening), clinically&#xD;
             stable and without requirement of steroid treatment for at least 14 days prior to&#xD;
             first dose of study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of deep vein thrombosis and/or pulmonary embolus within 1 month of C1D1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality&#xD;
             that might confound the results of the study, interfere with the subject's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the study, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the subject to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received radiotherapy within 4 weeks of start of study treatment. Participants&#xD;
             must have recovered from all radiation-related toxicities, not require&#xD;
             corticosteroids, and not have had radiation pneumonitis. A 1-week washout is permitted&#xD;
             for palliative radiation (≤2 weeks of radiotherapy) to non-CNS disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on stable dose of bisphosphonates or denosumab, which have been started no&#xD;
             less than 4 weeks prior to treatment start, may continue on this medication, however&#xD;
             patients are not allowed to initiate bisphosphonate/Denosumab therapy during the&#xD;
             DLT-assessment period of the study. These drugs may be added after week 12.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unless azoospermia is present (whether due to surgery or underlying medical&#xD;
             condition), having partners of childbearing potential and not willing to use a method&#xD;
             of birth control deemed acceptable by the principal investigator and chairperson&#xD;
             during the study and for 4 months after last study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is expecting to conceive or father children within the projected duration of the&#xD;
             study, starting with the screening visit through 120 days after the last dose of trial&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days. Examples of live vaccines include, but are&#xD;
             not limited to, the following: measles, mumps, rubella, varicella/zoster (chicken&#xD;
             pox), yellow fever, rabies, Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG), and typhoid vaccine.&#xD;
             Seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are generally killed virus vaccines and are&#xD;
             allowed; however, intranasal influenza vaccines (eg, FluMist®) are live attenuated&#xD;
             vaccines and are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has severe hypersensitivity (≥Grade 3) to pembrolizumab and/or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or has current&#xD;
             pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy at the time of treatment initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known psychiatric or substance abuse disorders that would interfere with&#xD;
             cooperation with the requirements of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had an allogenic tissue/solid organ transplant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Metastatic Castrate Resistant Prostate Cancer</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Scott Tagawa, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Weill Medical College of Cornell University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>GUONC Research Team</last_name>
    <phone>212-746-1480</phone>
    <email>guonc@med.cornell.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Himisha Beltran, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Presbyterian/Brooklyn Methodist Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brooklyn</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Peter Gregos, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New York Presbyterian/Weill Cornell Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>GUOnc Research Team</last_name>
      <email>guonc@med.cornell.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Scott Tagawa, MD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Irving Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matthew Dallos, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Edetic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Androgens</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gallium 68 PSMA-11</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

