<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04943198</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BRAVO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04943198</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Optimization of the Time and Dosage of Vemurafenib in BRAF Positive Juvenile Patients With Refractory Histiocytosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>BRAVO</acronym>
  <official_title>Optimization of the Time and Dosage of Vemurafenib in BRAF Positive Juvenile Patients With Refractory Histiocytosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Anna Raciborska</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Maria Sklodowska-Curie Institute - Oncology Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Łukasiewicz Research Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wrocław University of Environmental and Life Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institute of Mother and Child, Warsaw, Poland</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prospective, interventional, open, randomized, single-center, non-commercial clinical trial&#xD;
      to optimize treatment and dosage of vemurafenib in juvenile patients with histiocytosis&#xD;
      resistant to conventional therapy and in whom the BRAF gene mutation has been found.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BRAVO clinical study is part of the POL HISTIO project. The POL HISTIO project is a&#xD;
      non-commercial clinical trial aimed at optimizing the diagnosis and treatment of juvenile&#xD;
      patients with histiocytosis. The project objectives are defined as follows: 1) to estimate&#xD;
      the nature and frequency of mutations in patients with histiocytosis in both tumor tissues&#xD;
      and free-circulating DNA; 2) to compare molecular test results with clinical data; 3) to&#xD;
      evaluate the diagnostic usefulness of the status of molecular analysis (MRD) as a prognostic&#xD;
      factor compared with other recognized factors; 4) in the case of failure of conventional&#xD;
      therapy - to modify treatment and to apply targeted treatment, based on molecular status of&#xD;
      gene mutation. The project is intended to include patients from all over Poland.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 23, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>event-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Event-free survival (EFS) was defined as the time interval from the date of diagnosis to the date of disease progression, recurrence, second malignancy, death or to date of last follow-up for patients without events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Molecular relapse (in ct DNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Molecular relapse was defined as the time interval from the date of BRAF negativization to the date of positive results of BRAF mutation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to negative mutation test results (in ct DNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time to negative mutation test results (in ct DNA) was defined as the time interval from the date of positive BRAF mutation to the date of negative results of BRAF mutation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Histiocytosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>R1 time of vemurafenib treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>vemurafenib will be given to 6 months after BRAF negativization</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>R2 time of vemurafenib treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>vemurafenib will be given to 12 months after BRAF negativization</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vemurafenib</intervention_name>
    <description>20 mg/kg/day</description>
    <arm_group_label>R1 time of vemurafenib treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>R2 time of vemurafenib treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The presence of mutations in the BRAF gene in tumor tissues and/or in ctDNA at any&#xD;
             stage of treatment or follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Failure of the treatment (at least one of below needs to apply in order for this&#xD;
             requirement to be satisfied):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Progression on the I and II line treatment, and involving of a minimum one risk&#xD;
                  organ; previous treatment should include a minimum of 6 weeks of weekly&#xD;
                  Vinblastine with a minimum of 28 days prednisolone or minimum 2 cycles of&#xD;
                  Cytosine Arabinoside in 4-day cycles and/or Cladribine in 5-day cycles as a&#xD;
                  treatment of 2 line, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Disease reactivation after an initial response to treatment with Vimblastine and&#xD;
                  prednisolone as the first line and no response to treatment of the second line&#xD;
                  using a minimum of 2 cycles of one of two drugs: Cytosine Arabinoside in 4-day&#xD;
                  cycles and/or Cladribine in 5-day cycles as a treatment of 2 line and the&#xD;
                  involving of a minimum one risk organ, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Third or subsequent reactivation of disease with or without risk organ&#xD;
                  involvement, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Reactivation of disease after Vemurafenib therapy has been completed, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The appearance of signs of neurodegenerative disorder (ND) in MRI of the CNS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Signing of informed consent for trial participation (including for Vemurafenib&#xD;
             treatment) according with current legal regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Consent to the use of effective contraception throughout the Vemurafenib&#xD;
             administration period and a minimum of 1 year after discontinuation in patients at&#xD;
             puberty and sexual maturity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participation in HISTIOGEN trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Lack of inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnancy and breastfeeding .&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hypersensitivity to the study drug or any of its ingredients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Iritis, uveitis, obstruction of the retinal veins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Simultaneous treatment with other drugs which might interact with Vemurafenib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Persistent toxicity related to prior therapy, making it impossible to treat with&#xD;
             Vemurafenib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Diagnosis of other malignancies before study inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Other acute or persistent disorders, behaviors or abnormal laboratory test results,&#xD;
             which might increase the risk related to the participation in this clinical trial or&#xD;
             to taking the study drug, or which might influence the interpretation of the study&#xD;
             results, or which, in the investigator's opinion, disqualify a patient from&#xD;
             participating in the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anna Raciborska</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mother and Child Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Katarzyna Maleszewska</last_name>
    <phone>+48 22 32 77 205</phone>
    <email>klinika.onkologii@imid.med.pl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mother and Child Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Warsaw</city>
        <state>Mazovian</state>
        <zip>01-211</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Katarzyna Maleszewska</last_name>
      <phone>+48 22 32 77 205</phone>
      <email>klinika.onkologii@imid.med.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Raciborska</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Badalian-Very G, Vergilio JA, Degar BA, MacConaill LE, Brandner B, Calicchio ML, Kuo FC, Ligon AH, Stevenson KE, Kehoe SM, Garraway LA, Hahn WC, Meyerson M, Fleming MD, Rollins BJ. Recurrent BRAF mutations in Langerhans cell histiocytosis. Blood. 2010 Sep 16;116(11):1919-23. doi: 10.1182/blood-2010-04-279083. Epub 2010 Jun 2.</citation>
    <PMID>20519626</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cardoso E, Mercier T, Wagner AD, Homicsko K, Michielin O, Ellefsen-Lavoie K, Cagnon L, Diezi M, Buclin T, Widmer N, Csajka C, Decosterd L. Quantification of the next-generation oral anti-tumor drugs dabrafenib, trametinib, vemurafenib, cobimetinib, pazopanib, regorafenib and two metabolites in human plasma by liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry. J Chromatogr B Analyt Technol Biomed Life Sci. 2018 Apr 15;1083:124-136. doi: 10.1016/j.jchromb.2018.02.008. Epub 2018 Feb 8.</citation>
    <PMID>29544202</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Donadieu J, Larabi IA, Tardieu M, Visser J, Hutter C, Sieni E, Kabbara N, Barkaoui M, Miron J, Chalard F, Milne P, Haroche J, Cohen F, Hélias-Rodzewicz Z, Simon N, Jehanne M, Kolenova A, Pagnier A, Aladjidi N, Schneider P, Plat G, Lutun A, Sonntagbauer A, Lehrnbecher T, Ferster A, Efremova V, Ahlmann M, Blanc L, Nicholson J, Lambilliote A, Boudiaf H, Lissat A, Svojgr K, Bernard F, Elitzur S, Golan M, Evseev D, Maschan M, Idbaih A, Slater O, Minkov M, Taly V, Collin M, Alvarez JC, Emile JF, Héritier S. Vemurafenib for Refractory Multisystem Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis in Children: An International Observational Study. J Clin Oncol. 2019 Nov 1;37(31):2857-2865. doi: 10.1200/JCO.19.00456. Epub 2019 Sep 12.</citation>
    <PMID>31513482</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Haroche J, Cohen-Aubart F, Emile JF, Arnaud L, Maksud P, Charlotte F, Cluzel P, Drier A, Hervier B, Benameur N, Besnard S, Donadieu J, Amoura Z. Dramatic efficacy of vemurafenib in both multisystemic and refractory Erdheim-Chester disease and Langerhans cell histiocytosis harboring the BRAF V600E mutation. Blood. 2013 Feb 28;121(9):1495-500. doi: 10.1182/blood-2012-07-446286. Epub 2012 Dec 20.</citation>
    <PMID>23258922</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Haroche J, Cohen-Aubart F, Emile JF, Donadieu J, Amoura Z. Vemurafenib as first line therapy in BRAF-mutated Langerhans cell histiocytosis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2015 Jul;73(1):e29-30. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2014.10.045.</citation>
    <PMID>26089069</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heisig A, Sörensen J, Zimmermann SY, Schöning S, Schwabe D, Kvasnicka HM, Schwentner R, Hutter C, Lehrnbecher T. Vemurafenib in Langerhans cell histiocytosis: report of a pediatric patient and review of the literature. Oncotarget. 2018 Apr 24;9(31):22236-22240. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.25277. eCollection 2018 Apr 24.</citation>
    <PMID>29774135</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Herbrink M, de Vries N, Rosing H, Huitema ADR, Nuijen B, Schellens JHM, Beijnen JH. Development and validation of a liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry analytical method for the therapeutic drug monitoring of eight novel anticancer drugs. Biomed Chromatogr. 2018 Apr;32(4). doi: 10.1002/bmc.4147. Epub 2017 Dec 19.</citation>
    <PMID>29165815</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Héritier S, Jehanne M, Leverger G, Emile JF, Alvarez JC, Haroche J, Donadieu J. Vemurafenib Use in an Infant for High-Risk Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis. JAMA Oncol. 2015 Sep;1(6):836-8. doi: 10.1001/jamaoncol.2015.0736.</citation>
    <PMID>26180941</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Raciborska A, Małas Z, Tysarowski A. [Vemurafenib in refractory langerhans histiocytosis]. Dev Period Med. 2018;22(4):376-378. Polish.</citation>
    <PMID>30636236</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Szmulewitz RZ, Ratain MJ. Vemurafenib oral bioavailability: an insoluble problem. J Clin Pharmacol. 2014 Apr;54(4):375-7.</citation>
    <PMID>24757719</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vikingsson S, Strömqvist M, Svedberg A, Hansson J, Höiom V, Gréen H. Novel rapid liquid chromatography tandem masspectrometry method for vemurafenib and metabolites in human plasma, including metabolite concentrations at steady state. Biomed Chromatogr. 2016 Aug;30(8):1234-9. doi: 10.1002/bmc.3672. Epub 2016 Jan 25.</citation>
    <PMID>26683023</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang W, Heinzmann D, Grippo JF. Clinical Pharmacokinetics of Vemurafenib. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2017 Sep;56(9):1033-1043. doi: 10.1007/s40262-017-0523-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28255850</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institute of Mother and Child, Warsaw, Poland</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Anna Raciborska</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof Ass MD PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>LCH</keyword>
  <keyword>vemurafenib</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <keyword>refractory histiocytosis</keyword>
  <keyword>paediatric patiens</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Histiocytosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vemurafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

