<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04940936</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SDM Lung SBRT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04940936</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Shared Decision Making on Radiation Dose for Lung Malignancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>Shared Decision Making on Radiation Dose for Stereotactic Body Radiotherapy of Malignancies Located Less Than 1 cm From the Thoracic Wall. A Randomized Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vejle Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vejle Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Patient Decision Aid (PtDA) is developed during a workshop in close collaboration with&#xD;
      selected patients. The PtDA is subsequently used in the consultation between patient and&#xD;
      physician to facilitate their shared decision on the dose of stereotactic body radiation&#xD;
      therapy (SBRT) for lung tumors located less than 1 cm from the thoracic wall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: The use of a PtDA will increase the extent of Shared Decision Making (SDM) during&#xD;
      the consultation and result in patients being more directly involved in the planning of their&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      When a lung tumor is located close to the thoracic wall, there is an increased risk of&#xD;
      developing chest wall pain or rib fracture following SBRT of the tumor. A meta-analysis has&#xD;
      shown the pooled risk of chest wall pain to be 11% and that of rib fracture to be 6.3% with&#xD;
      significant differences between individual studies. These side effects may occur several&#xD;
      years after the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SDM is a collaborative process allowing patients and healthcare professionals to make&#xD;
      decisions together taking into account the best scientific evidence as well as patients'&#xD;
      values, preferences, life situation, and knowledge about disease process and prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PtDAs are tools designed to assist caregivers in the process of informing patients about&#xD;
      relevant treatment options. PtDAs contain factual and balanced information about the options&#xD;
      and the pertaining pros, cons, and probabilities. The tools are relevant when the decision is&#xD;
      preference-sensitive, that is, the right treatment cannot be decided based on professional&#xD;
      knowledge alone. The use of PtDAs has shown to provide a number of positive effects on the&#xD;
      patients, including increased knowledge of options, better understanding of risks, and&#xD;
      clarity as to what matters most in their life situation. Other effects are decreased&#xD;
      decisional conflict and a higher degree of involvement in decision making.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a randomized trial enrolling eligible patients during a period of 16 months. SDM will&#xD;
      be used in the planning of SBRT to patients with peripheral non-small cell lung tumors or&#xD;
      lung metastases and offer them the choice between high (66 Gy in 3 fractions) and low (45 Gy&#xD;
      in 3 fractions) radiation dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 40 patients will be included in the study, i.e. 20 patients in each arm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>After inclusion in the study, the patients are randomized into Arm A and B as follows:&#xD;
Arm A: Consultation as usual. Patients are informed about treatment and the two dose options according to current standards and routines.&#xD;
Arm B: Consultation using the PtDA. Patients are informed about treatment and dose options using the PtDA to make the pros and cons clearer to the patients.&#xD;
The doctors and nurses in the Radiotherapy Department will be educated in the use of the PtDA before initiation of the study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The extent of shared decision making in the consultation between patient and oncologist as measured by the OPTION tool</measure>
    <time_frame>During the one hour primary consultation.</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value: 0. Maximum value: 48. The higher the value, the higher the extent of SDM during the consultation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in patient perceived level of shared decision making between arm A and B as measured by the tool SDM-Q9.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the primary consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value 0. Maximum value 45. The higher the value, the higher the patient experienced extent of SDM during the consultation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in patient perceived level of shared decision making between arm A and B as measured by the tool SDM_P4</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the primary consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value 0. Maximum value 4. The higher the value, the higher the patient experienced extent of SDM during the consultation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in patient perceived level of shared decision making between arm A and B as measured by the tool CollaboRATE</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the primary consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value 0. Maximum value 27. The higher the value, the higher the patient experienced extent of SDM during the consultation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in decisional conflict between patients in arm A and B as measured by the Decision Conflict Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately after the primary consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value: 0. Maximum value: 64. The higher the value, the more decisional conflict.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in decisional regret between patients in arm A and B as measured by the Decision Regret Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Reported by the patients six months and 3 years after the primary consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value: 5. Maximum value: 25. The higher the value, the more decisional regret.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in fear of cancer recurrence between patients in arm A and B as measured by the Fear of Cancer Recurrence - Short Form questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Reported by the patients six months and 3 years after the primary consultation</time_frame>
    <description>Minimum value: 0. Maximum value: 36. The higher the value, the more fear of recurrence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients developing chest wall pain and/or rib fracture during the 5-year follow-up program</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated by the physician every three months the first two years and then every six months the following three years.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life as measured by the questionnaire EORTC QLQ-C30.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Thirty questions with two different scales (1-4 and 1-7). The higher the value, the more symptoms/problems.&#xD;
Completed by the patients every three months the first two years and then every six months the following three years.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life as measured by the questionnaire EORTC QLQ-LC29</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Twenty-nine questions on a scale from 1 to 4. The higher the value, the more symptoms/problems.&#xD;
Completed by the patients every three months the first two years and then every six months the following three years.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Decision Making, Shared</condition>
  <condition>Stereotactic Body Radiation Therapy</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer, Non-small Cell</condition>
  <condition>Radiation Toxicity</condition>
  <condition>Lung Metastases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>A - control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The patients are offered high or lower dose according to usual practice</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B - Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Patient Decision Aid is used during the consultation to aid in the decision on high or lower dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>A Patient Decision Aid</intervention_name>
    <description>The Patient Decision Aid informs about the pros and cons of each option</description>
    <arm_group_label>B - Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed or high probability of non-small cell lung cancer, or&#xD;
             metastasis from other cancer, located ≤ 1 cm from the thoracic wall. High probability&#xD;
             refers to consensus on the diagnosis at the local multi-disciplinary lung tumor&#xD;
             conference.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible for stereotactic body radiation therapy in ablative doses (i.e. 66/45 Gy in 3&#xD;
             fractions) following national guidelines (2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can read and understand Danish.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written and orally informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy &gt; 6 months assessed by the physician during the consultation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous radiation therapy in the thoracic region (lung, breast or mediastinum), if it&#xD;
             is not possible to produce a new radiation plan of 66 or 45 Gy in 3 fractions that&#xD;
             considers previous radiation therapy and still complies with all constraints,&#xD;
             including dose to the thoracic wall. Previous surgery in the thorax is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental or social conditions preventing full understanding of the information or the&#xD;
             planned treatment and follow-up.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas L Fink, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Oncology, Vejle Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thomas L Fink, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+4579405446</phone>
    <email>thomas.leth.fink@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vejle Hospital, Department of Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vejle</city>
        <state>Region Of Southern Denmark</state>
        <zip>7100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Thomas L Fink, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+4579405446</phone>
      <email>thomas.leth.fink@rsyd.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 28, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Stereotactic body radiation therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung malignancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Shared decision making</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient Decision Aid</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Anonymized data will be available on relevant request.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

