<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04946084</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB 2031 A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04946084</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dynamic Change and Immune Response to Nasopharyngeal Carriage and Acute Otitis Media Pathogens</brief_title>
  <acronym>AOM</acronym>
  <official_title>Dynamic Change and Immune Response to Nasopharyngeal Carriage and Acute Otitis Media Pathogens</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rochester General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rochester General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators seek to conduct a prospective, longitudinal study to identify the dynamic&#xD;
      changes in nasopharyngeal (NP) colonization patterns and acute otitis media (AOM) etiology&#xD;
      involving antibiotic-resistant Streptococcus pneumoniae (Spn) and Haemophilus influenzae&#xD;
      (Hflu).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigator's proposed study design involves 2 cohorts. Cohort 1: Collection of middle&#xD;
      ear fluid(MEF), NP samples and blood at onset of AOM from otitis prone children and those who&#xD;
      have AOM antibiotic treatment failure since these children more frequently harbor antibiotic&#xD;
      resistant strains. Children will then be followed prospectively thereafter, collecting NP&#xD;
      samples at pre-determined time points when the children are healthy (see cohort 2) and MEF,&#xD;
      NP samples and blood if subsequent AOM infections occur. Cohort 2: Healthy children from whom&#xD;
      we will prospectively collect NP samplings and blood at any of 7 pre-determined time points&#xD;
      (age 6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 24, and/or 30-36 months old as they occur within the study time-frame)&#xD;
      to assess commensal carriage of Spn and Hflu. MEF will be obtained from the participants at&#xD;
      any AOM occurring, including the first and any subsequent AOM infection. Concurrently&#xD;
      detailed demographic, vaccination, epidemiologic and risk factor data known to influence AOM&#xD;
      epidemiology will be collected, providing scientific rigor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Viral respiratory infections will be another focus during this project. The investigators&#xD;
      will characterize dynamic changes in patterns of viral co-infections at onset of AOM&#xD;
      including the common respiratory viruses RSV A, B, influenza A, B, parainfluenzae virus type&#xD;
      3, rhinovirus, enterovirus, human metapneumovirus, human bocavirus, adenovirus B, C and&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. The studies will involve viral identification, evaluation of viral/bacterial&#xD;
      (otopathogen) interactions and mucosal and systemic immune responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have identified multiple deficiencies in innate and adaptive immunity among&#xD;
      young children who are AOM prone and introduced the term &quot;prolonged neonatal-like immune&#xD;
      profile (PNIP) because of striking similarities that resemble neonatal immunity. Another&#xD;
      focus of this project will be to expand understanding of the central immune deficiencies of&#xD;
      APM prone children using blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A a serum correlate of protection has been defined to predict the effectiveness of&#xD;
      pneumococcal conjugate vaccines using blood samples linked to occurrence of NP colonization&#xD;
      and AOM events in recent past work. Blood will be used to continue this work.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize which bacterial strains in the NP</measure>
    <time_frame>30 months</time_frame>
    <description>Identify the presence of Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae and Moraxella catharralis in the nasopharynx of children using in vitro culture</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize which bacterial strains are AOM causing pathogens</measure>
    <time_frame>30 months</time_frame>
    <description>Identify the presence of Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae and Moraxella catharralis in the nasopharynx of children using in vitro culture</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Characterize dynamic changes in patterns of viral co-infections at onset of AOM</measure>
    <time_frame>30 months</time_frame>
    <description>Identify respiratory viruses present in the nasopharynx at onset of acute otitis media in young children using polymerase chain reaction methods.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Determine immune responses after NP carriage and AOM infections by the common bacterial respiratory pathogens.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure serum and nasopharyngeal antibody levels to common bacterial and viral respiratory pathogens with ELISA and immune cellular responses (B cells, T cells, Antigen Presenting cells using flow cytometry and ELISPOT</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the serum antibody response that correlates with protection against NP colonization and AOM.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 months</time_frame>
    <description>Establish a correlate of protection for pneumococcal serotypes that colonize the nasopharynx and cause acute otitis media in young children using ELISA</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">320</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Otitis Media</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Children</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Samples taken from nasal swabs, nasal wash, blood draws and in the case of acute otitis media, tympanocentesis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tympanocentesis</intervention_name>
    <description>When acute otitis media is diagnosed, local anesthetic applied, small hole placed in eardrum, middle ear fluid extracted.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Children</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ear Tap</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nasal Phalangeal Swab and Wash</intervention_name>
    <description>Nasal phalangeal swab used to retrieve sample. Nasal wash used to retrieve sample.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Children</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nasal Swab, Nasal Wash</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood Draw</intervention_name>
    <description>Venipuncture</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Children</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female subject age 6 to 12 months + 30 days at the time of enrollment when&#xD;
             healthy or up to 36 months old + 30 days with an ear infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has received full (3 dose) infant series of PCV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent/legal guardian must be able and willing to bring subject to all study visits&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any major illness/condition that, in the investigator's judgment, will substantially&#xD;
             increase the risk associated with the subject's participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another investigational or interventional trial within the 28-day&#xD;
             period before enrollment and during the conduct of the study. Participation in&#xD;
             observational studies is permitted.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>36 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Pichichero, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rochester General Hospital Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michael Pichichero</last_name>
    <phone>922-5959</phone>
    <email>michael.pichichero@rochesterregional.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rochester General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14621</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michael Pichichiero, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rochester General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael Pichichero</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Rochester General Hospital Research Institute</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Otitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Otitis Media</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

