<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04943783</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BNI-20210601</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04943783</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Atorvastatin in the TREATment of Intracranial Unruptured VertebroBasilar Dissecting Aneurysms</brief_title>
  <acronym>ATREAT-VBD</acronym>
  <official_title>Application of Atorvastatin in the TREATment of Patients With Intracranial Unruptured Vertebrobasilar Dissecting Aneurysms</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study was designed to whether there is a measurable reduction in inflammation in walls&#xD;
      of unruptured vertebrobasilar dissecting aneurysms with atorvastatin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Unruptured vertebrobasilar dissecting aneurysms (UVBDAs) are a pathological condition of the&#xD;
      vertebrobasilar artery caused by hypertension, atherosclerosis, and infection. Hematoma&#xD;
      between intima and media can progressively occlude the parent artery. Thus lead to decreasing&#xD;
      perfusion of the distal perforator vessels and even cause cerebral infarction. Even worse,&#xD;
      ruptured VBDAs can lead to subarachnoid hemorrhage and eventually death of the patients.&#xD;
      Thus, risk of UVBDAs rupture should be weighed, and need an individual criterion for&#xD;
      predicting rupture in clinical decision making.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, many histopathological studies indicated that inflammation may play an important&#xD;
      role in the formation, growth, and rupture of aneurysms. High-resolution vessel wall MRI&#xD;
      (HR-VW-MRI) has been increasingly applied in clinical practice and is the only noninvasive&#xD;
      method for imaging the structure of the vascular wall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Wall enhancement of an aneurysm on high resolution magnetic resonance (HRMRI) is a proven&#xD;
      sign of inflammatory change and might predict an unsteady state of an intracranial aneurysm.&#xD;
      Besides, a previous study has demonstrated that HR-MRI can provide valuable information, such&#xD;
      as parameters of intramural hematomas, double lumens and intimal flaps, in the diagnosis and&#xD;
      follow-up UVBDAs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statins (3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A reductase inhibitors) are widely used&#xD;
      cholesterol-lowering drugs and are established as first-line treatments for&#xD;
      hypercholesterolemia. In addition, statins exert pleiotropic effects to protect the&#xD;
      vasculature. Statins can reduce the inflammation of the vessel wall and mobilize endothelial&#xD;
      progenitor cells for aneurysmal endothelial cell repair. Statins can also inhibit the&#xD;
      expression of several matrix metalloproteinases by smooth muscle cells and macrophages, which&#xD;
      may be important in reducing the growth and rupture of UVBDAs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, participants with UVBDAs that are not planned for surgical treatment and has&#xD;
      not yet ruptured, take atorvastatin daily for six months, and have a HRMRI scan before and&#xD;
      after conservative therapy to look for the role of atorvastatin in inflammation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1.Change of aneurysm wall inflammation as measured by HR-VW-MRI.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change of aneurysm wall enhancement index of at least 20% on HR-VM-MRI at the end of 6 months of atorvastatin 20mg daily treatment, compared to no treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of aneurysmal morphology parameter （the largest diamater）</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change of aneurysmal morphology parameter between pre-treatment and the 6 months follow-up periods.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of wall features of UVBDAs</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change of wall features of UVBDAs, which is intramural hematoma between pre-treatment and the 6 months follow-up periods. (The maximum diameter of the false lumen was compared)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of inflammatory markers in UVBDAs patients</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change of inflammatory markers in UVBDAs patients between pre-treatment and the 6 months follow-up periods. (CRP, TNF alpha, IL-2,6,8,10 and IL-1 beta)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Dissecting Aneurysm of Cerebral Artery</condition>
  <condition>Intramural Hematomas</condition>
  <condition>Inflammation Vascular</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Atorvastatin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Atorvastatin, 20mg once a day, for six months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>no drug</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atorvastatin 20mg</intervention_name>
    <description>One with the intervention (Atorvastatin, 20mg OD), 20 patients for this arm.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Atorvastatin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Be aged 18 or over, male or non-pregnant female;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients have a unruptured vertebrobasilar dissecting aneurysm identified on imaging&#xD;
             (CT, MRI or DSA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with wall enhancement and intramural hematomas of UVBDAs by HR-VW-MRI before&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who is able to understand the objective of the trail, agrees and signs the&#xD;
             written informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The aneurysm types of non-dissecting aneurysm, such as saccular aneurysms, fusiform&#xD;
             aneurysms and traumatic aneurysms, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with MRI contraindications: metallic implant, contrast allergy,&#xD;
             claustrophobia, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Planned treatment of the aneurysm within 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Several impaired liver or renal functions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Retreatment of recurrent aneurysm;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant or lactating women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with malignant diseases, such as liver disease, kidney diseases, congestive&#xD;
             heart failure, malignant tumors, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Poor compliance patients;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beijing Neurosurgical Institute and Beijing Tiantan Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>100070</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mirezhati Tuerhong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mirezhati Tuerhong, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+86-010-59978852</phone>
      <email>18699158800@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>High resolution magnetic resonance</keyword>
  <keyword>Atorvastatin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm, Dissecting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hematoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atorvastatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

