<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04946396</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CAAE 47593521.1.0000.5279</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04946396</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Continuous Dexmedetomidine Infusion on Systemic Microvascular Function in Laparoscopic Cholecystecthomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Effects of Continuous Dexmedetomidine Infusion on Systemic Microvascular Function in Patients Undergoing Laparoscopic Cholecystecthomy: a Prospective Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Cardiology, Laranjeiras, Brazil</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Cardiology, Laranjeiras, Brazil</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The microcirculation represents the primary site of exchange of oxygen and nutrients for&#xD;
      tissues, and the preservation of microcirculatory perfusion is essential for the maintenance&#xD;
      of organ function. The microcirculation is extremely dynamic and may vary according to the&#xD;
      individual's temperature, systemic blood pressure, the use of medications, during physical&#xD;
      and mental activity, age and pathological processes. In this context, the development of&#xD;
      portable microscopes for clinical use has made possible the non-invasive visualization of the&#xD;
      microcirculation and tissue perfusion in patients undergoing several highly complex&#xD;
      procedures in cardiology, including cardiac surgery with cardiopulmonary bypass, ECMO&#xD;
      (Extracorporeal Membrane Oxygenation) and in critically ill patients in intensive care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CytoCam, for example, is a handheld device that incorporates a darkfield incident light&#xD;
      illumination system with a series of high-resolution lenses that project images to a computer&#xD;
      dedicated to the system. Dexmedetomidine is a selective agonist of 2-adrenergic receptors in&#xD;
      the central nervous system, whose administration results in a reduction in the activity of&#xD;
      the sympathetic nervous system and a reduction in the systemic release of catecholamines. Its&#xD;
      use in the perioperative period has several beneficial effects, such as reducing&#xD;
      neuroendocrine and hemodynamic responses due to anesthesia and surgery, through induction of&#xD;
      sedation and analgesia, in addition to reducing the consumption of opioids and anesthetics in&#xD;
      general. Several recent studies report that the use of dexmedetomidine in the perioperative&#xD;
      period reduces the incidence of postoperative complications, reduces the time on mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation and attenuates the neuroendocrine response due to surgical trauma and&#xD;
      extracorporeal circulation in patients undergoing cardiac surgery. However, the effects of&#xD;
      dexmedetomidine on systemic microcirculation function during its use in anesthesia for&#xD;
      elective surgical procedures of medium complexity are not yet known. In conclusion, the&#xD;
      hypothesis of the present study is that continuous intravenous infusion of dexmedetomidine&#xD;
      during balanced general anesthesia increases the microvascular perfusion flow rate in the&#xD;
      sublingual mucosa, representing an increase in systemic microvascular perfusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CytoCam, is a handheld device that incorporates a darkfield incident light illumination&#xD;
      system with a series of high-resolution lenses that project images to a computer dedicated to&#xD;
      the system. Dexmedetomidine is a selective agonist of 2-adrenergic receptors in the central&#xD;
      nervous system, whose administration results in a reduction in the activity of the&#xD;
      sympathetic nervous system and a reduction in the systemic release of catecholamines. Its use&#xD;
      in the perioperative period has several beneficial effects, such as reducing neuroendocrine&#xD;
      and hemodynamic responses due to anesthesia and surgery, through induction of sedation and&#xD;
      analgesia, in addition to reducing the consumption of opioids and anesthetics in general.&#xD;
      Several recent studies report that the use of dexmedetomidine in the perioperative period&#xD;
      reduces the incidence of postoperative complications, reduces the time on mechanical&#xD;
      ventilation and attenuates the neuroendocrine response due to surgical trauma and&#xD;
      extracorporeal circulation in patients undergoing cardiac surgery. However, the effects of&#xD;
      dexmedetomidine on systemic microcirculation function during its use in anesthesia for&#xD;
      elective surgical procedures of medium complexity are not yet known. In conclusion, the&#xD;
      hypothesis of the present study is that continuous intravenous infusion of dexmedetomidine&#xD;
      during balanced general anesthesia increases the microvascular perfusion flow rate in the&#xD;
      sublingual mucosa, representing an increase in systemic microvascular perfusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will be randomized into two groups of 35 patients each: 1) patients who will receive continuous intraoperative infusion of dexmedetomidine hydrochloride (0.5 µg/kg/h) (DEX group) or 2) control group, patients who will receive continuous infusion of 0.9% saline solution (CONT group).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in microvascular flow index</measure>
    <time_frame>during surgery</time_frame>
    <description>sublingual microvascular density</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Laparoscopic Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>dexmedetomidine intravenous infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who will receive continuous intraoperative infusion of dexmedetomidine hydrochloride (0.5 µg/kg/h).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>0.9% saline solution intravenous infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who will receive continuous infusion of 0.9% saline solution (sham group).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>dexmedetomidine intravenous infusion</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexmedetomidine intravenous infusion during laparoscopic cholecystecthomy</description>
    <arm_group_label>dexmedetomidine intravenous infusion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9%sodium chloride</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9%sodium chloride intravenous infusion during laparoscopic cholecystecthomy</description>
    <arm_group_label>0.9% saline solution intravenous infusion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients of both sexes (age ≥ 18 and ≤ 60 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical state ASA I or II according to the criteria of the American Association of&#xD;
             Anesthesiology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned surgery of cholecystectomy by videolaparoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's refusal to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inflammation or infection in the sublingual mucosa&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergency surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Grade III obesity (BMI ≥39.9 kg/m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune diseases, malignant neoplasms&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>EDUARDO TIBIRICA, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Cardiology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>EDUARDO TIBIRICA, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+55-21-99914-6075</phone>
    <email>etibi@uol.com.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Institute of Cardiology, Laranjeiras, Brazil</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Eduardo Tibirica, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Senior Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>dexmedetomidine</keyword>
  <keyword>microcirculation</keyword>
  <keyword>general anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>central alpha-2 agonists</keyword>
  <keyword>tissue perfusion</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

