<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04949932</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HUBREC/2021/09/02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04949932</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Application of Poly-herbal Powder for Treating Acne Vulgaris</brief_title>
  <official_title>Application of Poly-herbal Powder for Treating Acne Vulgaris: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dr. Md. Shahab Uddin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hamdard University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acne is a common problem in adolescence to young adult. But there is no such remedy available&#xD;
      for acne treatment which has no side effects. Different types of herbs powder has been using&#xD;
      in patients with acne vulgaris in the traditional practice of Indian subcontinent as single&#xD;
      form or compound. Scientific evidence have shown many herbs has no known side effects and&#xD;
      effective on acne. These herbs have antibacterial, anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidant&#xD;
      effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, This study is intended to find out an inexpensive and safe alternative by using some&#xD;
      common herbs such as Azadirachta indica, Curcuma longa, Lens culinaris Mentha arvensis and&#xD;
      Trigonella foenum-graecum. The aim of the study is to evaluate the clinical efficacy of Poly&#xD;
      herbal powder (PHP) for treating patients with acne vulgaris.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Total of 42 adults with acne vulgaris was recruited for this study. Study subjects was&#xD;
      included both of male and female with age limit of 18 to 35 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of study is 05 months with &quot;day one advertisement&quot; for screening followed by&#xD;
      randomization for the treatment. The duration of active participation of each study subject&#xD;
      was 3 consecutive weeks or 21days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Difference of baseline and post intervention mean by Total lesion Count (TLC) compared with&#xD;
      placebo and assesses the % of reduction of acne based on The Global Acne Grading System&#xD;
      (GAGS) score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety assessment was obtained from the incidence and type of adverse events during study&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to increasing interest from acne patients concerned about the side effects associated&#xD;
      with conventional therapies, complementary and alternative medicine (CAM) has been suggested&#xD;
      as a new therapeutic modality for acne vulgaris. Herbal medicine is one of these CAM&#xD;
      treatments. Different types of herbs powder has been using in patients with acne vulgaris in&#xD;
      the traditional practice of Indian subcontinent as single form or compound. As for example,&#xD;
      Azadirachta indica, Curcuma longa, Ocimum sanctum, Lens culinaris, Trigonella foenum-graecum&#xD;
      and Mentha arvensis etc. These herbs have antibacterial, anti-inflammatory and anti-oxidant&#xD;
      effects. Therefore, this study was designed to evaluate the efficacy of poly-herbal powder&#xD;
      (PHP) for treating acne vulgaris using some of these plants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the clinical efficacy of PHP compared with that of placebo (PBO) in patients with&#xD;
      acne vulgaris.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Literature review have shown that sample size were included 20, 40, 75 and 503 study subjects&#xD;
      in various research for treating acne vulgaris. Prior study has shown that the mean±SD of&#xD;
      acne vulgaris at the baseline was 19.66 ±3.93 and after intervention it was 14.33±5.96&#xD;
      according to GAGS. Based on this results, the estimated enrollment of 15 per treatment group&#xD;
      among those with acne vulgaris would provide the study with a statistical power of 80% (α =&#xD;
      0.05) and Confidence interval of 95% to detect the significant efficacy in acne. By using&#xD;
      OpenEpi online calculator, required sample size is 30. But possibility of loss to follow up&#xD;
      the inflated sample size is 42.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For study subjects recruitment, advertisement was posted on online social networking&#xD;
      platforms (such as facebook, Facebook Messenger, facebook groups, linkedIn, what's up and&#xD;
      e-mail). The all relevant study requirements was included in the advertisement following a&#xD;
      link of Google Form Questionnaire (socio-demographic data, specially instructed photograph)&#xD;
      to participate in this study. Enrollment of respondent was done by acne lesions counting from&#xD;
      the photograph sent by the study subjects through Google Form following fulfillment of&#xD;
      inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thereafter, Study subject was assigned to either PHP or PBO randomly for 03 consecutive weeks&#xD;
      and intervention products was sent by courier according to study subject's present address.&#xD;
      After intervention period study subjects was had to fill another Google Form Questionnaire&#xD;
      including socio-demographic data, specially instructed photograph and other information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (Instructions for Taking Photograph: Mobile phone with camera, camera resolution must be 8 or&#xD;
      more than 8 Mega pixels. Study subject has to take photo from a distance of 12 inches from&#xD;
      face. Upload total of 6 photos (Right sided 2 photos, Left sided 2 photos and 2 photos from&#xD;
      front) of face.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      An intention-to-treat analysis will be conducted for patients who have received intervention&#xD;
      at least once. Data will be presented as mean±SD and percentage of reduction in the change of&#xD;
      counting acne lesions with 95% confidence interval and p=0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy Assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Difference of baseline and post intervention mean by Total lesion Count (TLC) compared with&#xD;
      placebo and assesses the % of reduction of acne based on GAGS score. Difference between two&#xD;
      means will be compared with independent two sample t-test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Global Acne Grading System (GAGS):&#xD;
&#xD;
      The GAGS is a quantitative scoring system to assess acne severity. It was first developed by&#xD;
      Doshi and colleagues in 1997. The total severity score is derived from summation of six&#xD;
      regional sub scores. Each is derived by multiplying the factors-2 for forehead, 2 for each&#xD;
      check, 1 for nose, 1 for chin, 3 for both chest and back by the most heavily weighted lesion&#xD;
      within each region (1 for ≥ one comedone, 2 for ≥ one papule,3 for ≥ one pustule, and 4 for ≥&#xD;
      one nodule). The regional factors were derived from consideration of surface area and&#xD;
      distribution and density of pilosebaceous units. The summation of local score indicates, &quot;0 =&#xD;
      None, 1-18 = Mild, 19-30 = Moderate, 31-38 = Severe, &gt; 39 = Very severe.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data and Safety Monitoring:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To maintain the quality of this trial, data &amp; safety monitoring will be conducted by Data &amp;&#xD;
      Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB). The members of the DSMB was included that individual who was&#xD;
      not involved directly in this research. For this clinical trial, DSMB members was joined from&#xD;
      the Faculty of Unani and Ayurvedic Medicine of Hamdard University Bangladesh (HUB).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety assessment was obtained from the incidence and type of adverse events during study&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 12, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Total Lesions Count (TLC)</measure>
    <time_frame>03 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Total Lesions Count (TLC) = Comedones + Papules + Pastules, before and after intervention will be presented as percentage as well as mean and standard deviation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in The Global Acne Grading System score</measure>
    <time_frame>03 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The total severity score is derived from summation of six regional (i.e forehead, check, nose, chin, chest and back) sub scores. The summation of local score indicates, &quot;0 = None, 1-18 = Mild, 19-30 = Moderate, 31-38 = Severe, &gt; 39 = Very severe.&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in non-inflammatory and inflammatory lesions count</measure>
    <time_frame>03 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Pre and post treatment changes in non-inflammatory ( i.e Comedones) and inflammatory (i.e papule, pustule &amp; nodule) acne lesions count will be presented as percentage as well as mean and standard deviation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Acne Vulgaris</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Poly herbal powder (PHP)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Powder of Cicer arietinum</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mixed powder of Lens culinaris, Curcuma longa, Mentha arvensis, Azadirachta indica, and Trigonella foenumgraecum.</intervention_name>
    <description>Study subjects were prescribed either PHP or placebo once daily at night for 3 weeks consecutively. A dose of 1-2 tea spoonfuls powder had to mixed with water to make paste. Then it was applied on face (except around the eyes) and had to wait for 20-30 minutes until it dries.Then they were washed face by using normal water.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cicer arietinum powder</intervention_name>
    <description>Study subjects were prescribed either PHP or placebo once daily at night for 3 weeks consecutively. A dose of 1-2 tea spoonfuls powder had to mixed with water to make paste. Then it was applied on face (except around the eyes) and had to wait for 20-30 minutes until it dries.Then they were washed face by using normal water.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women both aged between 18-35 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presenting minimum 5 acne lesions (whiteheads, blackheads, papules, pustules, nodules)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Study subject who will be agreed with Online informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have infected acne lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If study subject suffers from any serious medical conditions such as uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension, diabetes mellitus, past or current malignancy, liver or kidney&#xD;
             dysfunction, active pulmonary tuberculosis other severe dermatitis, or any infectious&#xD;
             or systemic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of a topical medication containing steroids for the treatment of skin disease more&#xD;
             than once per month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypersensitive skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Erythema, or telangiectasia at the test site.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of the same or similar cosmetics (or pharmaceutical) on the test site within three&#xD;
             months of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having undergone a skin peeling or having wrinkles removed within six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other reasons of unsuitability for the clinical trial at the discretion of the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr.Md. S Uddin, BUMS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MPH student, Hamdard University Bangladesh</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hamdard University Bangladesh</name>
      <address>
        <city>Munshiganj</city>
        <zip>1510</zip>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hamdard University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Md. Shahab Uddin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Poly-herbal</keyword>
  <keyword>Acne vulgaris</keyword>
  <keyword>Powder</keyword>
  <keyword>RCT</keyword>
  <keyword>Bangladesh</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acne Vulgaris</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Turmeric extract</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All Individual Participant Data that underlie results in a publication</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Starting 6 months after publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Request by email.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

