<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04947540</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IS in BTM patients</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04947540</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Iron Status in BTM With Blood Transfusion</brief_title>
  <official_title>Hematological and Biochemical Markers of Iron Status in Thalassemic Children Receiving Multiple Blood Transfusion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess the possible role of iron overload as a cause of liver dysfunction in thalassemic&#xD;
      childrens receiving multiple blood transfusion and its correlation with serum&#xD;
      aminotransferases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Thalassemia is derived from the Greek words, thals, which means sea, and emia, which means&#xD;
      blood, signifying that it is more common in the Mediterranean region . Globally, among&#xD;
      humans, thalassemia is the commonest single-gene disorder. It is defined as a group of&#xD;
      inherited disorders characterized by decreased or absent beta globin chain synthesis, leading&#xD;
      to a reduced level of hemoglobulin (Hb) in the red blood cells . Specifically in developing&#xD;
      countries, thalassemia is a huge health dilemma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Beta Thalassemia is the most common chronic hemolytic anemia in Egypt (85.1%) with an&#xD;
      estimated carrier rate of 9-10.2%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood transfusion is the primary way of treating thalassemia; it allows the normal growth of&#xD;
      the child as well as restrains abnormal erythropoiesis . Iron-chelating agents should be used&#xD;
      properly;otherwise, multiple blood transfusions can lead to iron overload. Yet, with no blood&#xD;
      transfusion, the increase rate of erythropoiesis intensifies dietary iron absorption from the&#xD;
      gut, leading to a severe form of iron overload .&#xD;
&#xD;
      iron overload can result in serious damage to various organs, for example, by depositing in&#xD;
      the liver, heart, and various other endocrine glands along with endocrine organ failure. .&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the last years, liver disease has emerged as a major cause of mortality in patients&#xD;
      with B- thalassemia major (TM).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The liver is the only site for ferritin and transferrin synthesis, as well as the primary&#xD;
      organ for iron storage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The liver has the maximum capacity to store excess iron in the body, and various other&#xD;
      organs, as well as the liver, are very susceptible to damage as a result of iron toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The correlation between serum ferritin and hepatic iron concentration has been reported in&#xD;
      multiple blood-transfused thalassemia patients .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thalassemia major patients who undergo routine transfusion have an increased risk of&#xD;
      acquiring transfusion-transmitted infections (TTI), including hepatitis B and C. These&#xD;
      diseases have serious implications and may affect the serum ferritin and aminotransferase&#xD;
      levels of thalassemia major patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although the risk of post-transfusion hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection dropped significantly&#xD;
      after the national screening of blood in 1993, more than 20% of children who were&#xD;
      multitransfused after that date were HCV-RNA positive .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Egypt, prevalence rate of HCV antibodies seropositivity in thalassemic children at 2011was&#xD;
      51.7% while in the study of El-Faramawy (2012) , a prevalence of 48 % was reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Iron overload and hepatitis-C virus (HCV) infection, have been implicated in the evolution of&#xD;
      liver disease, in patients with transfusion-dependent beta-thalassaemia major (BTM). The&#xD;
      impact of these factors and liver with BTM, has not been extensively studied yet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hepatitis virus C infection is the main risk factor for liver injury in transfusion-dependent&#xD;
      thalassemics . Dimitrios (2013) on the other hand suggested that in the late stages of liver&#xD;
      disease in BTM patients, iron overload may be the critical determinant, since fibrosis is&#xD;
      related to the minimal haemosiderosis, independently of HCV history. Injury to the liver,&#xD;
      whether acute or chronic, eventually results in an increase in serum concentrations of&#xD;
      Alanine transaminase (ALT) and Aspartate transaminase (AST)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hematological and biochemical markers of Iron status in thalassemic children receiving multiple blood transfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment the possible role of iron overload as a cause of liver dysfunction in thalassemic childrens receiving multiple blood transfusion and its correlation with serum aminotransferases.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Beta-Thalassemia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        all cases diagnosed as thalassemia major attending to thalassemic center at hematological&#xD;
        department at Assuit university childern hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thalassemic patients of both sex.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Beta-thalassemia major patients diagnosed Clinical and laboratory .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 5 : 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing multiple blood transfusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  -Age less than 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute illness as fever and infections.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed M Ghazally, professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Egypt</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rehab M Rashed, pediatrician</last_name>
    <phone>01064959241</phone>
    <phone_ext>Egypt</phone_ext>
    <email>rhabrashed950@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Hekma S Farghaly, Assist. prof</last_name>
    <phone>01091251040</phone>
    <phone_ext>Egypt</phone_ext>
    <email>Hekma.osman@med.au.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al-Moshary M, Imtiaz N, Al-Mussaed E, Khan A, Ahmad S, Albqami S. Clinical and Biochemical Assessment of Liver Function Test and Its Correlation with Serum Ferritin Levels in Transfusion-dependent Thalassemia Patients. Cureus. 2020 Apr 7;12(4):e7574. doi: 10.7759/cureus.7574.</citation>
    <PMID>32391223</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Amjad F, Fatima T, Fayyaz T, Khan MA, Qadeer MI. Novel genetic therapeutic approaches for modulating the severity of β-thalassemia (Review). Biomed Rep. 2020 Nov;13(5):48. doi: 10.3892/br.2020.1355. Epub 2020 Sep 2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32953110</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salama KM, Ibrahim OM, Kaddah AM, Boseila S, Ismail LA, Hamid MM. Liver Enzymes in Children with beta-Thalassemia Major: Correlation with Iron Overload and Viral Hepatitis. Open Access Maced J Med Sci. 2015 Jun 15;3(2):287-92. doi: 10.3889/oamjms.2015.059. Epub 2015 May 28.</citation>
    <PMID>27275237</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rehab Mohamed Rashed Gad</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thalassemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>beta-Thalassemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

