<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04812756</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>622085-5</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04812756</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Step-2-It: Feasibility of SMS Technology to Increase Physical Activity</brief_title>
  <acronym>Step-2-It</acronym>
  <official_title>Step-2-It: A Pilot Study to Assess Feasibility of Using SMS Based Mobile Technology to Increase Physical Activity in Adult Rural Women at Risk for Cardiovascular Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois College of Medicine Rockford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois College of Medicine Rockford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rural women are more likely to be obese and have a higher risk for chronic disease than their&#xD;
      non-rural counterparts. Inadequate physical activity (PA) at least in part contributes to&#xD;
      this increased risk. Rural women face personal, social and environmental barriers to PA&#xD;
      engagement. Interventions promoting walking among rural women have demonstrated success;&#xD;
      however, few of these studies use text messaging to promote PA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step-2-It was a pilot study to assess the feasibility, acceptability, and effectiveness of&#xD;
      text-messaging combined with a pedometer to promote PA, specifically walking among&#xD;
      English-speaking women, aged 40 and older, living in a rural, northwest Illinois county.&#xD;
      There were two components to the 13-week, Step-2-It intervention: (i) participants used the&#xD;
      pedometer to track and report their steps via text message daily; and (ii) participants&#xD;
      received an informational or motivational text message daily. Enrolled participants completed&#xD;
      baseline assessments, received pedometers and two types of automated text messages:&#xD;
      motivational messages to encourage walking, and accountability messages to report pedometer&#xD;
      steps. Participants engaged in 3, 6, 9, and 12-week follow-ups to download pedometer data,&#xD;
      and completed post-intervention assessments at 12 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rural women are significantly more likely to be obese than non-rural women, which is&#xD;
      associated at least in part to inadequate physical activity (PA). It is well established that&#xD;
      physical activity (PA) can lower the risk for heart disease, stroke, type 2 diabetes, and&#xD;
      certain cancers and that physical inactivity is the fourth leading risk factor for mortality&#xD;
      worldwide. Given these associations between PA engagement and mortality as well as disease&#xD;
      risk, and that PA levels typically decrease with age, interventions to encourage PA among&#xD;
      rural women who are middle-aged and older are essential. Rural women report personal barriers&#xD;
      to PA engagement including the lack of time and injury, as well as barriers in their physical&#xD;
      and social environments, including limited access to exercise facilities and lack of social&#xD;
      support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Walking is an affordable PA option that in part addresses the barriers to PA engagement and&#xD;
      is associated with a low injury risk. Previous interventions to encourage walking, including&#xD;
      those implemented in rural communities, have achieved success in increasing PA, weight loss&#xD;
      and improving risk factors for multiple chronic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mobile health (mHealth) technology and PA trackers are two technologies that can be used to&#xD;
      promote walking in rural women. Mobile health, or mHealth, is the application of wireless&#xD;
      devices to support medical or public health practices. Text-messaging is one mHealth strategy&#xD;
      that has the ability to reach a large number of people at a relatively low cost.Cell phone&#xD;
      use in the US is nearly universal, 97% of urban adults and 95% of rural adults are cell-phone&#xD;
      users. mHealth interventions using text messaging have been used to address a variety of&#xD;
      health concerns, including PA promotion. However, few studies have examined the use of mobile&#xD;
      health technologies to promote PA in rural women, and to our knowledge, no such studies have&#xD;
      focused on midlife and older, rural women. Mobile health or mHealth when used to promote&#xD;
      walking in rural women can broaden the reach of these interventions and gives the ability to&#xD;
      communicate with women in real-time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical activity trackers and wearable devices are easily available and affordable and there&#xD;
      is evidence to show that their use is helpful in promoting increasing physical activity. In&#xD;
      the America on the Move study, adults who were using a pedometer accumulated significantly&#xD;
      more steps than those who were not. This finding suggests that using physical activity&#xD;
      tacking devices such as pedometers might motivate individuals to increase their physical&#xD;
      activity and is supported by a review that shows that pedometer-based walking programs&#xD;
      increased participants' activity levels by 2,183 steps per day. A systematic review of 14&#xD;
      mobile health interventions with physical activity as an outcome showed that 7 of the 14&#xD;
      showed significant positive benefits on self-reported physical activity outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Step-2-It was a pilot study designed to evaluate the feasibility, acceptability and&#xD;
      effectiveness of text-messaging combined with a pedometer to promote PA, specifically&#xD;
      walking, among midlife and older women, residing in a rural Illinois county. This&#xD;
      prospective, one-group, pre-post study targeted women ages 40 and older living in Stephenson&#xD;
      County, IL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Flyers advertising the study were placed in the grocery stores and the health department, and&#xD;
      interested participants called the lead researcher who assessed eligibility using a&#xD;
      checklist. Women with a self-reported diagnosis of bronchitis, pneumonia, or severe asthma,&#xD;
      or those being treated for a severe health conditions were ineligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible women were invited to one of five enrollment meetings at SCHD. At least two&#xD;
      follow-up calls were made to interested women who did not attend their scheduled enrollment&#xD;
      meeting to invite them to the next meeting. Women were screened and those who met the study&#xD;
      eligibility criteria were enrolled in the study. At the enrollment meetings, participants&#xD;
      provided written consent, received a pedometer (Omron HJ-720ITC) and were trained on how to&#xD;
      use it. In addition, they completed a series of baseline instruments detailed below and were&#xD;
      provided educational materials on cardiovascular disease risk reduction through PA and&#xD;
      healthy eating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There were two components to the 13-week, Step-2-It intervention: (i) participants used the&#xD;
      pedometer to track and report their steps via text message daily; and (ii) participants&#xD;
      received an informational or motivational text message daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pedometer/Step Reporting: Starting in week 0, participants self-reported daily step counts&#xD;
      via text message, and continued to do so for the duration of the 13-week intervention.&#xD;
      Participants received a daily text reminder to report their steps. Those who did not report&#xD;
      steps for two days in a row received a reminder phone call. Every three weeks, participants&#xD;
      returned to SCHD to have their pedometer data downloaded. Participants received a $5&#xD;
      incentive for each download, for a total of $20 over 13 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Text messaging: Text messages were sent using mytapp, an online application that allowed for&#xD;
      scheduling individual and recurring messages via a cloud service, Twilio. Text messages used&#xD;
      for this study were limited to 160 characters and participants could choose their preferred&#xD;
      time of day to receive texts. In week 0, the only message participants received were to&#xD;
      remind them to report their steps. From week 1-12, in addition to the reminder to report&#xD;
      steps, participants received one informational or motivational text message per day (7&#xD;
      messages/week). All participants received the same text messages each day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Motivational messages were based on social cognitive theory with the intention of increasing&#xD;
      participant self-efficacy to engage in PA. These messages were adapted from a database of&#xD;
      messages from a previous study to increase PA among African American breast cancer survivors.&#xD;
      Adaptations were made to the messages based on two focus groups conducted with in the target&#xD;
      population prior to this study (unpublished study). Sample motivational messages included,&#xD;
      &quot;Nothing is impossible. The word itself says &quot;I'm Possible!&quot;and &quot;Always focus on how far you&#xD;
      have come, rather than how far you have left to go.&quot; Informational messages included local,&#xD;
      PA-related events and resources, such as walks and low-cost walking options. Sample&#xD;
      information messages included, &quot;Walk for a cause - sign up for charity walks&quot; and &quot;Find a&#xD;
      friend to walk with.&quot; In addition, there were also messages that reminded women to walk.&#xD;
      These messages included, &quot;Check out what is going on outside, go for a walk&quot;, &quot;Don't just&#xD;
      think about it, actually go for a walk&quot;, and &quot;Take a quick walking break.&quot; Data collected for&#xD;
      this study along with the time-points at which they were collected are described below.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Characteristics (collected at baseline): participant demographic information&#xD;
      including age, race, education, marital status, employment, and household income; and health&#xD;
      status information including self-reported previous diagnosis of diabetes, hypertension, high&#xD;
      blood cholesterol, and other heart health diagnoses, medication use for chronic conditions,&#xD;
      and tobacco use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical Activity Questionnaire (collected at baseline and post-intervention): Self-reported&#xD;
      PA was assessed using seven questions from the 2005 Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance&#xD;
      System (BRFSS) Physical Activity questionnaire. These data were used to determine whether&#xD;
      participants met the recommended aerobic PA levels. Questionnaire reliability and validity&#xD;
      have been established previously.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical Activity Pedometer Readings (collected at weeks 3,6,9, and 12) and Self-Reported&#xD;
      Steps (collected daily): The primary outcome measure was number of steps. The Omron HJ-720ITC&#xD;
      pedometer, validated in previous studies,40-42 was used for an objective measure of steps.&#xD;
      Data was downloaded from the pedometers every three weeks. Participants self-reported daily&#xD;
      steps via text message.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Body Weight (collected at baseline and postintervention): weight was measured using a&#xD;
      calibrated scale at SCHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention Satisfaction (collected at post-intervention): was assessed using a survey that&#xD;
      included questions on overall perceptions about Step-2-It, number of messages received,&#xD;
      preferred message types, perceptions about the effectiveness of text messages in promoting&#xD;
      health and PA, and plans to continue PA after participating in Step-2-It. Participants were&#xD;
      also asked about barriers to reporting steps. Participants who completed this survey received&#xD;
      a $20 incentive.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Descriptive statistics were used to characterize the study population and assess&#xD;
      post-intervention satisfaction. Baseline to post-intervention comparisons for body weight&#xD;
      were conducted using the paired categorical Wilcoxon Sign rank test. Comparisons of BRFSS PA&#xD;
      level was conducted using the Chi-square test. Self-reported step data were compared to&#xD;
      downloaded step data and a Pearson correlation was calculated. Correlation testing for&#xD;
      self-reported steps versus pedometer-recorded steps excluded observations where only one&#xD;
      variable was present. For analyzing mean steps, missing pedometer data was filled in with&#xD;
      self-reported step data. Mean steps by week of intervention was calculated and a box plot of&#xD;
      mean daily steps by intervention week was produced.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 15, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 15, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single group prospective pre-post study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Activity levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to end of intervention at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>mean steps per day measured using pedometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical Activity Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to end of intervention at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>PA measured via self-report using the BRFSS PA tool</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body-weight</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline to end of intervention at 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Body weight measured using a calibrated scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Behavior</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Texting intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a single arm study in which all participants received a pedometer and text messages for the 12 week intervention period. Participants received a content message and a message requesting them to report the number of steps from their pedometer daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Step-2-It - text messaging program</intervention_name>
    <description>participants received a pedometer and text messages to motivate them to increase walking daily for a period of 12 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Texting intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 40 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reside in Stephenson County&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Own a cell phone with ability to receive and send text messages&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unlimited texting plan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women under 40 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reside outside Stephenson County&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No cell phone or no texting ability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant health conditions (including pyelonephritis, current treatment for cancer,&#xD;
             other severe illness)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active severe asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current pneumonia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manorama M Khare, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois College of Medicine Rockford</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lundeen EA, Park S, Pan L, O'Toole T, Matthews K, Blanck HM. Obesity Prevalence Among Adults Living in Metropolitan and Nonmetropolitan Counties - United States, 2016. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018 Jun 15;67(23):653-658. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6723a1.</citation>
    <PMID>29902166</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Whitfield GP, Carlson SA, Ussery EN, Fulton JE, Galuska DA, Petersen R. Trends in Meeting Physical Activity Guidelines Among Urban and Rural Dwelling Adults - United States, 2008-2017. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2019 Jun 14;68(23):513-518. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm6823a1.</citation>
    <PMID>31194722</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bassett DR Jr, Wyatt HR, Thompson H, Peters JC, Hill JO. Pedometer-measured physical activity and health behaviors in U.S. adults. Med Sci Sports Exerc. 2010 Oct;42(10):1819-25. doi: 10.1249/MSS.0b013e3181dc2e54.</citation>
    <PMID>20305579</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trivedi T, Liu J, Probst J, Merchant A, Jhones S, Martin AB. Obesity and obesity-related behaviors among rural and urban adults in the USA. Rural Remote Health. 2015 Oct-Dec;15(4):3267. Epub 2015 Oct 13.</citation>
    <PMID>26458564</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olsen JM. An integrative review of literature on the determinants of physical activity among rural women. Public Health Nurs. 2013 Jul;30(4):288-311. doi: 10.1111/phn.12023. Epub 2013 Jan 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23808855</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Murtagh EM, Nichols L, Mohammed MA, Holder R, Nevill AM, Murphy MH. The effect of walking on risk factors for cardiovascular disease: an updated systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised control trials. Prev Med. 2015 Mar;72:34-43. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2014.12.041. Epub 2015 Jan 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25579505</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bravata DM, Smith-Spangler C, Sundaram V, Gienger AL, Lin N, Lewis R, Stave CD, Olkin I, Sirard JR. Using pedometers to increase physical activity and improve health: a systematic review. JAMA. 2007 Nov 21;298(19):2296-304. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18029834</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hall AK, Cole-Lewis H, Bernhardt JM. Mobile text messaging for health: a systematic review of reviews. Annu Rev Public Health. 2015 Mar 18;36:393-415. doi: 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-031914-122855. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25785892</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Free C, Phillips G, Watson L, Galli L, Felix L, Edwards P, Patel V, Haines A. The effectiveness of mobile-health technologies to improve health care service delivery processes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS Med. 2013;10(1):e1001363. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1001363. Epub 2013 Jan 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23458994</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

