<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04817098</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202101122</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04817098</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Journey of Life Psychosocial Support Program</brief_title>
  <official_title>Journey of Life Psychosocial Support for Conflict-Affected Populations in Uganda</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>TPO Uganda</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Agency for International Development (USAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study evaluates the impact and implementation of the Journey of Life&#xD;
      intervention among crisis-affected caregivers living in Western Uganda. In this quasi&#xD;
      experimental waitlist control design, participants will be assigned to treatment or waitlist&#xD;
      control group based on their geographic location. The intervention will be delivered in X&#xD;
      sessions weekly. Assessments will be conducted at baseline and following the intervention&#xD;
      period. Assessments will include mental health, functioning, social support, child protection&#xD;
      behaviors, parenting attitudes, and experiences of intimate partner violence. The study also&#xD;
      aims to examine implementation of the Journey of Life intervention through qualitative&#xD;
      assessments of feasibility, acceptability, adaptation, reach, and adoption.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aligned with the USAID HEARD (Health Evaluation and Applied Research Development) purpose to&#xD;
      leverage global partnerships to generate, synthesize, and use evidence to improve program&#xD;
      implementation in low and middle-income countries, the proposed study will examine the impact&#xD;
      and implementation of the Journey of Life (JoL) intervention in a humanitarian setting. The&#xD;
      JoL intervention aims to provide psychosocial support to adults and galvanize caregivers to&#xD;
      develop action plans for child protection in their communities. The proposed research will&#xD;
      involve an analysis of effect sizes for mental health, functioning, social support, child&#xD;
      protection behaviors, parenting attitudes and behaviors, and experiences of intimate partner&#xD;
      violence. The research also aims to interrogate implementation strategies that are useful&#xD;
      within humanitarian contexts through qualitative key informant interviews and focus group&#xD;
      discussions. Assessments include baseline and follow up data collection to measure effect&#xD;
      sizes and assess implementation strategy components. The study aims are to: (1) assess the&#xD;
      impact of JoL on child protection indicators, (2) examine the effects of JoL on behavioral&#xD;
      health functioning (i.e. mental health, social support, and functioning)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mental health</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in mental health symptoms according to the Kessler-6 from baseline to follow up assessments. The structure of the survey asks participants how frequently they have experienced certain symptoms in the past thirty days and presents a consistent scale of responses ranging from &quot;1 - All of the time&quot; to &quot;5 - None of the time&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in functioning according to the World Health Organization Disability Assessment Schedule (WHODAS) from baseline to follow up. The WHODAS uses a 12-item scale with a range of scores from 12 to 60, where higher scores indicate higher disability or loss of function.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Social support</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in social supports according to the Medical Outcomes Study Social Supports 8-item survey from baseline to follow up. The survey is scored using an average of scores for each item and transferring them to a 0-100 score where a higher score for an individual indicates more support.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Child protection attitudes</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the adoption of positive child protective behaviors from baseline to follow-up assessments according to the adapted Child Protection Index (CPI). The CPI is a 12-item instrument that assesses attitudes towards child protection with a scoring range of 0-12 wherein a higher number indicates more permissible attitudes towards beating children.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parenting behaviors</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the adoption of positive parenting behaviors from baseline to follow-up assessments according to the Parenting Acceptance and Rejection Questionnaire (PARQ). This 12-item subscale has a scoring range of 0-48 wherein higher scores indicate more acceptance of children.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1200</enrollment>
  <condition>Psychological</condition>
  <condition>Child Development</condition>
  <condition>Social Values</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Journey of Life Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Community members (caregivers, teachers, and community leaders) will participate in group workshops for a period of 6 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waitlist Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The waitlist control group will not receive the intervention during the first 6 months of implementation in order to assess the effects of the intervention compared to the control group. However, following intervention completion in the experimental group, the control group will receive 6 months of the intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Journey of Life</intervention_name>
    <description>The concept underlying the JoL intervention is that caregivers and community members can support each other and their children through reflection, dialogue, and action. JoL addresses children's and adolescents' ecologies by working with caregivers, educators, and community members to understand the importance of their support in protecting children.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Journey of Life Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Waitlist Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refugee living in Kiryandongo settlement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Caregiver for a child under age 18&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anyone aged 17 and under, unless written consent from the caregiver and assent from&#xD;
             the participant is provided&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anyone unable to provide consent to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>TPO Uganda</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bweyale</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>TPO Uganda</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kiryandongo</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Uganda</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Refugee</keyword>
  <keyword>Community development</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

