<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04814784</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Radiotherapy in rectal cancer</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04814784</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Role of Neoadjuvent Radiotherapy in Locally Advanced Cancer Rectum</brief_title>
  <official_title>Retrospective Study Comparing Neoadjuvent Short Course of Radiotherapy to Conventional Chemoradiation in Cancer Rectum</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Amany sayed Abass</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a retrospective study comparing neoadjuvent short course radiotherapy to conventional&#xD;
      chemoradiation in locally advanced cancer rectum and the effect of both regimens in overall&#xD;
      survival and disease free survival&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Colorectal cancer is the third most common cancer diagnosed in the western world. In 2019&#xD;
      there were approximately 44180 new cases of rectal cancer diagnosed in the United states.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the close proximity of the rectum to pelvic structures and organs, the absence of a&#xD;
      serious membrane surrounding the rectum and the restriction of the surgical view and access&#xD;
      by the pelvic cavity, the locoregional recurrence rate in rectal cancer is relatively high&#xD;
      after surgery alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neoadjuvent therapy rather than surgery followed by adjuvent therap has been the preferred&#xD;
      approach world wide in treatment of rectal cancer since the 2004 publication of the seminal&#xD;
      German CAO/ARO/AIO-94 study ,which compared preoperative with postoperative chemoradiation in&#xD;
      823 patients The use of neoadjuvent therapy is recommended for all newly diagnosed rectal&#xD;
      adenocarcinoma with a clinical stage T3 or T4 based on trans rectal endoscopic ultrasound or&#xD;
      pelvic MRI .Neoadjuvent therapy may comprise of either radiotherapy alone or in combination&#xD;
      with chemotherapy, commonly prescribed chemotherapy agents include 5-fluorouracil and&#xD;
      Oxaloplatin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both short course radiotherapy (25 Gy in 5 fractions) and long course radiotherapy (50.4Gy in&#xD;
      28 fractions, conventionally fractionated therapy)can be applied as neoadjuvent radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several phase lll RCTs,including three large well-designed international RCTs have reported&#xD;
      that short course neoadjuvent radiation treatment improves local control compared with&#xD;
      surgery alone in patients with respectable rectal cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also ,neoadjuvent chemoradiation with long course radiotherapy can be recommended for most&#xD;
      patients with stage ll- lll rectal cancer with the aim of reducing the risk of local&#xD;
      recurrence, for reducing rates of perioperative and post operative complications and in an&#xD;
      attempt to avoid radical surgery with permanent colostomy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of neoadjuvent radiotherapy in treatment of locally advanced cancer rectum</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Disease free survival.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Rectal Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Neoadjuvent radiotherapy either short or long course chemoradiation in treatment of locally advanced cancer rectum</intervention_name>
    <description>Study the effect of neoadjuvent radiotherapy in treatment of locally advanced cancer rectum e higher possiblity of preservation of anal sphincter and decreased rate of locoregional recurrence compared to surgery alone</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Locally advanced cancer rectum patients stage ll ,lll who received neoadjuvent radiotherapy&#xD;
        either short or long course chemoradiation before surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  histologically proved adenocarcinoma of the rectum&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 70 yrs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  T3 and T4 N1,N2 respectable tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The WHO performance score 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have a free metastatic work up excluded by chest x-ray , abdominal ultrasonography or&#xD;
             CT pelviabdomen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with locally advanced inoperable disease locally recurrent rectal cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  had a history of malignant tumor within 5 years except the skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant or lactating women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous irradiation in pelvis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  there was contraindication for neoadjuvent radiotherapy or surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mental disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amany Sayed Abass</last_name>
    <phone>+201066756847</phone>
    <email>amanysayed385@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Hanaa Sayed Abass</last_name>
    <phone>+201062149780</phone>
    <email>hanaasayed070@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Egypt cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mostafa Elsayed Abd Elwanees, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>+201221133032</phone>
      <email>mostafawanis@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Hoda Hassan Eisa, Professor</last_name>
      <phone>+201001732757</phone>
      <email>hodahassanessa@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mostafa Elsayed AbdElwanees, Professor</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018 Nov;68(6):394-424. doi: 10.3322/caac.21492. Epub 2018 Sep 12. Erratum in: CA Cancer J Clin. 2020 Jul;70(4):313.</citation>
    <PMID>30207593</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Song JH, Jeong JU, Lee JH, Kim SH, Cho HM, Um JW, Jang HS; Korean Clinical Practice Guideline for Colon and Rectal Cancer Committee. Preoperative chemoradiotherapy versus postoperative chemoradiotherapy for stage II-III resectable rectal cancer: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Radiat Oncol J. 2017 Sep;35(3):198-207. doi: 10.3857/roj.2017.00059. Epub 2017 Sep 15.</citation>
    <PMID>29037017</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sauer R, Becker H, Hohenberger W, Rödel C, Wittekind C, Fietkau R, Martus P, Tschmelitsch J, Hager E, Hess CF, Karstens JH, Liersch T, Schmidberger H, Raab R; German Rectal Cancer Study Group. Preoperative versus postoperative chemoradiotherapy for rectal cancer. N Engl J Med. 2004 Oct 21;351(17):1731-40.</citation>
    <PMID>15496622</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rödel C, Liersch T, Becker H, Fietkau R, Hohenberger W, Hothorn T, Graeven U, Arnold D, Lang-Welzenbach M, Raab HR, Sülberg H, Wittekind C, Potapov S, Staib L, Hess C, Weigang-Köhler K, Grabenbauer GG, Hoffmanns H, Lindemann F, Schlenska-Lange A, Folprecht G, Sauer R; German Rectal Cancer Study Group. Preoperative chemoradiotherapy and postoperative chemotherapy with fluorouracil and oxaliplatin versus fluorouracil alone in locally advanced rectal cancer: initial results of the German CAO/ARO/AIO-04 randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2012 Jul;13(7):679-87. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(12)70187-0. Epub 2012 May 23.</citation>
    <PMID>22627104</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li Y, Wang J, Ma X, Tan L, Yan Y, Xue C, Hui B, Liu R, Ma H, Ren J. A Review of Neoadjuvant Chemoradiotherapy for Locally Advanced Rectal Cancer. Int J Biol Sci. 2016 Jul 17;12(8):1022-31. doi: 10.7150/ijbs.15438. eCollection 2016. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27489505</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Amany sayed Abass</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Physician Dr</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

