<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04814862</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP210146</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>IDRCB: 2020-A02841-38</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04814862</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neurodevelopmental Disorders in Children With Systemic Inflammatory Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>Artemis</acronym>
  <official_title>Descriptive and Risk Factor Analysis of Neuropsychiatric and Neurodevelopmental Disorders in Children With Systemic Inflammatory Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Systemic inflammatory diseases in children include autoinflammatory diseases (deregulation of&#xD;
      the innate immune system with production of pro-inflammatory cytokines) and autoimmune&#xD;
      diseases (deregulation of the adaptive immune system with production of pathogenic&#xD;
      autoantibodies). Neurological damage has been reported in both cases, but the&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental psychiatric manifestations are poorly known, especially in children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neurodevelopmental disorders are a broad spectrum of pathologies that are underpinned by&#xD;
      common symptomatic dimensions. They have a common physiopathology combining genetic&#xD;
      predisposing factors as well as environmental risk factors, making it possible to study them&#xD;
      from a global point of view. Among the environmental risk factors, the immune system seems to&#xD;
      play an important role in the appearance of these pathologies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In recent years, fundamental and animal studies have pointed to an important role of the&#xD;
      immune system at the cerebral level. Indeed, far from the old notion of &quot;&quot;immune privilege&quot;&quot;,&#xD;
      the innate or adaptive immune balance seems to have a fundamental role in the proper&#xD;
      development and functioning of the brain. Consequently, any modification of the immune&#xD;
      balance could then disrupt neurodevelopment. Indeed, in recent years epidemiological studies&#xD;
      seem to indicate the role of immune-mediated events during pregnancy (maternal&#xD;
      autoimmune/inflammatory pathology or infection during pregnancy) or the first years of life&#xD;
      (autoimmune/inflammatory pathology) as risk factors for neurodevelopmental disorders.&#xD;
      Neurodevelopmental manifestations are very poorly known in systemic inflammatory pathologies.&#xD;
      They can have a significant impact and justify adapted care in order to limit the functional&#xD;
      impact. The main objective of our study will be to define the prevalence of&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental disorders in children with systemic inflammatory diseases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Systemic inflammatory diseases in children include auto-inflammatory diseases (deregulation&#xD;
      of the innate immune system with production of pro-inflammatory cytokines) and autoimmune&#xD;
      diseases (deregulation of the adaptive immune system with production of pathogenic&#xD;
      autoantibodies). Neurological damage has been reported in both cases, but the&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental psychiatric manifestations are poorly known, especially in children.&#xD;
      Neurodevelopmental disorders are a broad spectrum of pathologies with common symptomatic&#xD;
      dimensions. They present a common physiopathology combining genetic predisposition factors as&#xD;
      well as environmental risk factors, which allows them to be studied from a global&#xD;
      perspective. Among the environmental risk factors, the immune system seems to play an&#xD;
      important role in the appearance of these pathologies. In recent years, fundamental and&#xD;
      animal studies have highlighted an important role of the immune system at the cerebral level.&#xD;
      Indeed, far from the old notion of &quot;&quot;immune privilege&quot;&quot;, the innate or adaptive immune&#xD;
      balance seems to have a fundamental role in the proper development and functioning of the&#xD;
      brain. Consequently, any change in the immune balance could then disrupt neurological&#xD;
      development. Indeed, in recent years, epidemiological studies seem to indicate the role of&#xD;
      immune-mediated events during pregnancy (maternal autoimmune/inflammatory pathology or&#xD;
      infection during pregnancy) or the early years of life (autoimmune/inflammatory pathology) as&#xD;
      risk factors for neurodevelopmental disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neurodevelopmental manifestations are very poorly known in systemic inflammatory pathologies.&#xD;
      They can have a significant impact and justify adapted care in order to limit the functional&#xD;
      impact. Indeed, due to their pathology, these patients produce pro-inflammatory cytokines at&#xD;
      an early stage which could have an impact on their neurodevelopment. The identification of&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental disorders in these patients could be a clinical and epidemiological&#xD;
      validation of preclinical studies highlighting the importance of the immune system in the&#xD;
      proper development of the brain. The main objective of our study will be to define the&#xD;
      prevalence of neurodevelopmental disorders in children suffering from systemic inflammatory&#xD;
      diseases via the passing on by parents of children between 5 and 17 years old of three&#xD;
      hetero-questionnaires (i) SRS (assessing social interaction disorders), (ii) ADHD-RS&#xD;
      (assessing attentional and hyperactivity difficulties) (iii) BRIEF (assessing difficulties in&#xD;
      executive functions). All the results of these scales are adjusted for the age and sex of the&#xD;
      patients and provide a T-score (allowing a valid comparison).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a multi-centre cross-sectional study involving the collection of data from patients'&#xD;
      medical records and questionnaires from patients' parents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 6, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 6, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To define the prevalence of neurodevelopmental disorders in children with systemic inflammatory disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Number of children scoring above 75th percentile on ADHD-RS out of all patients presenting a systemic inflammatory pathology.&#xD;
All the results of these scales are adjusted for the age and sex of the patients (allowing a valid comparison).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To define the prevalence of neurodevelopmental disorders in children with systemic inflammatory disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Number of children scoring T-score above 60 on SRS out of all patients presenting a systemic inflammatory pathology.&#xD;
All the results of this scale are adjusted for the age and sex of the patients (allowing a valid comparison).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To define the prevalence of neurodevelopmental disorders in children with systemic inflammatory disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day</time_frame>
    <description>Number of children scoring above 1SD on BRIEF out of all patients presenting a systemic inflammatory pathology.&#xD;
All the results of this scale are adjusted for the age and sex of the patients (allowing a valid comparison).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Neurodevelopmental Disorders</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3 validated questionnaires (ADHD-RS, SRS, BRIEF) for the diagnosis of neurodevelopmental disorders</intervention_name>
    <description>Completion of three validated questionnaires for the diagnosis of neurodevelopmental disorders</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All pediatric patients with systemic inflammatory disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient with a systemic inflammatory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 5 and 17 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents informed and having signed a consent or having consented orally in case of&#xD;
             absence of one of the two parents&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient comprehension of the French language&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental retardation with IQ &lt;30&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not affiliated to a social security system&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Isabelle MELKI, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Isabelle MELKI, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+331 40 03 53 61</phone>
    <email>isabelle.melki@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pierre ELLUL, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+331 40 03 41 31</phone>
    <email>pierre.ellul@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neurodevelopmental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

