<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04819321</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>30339520.8.0000.5149</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04819321</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of White Adipose Tissue Remodeling by Cryolipolysis in Humans</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study of White Adipose Tissue Remodeling by Cryolipolysis in Humans</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Federal University of Minas Gerais</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Allergan Sales, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Federal University of Minas Gerais</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The sample will comprise 12 adult women (aged 18 to 40 years) and overweight (BMI&gt; 24.9 kg /&#xD;
      m² and &lt;30.0 kg / m²). The experimental design will consist of four assessments. In the first&#xD;
      assessments a structured questionnaire will be applied to obtain health and food consumption&#xD;
      data, in addition to evaluate anthropometric (weight, height, waist and hip circumference),&#xD;
      and collection of blood. In addition, an ultrasound examination, digital photography and&#xD;
      biopsy of the subcutaneous WAT, of the abdominal region, will be performed. After 30 day&#xD;
      subjects will undergo CoolSculpting treatment(s) in an outpatient clinical setting. The&#xD;
      treatment is comprised of timed segments of cooling and heating; a vacuum treatment may&#xD;
      include an optional massage. Treatments will be administered according to the User Manual&#xD;
      CoolSculpting System. The volunteers will return for the biopsy of the subcutaneous WAT, from&#xD;
      the abdominal region, in 3 days after the procedure. In 4º assessment, 60 days after&#xD;
      cryolipolysis, all evaluations performed in the first assessment will be repeated and to&#xD;
      evaluate overall patient satisfaction for non-invasive fat reduction in CoolSculpting&#xD;
      subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a longitudinal, non-randomized clinical trial to assess the biology of AT after the&#xD;
      use of cryolipolysis. The study will be developed at &quot;Clinica Dra Ligia Colucci&quot; in&#xD;
      partnership with the Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG). The project will be submitted&#xD;
      for evaluation by the Research Ethics Committee (COEP / UFMG). All participants must sign the&#xD;
      informed consent form (ICF), before the study begins.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The experimental design will consist of five stages. Initially, women will be public&#xD;
      recruitment. Through telephone contact, the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be&#xD;
      verified, and volunteers who meet the criteria will be invited to attend the clinic for the&#xD;
      first stage of the study. The presentation of the research, will be carried out 7 days before&#xD;
      the beginning of the treatment, will consist of presenting the project to the volunteers,&#xD;
      explaining all the risks and benefits related to the study and request the signature of the&#xD;
      ICF. After 7 days, the volunteers must return to the clinic, then start the study. In the&#xD;
      initial evaluation, an anamnesis of the volunteers will be carried out with a standardized&#xD;
      form, including socioeconomic and clinical data, data on the use of medications, alcohol&#xD;
      consumption, physical activity and food consumption. In addition, anthropometric assessments&#xD;
      will be performed where weight, height, waist, abdominal and hip circumference will be&#xD;
      measured. Ultrasonography will also be performed; the abdominal region will be photographed&#xD;
      and blood will be collected to measure lipolytic and inflammatory markers and a biopsy of the&#xD;
      subcutaneous WAT in the lower abdomen via umbilical scar. In addition, questionnaires will be&#xD;
      applied to check the volunteers' satisfaction with the treatment. After 30 days, the&#xD;
      volunteers must return to the clinic for time 0 (T0), where anthropometric assessments will&#xD;
      be repeated as control variables. Ultrasound and blood collection will also be performed.&#xD;
      Then the volunteers will be submitted to cryolipolysis in the abdominal region by the&#xD;
      Coolsculpting® system. After 3 days of performing the Coolsculpting® procedure, the&#xD;
      volunteers must return to the clinic for time 3 (T3), to perform a new biopsy of the&#xD;
      subcutaneous WAT in the lower abdomen via the umbilical scar. After 60 days of the&#xD;
      cryolipolysis, the volunteers must return to the clinic for the time 60 (T60), where all the&#xD;
      evaluations of the initial evaluation will be carried out again and a personal satisfaction&#xD;
      questionnaire will be applied in relation to the result of the procedure. Therefore, the&#xD;
      study will total 97 days of monitoring of women, who will be instructed to maintain healthy&#xD;
      lifestyle habits, according to the conventional lifestyle of each one of them. The data,&#xD;
      images and biological materials (blood and adipose tissue biopsy) collected in the research&#xD;
      will be filed with the researcher responsible for a period of 5 (five) years at the&#xD;
      Experimental Nutrition Laboratory, room 315, of the UFMG School of Nursing and after that&#xD;
      time will be destroyed. In case of occurrence of paradoxical adipose hyperplasia after the&#xD;
      procedure, a case study of the possible affected patients will be carried out.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The sample will comprise 12 adult women (aged 18 to 40 years) and overweight (BMI&gt; 24.9 kg / m² and &lt;30.0 kg / m²).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adipose tissue biology</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Fat cell death after cooling by cryolipolysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in volume of fat from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate change in volume of fat after CoolSculpting treatment(s) using ultrasound and photography.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Decrease in abdominal circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>decreased abdominal circumference after death of adipocytes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Browning of white adipose tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>3 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>browning of white adipose tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Paradoxical adipose hyperplasia</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 60 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>In case of occurrence of paradoxical adipose hyperplasia after the procedure, a case study of the possible affected patients will be carried out</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Lipid Metabolism Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CoolSculpting® System</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A treatment is comprised of timed segments of cooling and heating; a vacuum treatment may include an optional massage</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CoolSculpting® System</intervention_name>
    <description>A treatment is comprised of timed segments of cooling and heating; a vacuum treatment may include an optional massage</description>
    <arm_group_label>CoolSculpting® System</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has clearly visible fat in the flanks and/or abdomen, which in the&#xD;
             investigator's opinion, may benefit from the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject has not had weight change fluctuations exceeding 4.5 kg (or 5% of body weight) in&#xD;
        the preceding month.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject has a BMI of 24.9 to 30. A BMI is defined as weight in kilograms divided by height&#xD;
        in meters squared (kg/m2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject agrees to maintain weight (ie, within 5% of body weight) by not making any changes&#xD;
        in diet or exercise routine during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject agrees to have photographs taken of the treatment area(s) during the scheduled time&#xD;
        periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has had liposuction, or another surgical procedure(s) or mesotherapy in area&#xD;
             of intended treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject has had a non-invasive fat reduction and/or body contouring procedure in the&#xD;
        area(s) of intended treatment within the past 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject needs to administer, or has a known history of subcutaneous injections into the&#xD;
        area(s) of intended treatment (eg, cortisone, heparin, insulin) within the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject is pregnant or intending to become pregnant. Subject is lactating or has been&#xD;
        lactating in the past 6-9 months. Subject is unable or unwilling to comply with study&#xD;
        requirements. Subject is currently enrolled in a clinical study of any unapproved&#xD;
        investigational device, investigational product or any other type of medical research&#xD;
        judged not to be scientifically or medically compatible with this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject has an active implanted device such as a pacemaker, defibrillator, or drug delivery&#xD;
        system or any other metal containing implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with known history of cryoglobulinemia, cold agglutinin disease, or paroxysmal cold&#xD;
        hemoglobinuria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with known sensitivity to cold or has any condition with a known response to cold&#xD;
        exposure that limits blood flow to the skin such as cold urticaria or Raynaud's disease, or&#xD;
        Chilblains (pernio).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with known sensitivity or allergy to fructose, glycerin, isopropyl alcohol, or&#xD;
        propylene glycol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with impaired peripheral circulation in the area to be treated Subject with&#xD;
        neuropathic disorders such as post-herpetic neuralgia or diabetic neuropathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with impaired skin sensation. Subject with open or infected wounds. Subject with&#xD;
        bleeding disorders, or concomitant use of blood thinners, or is taking any medication that&#xD;
        in the investigator's opinion may increase the subject's risk of bruising.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with recent surgery or scar tissue in the area to be treated. Subject has history&#xD;
        of hernia in or adjacent to the treatment area(s) site. Subject with skin conditions such&#xD;
        as eczema, dermatitis, or rashes in the area to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject has any dermatological conditions, such as moderate to excessive skin laxity, or&#xD;
        scars in the location of the treatment sites that may interfere with the treatment or&#xD;
        evaluation (stretch marks is not an exclusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject is taking or has taken diet pills or supplements within the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any other condition or laboratory value that would, in the professional opinion of the&#xD;
        investigator, potentially affect the subject's response or the integrity of the data or&#xD;
        would pose an unacceptable risk to the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject diagnosed with fibrosis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mariele L Silva, Master</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Federal University of Minas Gerais</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Amanda CC Oliveira, Master</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Federal University of Minas Gerais</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adma M Babetto, Student</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Federal University of Minas Gerais</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adaliene VM Ferreira, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Federal University of Minas Gerais</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adaliene VM Ferreira, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+553134093680</phone>
    <email>adaliene@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Mariele L Silva, Master</last_name>
    <email>nutricionistamariele@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Departamento de Nutrição Escola de Enfermagem Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belo Horizonte</city>
        <state>MG</state>
        <zip>30130-100</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agrawal M, Kern PA, Nikolajczyk BS. The Immune System in Obesity: Developing Paradigms Amidst Inconvenient Truths. Curr Diab Rep. 2017 Aug 15;17(10):87. doi: 10.1007/s11892-017-0917-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28812211</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aldiss P, Betts J, Sale C, Pope M, Budge H, Symonds ME. Exercise-induced 'browning' of adipose tissues. Metabolism. 2018 Apr;81:63-70. doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2017.11.009. Epub 2017 Nov 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29155135</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Avram MM, Harry RS. Cryolipolysis for subcutaneous fat layer reduction. Lasers Surg Med. 2009 Dec;41(10):703-8. doi: 10.1002/lsm.20864. Review. Erratum in: Lasers Surg Med. 2012 Jul;44(5):436.</citation>
    <PMID>20014262</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Garibyan L, Sipprell WH 3rd, Jalian HR, Sakamoto FH, Avram M, Anderson RR. Three-dimensional volumetric quantification of fat loss following cryolipolysis. Lasers Surg Med. 2014 Feb;46(2):75-80. doi: 10.1002/lsm.22207. Epub 2013 Dec 3.</citation>
    <PMID>24535759</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Harms M, Seale P. Brown and beige fat: development, function and therapeutic potential. Nat Med. 2013 Oct;19(10):1252-63. doi: 10.1038/nm.3361. Epub 2013 Sep 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24100998</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ingargiola MJ, Motakef S, Chung MT, Vasconez HC, Sasaki GH. Cryolipolysis for fat reduction and body contouring: safety and efficacy of current treatment paradigms. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2015 Jun;135(6):1581-1590. doi: 10.1097/PRS.0000000000001236. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26017594</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kajimura S, Spiegelman BM, Seale P. Brown and Beige Fat: Physiological Roles beyond Heat Generation. Cell Metab. 2015 Oct 6;22(4):546-59. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2015.09.007. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26445512</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kilmer SL. Prototype CoolCup cryolipolysis applicator with over 40% reduced treatment time demonstrates equivalent safety and efficacy with greater patient preference. Lasers Surg Med. 2017 Jan;49(1):63-68. doi: 10.1002/lsm.22550. Epub 2016 Jun 21.</citation>
    <PMID>27327898</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kilmer SL, Burns AJ, Zelickson BD. Safety and efficacy of cryolipolysis for non-invasive reduction of submental fat. Lasers Surg Med. 2016 Jan;48(1):3-13. doi: 10.1002/lsm.22440. Epub 2015 Nov 26.</citation>
    <PMID>26607045</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Krueger N, Mai SV, Luebberding S, Sadick NS. Cryolipolysis for noninvasive body contouring: clinical efficacy and patient satisfaction. Clin Cosmet Investig Dermatol. 2014 Jun 26;7:201-5. doi: 10.2147/CCID.S44371. eCollection 2014. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25061326</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee P, Smith S, Linderman J, Courville AB, Brychta RJ, Dieckmann W, Werner CD, Chen KY, Celi FS. Temperature-acclimated brown adipose tissue modulates insulin sensitivity in humans. Diabetes. 2014 Nov;63(11):3686-98. doi: 10.2337/db14-0513. Epub 2014 Jun 22.</citation>
    <PMID>24954193</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Manstein D, Laubach H, Watanabe K, Farinelli W, Zurakowski D, Anderson RR. Selective cryolysis: a novel method of non-invasive fat removal. Lasers Surg Med. 2008 Nov;40(9):595-604. doi: 10.1002/lsm.20719.</citation>
    <PMID>18951424</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nelson AA, Wasserman D, Avram MM. Cryolipolysis for reduction of excess adipose tissue. Semin Cutan Med Surg. 2009 Dec;28(4):244-9. doi: 10.1016/j.sder.2009.11.004.</citation>
    <PMID>20123423</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shek SY, Chan NP, Chan HH. Non-invasive cryolipolysis for body contouring in Chinese--a first commercial experience. Lasers Surg Med. 2012 Feb;44(2):125-30. doi: 10.1002/lsm.21145. Erratum in: Lasers Surg Med. 2012 Jul;44(5):435.</citation>
    <PMID>22334296</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Leal Silva H, Carmona Hernandez E, Grijalva Vazquez M, Leal Delgado S, Perez Blanco A. Noninvasive submental fat reduction using colder cryolipolysis. J Cosmet Dermatol. 2017 Dec;16(4):460-465. doi: 10.1111/jocd.12383. Epub 2017 Sep 12.</citation>
    <PMID>28901051</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stevens WG, Bachelor EP. Cryolipolysis conformable-surface applicator for nonsurgical fat reduction in lateral thighs. Aesthet Surg J. 2015 Jan;35(1):66-71. doi: 10.1093/asj/sju024.</citation>
    <PMID>25568236</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sun K, Kusminski CM, Scherer PE. Adipose tissue remodeling and obesity. J Clin Invest. 2011 Jun;121(6):2094-101. doi: 10.1172/JCI45887. Epub 2011 Jun 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21633177</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yoneshiro T, Aita S, Matsushita M, Kayahara T, Kameya T, Kawai Y, Iwanaga T, Saito M. Recruited brown adipose tissue as an antiobesity agent in humans. J Clin Invest. 2013 Aug;123(8):3404-8. doi: 10.1172/JCI67803. Epub 2013 Jul 15.</citation>
    <PMID>23867622</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Federal University of Minas Gerais</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Adaliene Versiani M. Ferreira</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Adaliene Versiani M. Ferreira, PHD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CoolSculpting</keyword>
  <keyword>adipose tissue</keyword>
  <keyword>cryolipolysis</keyword>
  <keyword>browning</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lipid Metabolism Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

