<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04812158</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VAMDB01</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>INTI-FHLS-04-01-2016</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>EMOTIV, 6251/L29</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04812158</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Video Aided Mindful Deep Breathing for Pain Management</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Mindfulness Training in Chronic Ankle Instability Among Collegiate Athletes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic ankle instability (CAI) is the most common musculoskeletal injury in sports and the&#xD;
      rate of CAI accounts for 85% of ankle injuries. It has been estimated that 23,000 ankle&#xD;
      sprains occur each day in the United States, representing approximately 1 sprain per 10,000&#xD;
      people per day and nearly one in five ankle injuries result in chronic symptoms. Numerous&#xD;
      researchers applied mindfulness for improving the performance of various sports such as table&#xD;
      tennis, shooting, cricket, archery, golf, swimming, and cycling. Since many of the players do&#xD;
      not possess effective pain coping skills, they are at risk for lifelong impairment of their&#xD;
      emotional, social, and physical functioning. Mindfulness-centered interventions may well&#xD;
      serve to mitigate pain-related disability. Training in mindfulness meditation improves&#xD;
      anxiety, depression, stress, and cognition. Mindfulness-related health benefits are&#xD;
      associated with enhancements in cognitive control, emotion regulation, positive mood, and&#xD;
      acceptance, each of which have been associated with pain modulation. Since mindfulness has&#xD;
      been proven effective in managing various health disorders and in enhancing sports&#xD;
      performance, our study aims to apply the mindfulness approach in rehabilitating the most&#xD;
      common sports injury, CAI. The improvement in CAI due to the mindfulness approach will be&#xD;
      assessed by the improvement in pain response through the Cumberland ankle instability tool,&#xD;
      Functional ankle disability index (FADI), Visual analog scale (VAS), Brief Pain Inventory&#xD;
      (BPI), Y-balance test, Mindfulness attention awareness score (MAAS), Oxford Happiness&#xD;
      Questionnaire (OHQ) quantitative electroencephalography (Q-EEG). This study finding will be&#xD;
      useful in assessing the effectiveness of mindfulness in rehabilitating CAI and identify the&#xD;
      correlation of CAI pain response with VAS &amp; BPI, quantitative electroencephalography - Q-EEG.&#xD;
      In this clinical trial, the investigators wish to use noninvasive methods such as&#xD;
      quantitative EEG (electroencephalogram) to find the brainwave patterns during the different&#xD;
      stages of mindfulness intervention (pre and post). The outcome of this study will eventually&#xD;
      lead to the identification of a better assessment method to indicate the pain response for&#xD;
      the appropriate physiotherapy management. The application of mindfulness technique in CAI&#xD;
      management and the usage of Q- EEG to assess the pain response in chronic ankle injury&#xD;
      athletes are the novel approaches of this research study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inversion Ankle injuries (IAS) are among the most common musculoskeletal injuries in sports&#xD;
      and the rate of IAS accounts for 85% of ankle injuries. The hallmarks of chronic ankle&#xD;
      instability (CAI) include repeated ankle sprains that have led to an altered patient activity&#xD;
      level. Important factors include injuries sustained, frequency of events, localization of&#xD;
      pain, and prior treatment modalities. The degree of disability appreciated by the patient is&#xD;
      one of the most important factors and can be significant in both high- and low-demand&#xD;
      individuals. The most commonly cited characteristics of CAI include giving way to the ankle,&#xD;
      mechanical instability, pain and swelling, loss of strength, recurrent sprain, and functional&#xD;
      instability. Residual problems can persist for decades, with up to 72% of people unable to&#xD;
      return to their previous level of activity, such as fear of the ankle giving way. Functional&#xD;
      ankle instability includes a perceived or actual giving way of the ankle (or both) and other&#xD;
      characteristics previously associated with CAI in general: pain, swelling, and recurrent&#xD;
      sprain. Functional insufficiencies among individuals with either CAI have been demonstrated&#xD;
      by quantifying deficits in ankle neuromuscular response times, postural control, and&#xD;
      strength.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers have found that injured athletes experience clinically significant depression 6&#xD;
      times as often as non-injured athletes. Injured athletes also exhibit significantly greater&#xD;
      anxiety and lower self-esteem than non-injured. Athletes with more severe injuries are more&#xD;
      likely to become depressed than the non-injured. Since many of the players do not possess&#xD;
      effective pain coping skills, they are at risk for lifelong impairment of their emotional,&#xD;
      social, and physical functioning. Mindfulness-centered interventions may well serve to&#xD;
      mitigate a pain-related disability. Training in mindfulness meditation improves anxiety,&#xD;
      depression, stress, and cognition. Mindfulness-related health benefits are associated with&#xD;
      enhancements in cognitive control, emotion regulation, positive mood, and acceptance,&#xD;
      happiness each of which have been associated with pain modulation. Successively mindfulness&#xD;
      has been proven effective in managing various health disorders and in enhancing sports&#xD;
      performance. This study aims to apply the video-assisted mindfulness deep breathing training&#xD;
      (VAMDBT) approach in rehabilitating CAI, the most common sports injury. In addition, applies&#xD;
      Quantitative Electroencephalogram (QEEG) as one of the parameters to measure the pain&#xD;
      response of collegiate athletes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Literature Chronic ankle pain can affect all age groups, ranging from young athletes to&#xD;
      elderly patients with degenerative joint and soft-tissue disorders. Although physical&#xD;
      activity brings a range of lifelong health benefits, it may also lead to injuries that pose a&#xD;
      significant threat to health. Among 90 Plus League volleyball players age 18-37, over 87% of&#xD;
      the respondents suffered from at least one sport-related injury. In total, 362 injuries&#xD;
      occurred, on average 4.02 injuries per one volleyball player. The most commonly involved&#xD;
      sports injuries were ankle sprains (46 injuries), knee and lower leg muscles (30),&#xD;
      interphalangeal articulations of fingers (30) as well as the shoulder joint. More than half&#xD;
      of the injuries (57%) occurred twice or three times.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pattern of musculoskeletal injuries sustained by Malaysian badminton players who attended&#xD;
      the National Sports Institute (NSI) Clinic, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. The mean age of the&#xD;
      players who attended the clinic was 19.2 (range 13-52) years. Approximately 60 percent of the&#xD;
      injuries occurred in players younger than 20 years of age. The majority of injuries (91.5&#xD;
      percent) were categorized as mild overuse injuries and mostly involved the knee and ankle.&#xD;
      The prevalence of sports injuries among 475 male professional athletes participating in ball&#xD;
      sports who are aged 15 years and older, from 5 sports clubs in Kuwait. About 452 athletes&#xD;
      from four ball games (football (soccer), basketball, handball, and volleyball) were included&#xD;
      in this study. The study found that the overall 12-month and lifetime prevalence of sports&#xD;
      injuries were 73.8 and 89.8%, respectively. Lower limbs (73.1%) were the most common site of&#xD;
      injuries and joint injuries (43.6%) were the most common type of injury reported. The study&#xD;
      analyzed the characteristics of injuries and associated personal and training characteristics&#xD;
      in young basketball players of both sexes. A conducted one-year retrospective cross-sectional&#xD;
      survey with 581 basketball players (350 males and 231 females) participated in the school&#xD;
      games and high school Olympics in the state of São Paulo, Brazil. The study used a&#xD;
      questionnaire that contained items addressing anthropometric data and characteristics of&#xD;
      injuries that have occurred in the previous 12 months. Results showed a total of 167 of the&#xD;
      athletes reported injuries and the male gender exhibited a greater risk of injury than the&#xD;
      female gender. The most affected anatomic sites were the ankle/foot and knee. A study that&#xD;
      investigates the pattern of muscle injuries and the factors that predict the return-to-play&#xD;
      duration among Malaysian athletes who attended the National Sports Institute Clinic. About&#xD;
      397 muscle injuries were diagnosed among 360 athletes from the period June 2006 to December&#xD;
      2009. The median age of the athletes with muscle injuries was 20.0 years. Muscle injuries&#xD;
      were mostly diagnosed among national-level athletes and frequently involved the lower limb.&#xD;
      There is a twofold increased risk for ankle injury recurrence for at least one-year&#xD;
      post-injury. In up to 50% of all cases, recurrences result in disability and lead to chronic&#xD;
      pain or instability, requiring prolonged medical care. Therefore, ankle sprain recurrence&#xD;
      prevention in athletes is essential. A study that measured preseason anxiety and depression&#xD;
      reported a total of 597 injuries with 40.6% preseason injuries, 28.8%, and 21.7% of athletes&#xD;
      suffered from anxiety and depressive symptoms. Another study stated depression and anxiety&#xD;
      disorders have a negative effect on subjective well-being. The Oxford Happiness Scale, Life&#xD;
      Satisfaction Scale response among 284 patients shows that participants were found to be&#xD;
      moderately happy and satisfied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic Ankle Injury Rehabilitation Ankle sprains are a common problem seen by primary care&#xD;
      physicians, especially among teenagers and young adults. Early mobilization speeds healing&#xD;
      and reduce pain more effectively than prolonged rest. A previous ankle sprain is the greatest&#xD;
      risk factor for an acute ankle sprain, it is important to counsel the recovering patients on&#xD;
      prevention strategies. Ankle braces and supports, ankle taping, a focused neuromuscular&#xD;
      training program, and regular sport-specific warm-up exercises have proven to protect against&#xD;
      ankle injuries, and have to be considered for patients returning to sports or other high-risk&#xD;
      activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mindfulness Recent attention in healthcare research has been paid to the concept of&#xD;
      mindfulness and its contributions to clinical practice. Mindfulness refers to the way&#xD;
      individuals pay attention to their experiences from moment to moment with non-judgmental&#xD;
      attitudes. The cultivation of mindfulness requires regular practice of mindful breathing and&#xD;
      different types of meditation. Mindfulness meditation has been found to improve a wide&#xD;
      spectrum of cognitive and health outcomes. Training in mindfulness meditation improves&#xD;
      anxiety, depression, stress, and cognition. Mindfulness-related health benefits are&#xD;
      associated with enhancements in cognitive control, emotion regulation, positive mood, and&#xD;
      acceptance, each of which has been associated with pain modulation. Thus, it seems reasonable&#xD;
      to hypothesize that mindfulness meditation itself would attenuate pain through some of these&#xD;
      mechanisms. A mindfulness training for eight weeks duration was shown to improve pain&#xD;
      acceptance in lower back pain patients. Neurophysiological changes are consistent with a&#xD;
      bio-psycho-social formulation reflecting the underlying mechanisms associated with sensory&#xD;
      and motor findings, psychological traits, and perceptual changes associated with chronic&#xD;
      musculoskeletal conditions. These changes, therefore, have important implications in the&#xD;
      clinical manifestation, pathophysiology, and rehabilitative treatment of chronic&#xD;
      musculoskeletal disorders. Musculoskeletal rehabilitation professionals have at their&#xD;
      disposal tools to address these neuroplastic changes including top-down cognitive-based&#xD;
      interventions (such as education, cognitive behavioral therapy, mindfulness meditation, and&#xD;
      motor imagery), and bottom-up physical interventions (such as motor learning, peripheral&#xD;
      sensory stimulation, and manual therapy) that induce neuroplastic changes across distributed&#xD;
      areas of the nervous system and impact outcomes in patients with chronic musculoskeletal&#xD;
      disorders. Mindful exercise executed with profound and nonjudgmental attention to breathing&#xD;
      and proprioceptive awareness of muscles and movements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of Mindfulness Approach:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pilot study using an 8-week mindfulness-based stress reduction (MBSR) program on a sample&#xD;
      of low back pain patients was conducted in order to assess the feasibility and effectiveness&#xD;
      of the intervention as well as changes in an EEG pattern called thalamocortical dysrhythmia&#xD;
      which is associated with chronic pain. The study involved 22 patients with chronic low back&#xD;
      pain who participated in an MBSR program. The result showed a medium-sized effect for&#xD;
      psychological functioning, pain severity, and quality of life. However, EEG analyses revealed&#xD;
      no differences between the pre-and post-intervention. The major concerns from the previous&#xD;
      mindfulness studies about the participant's compliance reported were time constraints and&#xD;
      personal commitments. The high demand in time and the need for guidance from a coach can&#xD;
      discourage the community from taking up these practices as well. For a full MBSR course, it&#xD;
      can take up to eight weeks, with weekly meetings that last for about three hours and the&#xD;
      daily practice of about an hour. This can be difficult to adhere to especially in the current&#xD;
      fast-paced lifestyle of young people. With due consideration of participants' compliance, the&#xD;
      mindfulness intervention practice of the present study has been modified to 5- min&#xD;
      video-assisted mindfulness deep breathing. Furthermore, the follow-up of participants' home&#xD;
      practices will be monitored with the use of a smartphone app that has the facility to send&#xD;
      reminders as text messages to fill in the practice diaries or online portals to record the&#xD;
      frequency of home practice of our intervention. A recent study on short-duration,&#xD;
      video-assisted deep breathing among healthy young adults showed that the participants engaged&#xD;
      for 5 min deep breathing revealed profound NoGo N2 amplitude increment as compared to the&#xD;
      control group in the follow-up session. Results indicated the possibility of performing&#xD;
      short-duration deep breathing guided by video-assisted deep breathing to achieve an enhanced&#xD;
      conflict monitoring as an alternative to other mindfulness practices. Therefore the objective&#xD;
      of this study is to find the effectiveness of VAMDBT in the recovery of chronic ankle&#xD;
      instability among collegiate athletes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 19, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 19, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline ankle stability by Cumberland Ankle Instability Tool (CAIT), 9-item scores at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Cumberland Ankle Instability Tool (CAIT), is a reliable and valid tool to assess the balance of participants with ≤27 in the CAIT tool over 30, where lower scores represent &quot;poor&quot; ankle stability and higher scores represent &quot;better&quot; ankle stability. Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline dynamic ankle stability by Y-balance test (YBT) scores at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Y balance test (YBT) is a valid and reliable tool to measure participants' dynamic balance of affected ankle distance in anterior, posterolateral, and posteromedial directions, where lower scores represent &quot;poor&quot; ankle stability and higher scores represent &quot;better&quot; ankle stability. Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in pain by visual analog scale (VAS) at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A visual analog scale (VAS) is a valid and reliable self-reported tool to record participants' pain intensity on a 10 cm line to point out the pain level. The point at 0 cm represents &quot;no pain&quot; and 10 cm represents &quot;worst pain&quot;, where higher scores represent better ankle stability. Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in pain by Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Brief Pain Inventory (BPI) is a valid and reliable tool to record participants pain intensity and interference with the 4- items (worst pain, least pain, average pain, and pain right now) to measure the pain intensity, and 7 -items (general activity, mood, walking, normal work, relations, sleep, enjoyment of life) to assess the pain interference. The participants are instructed to report the pain intensity from 0 (no pain) to 10 (as pain bad as the participants can imagine). Similarly, the pain interference is recorded from 0 (does not interfere) to 10 (completely interferes). Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline ankle stability by Functional ankle disability index (FADI ), 34-item scores at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Functional ankle disability index (FADI) is a validated tool to assess participant's balance during general daily activity and sports-specific functions, where lower scores represent &quot;poor&quot; ankle stability and higher scores represent &quot;better&quot; ankle stability. Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline attention by Mindful Attention Awareness Scale (MAAS), 15-item scores at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The changes in the mind adaptation of participants are obtained from the Likert scale rating from 1(almost always) to 6 (almost never), MAAS is a reliable tool. Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline attention by Oxford Happiness Questionnaire (OHQ), 29-item scores at week 3, week 6 and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The participants' happiness level is assessed using the reliable tool Oxford Happiness Questionnaire (OHQ), which consists of a 29-item questionnaire. The OHQ score will be recorded on 6 points Likert scale from 1 (strongly disagree) to 6 (strongly agree).&#xD;
Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline Alpha waves by Non-invasive wireless electroencephalogram (EEG) at week 3, week 6, and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The 14- channel electrodes were placed at a sampling rate of 128 Hz, in compliance with the International 10-20 System nomenclature. The increase or decrease in alpha wave EEG recordings of the participants are recorded in eyes closed and eyes open for 2mins.&#xD;
Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline Beta waves by Non-invasive wireless electroencephalogram (EEG) at week 3, week 6, and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The 14- channel electrodes were placed at a sampling rate of 128 Hz, in compliance with the International 10-20 System nomenclature. The increase or decrease in beta wave EEG recordings of the participants are recorded in eyes closed and eyes open for 2mins.&#xD;
Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline Theta waves by Non-invasive wireless electroencephalogram (EEG) at week 3, week 6, and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The 14- channel electrodes were placed at a sampling rate of 128 Hz, in compliance with the International 10-20 System nomenclature. The increase or decrease in theta wave EEG recordings of the participants are recorded in eyes closed and eyes open for 2mins.&#xD;
Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline delta waves by Non-invasive wireless electroencephalogram (EEG) at week 3, week 6, and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The 14- channel electrodes were placed at a sampling rate of 128 Hz, in compliance with the International 10-20 System nomenclature. The increase or decrease in delta wave EEG recordings of the participants are recorded in eyes closed and eyes open for 2mins.&#xD;
Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline gamma waves by Non-invasive wireless electroencephalogram (EEG) at week 3, week 6, and week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3 Weeks,6 Weeks, 12 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The 14- channel electrodes were placed at a sampling rate of 128 Hz, in compliance with the International 10-20 System nomenclature. The increase or decrease in gamma wave EEG recordings of the participants are recorded in eyes closed and eyes open for 2mins.&#xD;
Change =(Week 3 score - Baseline, Week 6 score - Baseline, Week 12 score - Baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Pain</condition>
  <condition>Ankle Injuries</condition>
  <condition>Joint Instability</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>participants in the control group receive gold standard physiotherapy intervention 5 times a week for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3 min video-aided mindful deep breathing (VAMDB) or visual guiding on deep breathing with 6 deep breath per minute along with standard physiotherapy (SP) protocol and the control group was given standard physiotherapy (SP) protocol 5 times a week for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Active healthy participants who engaged in regular collegial sports</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>standard ankle physiotherapy or rehabilitation for chronic ankle instability</intervention_name>
    <description>6 weeks of combined interventions of video aided mindful deep breathing and standard ankle physiotherapy in rehabilitating the chronic ankle instability for participants with chronic ankle instability</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Video aided mindful deep breathing with standard ankle physiotherapy or rehabilitation for chronic ankle instability</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CAIT scores ≤27&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ranging from 18 to 25&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  male participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous history of ankle sprains&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  referred chronic ankle instability for physiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of previous surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  under pain-relieving medicine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  under deep breathing or meditation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  bilateral ankle sprains&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acute musculoskeletal injuries of lower limb&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>The brain signals response differs between the genders and the relative power of beta and theta waves found to be dominant in males</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>INTI physiotherapy centre, Nilai</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seremban</city>
        <state>Negeri Sembilan</state>
        <zip>71800</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universiti Tunku Abdul Rahman</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lee Poh Foong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>Breathing</keyword>
  <keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>Athletes</keyword>
  <keyword>Physiotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Electroencephalography</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Joint Instability</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ankle Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Based on informed consent participants data not shared</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 15, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/58/NCT04812158/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

