<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04815434</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RNI 2020 FAULKS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04815434</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Experience and Understanding of the Mouth, Oral Health and Function Amongst Adults With Disabilities and Complex Health Conditions.</brief_title>
  <acronym>FAULKS</acronym>
  <official_title>Experience and Understanding of the Mouth, Oral Health and Function Amongst</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre de Recherche en Odontologie Clinique (CROC), Clermont-Ferrand</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dental institute, King's College, Londres, UK</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Dublin, Trinity College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cork Dental School, Irlande</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Oral health is the one of the commonest causes of health problems in the world, with almost&#xD;
      all individuals suffering from reduced oral health at some stage over their life span. As&#xD;
      such, oral health is a major public health issue and a major consumer of health spending.&#xD;
      Poor oral health results in pain, infection, structural degradation, functional restrictions&#xD;
      in chewing, swallowing and speech, change in facial appearance, social stigma, altered body&#xD;
      image, and reduced capacity to participate in social events, amongst others. Global problems&#xD;
      of human functioning, disability, health and environment in turn affect oral status in many&#xD;
      complex ways (for example, ability to maintain oral hygiene, nutritional restrictions,&#xD;
      neuromotor incapacity, dysphagia, ability to access and cooperate with treatment, etc).&#xD;
      Disability arises from a social environment that fails to enable everyone to access it&#xD;
      regardless of his or her impairment. Disabilities are thus socially created and not dependent&#xD;
      on the individual's type or location of impairment. There is currently very limited&#xD;
      qualitative research exploring perceptions of the mouth, or oral health within a social&#xD;
      environment, from the perspective of disabled adults. No universal, holistic, comprehensive&#xD;
      tool exists to describe oral health, the functional impact of oral health, and the&#xD;
      environmental factors influencing oral health within the biopsychosocial model. It has been&#xD;
      suggested that a framework for such an instrument may be supplied by the International&#xD;
      Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health (ICF: World Health Organisation, 2001)&#xD;
      This research seeks to address these gaps by describing perceptions of the mouth from the&#xD;
      perspective of adults with disabilities and complex health conditions, and by linking this&#xD;
      qualitative data to the ICF in order to assess the feasibility of using the ICF to&#xD;
      conceptualise oral health. Adults with disabilities and complex health conditions were chosen&#xD;
      for this ICF core set preliminary study as existing literature suggests that these&#xD;
      respondents would accumulate not only a high level of oral health need but also experience&#xD;
      high impact of functioning and environment on oral health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A Case Record Form will be completed during the interview with the participant and/or their&#xD;
      carer. The form will record data relating to sociodemographics along with a subjective&#xD;
      appreciation of general health, oral health and mental health. Sociodemographic data will&#xD;
      include age, gender, level of education (age on completion / highest level), occupation,&#xD;
      income band and housing tenure (own house, parent's house, institution).&#xD;
&#xD;
      An investigator will undertake the interviews. Before starting data collection, the procedure&#xD;
      of the session will be explained and the aims of the study presented in lay terms. The&#xD;
      investigator will state that the individual has the possibility to refuse or withdraw his/her&#xD;
      participation at any time without consequences, and on simple request. Where possible, the&#xD;
      interviews will take place face to face, but may be undertaken over the telephone or by&#xD;
      video-conferencing if necessary. Audio recording will be undertaken during each interview.&#xD;
      During the interview, field notes will be taken in order to record elements of non-verbal&#xD;
      communication. The investigator will use a indicative topic guide covering six areas to&#xD;
      initiate a discussion. The investigator will use a indicative topic guide covering six areas&#xD;
      to initiate a discussion:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  How would you describe your health and your oral health?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Do you have any health conditions which affect your mouth in any way?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If so, which part of your mouth is affected and how?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What is the impact of your oral health on your daily life?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Do your living conditions or your social environment impact on your oral health in any&#xD;
           way?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If you had to describe the impact of your oral health on daily life to someone what&#xD;
           would you say? Each question includes a series of prompts to assist participants in&#xD;
           answering the question.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is anticipated that each interview will take around 60 minutes to complete.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 27, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 27, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview &quot;experiences of the mouth in adults with disabilities and complex health conditions&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Interview will allow to gain understanding of the experiences of the mouth in adults with disabilities and complex health conditions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview &quot;Inter-relationships between the mouth, oral health, functioning and the social environment amongst adults with disabilities and complex health conditions.&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Interview will allow to gain understanding of the inter-relationships between the mouth, oral health, functioning and the social environment amongst adults with disabilities and complex health conditions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Interview &quot;Ability of the ICF to contextualize experiences of oral health&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Interview will allow to gain insight into the ability of the ICF to contextualise experiences of oral health</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">18</enrollment>
  <condition>Adult</condition>
  <condition>Disability</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Disease</condition>
  <condition>Oral Health</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adults with disabilities and complex health conditions</arm_group_label>
    <description>Interviews, experience of the mouth and oral health and function</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interview</intervention_name>
    <description>Interviews will be conducted.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Adults with disabilities and complex health conditions</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults with self-defined disabilities and/or complex health conditions&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adults 18 years of age or over on day of data collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adults with self-defined disabilities and/or complex health conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  agreement to participate from the disabled adult or his/her carer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adults under 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adults without self-defined disabilities and/or complex health conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  refusal to participate from the disabled adult or his/her carer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UFR d'Odontologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-Ferrand</city>
        <state>Aura</state>
        <zip>63000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Disable person</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Qualitative research</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral Health</keyword>
  <keyword>Sociological factors</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>Body image</keyword>
  <keyword>Adult</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

