<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04819607</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21/44</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04819607</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Evaluating Multidisciplinary Bone Marrow Failure Care in Bone Marrow Failure and Related Disorders.</brief_title>
  <acronym>EMBRACE</acronym>
  <official_title>The Evaluating Multidisciplinary Bone Marrow Failure Care in Bone Marrow Failure and Related Disorders.(The EMBRACE Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre, Australia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre, Australia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective hybrid implementation-effectiveness study of a model of care for&#xD;
      patients with bone marrow failure syndromes and inherited predisposition to haematological&#xD;
      malignancy that includes comprehensive diagnostic genomic evaluation, multidisciplinary case&#xD;
      review, provision of clinical care including from clinical haematologists, medical&#xD;
      geneticists and genetic counsellors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The inherited bone marrow disorders (IBMD) comprise both the traditional inherited bone&#xD;
      marrow failure syndromes (BMFS) and the more recently described entity of germline&#xD;
      predisposition to haematological malignancy. Patients with IBMD often present highly complex&#xD;
      health issues that are unique and not commonly encountered. As a consequence, clinicians may&#xD;
      feel less confident in managing these unique issues given their lack of frequent exposure to&#xD;
      this patient group. Recent advances in genomics have resulted in more accurate diagnosis of&#xD;
      IBMD and their subtyping and have resulted in a rapidly evolving field with multiple&#xD;
      opportunities to improve patient outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stage 1 of this study evaluated and quantified the current challenges faced by 3 stakeholder&#xD;
      groups, patients with IBMD, patient advocates and nationally, clinicians who care for IBMD&#xD;
      patients. The results demonstrated that the challenges described in Stage 1 may be overcome&#xD;
      by instigating a multidisciplinary approach to care for BMF patients. Interventions designed&#xD;
      to address the challenges identified in stage 1 form the model of multidisciplinary care to&#xD;
      be implemented in the Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre/ Royal Melbourne Hospital clinic. The&#xD;
      model of care involves:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Provide access to genetic testing with expert result interpretation&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Presentation of clinical information and relevant investigations (including genetic) at&#xD;
           a multidisciplinary team meeting involving haematologists, molecular&#xD;
           haematopathologists, clinical genetics, genetic counsellors, scientists and specialised&#xD;
           nurses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Provision of a suggested care plan to clinician&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Genetic counselling and provision of written disease specific information including&#xD;
           details of suggested care plan to patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Genetic counselling and provision of written information and access to testing for at&#xD;
           risk family members&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Dedicated team focused on many individually rare diseases with a demonstrated focus on&#xD;
           provision of comprehensive care&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Opportunity to participate in local and international research&#xD;
&#xD;
      The EMBRACE study will focus on evaluating the model of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>to assess the effectiveness and implementation of the model of care through a mixture of objective metrics and patient /physician reported outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Effectiveness - patient/physician reported outcomes of satisfaction with model of care as measured by questionnaire Implementation - compliance with of model as measured by audit against pre-specified key performance indicators</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess longitudinal quality of life assessment in patients being treated with the model</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Longitudinal quality of life assessment in patients being treated with the model measured by the EORTC QLQ-C30</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To quantitate healthcare usage of patients within the model</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitate healthcare usage of patients within the model measured by questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Bone Marrow Failure Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Aplastic Anemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BMFS patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with BMFS attending Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre haematology clinic.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>model of care</intervention_name>
    <description>Multidisciplinary model of care for BMFS patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BMFS patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with a diagnosis of inherited bone marrow disorder (IBMD) including traditional&#xD;
        inherited bone marrow failure syndromes (BMFS) and germline predisposition to&#xD;
        haematological malignancy who meet all the inclusion criteria will be eligible for&#xD;
        participation in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must meet all the following criteria for study entry:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age &gt; or = 18 years at enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to give informed consent (or responsible family member able to give informed&#xD;
             consent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient is receiving care under the institutional guidelines/stream model of care&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patient not eligible for management under the model of care&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Piers Blombery, MBBS(Hons)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre, Australia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mary Panjari, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>03 8559 5000</phone>
    <email>mary.panjari@petermac.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Peter MacCallum Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lucy Fox</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Aplastic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Marrow Failure Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pancytopenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

