<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04813029</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SLR2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04813029</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Thresholds of Straight Leg Raise Maneuver During High-Resolution-Manometry</brief_title>
  <official_title>Defining High-Resolution Manometry Thresholds of Backward Pressure Across the Lower Esophageal Sphincter Through Straight Leg Raise Maneuver Predictive of Pathologic Acid Exposure Time</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Milan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medical University of Vienna</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital Padova</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Missouri, St. Louis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Oregon Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Functional Gut Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Texas at Austin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Athens</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ohio State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jikei University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Milan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      High resolution manometry (HRM) is a key test in the preoperative assessment of patients with&#xD;
      gastro-esophageal reflux disease (GERD) who are potential candidates for antireflux surgery.&#xD;
      The recent Lyon consensus suggested the potential usefulness of HRM in diagnosing GERD,&#xD;
      however, sensitivity and specificity of HRM for GERD remains low (53.6% and 72.5%&#xD;
      respectively). Among recently proposed provocative tests during manometry, a traditional&#xD;
      maneuver (straight leg raise maneuver, SLR) appeared promising in predicting reflux.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a multicenter study involving high-volume esophageal function laboratories around the&#xD;
      world. Patients with suspected GERD and tested with HRM and pH-impedance will be asked to&#xD;
      perform SLR during HRM. Intra-abdominal and intra-esophageal pressure during SLR will be&#xD;
      recorded and compared with acid exposure time (AET) at pH-impedance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary aim is to determine the optimal threshold of intra-esophageal pressure augmentation&#xD;
      during straight leg raise (SLR) maneuver that predicts pathological esophageal acid exposure&#xD;
      time (AET). Secondary aim is to assess the diagnostic performance of HMR with SRL maneuver,&#xD;
      calculating sensitivity, specificity, false-positive rate (FPR), false-negative rate (FNR),&#xD;
      positive predictive value and total misclassification rate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      It has been demonstrated a low sensitivity and specificity of HRM for GERD (53.6% and 72.5%&#xD;
      respectively), since there was a significant overlap between patients and controls in the&#xD;
      majority of parameters. Masuda et al. attempted to improve HRM accuracy using a comprehensive&#xD;
      index and new parameters, such as the backflow preventive and promotive pressure through the&#xD;
      lower esophageal sphincter (LES). Although a significant correlation between reflux burden&#xD;
      and the new index was found, sensitivity and specificity of HRM for GERD remained unchanged.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, provocative tests have been added to the standard protocol of HRM studies. Among&#xD;
      these, a traditional maneuver in water perfused manometry (straight leg raise maneuver, SLR)&#xD;
      appeared promising in predicting reflux even with HRM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A multicenter study with a large number of patients could provide more precise thresholds to&#xD;
      predict pathologic esophageal acid exposure time and proof of real-life generalizability of&#xD;
      SLR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A thorough clinical evaluation will be performed. GerdQ, GERD Health Related Quality of Life&#xD;
      (GERD-HRQL) and Reflux Symptom Index (RSI) questionnaires will be administered. HRM will be&#xD;
      performed according to the standard protocol defined by Chicago Classification 4.0. Upon&#xD;
      completion of the test, the SLR maneuver will be performed. With the patient in supine&#xD;
      position, one leg is raised to form an angle of at least 45 degrees with the bed. The patient&#xD;
      will be asked to keep that position for at least 5 seconds. The maneuver will be repeated&#xD;
      after 20-30 seconds. The first adequate maneuver will be considered for the study.&#xD;
      Intra-esophageal and intra-abdominal pressure will be analyzed both during baseline and SLR&#xD;
      maneuver. Intra-esophageal pressure is measured as peak and mean over 5 seconds, 1 cm and 5&#xD;
      cm above the proximal margin of the LES. Intra-abdominal pressure will be measured as peak&#xD;
      and mean over 5 seconds 1 cm below the distal margin of the diaphragm notch.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary aim is to determine the optimal threshold of intra-esophageal pressure augmentation&#xD;
      during straight leg raise (SLR) maneuver that predicted pathological esophageal acid exposure&#xD;
      time (AET). Secondary aim is to assess the diagnostic performance of HMR with SRL maneuver in&#xD;
      patients with GERD symptoms, calculating sensitivity, specificity, false-positive rate (FPR),&#xD;
      false-negative rate (FNR) and total misclassification rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Principal Investigator will maintain research data on an encrypted file server with&#xD;
      access controls only accessible to approved study investigators. Research records will be&#xD;
      de-identified using coded subject identifiers prior to transfer from sites to the Principal&#xD;
      Investigator to protect patient confidentiality. Study data will be maintained by the&#xD;
      Principal Investigator and deleted 3 years after the end of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from each site will be electronically transferred to Principal Investigator. The&#xD;
      electronic copy will contain no patient identifying data elements such as name, date of&#xD;
      birth, medical record numbers. Participating institutions will create unique patient&#xD;
      participant numbers based on a standard formula allocated by Principal investigator (two&#xD;
      digit institution code, two digit patient identifier, 01-20).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak esophageal pressure during SLR</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Peak esophageal pressure during straight leg raise maneuver, measured 5 cm above the lower esophageal sphincter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean esophageal pressure during SLR</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean esophageal pressure during straight leg raise maneuver, measured 5 cm above the lower esophageal sphincter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">336</enrollment>
  <condition>Gastroesophageal Reflux</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Straight Leg Raise</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients perform straight leg raise maneuver at the end of High-resolution Manometry test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Straight leg raise maneuver</intervention_name>
    <description>With the patient in supine position, one leg is raised to form an angle of at least 45 degrees with the bed. The patient will be asked to keep that position for at least 5 seconds. The maneuver will be repeated after 20-30 seconds. The first adequate maneuver will be considered for the study. Intra-esophageal and intra-abdominal pressure will be analyzed both during baseline and SLR maneuver. Intra-esophageal pressure is measured as peak and mean over 5 seconds, 1 cm and 5 cm above the proximal margin of the LES. Intra-abdominal pressure will be measured as peak and mean over 5 seconds 1 cm below the distal margin of the diaphragm notch.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Straight Leg Raise</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete and adequate HRM and pH-impedance study performed within 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Successfully performed SLR maneuver (adequate intra-abdominal pressure augmentation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with prior foregut surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obese with BMI&gt;35 Kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Paraesophageal hiatal hernia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scleroderma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eosinophilic esophagitis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Luigi Bonavina, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Milan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stefano Siboni, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+393493232750</phone>
    <email>stefano.siboni@grupposandonato.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Policlinico San Donato</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Donato Milanese</city>
        <state>Milano</state>
        <zip>20097</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stefano Siboni</last_name>
      <phone>+393493232750</phone>
      <email>stefano.siboni@grupposandonato.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Luigi Bonavina, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stefano Siboni, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erika Andreatta, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rogers BD, Rengarajan A, Ali IA, Hasak SL, Hansalia V, Gyawali CP. Straight leg raise metrics on high-resolution manometry associate with esophageal reflux burden. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020 Dec;32(12):e13929. doi: 10.1111/nmo.13929. Epub 2020 Jul 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32633016</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Masuda T, Mittal SK, Kovacs B, Csucska M, Bremner RM. Simple Manometric Index for Comprehensive Esophagogastric Junction Barrier Competency Against Gastroesophageal Reflux. J Am Coll Surg. 2020 May;230(5):744-755.e3. doi: 10.1016/j.jamcollsurg.2020.01.034. Epub 2020 Mar 3.</citation>
    <PMID>32142925</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yadlapati R, Kahrilas PJ, Fox MR, Bredenoord AJ, Prakash Gyawali C, Roman S, Babaei A, Mittal RK, Rommel N, Savarino E, Sifrim D, Smout A, Vaezi MF, Zerbib F, Akiyama J, Bhatia S, Bor S, Carlson DA, Chen JW, Cisternas D, Cock C, Coss-Adame E, de Bortoli N, Defilippi C, Fass R, Ghoshal UC, Gonlachanvit S, Hani A, Hebbard GS, Wook Jung K, Katz P, Katzka DA, Khan A, Kohn GP, Lazarescu A, Lengliner J, Mittal SK, Omari T, Park MI, Penagini R, Pohl D, Richter JE, Serra J, Sweis R, Tack J, Tatum RP, Tutuian R, Vela MF, Wong RK, Wu JC, Xiao Y, Pandolfino JE. Esophageal motility disorders on high-resolution manometry: Chicago classification version 4.0(©). Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2021 Jan;33(1):e14058. doi: 10.1111/nmo.14058.</citation>
    <PMID>33373111</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gyawali CP, Kahrilas PJ, Savarino E, Zerbib F, Mion F, Smout AJPM, Vaezi M, Sifrim D, Fox MR, Vela MF, Tutuian R, Tack J, Bredenoord AJ, Pandolfino J, Roman S. Modern diagnosis of GERD: the Lyon Consensus. Gut. 2018 Jul;67(7):1351-1362. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2017-314722. Epub 2018 Feb 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29437910</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van Hoeij FB, Smout AJ, Bredenoord AJ. Predictive value of routine esophageal high-resolution manometry for gastro-esophageal reflux disease. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2015 Jul;27(7):963-70. doi: 10.1111/nmo.12570. Epub 2015 Apr 30.</citation>
    <PMID>25930019</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Milan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Luigi Bonavina</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>High Resolution Manometry</keyword>
  <keyword>pH-impedance</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastroesophageal Reflux disease</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

