<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04817189</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IBA1160</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04817189</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oral Akynzeo® vs Standard of Care in Preventing CINV in High-risk MEC Patients (MyRisk)</brief_title>
  <acronym>CINV</acronym>
  <official_title>MyRisk: Efficacy and Safety Evaluation of Oral Akynzeo® in Patients Receiving MEC at High Risk of Developing CINV Based on a Prediction Tool: A Multinational and Multicenter Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Helsinn Healthcare SA</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Helsinn Healthcare SA</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      MyRisk: Efficacy and safety evaluation of oral Akynzeo® in patients receiving MEC at high&#xD;
      risk of developing CINV based on a prediction tool. A multinational and multicenter study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antiemetic guidelines recommendations are based on the emetogenic potential of the&#xD;
      chemotherapy. Chemotherapy (CT) agents are divided in Highly, Moderately, Low and Minimally&#xD;
      Emetogenic potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to type of chemotherapy, several patient-related risk factors can increase the&#xD;
      risk of CINV (chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting). Currently, there is limited&#xD;
      consensus surrounding the most relevant patient risk factors that may predict the risk of&#xD;
      CINV. Based on a recent study by Dranitsaris et al. (Dranitsaris et al. Ann Oncol. 2017 Jun&#xD;
      1; 28(6):1260-1267.), eight (8) predictive factors have been identified and an algorithm has&#xD;
      been developed to incorporate these factors into the optimal selection of prophylactic&#xD;
      antiemetics:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. nausea and/or vomiting in the prior cycle of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. use of non-prescribed antiemetics at home in the prior cycle of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. platinum or anthracycline-based chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. age &lt; 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. expectations for (anticipating) nausea and/or vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. &lt;7 h of sleep the night before chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. history of morning sickness during previous pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. cycle of chemotherapy (A negative association between risk and number of cycles was&#xD;
           identified where the hazard for CINV was highest in cycles 1 and 2, with a gradual&#xD;
           decline and plateau from cycle 3 onward).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical application of this prediction tool has the potential to be an important&#xD;
      resource for clinicians and may help to enhance patient care by optimizing the use of the&#xD;
      antiemetics in a proactive manner.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Antiemetic guideline recommendations are based on the emetogenic potential of chemotherapy&#xD;
      and involve 4 levels of classification of intravenous chemotherapy agents, i.e., high,&#xD;
      moderate, low and minimal; these have been accepted by major organisations. Moderate&#xD;
      emetogenic chemotherapy (MEC) results in acute vomiting in 30% to 90% of cancer patients in&#xD;
      the absence of antiemetic therapy. In addition to the chemotherapy type, several&#xD;
      patient-related risk factors and clinical characteristics can increase CINV risk. These can&#xD;
      include use of antiemetics inconsistent with international guidelines, younger age,&#xD;
      prechemotherapy nausea, no complete CINV response in an earlier cycle, history of&#xD;
      nausea/vomiting, (trait) anxiety, fatigue experience, and expectations of nausea/vomiting.&#xD;
      Other studies have largely confirmed some of the key risk factors for CINV (history of&#xD;
      vomiting during pregnancy, history of motion sickness, age, gender) and added other factors&#xD;
      such as (chronic) alcohol consumption, body surface area, fewer hours slept the night prior&#xD;
      to infusion, or advanced stage cancer. Currently, there is a limited consensus surrounding&#xD;
      the most relevant patient risk factors that may predict CINV risk. Based on a recent study by&#xD;
      Dranitsaris et al. eight predictive factors have been identified, and an algorithm has been&#xD;
      developed to combine these patient-related risk factors into the optimal treatment of&#xD;
      prophylactic antiemetics. These include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. nausea and/or vomiting in the prior cycle of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. use of non-prescribed antiemetics at home in the prior cycle of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. platinum or anthracycline-based chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. age &lt; 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. expectations for (anticipating) nausea and/or vomiting&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. &lt;7 h of sleep the night before chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. history of morning sickness during previous pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. cycle of chemotherapy (A negative association between risk and number of cycles was&#xD;
           identified where the hazard for CINV was highest in cycles 1 and 2, with a gradual&#xD;
           decline and plateau from cycle 3 onward).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Akynzeo®, an oral combination of the neurokinin 1 receptor antagonists (NK1 RA), netupitant&#xD;
      and the 5-hydroxytryptamine (HT3) receptor antagonists (5-HT3 RA), palonosetron, is&#xD;
      recommended by guidelines for the prevention of CINV. Akynzeo® has been evaluated in a&#xD;
      multicentre, randomised, double-blind, double-dummy phase II clinical trial at various dose&#xD;
      ranges among 694 cisplatin-treated cancer patients from 44 sites (two countries); each NEPA&#xD;
      (netupitant-palonosetron) dose significantly improves CINV prevention in cancer patients.&#xD;
      Similar results were obtained in another international, randomised, double-blind and parallel&#xD;
      group phase III clinical trial; NEPA prevented CINV in patients receiving MEC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current study primarily aimed to evaluate whether Akynzeo® leads to a higher response&#xD;
      rate compared with standard care in MEC regimen-treated patients who are identified to be at&#xD;
      high risk based on the algorithm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>interventional, open label, randomized, active controlled, parallel arms, multicenter and multinational study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of complete responses over three cycles of chemotherapy after the start of the MEC administration</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all three chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate if the use of NEPA (netupitant and palonosetron) in patients treated with IV moderately emetogenic chemotherapy and at high risk of CINV is more effective in preventing CINV than a standard of care antiemetics over three cycles of chemotherapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of acute (0 to 24 hours), delayed (&gt;24 to 120 hours), and overall (0-120 hours) CINV indicators in each cycle of chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of:&#xD;
No emetic episode during the acute, delayed, and overall phase and daily in each cycle&#xD;
Number of vomiting episodes during the acute, delayed, and overall phase in each cycle&#xD;
No rescue medication during the acute, delayed, and overall phase and daily in each cycle&#xD;
No significant nausea (maximum MAT scale = 2) during the acute, delayed, and overall phase and daily in each cycle;&#xD;
No nausea (MAT scale = 0) during the acute, delayed, and overall phase and daily in each cycle;&#xD;
Complete protection (no emetic episode, no rescue medication, and no significant nausea) during the acute, delayed, and overall phase and daily in each cycle&#xD;
Time 0 is defined as the start time of the chemotherapy administration on Day 1 of each of the three cycles.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the predictive role of potential risk factors in the development of CINV over three cycles of chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis of the development of CINV as a dependent variable will be performed to identify additional potential risk factors of CINV thought to be increasing the risk of CINV in patients receiving MEC.&#xD;
The outcome measure is the development of CINV, defined as any occurrence of nausea or a vomiting episode.&#xD;
The data on the development of CINV will be taken from data collection tools, patients' diaries and MASCC Antiemesis Tool (MAT).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the safety profile of the antiemetic drug over three cycles of chemotherapy - the frequency of adverse events (AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>An overall summary of adverse events (AE) will be presented, including the frequency of patients with:&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent adverse event&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent adverse event related to a study drug&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent adverse event leading to chemotherapy dose reductions or interruptions&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent serious adverse event&#xD;
All AEs will be summarized by their:&#xD;
Severity&#xD;
Seriousness&#xD;
Relationship to a drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the safety profile of the antiemetic drug over three cycles of chemotherapy - the percentage of adverse events (AE)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>An overall summary of adverse events (AE) will be presented, including the percentage of patients with:&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent adverse event&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent adverse event related to a study drug&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent adverse event leading to chemotherapy dose reductions or interruptions&#xD;
Any treatment-emergent serious adverse event&#xD;
All AEs will be summarized by their:&#xD;
Severity&#xD;
Seriousness&#xD;
Relationship to a drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the frequency of discontinuations due to adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of discontinuations due to adverse events (AE) will be presented.&#xD;
All AEs leading to discontinuation will be summarized by their:&#xD;
Severity&#xD;
Seriousness&#xD;
Relationship to a drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the percentage of discontinuations due to adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of patients with discontinuations due to adverse events (AE) will be presented.&#xD;
All AEs leading to discontinuation will be summarized by their:&#xD;
Severity&#xD;
Seriousness&#xD;
Relationship to a drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of frequency of on treatment deaths due to adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>The frequency of on treatment deaths due to adverse events (AE) will be presented.&#xD;
All AEs leading to on treatment deaths will be summarized by their:&#xD;
Severity&#xD;
Seriousness&#xD;
Relationship to a drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the percentage of patients with on treatment death due to adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of patients with on treatment death due to adverse events (AE) will be presented.&#xD;
All AEs leading to on treatment death will be summarized by their:&#xD;
Severity&#xD;
Seriousness&#xD;
Relationship to a drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Listings concerning the safety profile of the antiemetic drug over three cycles of chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>The following listings will be presented:&#xD;
All AEs (including pre-treatment AEs)&#xD;
Serious adverse events&#xD;
Adverse events resulting in withdrawn of study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exploration of the effect of CINV on daily activities and quality of life in patients receiving moderately-emetogenic chemotherapy over three cycles of chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the effect of CINV on daily activities and quality of life that will be measured by using the Functional Living Index-Emesis (FLIE) questionnaire, a validated, nausea and vomiting specific, patient-reported outcome instrument.&#xD;
The Functional Living Index-Emesis (FLIE) has 18 questions. These questions are divided into two domains: Nausea (questions 1-9) and Vomiting (questions 10-18).&#xD;
The minimum score for any question is 0 and the maximum score is 100. Higher scores indicate less impairment on daily life as a result of nausea or vomiting.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - number of days with rescue medication administered for the treatment of CINV</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of days with rescue medication administered for the treatment of CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - daily doses of rescue medication administered for the treatment of CINV</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the daily doses of rescue medication administered for the treatment of CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - the number of re-hydration bags</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of re-hydration bags given for at least grade 2 vomiting (more details below), will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - the number of days of unplanned hospitalisations</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of days of unplanned hospitalizations related to CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles&#xD;
All hospitalizations will be summarized according to the department of hospitalization (type of ward)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - the number of outpatient physician visits</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of outpatient physician visits and health care consultations due to CINV (e.g., general practitioner), will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - the number of unplanned laboratory test</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of unplanned laboratory test including those at unplanned hospitalizations due to CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - discontinuation of chemotherapy treatment due to CINV</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of discontinuations of chemotherapy treatment due to CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - the number of delays of chemotherapy administration due to CINV</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of delays of chemotherapy administration due to CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - the average length of delay of chemotherapy administration due to CINV</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the average length of delay (in days) of chemotherapy administration due to CINV, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of resource utilization and health economic outcome - days of absence from work</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of each cycle and after all 3 chemotherapy cycles. The length of a cycle depends on the treatment being given (cycles range from 2 to 6 weeks).</time_frame>
    <description>Health economic endpoint, the number of days of absence from work, will be evaluated during the study cycles</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">530</enrollment>
  <condition>Chemotherapy-induced Nausea and Vomiting</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NEPA (300mg netupitant/0.5mg palonosetron) + Dexamethasone 8 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral netupitant/palonosetron (300 mg/0.50 mg) fixed-dose combination on Day 1 of each cycle.&#xD;
Dexamethasone (8 mg) will be administered on Day 1 of each cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care + Dexamethasone 8 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dexamethasone (or equivalent corticosteroids) 8 mg administered by the oral route (or equivalent IV dose) on Day 1, approximately 1 hour before chemotherapy and one of the 5-HT3-RAs recommended by European Society for Medical Oncology (ESMO) and Multinational Association of Supportive Care in Cancer (MASCC) guidelines (standard of care), i.e. either:&#xD;
Granisetron, 2 mg (oral) or 1 mg (IV) OR Palonosetron, 0.5 mg (oral), 0.25mg (IV) OR Ondansetron, 16 mg (oral) or 8 mg (IV) OR Dolasetron 100 mg (oral) OR Tropisetron 5 mg (oral or IV)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NEPA (300mg netupitant/0.5mg palonosetron)</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral netupitant/palonosetron (300 mg/0.50 mg) fixed-dose combination on Day 1 of each cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NEPA (300mg netupitant/0.5mg palonosetron) + Dexamethasone 8 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Akynzeo® capsules</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Granisetron, 2 mg (oral) or 1 mg (IV) OR Palonosetron, 0.5 mg (oral), 0.25mg (IV) OR Ondansetron, 16 mg (oral) or 8 mg (IV) OR Dolasetron 100 mg (oral) OR Tropisetron 5 mg (oral or IV)</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard of care will be administered on Day 1 of each cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care + Dexamethasone 8 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>5-HT3 RA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone, 8 mg (oral) or equivalent IV dose</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexamethasone (8 mg) will be administered on Day 1 of each cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>NEPA (300mg netupitant/0.5mg palonosetron) + Dexamethasone 8 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care + Dexamethasone 8 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>corticosteroid</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients aged ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a risk score of ≥ 13 as calculated by the algorithm - see 3.6.3.1.&#xD;
             Baseline/screening: VISIT 0&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both sexes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with diagnosis of any cancer scheduled and intended to be treated for three&#xD;
             consecutive cycles with a single dose of any IV MEC regimen, per cycle, including&#xD;
             adjuvant or neo-adjuvant chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0, 1 or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Standard of Care defined as a 5-HT3 RA + Dexamethasone (or equivalent&#xD;
             corticosteroid) based-regimen on day 1 of chemotherapy for CINV prevention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Naïve and non- naïve to chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The enrolled women should be a) of non-childbearing potential or b) of childbearing&#xD;
             potential using reliable contraceptive measures and having a negative urine pregnancy&#xD;
             test done by health care team within 1-24 hours before dosing the antiemetic treatment&#xD;
             in both arms and outcome recorded in the medical records&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to comply with study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving highly emetogenic chemotherapy (including&#xD;
             anthracycline+cyclophosphamide-based chemotherapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving oral moderately emetogenic chemotherapy drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving opioids within 2 weeks prior to trial enrollment (longer use&#xD;
             allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of olanzapine as prophylaxis of CINV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients scheduled to receive radiotherapy concurrently with chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any illness or condition that, in the opinion of the physician, may confound the&#xD;
             results of the study or pose unwarranted risks in administering the investigational&#xD;
             product to the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with mechanical risk factors for nausea (i.e. intestinal obstruction)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with liver disease (as nausea is a common presenting symptom)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with metabolic risk factors for nausea (i.e. electrolyte imbalances causing&#xD;
             nausea/vomiting)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic treatment with steroids (with the exception of inhaled or topical steroids)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy and/or breast-feeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential refusing to use effective contraception during the&#xD;
             whole study treatment and up to one month after study treatment with Akynzeo®&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Standard of Care including an NK-1 RA-based regimen to prevent CINV&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex Molasiotis, prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>The Hong Kong Polytechnic University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alessandro Alonzi, MSc.</last_name>
    <phone>+41 91 985 18 81</phone>
    <email>Alessandro.Alonzi@helsinn.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marika Chrápavá, MSc.</last_name>
    <phone>+420 605 550 715</phone>
    <email>chrapava@biostatistika.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thomayerova nemocnice</name>
      <address>
        <city>Praha</city>
        <zip>14059</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tomáš Büchler, Assoc.prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+420 261 083 530</phone>
      <email>tomas.buchler@ftn.cz</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sotiria General Hospital, 3rd Deúpartment of Medicine, School of Medicine, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Konstantinos Syrigos, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>0030 2107700220</phone>
      <email>ksyrigos.trials@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>General University Hospital of Heraklion</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heraklion</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dimitris Mavroudis, professor</last_name>
      <phone>0030 2810392091</phone>
      <email>mavroudis@uoc.gr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Basel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Basel</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Viola Heinzelmann, professor</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Swiss Medical Network - Clinique de Genolier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Genolier</city>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matti Aapro, professor</last_name>
      <phone>+41 22 366 91 34</phone>
      <email>maapro@genolier.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ondansetron</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Palonosetron</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Granisetron</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tropisetron</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dolasetron</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

