<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02639312</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>160040</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>16-D-0040</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02639312</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Natural History of Craniofacial Anomalies and Developmental Growth Variants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Natural History of Craniofacial Anomalies and Developmental Growth Variants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research (NIDCR)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some head and facial abnormalities are rare and present at birth. Others are more common, and&#xD;
      may not show up until puberty. These conditions have different causes and characteristics.&#xD;
      Researchers want to learn more about these conditions by comparing people with face, head,&#xD;
      and neck abnormalities to family members and to healthy volunteers without such conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn more about abnormal development of the face, head, and neck. To determine their&#xD;
      genetic variants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People who have not had surgery for facial trauma:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 2 and older with craniofacial abnormalities (may participate offsite)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unaffected relatives ages 2 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy volunteers ages 6 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with medical history and physical exam focusing on head, face,&#xD;
      and neck&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may be followed for several years. Visits may require staying near the clinic&#xD;
      for a few days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A visit is required for the following developmental stages, along with follow-up visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age 2-6&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age 6-10&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age 11-17&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age 18 and older&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visits may include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
      Oral exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cheek swab: a cotton swab will be wiped across the inside of the cheek several times.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cone beam CT scan (CBCT): x-rays create an image of the head, face, teeth, and neck.&#xD;
      Participants will&#xD;
&#xD;
      stand still or sit on a chair for about 20 minutes while the scanner rotates around the head.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Photos of the head and face&#xD;
&#xD;
      Offsite participants will provide:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Copies of medical and dental records&#xD;
&#xD;
      Leftover tissue samples from previous surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood sample or cheek swab&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a natural history study that will examine craniofacial anomalies that affect the&#xD;
      normal development of the facial skeleton, including birth defects and dentofacial&#xD;
      developmental abnormalities that express themselves with the growth of the individual.&#xD;
      Craniofacial anomalies may be rare and present at birth, such as hemifacial microsomia (1 in&#xD;
      every 7500 live births), or common, such as dentofacial deformities including the Habsburg&#xD;
      Jaw or mandibular prognathism (1% of the US population) that becomes apparent as a child&#xD;
      enters puberty. These are striking disorders as they involve the face and surrounding&#xD;
      structures, which is a focal point of self-identity and are intimately tied to quality of&#xD;
      life and daily function. The primary objectives of this study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To characterize rare and common craniofacial anomalies using both extensive clinical&#xD;
           evaluations, 3D cone-beam computed tomography-based geometric morphometric and&#xD;
           cephalometric analyses and surface morphology&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine the genetic variants for rare and common craniofacial anomalies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objective is to establish a curated craniofacial phenomic/genomic database and&#xD;
      to collect data related to clinically-indicated procedures and care performed at the NIH for&#xD;
      the treatment of craniofacial disorders and anomalies. The study population includes&#xD;
      individuals ages greater than or equal to 2 years with any craniofacial anomaly but will&#xD;
      focus on two specific conditions that affect facial skeletal development: hemifacial&#xD;
      microsomia and mandibular prognathism in children and adults. Up to 1920 subjects and family&#xD;
      members as well as 480 healthy volunteers will be recruited through referrals from NIH or&#xD;
      outside providers and institutions. This natural history protocol will generate research data&#xD;
      that will improve the understanding and etiology of craniofacial dysmorphologies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 18, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 18, 2036</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 18, 2036</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Database or registry</measure>
    <time_frame>17 years</time_frame>
    <description>using both extensive clinical evaluations, 3D cone-beam computed tomography-based geometric morphometric and cephalometric analyses, and surface morphology</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2400</enrollment>
  <condition>Prognathism</condition>
  <condition>Retrognathism</condition>
  <condition>Dentofacial Deformities</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <description>hemifacial microsomia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <description>mandibular prognathism</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -Subjects w/craniofacial anomalies or dentofacial deformities -Families of subjects with&#xD;
        craniofacial anomalies or dentofacial deformities -Case Controls&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 2 to less than or equal to 100 with craniofacial&#xD;
             anomalies/abnormalities. Affected family member (defined as an individual with a&#xD;
             demonstrable relationship (any family relationship no matter how distant) with the&#xD;
             above subject in the pedigree) who expresses craniofacial anomalies will be classified&#xD;
             as a subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide consent or in the case, of minors, have a legally-authorized&#xD;
             representative to provide consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Unaffected Family Members:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  These family members are defined as individuals with a demonstrable relationship (any&#xD;
             family relationship no matter how distant) with a proband subject by pedigree who do&#xD;
             not express craniofacial anomalies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  greater than or equal to 2 years old to less than or equal to 100 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide consent or in the case, of minors, have a legally-authorized&#xD;
             representative to provide consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Healthy Volunteers:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In good general health.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Greater than or equal to 6 years old to &lt; 100 years old..&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide consent or in the case, of minors, have a legally-authorized&#xD;
             representative to provide consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of a craniofacial congenital anomaly or malocclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No family history of a craniofacial syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For All Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of facial trauma requiring surgical treatment and facial reconstruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal for both genetic testing and CBCT imaging. Participants must agree to at least&#xD;
             one of the two (both are not required to participate).&#xD;
&#xD;
        For Healthy Volunteers:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Female volunteers who are pregnant or nursing.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janice S Lee, DDS, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research (NIDCR)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pamela M Orzechowski, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-7373</phone>
    <email>ps363q@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2016-D-0040.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Proffit WR, Fields HW Jr, Moray LJ. Prevalence of malocclusion and orthodontic treatment need in the United States: estimates from the NHANES III survey. Int J Adult Orthodon Orthognath Surg. 1998;13(2):97-106.</citation>
    <PMID>9743642</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cruz RM, Krieger H, Ferreira R, Mah J, Hartsfield J Jr, Oliveira S. Major gene and multifactorial inheritance of mandibular prognathism. Am J Med Genet A. 2008 Jan 1;146A(1):71-7.</citation>
    <PMID>18074368</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Frazier-Bowers S, Rincon-Rodriguez R, Zhou J, Alexander K, Lange E. Evidence of linkage in a Hispanic cohort with a Class III dentofacial phenotype. J Dent Res. 2009 Jan;88(1):56-60. doi: 10.1177/0022034508327817.</citation>
    <PMID>19131318</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 24, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 23, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 23, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 24, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Craniofacial</keyword>
  <keyword>Microsomia</keyword>
  <keyword>Mandibular</keyword>
  <keyword>Facial Defects</keyword>
  <keyword>Hasburg Jaw</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dentofacial Deformities</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retrognathia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prognathism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Craniofacial Abnormalities</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

