<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00398775</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2006/36</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00398775</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Procalcitonin in Fever of Unknown Etiology</brief_title>
  <official_title>Procalcitonin Guided Antimicrobial Discontinuation in Hospitalised Patients With Fever of Unknown Etiology</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Changi General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Changi General Hospital</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether new blood test (procalcitonin) can help to&#xD;
      reduce unnecessary use of antibiotics in patients with unexplained fever.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although fever is most commonly caused by bacterial infection there are multiple other&#xD;
      conditions that can cause fever. It can be caused by viral infection. It can also be caused&#xD;
      by other non infectious disease. Patients with malignancy, inflammation (such as gout or&#xD;
      arthritis), or clots in veins can present with fever. Occasionally medications themselves can&#xD;
      cause fever. If fever is not caused by infection antibiotics will not help. Instead they may&#xD;
      cause side effects such as diarrhea and allergic reactions. We want to determine whether&#xD;
      simple blood test (procalcitonin) can help us to make a difference between fever caused by&#xD;
      infection and fever caused by others (above mentioned) non-infectious problems. We also want&#xD;
      to determine whether such test would help us to reduce unnecessary antibiotic use and help us&#xD;
      to find faster the real cause of the fever.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 90 patients with the unexplained fever will be participating in this study. This&#xD;
      study will involve single, additional blood test, performed only if patient continue to have&#xD;
      fever despite a few days of investigations and therapy with antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be assigned by drawing to one of two groups. In the first group blood test&#xD;
      (procalcitonin) will help a doctor to decide whether to stop or continue antibiotics. If&#xD;
      procalcitonin level is high antibiotics will be continued and the doctor will most probably&#xD;
      order additional tests to determine the source of infection. If procalcitonin level is low&#xD;
      serious bacterial infection is unlikely. The antibiotics will be stopped and a doctor will&#xD;
      try to look for other cause of fever.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the second group blood for the tests will be collected but not reported to a doctor. You&#xD;
      will be treated in traditional manner by a doctor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      By following this procedure we will be able to determine whether therapy guided by&#xD;
      procalcitonin level is as safe and possibly more effective than traditional approach. This&#xD;
      study does not involve any other tests or study medications. We will attempt to contact all&#xD;
      patients one month later by phone to determine whether you remain well after discharge.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Antimicrobial resistance has increasingly become a threat to patient safety in health care&#xD;
      settings.1 Several studies have identified the inappropriate use of antimicrobials as&#xD;
      important risk factor for antimicrobial resistance and the important area of opportunity for&#xD;
      increasing patient safety and improving patient outcomes.2 High rates of antimicrobial use&#xD;
      have been linked to high rates of antimicrobial resistance,3 and increased exposure to&#xD;
      antimicrobials has been associated with an increased probability of colonization with&#xD;
      resistant pathogens. It has also been shown that antimicrobial control results in significant&#xD;
      cost savings4 and it may reduce antimicrobial resistance Surveys reveal that 25 - 33% of&#xD;
      hospitalized patients receive antibiotics6 and that 22 - 65% of antibiotic use in&#xD;
      hospitalized patients is inappropriate.7&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reasons for inappropriate antimicrobial therapy include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. treating anybody with fever (even when it is not caused by infection) with broad&#xD;
           spectrum antibiotics&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. treating colonization or contamination (rather than real infection)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. continuing antibiotics even when infection was cured or is unlikely8&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is quite clear that clinicians need reliable marker for bacterial infections that would&#xD;
      allow an early diagnosis, inform about the course and prognosis of the disease and facilitate&#xD;
      therapeutic decisions.9 Procalcitonin covers these features better as compared to other, more&#xD;
      commonly used biomarkers (such as CRP).10 It has been shown recently that procalcitonin&#xD;
      guidance substantially reduces antibiotic use in community-acquired pneumonia without&#xD;
      compromising patients' safety. 11, 12 However, the efficacy and safety of PGAD in&#xD;
      hospitalized patients with undefined fever has not been previously investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We think that PGAD should be equally safe and effective intervention in hospitalized patients&#xD;
      with fever of unknown etiology. It should help to reduce inappropriate antibiotic use and in&#xD;
      effect, help to control antimicrobial resistance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Very low recruitment&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>January 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2007</completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure to systemic antimicrobial treatment:</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>duration of antibiotic treatment (in days).</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>total antibiotic exposure (in defined daily doses).</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>28-day case-fatality rate (in %)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of hospital stay (in days)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Costs of antimicrobial therapy (in SGD)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of nosocomial super-infection (in N super-infections per 100 patients)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Isolation of multi-resistant microorganisms (in clinical isolates per 100 patient-days)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Fever</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>antibiotic discontinuation</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. All hospitalized patients admitted to general medical or GRM wards with fever and no&#xD;
             obvious source of infection, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. remain febrile after 72 hours of empiric, antimicrobial therapy, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. initial blood cultures are negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with clinically suspected infection (strongly suggestive symptoms, signs or&#xD;
             laboratory/imaging studies) such as pneumonia, urinary tract infection, meningitis,&#xD;
             endocarditis, skin and soft tissue infection, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Confirmed bacterial, viral or fungal infection (positive stain, culture or serology&#xD;
             from appropriate clinical specimen).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hypotension (systolic blood pressure &lt;90mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Respiratory failure (oxygen requirement &gt; 4L/min via nasal canula)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients admitted to intensive care unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Severely immunocompromised patients: (febrile neutropenia, HIV infection with CD4&#xD;
             count &lt; 200, immuno-suppressive therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients younger than 21.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maciej P Chlebicki, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Changi General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Changi General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Singapore</city>
        <zip>529889</zip>
        <country>Singapore</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Singapore</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Christ-Crain M, Jaccard-Stolz D, Bingisser R, Gencay MM, Huber PR, Tamm M, Müller B. Effect of procalcitonin-guided treatment on antibiotic use and outcome in lower respiratory tract infections: cluster-randomised, single-blinded intervention trial. Lancet. 2004 Feb 21;363(9409):600-7.</citation>
    <PMID>14987884</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Briel M, Christ-Crain M, Young J, Schuetz P, Huber P, Périat P, Bucher HC, Müller B. Procalcitonin-guided antibiotic use versus a standard approach for acute respiratory tract infections in primary care: study protocol for a randomised controlled trial and baseline characteristics of participating general practitioners [ISRCTN73182671]. BMC Fam Pract. 2005 Aug 18;6:34.</citation>
    <PMID>16107222</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Christ-Crain M, Stolz D, Bingisser R, Müller C, Miedinger D, Huber PR, Zimmerli W, Harbarth S, Tamm M, Müller B. Procalcitonin guidance of antibiotic therapy in community-acquired pneumonia: a randomized trial. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2006 Jul 1;174(1):84-93. Epub 2006 Apr 7.</citation>
    <PMID>16603606</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Christ-Crain M, Müller B. Procalcitonin in bacterial infections--hype, hope, more or less? Swiss Med Wkly. 2005 Aug 6;135(31-32):451-60. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16208582</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 13, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 13, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 14, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 19, 2007</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 19, 2007</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 20, 2007</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>procalcitonin guided antibiotic discontinuation</keyword>
  <keyword>fever of unknown origin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

