<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03514043</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1718/01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03514043</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patient and Staff Experience of Ambulatory Emergency Care on the Surgical Admissions Unit (SAU)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Patient and Staff Experience of Ambulatory Emergency Care on the Surgical Admissions Unit (SAU)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Exeter</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Royal Devon and Exeter NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Exeter</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Emergency ambulatory care (&quot;day-case&quot; care that does not involve staying in a hospital bed&#xD;
      overnight) is now well-established for medical patients and is being used increasingly for&#xD;
      surgical patients. However, it is not known how emergency surgical patients feel about being&#xD;
      managed in this way compared to being admitted to a hospital ward. The investigating team&#xD;
      believe that some people will find it easier and would prefer to be able to stay at home&#xD;
      overnight but others may find this difficult or dislike this method of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators want to explore staff and patients' experience of this type of care with&#xD;
      semi-structured telephone interviews. The interviews will take around 20-30mins each. The&#xD;
      anticipated number of patient participants needed is 20 and 12-15 staff members.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a qualitative study of patient and staff experience. Data will be collected by&#xD;
      semi-structured telephone and face-to-face interviews.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abdominal pain is a common reason for people to attend hospital as an emergency. It makes up&#xD;
      a considerable proportion of the patients being admitted under the care of general surgeons.&#xD;
      Other common reasons for people attending include infections such as abscesses and problems&#xD;
      following previous surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Surgical Assessment Unit (SAU) is an ambulatory area with a waiting room and assessment&#xD;
      cubicles. It is staffed by a triage nurse or healthcare assistant and doctors from the&#xD;
      surgical team. Patients can be assessed and have investigations including blood tests and&#xD;
      radiology procedures including x-rays, ultrasound and CT. After assessment they are either&#xD;
      admitted to the ward, discharged home or have their care continued in an ambulatory manner&#xD;
      returning in the next few days for further or repeat assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previously patients were either discharged or admitted for observation, investigation and&#xD;
      treatment such as intravenous antibiotics. Many of these patients could be managed safely in&#xD;
      a &quot;day case&quot; manner. This pathway allows for re-attendance should it be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Emergency ambulatory care is well-established in medicine for conditions such as suspected&#xD;
      deep vein thrombosis (DVT) and transient ischaemic attack (TIA) but has not yet been widely&#xD;
      adopted in surgery. There is uncertainty surrounding the best way of looking after these&#xD;
      patients as the diagnosis is often uncertain and it can be difficult to judge which patients&#xD;
      require admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pilot studies have shown that up to 30% of emergency general surgical patients could be&#xD;
      managed in this way. These studies also report a high patient satisfaction score but do not&#xD;
      inform us what works, why and for whom. These would be important considerations for&#xD;
      organisations looking to expand their emergency general surgical ambulatory service.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to expand upon previous work in this area by conducting semi-structured&#xD;
      interviews with patients who have experienced emergency general surgical ambulatory care. The&#xD;
      investigating team aim to achieve a representative sample of participants by age, attending&#xD;
      condition and satisfaction score. They will identify themes that influence patient experience&#xD;
      of emergency ambulatory care and whether this might vary depending on patient factors such as&#xD;
      age, social support/responsibilities and attending condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient participants will be recruited to the study by the clinical team by means of short&#xD;
      verbal explanation and the provision of an information sheet. Potential participants will&#xD;
      give their contact details to be passed to the study team or will make contact themselves at&#xD;
      a later stage. They will then by contacted by the study team and given further information&#xD;
      over the telephone. Those wishing to proceed will have arrangements made for a telephone&#xD;
      interview. A recording of consent will be made prior to the start of the interview and will&#xD;
      be stored as a separate audio file.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The interview schedule has been drawn up based on areas that have emerged from work in the&#xD;
      past using patient diaries. (Improving the Patient Experience of Ambulatory Care in the&#xD;
      Surgical Assessment Unit, 2014) The PPI work done has included review of these questions for&#xD;
      acceptability and ease of understanding and minor changes have been made to the wording of&#xD;
      questions as a result. The prompts used are mainly to encourage explanations of why&#xD;
      participants have answered the way they have.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The interviews will last 20-40mins and will be recorded using digital recording software.&#xD;
      They will be conducted by the principal investigator. No potentially identifiable information&#xD;
      will be recorded and participants will be advised not to divulge identifiable information&#xD;
      prior to the interview. If this occurs inadvertently it will be deleted prior to&#xD;
      transcription. These audio recordings will be given an anonymous identification number and&#xD;
      then be transcribed into text documents using a paid transcription service within the UK.&#xD;
      Once the transcription has been completed the recording will be deleted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The transcribed data will be stored on a NHS server. It will be available for access to the&#xD;
      study team by password protection and on request in an anonymised form by the university&#xD;
      sponsor. Once the study is complete it will be stored on a university repository for the&#xD;
      period required for archive and deleted from the NHS server.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The transcribed data will be coded and then undergo thematic analysis using NVIVO software.&#xD;
      Coding will be done by the principal investigator and a proportion of the data will be&#xD;
      separately coded by the 2 senior members of the study team. Interim analysis will be&#xD;
      conducted after each 5 patients and the interview schedule may undergo some change to explore&#xD;
      in more detail areas of interest that emerge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If groups are underrepresented in the interim analysis then there may be targeted recruitment&#xD;
      to the underrepresented group. This may include the characteristics of patient age and&#xD;
      overall satisfaction with care given.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 5, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors affecting patient satisfaction: semi-structured interviews</measure>
    <time_frame>Will be measured within 3 weeks of attendance</time_frame>
    <description>Factors that influence patients' experience of emergency general surgical care [semi-structured interviews with patients]</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Factors affecting implementation of ambulatory emergency care</measure>
    <time_frame>Interviews will be conducted at a single timepoint from May 2019 to October 2019.</time_frame>
    <description>Factors which affect how staff use ambulatory emergency care and what they perceive this issues to be with this method of care.&#xD;
This will be measured using semi-structured interviews with staff.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Emergencies</condition>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ambulatory care surgical patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients who have attended the surgical assessment unit with an emergency general surgical condition and have their care completed without an inpatient stay.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical assessment unit staff</arm_group_label>
    <description>Staff who are involved in the care of patients on the surgical assessment unit. This includes senior and junior doctors, nurses, healthcare assistants and ward receptionists.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults presenting to the surgical assessment unit under the care of general surgeons who&#xD;
        have their care managed in an ambulatory manner without inpatient admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Staff who are involved in the care of these patients in the groups described in the group&#xD;
        section.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English-speaking adult patients of any gender over the age of 18 undergoing emergency&#xD;
             ambulatory care via the surgical assessment unit for a general surgical condition will&#xD;
             be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children under the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults without capacity to consent as participants for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient participant exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who have primarily presented with a condition that is not within the remit of&#xD;
             general surgeons&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who had their care continued as an inpatient immediately following their initial&#xD;
             presentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to understand or speak English to the level required to understand the&#xD;
             information sheet or conduct the interview&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisa H Massey, MBBS (BSc)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Royal Devon and Exeter Hospital NHS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Devon and Exeter Hospital NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <zip>EX2 5DW</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 13, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 1, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 2, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ambulatory care</keyword>
  <keyword>Emergency general surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient satisfaction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>At the end of the study the research data will be uploaded to an open access repository held on a University of Exeter server. Depending on practicality this may include individual participant data at interview level or may include the data post-analysis.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>March 6, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/43/NCT03514043/Prot_002.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

