<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03513900</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2018017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03513900</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Non-invasive Methods to Predict PHG in Cirrhosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Non-invasive Methods to Predict Portal Hypertensive Gastropathy in Patients With Cirrhosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Portal hypertensive gastropathy (PHG) is used to describe the endoscopic appearance of&#xD;
      gastric mucosa in patients with cirrhotic portal hypertension, with a characteristic&#xD;
      mosaic-like pattern with or without red spots. The severity of PHG can vary from mild to&#xD;
      severe, and patients with PHG are at an increased risk of acute and chronic gastrointestinal&#xD;
      bleeding. According to the study by Kim et al, severe PHG showed a significantly high-risk of&#xD;
      mortality and reduced expected survival time than none or mild PHG. Therefore, we need to&#xD;
      detect PHG as soon as possible.However, as an invasive examination, endoscopy examination may&#xD;
      massive gastrointestinal bleeding or gastric perforation. Most patients are afraid and&#xD;
      disable to tolerate it, which significantly reduces the real morbidity of PHG and delays the&#xD;
      time for diagnosis and treatment. Therefore, there is a need to find effective non-invasive&#xD;
      methods that can predict patients with PHG in the early stage, especially which require&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cirrhosis is the end-stage of every chronic liver disease. Histologically, cirrhosis is&#xD;
      characterized by regenerative nodules surrounded by fibrous bands, which can be divided into&#xD;
      compensated phase and decompensated one. Compensated phase is referred to as asymptomatic&#xD;
      stages, also known as compensated advanced chronic liver disease (cACLD). Decompensated&#xD;
      cirrhosis is a rapidly progressive phase marked by the development of complications of portal&#xD;
      hypertension (PH) and/or liver dysfunction. As the disease progresses, the presence of PH and&#xD;
      liver dysfunction can lead to the appearance of ascites, esophagogastric variceal bleeding&#xD;
      (EVB), hepatic encephalopathy (HE) and so on, marking the transition from a compensated to a&#xD;
      decompensated phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Portal hypertensive gastropathy (PHG) is one of the common complications of cirrhosis as&#xD;
      well, which is considered to be a potential cause of upper gastrointestinal bleeding (UGIB).&#xD;
      PHG is used to describe the endoscopic appearance of gastric mucosa in cirrhosis patients,&#xD;
      with a characteristic mosaic-like pattern with or without red spots, which was significantly&#xD;
      underestimated due to its absence of typical clinical manifestations. The pathogenesis and&#xD;
      risk factors of PHG in patients with liver cirrhosis are still controversial, but the&#xD;
      pathogenesis are generally believed to be related to PH and advanced liver dysfunction. The&#xD;
      presence of PHG is usually combined with esophageal varices (EVs). The severity degree of PHG&#xD;
      can vary from no/mild to severe, and patients with PHG are at an increased risk of acute and&#xD;
      chronic gastrointestinal bleeding . The overall prevalence of PHG varies from 4% to 98% . PHG&#xD;
      accounts for 0.8-40% of UGIB in patients with cirrhosis and 8-50% of non-variceal UGIB, among&#xD;
      which 2-12% of PHG can cause acute upper gastrointestinal bleeding (AUGIB), up to 95% of&#xD;
      which is associated with severe PHG and may be life-threatening. The prevalence of chronic&#xD;
      UGIB in patients with PHG ranges from 3 to 26%, which can lead to iron-deficiency anemia. The&#xD;
      proportion of UGIB that also can be attributed to mild PHG (range, 3.5-31%). The mortality&#xD;
      rate related to PHG bleeding is nearly 12.5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the study by Kim et al., severe PHG showed a significantly high risk of&#xD;
      mortality and reduced expected survival time than none or mild PHG. At present, most of the&#xD;
      researches and guidelines usually do not recommend primary prevention for patients with mild&#xD;
      PHG, however NSBB as primary prevention should be used for mild PHG combined with small EV&#xD;
      (guidelines recommend don't need primary prevention for small EV). The risk of UGIB with&#xD;
      severe PHG is higher than that with mild PHG, which means that NSBB should also be considered&#xD;
      for prevention even without EVs. For PHG patients with chronic iron deficiency anemia, after&#xD;
      excluding anemia caused by other causes, not only should use NSBB to reduce portal venous&#xD;
      pressure and the risk of bleeding, but also should pay attention to iron supplementation.&#xD;
      From the above, obviously, it is of great important to detect patients with PHG as soon as&#xD;
      possible. Nowadays, upper gastrointestinal endoscopy (UGIE) is the gold standard for&#xD;
      measuring PHG. However, as an invasive examination, endoscopy examination may massive&#xD;
      gastrointestinal bleeding or gastric perforation. Most patients are afraid and disable to&#xD;
      tolerate it, which significantly reduces the real morbidity of PHG and delays the time for&#xD;
      diagnosis and treatment. Therefore, there is a need to find effective non-invasive methods&#xD;
      that can predict patients with PHG in the early stage, especially which require treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, there had been significant efforts in the last decade to assess the utility of&#xD;
      non-invasive techniques and methods for the evaluation of liver fibrosis (LS) and portal&#xD;
      pressure as well as the presence of EVs in patients with cirrhosis. Recently, the most&#xD;
      promising technique is the measurement of LS by transient elastography (TE), either alone or&#xD;
      combined with other parameters, had confirmed to be evaluated the seviety of liver fibrosis&#xD;
      in patients with chronic liver disease, predicted the presence of clinically significant&#xD;
      portal hypertension (CSPH) and ruled out high-risk esophageal varices (HEVs) in patients with&#xD;
      cirrhosis. The use of TE alone can effectively assess liver fibrosis and portal hypertension&#xD;
      by liver stiffness measurement (LSM), but the diagnostic accuracy of EVs is limited.The&#xD;
      Baveno VI report guidelines acknowledged this application and recommend that LS combined with&#xD;
      platelet count (PLT) can rule out HEVs in patients with cACLD, it means that LS&lt;20 kPa plus&#xD;
      PLT&gt;150×109/L had a very low risk of having HEVs and therefore do not require routine&#xD;
      screening endoscopy. The criteria were validated and expanded extent to allow more people to&#xD;
      avoid endoscopic screening. According to the studies by Kim et al, LS-spleen diameter to&#xD;
      platelet ratio score (liver stiffness×spleen diameter/platelet count, LSPS) , LS combined&#xD;
      with other parameters，was clearly superior to the performance of LS alone for predicting EVs&#xD;
      in patients with hepatitis B-related cirrhosis, and subsequently validated as a reliable&#xD;
      predictor for CSPH in patients with cirrhosis by several studies. The PH risk score&#xD;
      (-5.953+0.188×LS + 1.583 ×sex (1: male; 0: female) +26.705×spleen diameter/platelet count)&#xD;
      has been firstly developed by Berzigotti et al.for diagnosis of CSPH in patients with&#xD;
      cirrhosis of any cause. In addition, platelet count to spleen diameter ratio (PSR) and&#xD;
      aspartate transaminase to platelet ratio (APRI) have also been confirmed by some studies that&#xD;
      can partly predict the seviety of liver fibrosis and EVs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some recent studies have reported that non-invasive methods also can predict PHG in patients&#xD;
      with cirrhosis to some extent. Zhang et al.established a model for predicting PHG combined&#xD;
      with ultrasound examination related indicators, but the model was complex and diagnostic&#xD;
      accuracy was poor. Yang et al.proposed a VAP scoring system combined spleen volume, platelet&#xD;
      count and albumin, which can predict the presence of EVs and PHG in patients with chronic&#xD;
      liver disease, but the results of this study have not been validated. Mandhwani et&#xD;
      al.explored the efficacy of PSR and right liver lobe diameter to albumin ratio (PLAR) in&#xD;
      predicting PHG in patients with cirrhosis, PSR was the better predictor better than PLAR.&#xD;
      More recently, a study suggested that the accuracy of LS in predicting the presence of PHG in&#xD;
      patients with hepatitis B-related cirrhosis was good. However, few high-quality studies used&#xD;
      non-invasive methods combined LS and other parameters to predict the PHG in patients with&#xD;
      liver cirrhosis, considering portal hypertension was the common pathogenesis of EVs and PHG,&#xD;
      we speculated that the above non-invasive methods combined LS and other routine parameters&#xD;
      are also suitable for predicting PHG in patients with cirrhosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study was to establish a new predictive model (PHG risk score) for diagnosing&#xD;
      PHG in patients with cirrhosis, then to compare the diagnostic accuracy of PHG risk score,&#xD;
      the non-invasive models combined with LS and other non-invasive models combined with routine&#xD;
      parameters in predicting PHG in patients with cirrhosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 6, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 20, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 20, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PHG and EVs detected by endoscopy</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>All patients will undergo or have been undergone endoscopy, endoscopy is performed by a small number of experienced endoscopy operators.The severity of PHG and the presence of EVS will be recorded.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">115</enrollment>
  <condition>Cirrhosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cirrhosis</arm_group_label>
    <description>In this cross-sectional study , we will collect all patients with cirrhosis who meet the inclusion and exclusion criteria criteria coming to The Second Affiliated Hospital, Xi'an Jiaotong University since March 2018 to December 2018.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        In this cross-sectional study , we will collect all patients with cirrhosis who meet the&#xD;
        inclusion and exclusion criteria criteria coming to The Second Affiliated Hospital, Xi'an&#xD;
        Jiaotong University since March 2018 to December 2018 .&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. aged 18-80 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. confirmed patients with cirrhosis : Cirrhosis is diagnosed using standard laboratory,&#xD;
             radiological, and physical examination findings, or by liver histology in equivocal&#xD;
             cases&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. paired noninvasive tests (blood tests, TE, and CT/enhanced CT) and gastroscopy within&#xD;
             3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The nature of the present study was explained to all patients and informed consent was&#xD;
             obtained from each case.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. the presence of severe ascites that might significantly hamper the accurate assessment&#xD;
             of LSM , obesity (body mass index&gt;35kg/m2) or intercostal space was too narrow;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. severe cardiopulmonary diseases, renal failure, acute illness, infectious diseases,&#xD;
             acute liver failure or cholestasis or hepatic congestion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. malignant tumors or other serious medical diseases (such as hepatocellular carcinoma,&#xD;
             gastric cancer, pancreatic cancer and colon cancer) that may reduce expected survival&#xD;
             time;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. non-cirrhotic portal hypertension and those with portal vein thrombosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. previous or ongoing treatment for portal hypertension, spleen diameter&lt;4cm or&#xD;
             splenectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. pregnant women and patients with implanted pacemakers;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. patients can not cooperate with the endoscopy, CT/enhanced CT, FibroTouch /FibroScan&#xD;
             and other related examination.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jinhai Wang, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>The Second Affiliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University,Xi'an, Shaanxi, China</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The second affiliated hospital of xi'an jiaotong university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Xi'an</city>
        <state>Shaanxi</state>
        <zip>710004</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 19, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 2, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 10, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 10, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 12, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Non-invasive methods</keyword>
  <keyword>Cirrhosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Potal hypertensive gastropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>Diagnostic accuracy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Cirrhosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

