<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03510260</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18-0063</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03510260</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Electronic Confirmed Versus Conventional Consenting Process: A Randomized Controlled Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>ECCCO</acronym>
  <official_title>Electronic Confirmed Versus Conventional Consenting Process (ECCCO)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Medical Branch, Galveston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      · The target population for our study is women who present in their last clinic visit before&#xD;
      delivery and are scheduled for an elective cesarean section. In that visit, the provider will&#xD;
      notify the research team in order for the subject to be screened for the study. If the&#xD;
      subject consents to participation, written informed consent will be obtained by&#xD;
      person-to-person contact. The PI, study coordinator, or a collaborator will be responsible&#xD;
      for the informed consent. After in-formed consent is obtained, the patient will be randomized&#xD;
      to the following study groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The control group will undergo regular consenting only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study group I (e-confirmed consent only) will receive an electronic invitation to complete&#xD;
      the consent process electronically and will proceed through the Confirmed Consent system&#xD;
      prior to arrival to labor and delivery on day of surgery, which is the routine patient flow&#xD;
      at this time. After completion of the survey, the subject will sign the regular paper consent&#xD;
      for the procedure as standard in our institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study group II will undergo the same intervention as group II but the COMRADE survey&#xD;
      questionnaire will be obtained by phone or in person after the completion of the paper&#xD;
      consent form.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      4.1 Screening, Recruitment, and Consenting:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Under the direction of the PI, trained research staff will be available 24/7 to screen&#xD;
           and con-sent patients according to study protocol. Patients will be enrolled at the time&#xD;
           a decision for planned repeat cesarean after VBAC counseling is made in clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After informed consent is obtained, the patient will be randomized to the study group or&#xD;
           the control group. A screening log will be used to track all patients approached for the&#xD;
           study. Women will only be randomized in clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recruitment: We will recruit all pregnant patient's decision was made for scheduled&#xD;
           cesarean after VBAC counseling made by their managing clinical team who do not meet any&#xD;
           of the ex-clusion criteria listed below. Once the inclusion criteria for our study are&#xD;
           met, the primary team will inform the patient about the study and ask her authorization&#xD;
           to contact one of the study personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Consenting process: Written consent will be obtained by direct person-to-person contact.&#xD;
           The principal investigator, study coordinator, or a collaborator will be responsible for&#xD;
           the informed consent. Non-English-speaking subjects are anticipated to be part of the&#xD;
           study population and informed consent will be provided in their primary language.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data collected will not be used for clinical diagnosis or treatment purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be reassured that participation in the study is voluntary and will not&#xD;
      interfere with diag-nose or treatment of her condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects will receive the same care and expertise as any other patient treated in our&#xD;
      institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.2. Randomization and Masking A confidential computer-generated simple randomization scheme&#xD;
      (using STATA 14, Dallas, TX) will be prepared and provided on an ongoing basis to our study&#xD;
      coordinator. A randomization log with group assignment, subject name, and medical record&#xD;
      number will be used to track the randomization process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subject will be included in the analysis by intent-to-treat once the randomization&#xD;
      assignment has been made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.3. Interventions The control group will undergo regular consenting only. At our unit&#xD;
      consent for an elective ce-sarean delivery occurs in the same day of surgery, few hours&#xD;
      before the procedure in a private room in labor and delivery while awaiting surgery. The&#xD;
      COMRADE questionnaire (our primary outcome) will be obtained after the completion of the&#xD;
      paper consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study group I (e-confirmed consent only) will receive an electronic invitation to complete&#xD;
      the consent process electronically and will proceed through the Confirmed Consent system&#xD;
      prior to arrival to labor and delivery on day of surgery, which is the routine patient flow&#xD;
      at this time. The COMRADE questionnaire (our primary outcome) will be obtained prior to the&#xD;
      initiation of the traditional consent (as in control group) before the completion of the&#xD;
      paper consent form, in order to assess satisfaction and understanding of the e-confirmed&#xD;
      consenting process completed before the procedure. After completion of the survey, the&#xD;
      subject will sign the regular paper consent for the procedure as standard in our institution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study group II will undergo the same intervention as group II but the COMRADE survey&#xD;
      questionnaire will be obtained after the paper consent is obtained in order to assess whether&#xD;
      both methods combined together improve the subjects' satisfaction of the consenting methods&#xD;
      and better understanding of the surgical procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.4. Survey Collection This is our primary outcome. Before the subject has the procedure, our&#xD;
      research staff will be collecting a survey assessing understanding of procedure and&#xD;
      satisfaction, please see attached survey with appli-cation. This survey will be obtained&#xD;
      according to the interventions detailed in sections 3 &amp; 4.3&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 8, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Unblinded randomized clinical trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COMRADE Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 7 days after delivery</time_frame>
    <description>a survey assessing understanding of procedure and satisfaction,</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Understanding Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 7 days after delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Survey or questionnaire to assess subject's understanding of the planned procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">105</enrollment>
  <condition>Satisfaction</condition>
  <condition>Risk Reduction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject will undergo regular consenting only. At our unit consent for an elective cesarean delivery occurs in the same day of surgery, few hours before the procedure in a private room in labor and delivery while awaiting surgery. The COMRADE questionnaire (our primary outcome) will be obtained after the completion of the paper consent form.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group I</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject will receive an electronic invitation to complete the consent process electronically and will proceed through the Confirmed Consent system prior to arrival to labor and delivery on day of surgery, which is the routine patient flow at this time. The COMRADE questionnaire (our primary outcome) will be obtained prior to the initiation of the traditional consent (as in control group) before the completion of the paper consent form, in order to assess satisfaction and understanding of the e-confirmed consenting process completed before the procedure. After completion of the survey, the subject will sign the regular paper consent for the procedure as standard in our institution.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group II</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject will undergo the same intervention as group II but the COMRADE survey questionnaire will be obtained after the paper consent is obtained in order to assess whether both methods combined together improve the subjects' satisfaction of the consenting methods and better understanding of the surgical procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Study Group I</intervention_name>
    <description>Study group I (e-confirmed consent only) will receive an electronic invitation to complete the consent process electronically.The COMRADE questionnaire (our primary outcome) will be obtained prior to the initiation of the traditional consent (as in control group).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group I</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>e-confirmed consent</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Study Group II</intervention_name>
    <description>The study group II will undergo the same intervention as group II but the COMRADE survey questionnaire will be obtained after the paper consent</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group II</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>e-confirmed consent plus paper consent</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will go through the consenting process at the day of surgery at the preop visit as standard in our institution only.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Standard paper consent only</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women &gt;18 and &lt;50&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plan for scheduled elective Cesarean&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient unwilling or unable to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Incarcerated patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to complete e-confirmed consent (not able to access the confirmed consent from&#xD;
             home)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Obstetrical population</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UTMB Galveston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Galveston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77555</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 25, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 27, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cesarean, Consent, Electronic, Satisfaction</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

