<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03592745</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18-0404</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03592745</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) and Robotic Training to Improve Arm Function After Stroke</brief_title>
  <acronym>tVNS</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Use of Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) and Robotic Training to Improve Upper Limb Motor Recovery After Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Northwell Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Northwell Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate if multiple therapy sessions of Transcutaneous Vagus&#xD;
      Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) combined with robotic arm therapy lead to a greater functional&#xD;
      recovery in upper limb mobility after stroke than that provided by robotic arm therapy in a&#xD;
      sham stimulation condition.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Promising new animal research suggests that vagus nerve stimulation paired with motor&#xD;
      intervention induces movement-specific plasticity in the motor cortex and improves limb&#xD;
      function after stroke. These results were recently extended to the first clinical trial, in&#xD;
      which patients with stroke demonstrated significant improvements in upper limb function&#xD;
      following rehabilitation paired with implanted VNS. Currently, vagus nerve stimulation is&#xD;
      being used clinically to treat a number of human diseases including migraine headaches,&#xD;
      epilepsy, and depression, and these investigations are expanding to deliver stimulation via a&#xD;
      transcutaneous route to potentially improve intervention efficacy and decrease side effects.&#xD;
      This pilot study will combine non-invasive transcutaneous stimulation of the vagus nerve with&#xD;
      upper limb robotic therapy to investigate the potential of tVNS to augment improvements&#xD;
      gained with robotic therapy in patients with chronic hemiparesis after stroke.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 9, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 12, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a double-blind, sham controlled treatment study in which patients will have a 50/50 chance of receiving robotic arm therapy with either active transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation (tVNS) or sham tVNS (placebo).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Both the participants and investigators performing and analyzing clinical and objective outcome measures will remain blind to condition. Participants will be told that they have a 50-50 chance of receiving either active or sham stimulation, but they will not be told which condition they receive.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Absolute Change From Baseline in Electromyographic (EMG) Peak Amplitude of the Bicep/Tricep</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention), and follow-up at 16 weeks (3 months after the intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The median absolute change in surface electromyographic (sEMG) peak amplitude of the bicep/tricep during gravity-eliminated, unassisted extensor movements was calculated from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention) and again at 16 weeks (3 months follow-up from the intervention) in each training condition (sham tVNS + robotic arm training vs. active tVNS + robotic arm training). Bicep and tricep peak sEMG amplitude scores were calculated as a percentage of the maximal volitional contraction (MVC), with larger values indicating a greater absolute change (negative or positive) in bicep/tricep peak muscle activity during extensor movements.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Change From Baseline in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer Assessment Score</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention), and follow-up at 16 weeks (3 months after the intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The median change in Upper Extremity Fugl-Meyer Score will be calculated from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention) and again at 16 weeks (3 months follow-up from the intervention) in each training condition (sham tVNS + robotic arm training vs. active tVNS + robotic arm training). The median change in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score is reported, with a range 0-66 points, and with higher values indicating better functional status.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Cerebrovascular Accident (CVA)</condition>
  <condition>Hemiparesis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>active tVNS + robotic arm therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sham tVNS + robotic arm therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sham (placebo) transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS)</intervention_name>
    <description>tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear.</description>
    <arm_group_label>active tVNS + robotic arm therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Transauricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS)</intervention_name>
    <description>tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear. Sham tVNS means the patient is wearing the device, but it is turned off and not delivering current during the treatment. This is a placebo condition, which is used as a study control.</description>
    <arm_group_label>sham tVNS + robotic arm therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sham Transauricular Vagus Nerve Stimulation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals between 18 and 85 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First single focal unilateral supratentorial ischemic stroke with diagnosis verified&#xD;
             by brain imaging (MRI or CT scans) that occurred at least 6 months prior&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive function sufficient to understand the experiments and follow instructions&#xD;
             (per interview with Speech Pathologist or PI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fugl-Meyer assessment 12 to 44 out of 66 (neither hemiplegic nor fully recovered motor&#xD;
             function in the muscles of the shoulder, elbow, and wrist).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Botox treatment within 3 months of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fixed contraction deformity in the affected limb&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete and total flaccid paralysis of all shoulder and elbow motor performance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior injury to the vagus nerve&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe dysphagia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Introduction of any new rehabilitation interventions during study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with scar tissue, broken skin, or irremovable metal piercings that may&#xD;
             interfere with the stimulation or the stimulation device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Highly conductive metal in any part of the body, including metal injury to the eye;&#xD;
             this will be reviewed on a case by case basis for PI to make a determination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or plan on becoming pregnant or breastfeeding during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant arrhythmias, including but not limited to, atrial fibrillation, atrial&#xD;
             flutter, sick sinus syndrome, and A-V blocks (enrollment to be determined by PI&#xD;
             review)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of an electrically, magnetically or mechanically activated implant (including&#xD;
             cardiac pacemaker), an intracerebral vascular clip, or any other electrically&#xD;
             sensitive support system; Loop recorders will be reviewed on a case by case basis by&#xD;
             PI and the treating Cardiologist to make a determination&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Feinstein Institute for Medical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manhasset</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dawson J, Pierce D, Dixit A, Kimberley TJ, Robertson M, Tarver B, Hilmi O, McLean J, Forbes K, Kilgard MP, Rennaker RL, Cramer SC, Walters M, Engineer N. Safety, Feasibility, and Efficacy of Vagus Nerve Stimulation Paired With Upper-Limb Rehabilitation After Ischemic Stroke. Stroke. 2016 Jan;47(1):143-50. doi: 10.1161/STROKEAHA.115.010477. Epub 2015 Dec 8.</citation>
    <PMID>26645257</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Capone F, Miccinilli S, Pellegrino G, Zollo L, Simonetti D, Bressi F, Florio L, Ranieri F, Falato E, Di Santo A, Pepe A, Guglielmelli E, Sterzi S, Di Lazzaro V. Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation Combined with Robotic Rehabilitation Improves Upper Limb Function after Stroke. Neural Plast. 2017;2017:7876507. doi: 10.1155/2017/7876507. Epub 2017 Dec 10.</citation>
    <PMID>29375915</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khodaparast N, Hays SA, Sloan AM, Fayyaz T, Hulsey DR, Rennaker RL 2nd, Kilgard MP. Vagus nerve stimulation delivered during motor rehabilitation improves recovery in a rat model of stroke. Neurorehabil Neural Repair. 2014 Sep;28(7):698-706. doi: 10.1177/1545968314521006. Epub 2014 Feb 18.</citation>
    <PMID>24553102</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khodaparast N, Hays SA, Sloan AM, Hulsey DR, Ruiz A, Pantoja M, Rennaker RL 2nd, Kilgard MP. Vagus nerve stimulation during rehabilitative training improves forelimb strength following ischemic stroke. Neurobiol Dis. 2013 Dec;60:80-8. doi: 10.1016/j.nbd.2013.08.002. Epub 2013 Aug 15.</citation>
    <PMID>23954448</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hays SA. Enhancing Rehabilitative Therapies with Vagus Nerve Stimulation. Neurotherapeutics. 2016 Apr;13(2):382-94. doi: 10.1007/s13311-015-0417-z. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26671658</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Volpe BT, Huerta PT, Zipse JL, Rykman A, Edwards D, Dipietro L, Hogan N, Krebs HI. Robotic devices as therapeutic and diagnostic tools for stroke recovery. Arch Neurol. 2009 Sep;66(9):1086-90. doi: 10.1001/archneurol.2009.182. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19752297</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 5, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 18, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>May 12, 2021</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Northwell Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bruce Volpe</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Transcutaneous vagus nerve stimulation (tVNS)</keyword>
  <keyword>VNS</keyword>
  <keyword>robotic therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>occupational therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>motor rehabilitation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 23, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/45/NCT03592745/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 23, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/45/NCT03592745/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Active tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
          <description>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Sham tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
          <description>Sham (placebo) transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Sham Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear. Sham tVNS means the patient is wearing the device, but it is turned off and not delivering current during the treatment. This is a placebo condition, which is used as a study control.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="18"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="18"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="15"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="15"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="3"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="3"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Adverse Event</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Lost to Follow-up</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="2"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>study temporary closure due to covid-19 pandemic</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="1"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Active tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
          <description>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Sham tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
          <description>Sham (placebo) transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Sham Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear. Sham tVNS means the patient is wearing the device, but it is turned off and not delivering current during the treatment. This is a placebo condition, which is used as a study control.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="18"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="18"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="36"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Full Range</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="56.0" lower_limit="27.9" upper_limit="81.1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="62.0" lower_limit="45.9" upper_limit="75.6"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="59.0" lower_limit="27.9" upper_limit="81.1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="18"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="18"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="7"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="10"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="17"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="18"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="18"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="36"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Median Absolute Change From Baseline in Electromyographic (EMG) Peak Amplitude of the Bicep/Tricep</title>
        <description>The median absolute change in surface electromyographic (sEMG) peak amplitude of the bicep/tricep during gravity-eliminated, unassisted extensor movements was calculated from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention) and again at 16 weeks (3 months follow-up from the intervention) in each training condition (sham tVNS + robotic arm training vs. active tVNS + robotic arm training). Bicep and tricep peak sEMG amplitude scores were calculated as a percentage of the maximal volitional contraction (MVC), with larger values indicating a greater absolute change (negative or positive) in bicep/tricep peak muscle activity during extensor movements.</description>
        <time_frame>baseline, discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention), and follow-up at 16 weeks (3 months after the intervention)</time_frame>
        <population>30 patients completed 9 sessions (3x/week for 3 weeks) of robotic arm training + sham or active tVNS, and 3 month follow-up at 16 weeks. One patient in the sham condition had corrupted sEMG measures, so 29 participants were consequently included in the efficacy analysis.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Active tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
            <description>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Sham tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
            <description>Sham (placebo) transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Sham Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear. Sham tVNS means the patient is wearing the device, but it is turned off and not delivering current during the treatment. This is a placebo condition, which is used as a study control.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Median Absolute Change From Baseline in Electromyographic (EMG) Peak Amplitude of the Bicep/Tricep</title>
          <description>The median absolute change in surface electromyographic (sEMG) peak amplitude of the bicep/tricep during gravity-eliminated, unassisted extensor movements was calculated from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention) and again at 16 weeks (3 months follow-up from the intervention) in each training condition (sham tVNS + robotic arm training vs. active tVNS + robotic arm training). Bicep and tricep peak sEMG amplitude scores were calculated as a percentage of the maximal volitional contraction (MVC), with larger values indicating a greater absolute change (negative or positive) in bicep/tricep peak muscle activity during extensor movements.</description>
          <population>30 patients completed 9 sessions (3x/week for 3 weeks) of robotic arm training + sham or active tVNS, and 3 month follow-up at 16 weeks. One patient in the sham condition had corrupted sEMG measures, so 29 participants were consequently included in the efficacy analysis.</population>
          <units>percentage of MVC</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>Inter-Quartile Range</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="15"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="14"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Median absolute change in bicep peak amplitude from baseline to discharge after 3 weeks of training</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="22.310" lower_limit="16.780" upper_limit="32.630"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="7.010" lower_limit="2.057" upper_limit="13.845"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Median absolute change in tricep peak amplitude from baseline to discharge after 3 weeks of training</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="16.070" lower_limit="11.460" upper_limit="19.930"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="10.055" lower_limit="5.330" upper_limit="32.553"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Median absolute change in bicep peak amplitude from baseline to 3 month follow-up</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="21.730" lower_limit="3.240" upper_limit="33.850"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="13.545" lower_limit="3.010" upper_limit="29.618"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Median absolute change in tricep peak amplitude from baseline to 3 month follow-up</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="10.520" lower_limit="6.420" upper_limit="24.070"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="11.455" lower_limit="7.303" upper_limit="18.848"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Equivalence</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>Statistical analysis of the median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude from baseline to DC immediately following 3 weeks of training was measured in the active vs. sham tVNS conditions. Null hypothesis is that there is no difference in median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude between the active and sham tVNS conditions. A significance level of 0.05 was used (two-tailed).</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.002</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>The Mann-Whitney Wilcoxon test was performed to compare median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude from baseline to 3 weeks (discharge) across two separate study conditions (active vs. sham tVNS).</p_value_desc>
            <method>Wilcoxon (Mann-Whitney)</method>
            <param_type>U value</param_type>
            <param_value>32.000</param_value>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
          </analysis>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Equivalence</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>Statistical analysis of the median absolute change in tricep peak sEMG amplitude from baseline to DC immediately following 3 weeks of training was measured in the active vs. sham tVNS conditions. Null hypothesis is that there is no difference in median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude between the active and sham tVNS conditions. A significance level of 0.05 was used (two-tailed).</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.445</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>The Mann-Whitney Wilcoxon test was performed to compare median absolute change in tricep peak sEMG amplitude from baseline to 3 weeks (discharge) across two separate study conditions (active vs. sham tVNS).</p_value_desc>
            <method>Wilcoxon (Mann-Whitney)</method>
            <param_type>U value</param_type>
            <param_value>87.000</param_value>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
          </analysis>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Equivalence</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>Statistical analysis of the median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude from baseline to week 16 (3 month follow-up after training) was measured in the active vs. sham tVNS conditions. Null hypothesis is that there is no difference in median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude between the active and sham tVNS conditions. A significance level of 0.05 was used (two-tailed).</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.678</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>The Mann-Whitney Wilcoxon test was performed to compare the median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG from baseline to 16 weeks (follow-up) across two separate study conditions (active vs. sham tVNS).</p_value_desc>
            <method>Wilcoxon (Mann-Whitney)</method>
            <param_type>U value</param_type>
            <param_value>95.000</param_value>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
          </analysis>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Equivalence</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>Statistical analysis of the median absolute change in tricep peak sEMG amplitude from baseline to week 16 (3 month follow-up after training) was measured in the active vs. sham tVNS conditions. Null hypothesis is that there is no difference in median absolute change in bicep peak sEMG amplitude between the active and sham tVNS conditions. A significance level of 0.05 was used (two-tailed).</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.777</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>The Mann-Whitney Wilcoxon test was performed to compare the median absolute change in tricep peak sEMG from baseline to 16 weeks (follow-up) across two separate study conditions (active vs. sham tVNS).</p_value_desc>
            <method>Wilcoxon (Mann-Whitney)</method>
            <param_type>U value</param_type>
            <param_value>98.000</param_value>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Median Change From Baseline in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer Assessment Score</title>
        <description>The median change in Upper Extremity Fugl-Meyer Score will be calculated from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention) and again at 16 weeks (3 months follow-up from the intervention) in each training condition (sham tVNS + robotic arm training vs. active tVNS + robotic arm training). The median change in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score is reported, with a range 0-66 points, and with higher values indicating better functional status.</description>
        <time_frame>baseline, discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention), and follow-up at 16 weeks (3 months after the intervention)</time_frame>
        <population>30 patients completed 9 sessions (3x/week for 3 weeks) of robotic arm training + sham or active tVNS, and 3 month follow-up at 16 weeks. A total of 30 participants were consequently included in the efficacy analysis.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Active tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
            <description>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Sham tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
            <description>Sham (placebo) transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Sham Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear. Sham tVNS means the patient is wearing the device, but it is turned off and not delivering current during the treatment. This is a placebo condition, which is used as a study control.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Median Change From Baseline in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer Assessment Score</title>
          <description>The median change in Upper Extremity Fugl-Meyer Score will be calculated from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks (immediately following the intervention) and again at 16 weeks (3 months follow-up from the intervention) in each training condition (sham tVNS + robotic arm training vs. active tVNS + robotic arm training). The median change in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score is reported, with a range 0-66 points, and with higher values indicating better functional status.</description>
          <population>30 patients completed 9 sessions (3x/week for 3 weeks) of robotic arm training + sham or active tVNS, and 3 month follow-up at 16 weeks. A total of 30 participants were consequently included in the efficacy analysis.</population>
          <units>scores on a scale</units>
          <param>Median</param>
          <dispersion>Inter-Quartile Range</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="15"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="15"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Median change from baseline to discharge at 3 weeks</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2.000" lower_limit="1.500" upper_limit="5.500"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="2.500" lower_limit="1.500" upper_limit="4.500"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Median change from baseline to 3 month follow-up</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2.330" lower_limit=".0500" upper_limit="5.500"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="1.670" lower_limit="1.000" upper_limit="4.500"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <analysis_list>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Equivalence</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>Statistical analysis of median change from baseline to DC immediately following 3 weeks of training was assessed with the upper extremity fugl meyer score in the active vs. sham tDCS conditions. Null hypothesis is that there is no difference in median change in upper extremity fugl meyer score between the active and sham tDCS conditions. A significance level of 0.05 was used (two-tailed).</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>1.000</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>The Mann-Whitney Wilcoxon test was performed to compare median change in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score from baseline to 3 weeks (discharge) across two separate study conditions (active vs. sham tVNS).</p_value_desc>
            <method>Wilcoxon (Mann-Whitney)</method>
            <param_type>U value</param_type>
            <param_value>112.000</param_value>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
          </analysis>
          <analysis>
            <group_id_list>
              <group_id>O1</group_id>
              <group_id>O2</group_id>
            </group_id_list>
            <non_inferiority_type>Equivalence</non_inferiority_type>
            <non_inferiority_desc>Statistical analysis of median change from baseline to week 16 (3 month follow-up) was assessed with the Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score in the active vs. sham tVNS conditions. Null hypothesis is that there is no difference in median change in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score between the active and sham tVNS conditions. A significance level of 0.05 was used (two-tailed).</non_inferiority_desc>
            <p_value>0.950</p_value>
            <p_value_desc>The Mann-Whitney Wilcoxon test was performed to compare median change in Upper Extremity Fugl Meyer score from baseline to 16 weeks (follow-up) across two separate study conditions (active vs. sham tVNS).</p_value_desc>
            <method>Wilcoxon (Mann-Whitney)</method>
            <param_type>U value</param_type>
            <param_value>110.500</param_value>
            <ci_n_sides>2-Sided</ci_n_sides>
          </analysis>
        </analysis_list>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>Adverse event data were collected for approximately 4 months, including the 3 week duration of the study intervention and the subsequent 3 month follow-up period.</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Active tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
          <description>Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Sham tVNS + Robotic Arm Therapy</title>
          <description>Sham (placebo) transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS) will be delivered non-invasively via the ear (targeting the auricular branch of the vagus nerve) during robotic arm therapy sessions lasting ~60 minutes, 3x per week for 3 weeks.&#xD;
Sham Transcutaneous Vagus Nerve Stimulation (tVNS): tVNS is a non-invasive form of vagus nerve stimulation, activating the auricular branch of the vagus nerve transcutaneously through the cymba concha at the pinna of the ear. Sham tVNS means the patient is wearing the device, but it is turned off and not delivering current during the treatment. This is a placebo condition, which is used as a study control.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Non-systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Infections and infestations</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>flu</sub_title>
                <description>Subject suffered from the flu (unrelated to study intervention) and consequently missed repeated sessions. Subject was ultimately withdrawn from the study as a consequence.</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Injury, poisoning and procedural complications</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>wrist fracture</sub_title>
                <description>Subject fractured wrist and was consequently unable to return for follow-up.</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="0" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="18"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>Principal Investigators are NOT employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Senior Research Coordinator</name_or_title>
      <organization>Feinstein Institutes for Medical Research at Northwell Health</organization>
      <phone>5165623646</phone>
      <email>jchang14@northwell.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

