<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03593460</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>sPIF-US-AIH-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03593460</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II AutoImmune Hepatitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II, Open Label, Adaptive Design, Multiple Dose Finding Study to Investigate Synthetic PreImplantation Factor (sPIF) in Patients With Autoimmune Hepatitis (AIH)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Christopher O'Brien, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>BioIncept LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Miami</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase IIa open label adaptive design dose finding study in male and female patients&#xD;
      with autoimmune hepatitis (AIH) with compensated liver function currently under standard of&#xD;
      care. The purpose of this study is to evaluate the sPIF dose that normalizes and maintains&#xD;
      the serum ALT when given for 14 doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Autoimmune Hepatitis is disease where the patient's immune system produces an inappropriate&#xD;
      immune response against their own liver. PreImplantation factor (PIF) is a substance that is&#xD;
      secreted by viable fetuses during pregnancy. PIF initiates both maternal tolerance preventing&#xD;
      the loss/rejection of the fetus. Synthetic PIF (sPIF) successfully translates PIF endogenous&#xD;
      properties to pregnant and non-pregnant immune disorders. sPIF was found to be effective in&#xD;
      preclinical models of autoimmunity and transplantation. Specifically, sPIF protected the&#xD;
      liver against immune attack.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is an open label, dose finding trial in patients with AIH who have an elevated ALT&#xD;
      levels. Patients will be administered a starting dose of sPIF 1mg/kg (n=10/cohort) for 14&#xD;
      days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT levels&#xD;
      until day 84. This will be followed by enrolling (n=10) patients administering 2mg/kg sPIF&#xD;
      for 14 days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT&#xD;
      levels until day 84. This be followed by an interim analysis that will determine clinical&#xD;
      efficacy by comparing the 1mg and 2mg dose results; testing the decrease in mean ALT percent&#xD;
      and determining the number of patients in remission defined as normalized ALT level. The&#xD;
      successful cohort will enroll additional patients to enable power analysis. If no significant&#xD;
      improvement is observed in the two cohorts, N=10 patients will be enrolled and administered&#xD;
      3mg/kg sPIF for 14 days assessing safety and tolerability. If no significant improvement is&#xD;
      noted and safety and tolerability is maintained additional 10 patients will be enrolled at&#xD;
      4mg/kg. Following the same analysis, the maximal dose to be administered will be 5mg/kg.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    BioIncept changed the focus of future drug development&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Adaptive Design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the safety and tolerability of multiple ascending, subcutaneously administered doses of sPIF in patients with autoimmune hepatitis (AIH) by measuring changes in ALT</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change of ALT from baseline to normal range</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the pharmacokinetics of sPIF levels in the circulation after multiple ascending, subcutaneously administered doses of sPIF by normalization of liver enzymes, immunoglobulins, and bilirubin levels</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>normalized AST, ALP, GGT, IgG, and bilirubin levels</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the safety and tolerability of the increased sPIF dose and treatment duration by no SAEes greater than grade 3</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>No SAE &gt; Grade 3 observed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the proportion of patients achieving total remission by normalization of serum ALT levels</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Normalization in serum ALT levels (Males &lt;45U/L and females &lt;30 U/L)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the proportion of patients achieving partial remission by obervation of ALT levels greater than 1 but less than 2 the upper limit of normal</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>ALT levels &gt; 1x ULN and &lt;2x ULN</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis, Autoimmune</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 1 mg/kg (Starting Dose)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be administered a starting dose of sPIF 1mg/kg (n=10/cohort) for 14 days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT levels</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 2 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be dosed at 2mg/kg sPIF for 14 days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT levels.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 3 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be administered a starting dose of sPIF 3mg/kg (n=10/cohort) for 14 days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT levels</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 4 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be administered a starting dose of sPIF 4mg/kg (n=10/cohort) for 14 days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT levels</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 5 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be administered a starting dose of sPIF 5mg/kg (n=10/cohort) for 14 days assessing safety, tolerability and clinical response based on the effect on ALT levels.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Synthetic PreImplantation Factor</intervention_name>
    <description>peptide</description>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 1 mg/kg (Starting Dose)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 2 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 3 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 4 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>sPIF 5 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>sPIF</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Written informed consent must be obtained before any assessment is performed. Patients with&#xD;
        a confirmed diagnosis of AIH either Type II or Type II, based on the International Criteria&#xD;
        for the Diagnosis of AIH, will be enrolled at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females aged from 18 to 75 years old, of non-child bearing potential&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must be either:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Postmenopausal for greater than two years Postmenopausal for less than two years with an&#xD;
        FSH level greater &gt; 40mIU/mL Documented as surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation,&#xD;
        bilateral oophorectomy or post-hysterectomy) at least three months prior to the screening&#xD;
        evaluation Or be greater than age 40, does not want more children, is currently using at&#xD;
        least one effective method of birth control at the time of screening and agrees to using&#xD;
        two effective methods of birth control starting with Study day 0 and through the 42 days&#xD;
        duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Must have in the judgment of the Investigator, the diagnosis of AIH, or have a score on&#xD;
        the International Criteria for the Diagnosis of AIH (Appendix 2) of: Pretreatment score ≥15&#xD;
        Post-treatment score of ≥17&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with prednisone and/or other oral, immunosuppressive drug(s) must be&#xD;
             stabilized for 6 weeks prior to screening for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients with an abnormal ALT confirmed by two measurements 2 weeks apart at&#xD;
             screening, with the present dose(s) of their immunosuppressant medication(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients do not have to have a documented relapse after completion of an initial&#xD;
             course of therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permitted concomitant immunosuppressant medications will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Azathioprine dose equal to/or less 100 mg per day Budesonide dose equal to/or less 9 mg per&#xD;
        day Mycophenolate metil equal to/or less 3000 mg per day Prednisone equal to/or less than&#xD;
        30 mg per day Ursodeoxycholic acid equal to/or less than 1500 mg er day Prograf equal to/or&#xD;
        less than 6 mg per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to abstain from alcohol and illicit drugs use during their&#xD;
             participation in the study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT and AST levels greater than 2 times less than five times the upper limit of the&#xD;
             normal (reference) range (ULN) and have no clinical or laboratory evidence of hepatic&#xD;
             decompensation (i.e., platelets ≥ 100,000/mm, total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × ULN, prothrombin&#xD;
             time ≤ 1.2 × ULN and albumin ≥ 3.0 g/dL) for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal renal function as determined by a serum creatinine&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients fulfilling any of the following criteria are not eligible for inclusion in this&#xD;
        study. No additional exclusions may be applied by the Investigator, to ensure that the&#xD;
        study population will be representative of all eligible patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other forms of chronic liver disease that is not under treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Decompensated liver disease defined on the basis of any one of the following&#xD;
             laboratory parameters at the screening evaluation: total bilirubin &gt; 1.5 × ULN,&#xD;
             prothrombin time &gt; 1.2 × ULN, platelets ≤ 100,000/mm3, or albumin &lt; 3 g/dL OR current&#xD;
             or prior history of clinical hepatic decompensation (e.g., ascites, jaundice,&#xD;
             encephalopathy or variceal hemorrhage)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &lt; 11 g/dL at the screening evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serological evidence of infection with HIV upon review of the medical record&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of hepatocellular carcinoma (i.e., screening α-fetoprotein &gt; 50 ng/mL or&#xD;
             other standard of care measure and ultrasound)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with, or a history of clinically significant oncologic, pulmonary, hepatic,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, renal, other cardiovascular, hematologic, metabolic, endocrine,&#xD;
             neurologic, immunologic or hematologic illness or any other major medical disorder&#xD;
             that, in the judgment of the Investigator, would interfere with patient treatment,&#xD;
             assessment or compliance with the protocol or should otherwise preclude their&#xD;
             participation in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received therapy with potentially hepatotoxic drugs within 3 months (90 days)&#xD;
             prior to day 1 or are expected to receive such therapy during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are expected to receive a change in their immunosuppressant therapies&#xD;
             during the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who may receive chemotherapeutic agents (e.g. immunoglobulins and other&#xD;
             immune- or cytokine-based therapies) during the study for any other medical condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of other investigational drugs within 5 half-lives of enrollment, or within 30&#xD;
             days until the expected pharmacodynamic effect has returned to baseline, whichever is&#xD;
             longer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to study drug or its excipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B and C, infectious hepatitis (documented in medical record may need to&#xD;
             repeat prior to enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tuberculosis (documented in medical record)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary sclerosing cholangitis, primary biliary cholangitis (documented in medical&#xD;
             record and may need to repeat prior to enrollment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency, hemochromatosis, or Wilson's disease (documented in&#xD;
             the medical record)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>eytan barnea, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>BioIncept LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Barnea ER, Rambaldi M, Paidas MJ, Mecacci F. Reproduction and autoimmune disease: important translational implications from embryo-maternal interaction. Immunotherapy. 2013 Jul;5(7):769-80. doi: 10.2217/imt.13.59. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23829627</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>December 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 7, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 9, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 31, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 31, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 3, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Miami</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christopher O'Brien, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis, Autoimmune</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

