<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02743728</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PT-2015-23643</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02743728</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Perinatal Stroke: Understanding Brain Reorganization</brief_title>
  <official_title>Perinatal Stroke: Understanding Brain Reorganization Through Infant Neuroimaging and Neuromodulation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cerebral Palsy Alliance</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>American Academy of Cerebral Palsy and Developmental Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development (NICHD)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Minnesota</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The incidence of perinatal stroke is relatively common, as high as 1 in 2,300 births, but&#xD;
      little is known about the resulting changes in the brain that eventually manifest as cerebral&#xD;
      palsy (CP). Motor signs that indicate the infant is beginning to develop CP often do not&#xD;
      become evident for several months after the diagnosis of perinatal stroke which delays&#xD;
      therapy. The main purpose of this study is to examine early brain reorganization in infants&#xD;
      3-12 months of age corrected for prematurity with perinatal stroke using magnetic resonance&#xD;
      imaging (MRI) and non-invasive transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS). In addition, the&#xD;
      association between the brain reorganization and motor outcomes of these infant participants&#xD;
      will be identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the MRI scans will include diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) - an established&#xD;
      method used to investigate the integrity of pathways in the brain that control limb movement.&#xD;
      Infants will be scanned during nature sleeping after feeding. The real scanning time will be&#xD;
      less than 38 minutes. TMS is a painless, non-surgical brain stimulation device which uses&#xD;
      principles of electromagnetic induction to excite cortical tissue from outside the skull.&#xD;
      Using TMS as a device to modulate and examine cortical excitability in children with&#xD;
      hemiparetic CP and in adults has been conducted previously.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this infant study, we will assess cortical excitability from the motor cortex of both the&#xD;
      ipsilesional and contralesional hemispheres under the guidance of a frameless stereotactic&#xD;
      neuronavigation system. Additionally, the investigators will assess infants' movement quality&#xD;
      using an age-appropriate standardized movement assessment. This will allow the investigators&#xD;
      to examine the relationship between measures of motor pathway integrity and early signs of&#xD;
      potential motor impairment. We will longitudinally follow enrolled infants, and complete&#xD;
      repeat assessments at 12- and 24-months corrected age to assess how infants develop over time&#xD;
      after perinatal stroke. The remote follow-up will occur at 5 years or less.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Understanding the early brain reorganization before the brain has not yet largely reorganized&#xD;
      is critical for developing efficacious early intervention. As a unique aspect of&#xD;
      investigation, this study will combine Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI)/ Diffusion Tensor&#xD;
      Imaging (DTI) and TMS to provide an additional opportunity to assess both the cortical&#xD;
      excitability and corticospinal tract (CST) integrity in infants with perinatal stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Identifying the association between laboratory assessment results and developmental outcomes&#xD;
      is also critical. This study is to use MRI/DTI and TMS to comprehensively examine both the&#xD;
      CST integrity and cortical excitability in infants following perinatal stroke, and to&#xD;
      identify association with motor outcome as evaluated by movement assessment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cortical Excitability MEP amplitude (µV)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Cortical excitability of ipsilesional and contralesional hemispheres assessed by transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) in infants with perinatal stroke.&#xD;
TMS will be used to assess cortical excitability through electromagnetic depolarization of targeted cortical neurons through painless pulses delivered over the scalp. The estimated time of TMS assessment is around 2 hours during Visit 2. Outcome is reported as MEP amplitude in units of microvolts (µV).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cortical Excitability percentage of maximum</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Cortical excitability of ipsilesional and contralesional hemispheres assessed by transcranial magnetic stimulation (TMS) in infants with perinatal stroke.&#xD;
TMS will be used to assess cortical excitability through electromagnetic depolarization of targeted cortical neurons through painless pulses delivered over the scalp. The estimated time of TMS assessment is around 2 hours during Visit 2. The outcome of motor threshold will be reported as the percentage of maximum stimulator output.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bilateral Corticospinal Tract Integrity (fractional anisotropy)</measure>
    <time_frame>38 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Bilateral corticospinal tract integrity (fractional anisotropy) will be derived from diffusion tensor imaging. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)/diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) will be performed when infants are sleeping with a real scanning time of 38 minutes during visit. Fractional anisotropy is an index (unitless measure) with a range of 0-1. Higher scores on the index indicate greater movement of water molecules in tissue being examined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>General Movement Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Movement quality will be assessed by general movement assessment (GMA). GMA requires 5-10 minutes videotaping when infants are placed in spine position for scoring. Infants are scores categorically as typical or atypical. Outcome is reported as the number of typical infants and number of atypical infants.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>2 days</time_frame>
    <description>Recording of adverse events will take place during TMS cortical mapping and MRI scanning of infants with perinatal stroke. Assessment of vital signs changes and pain/stress responses during both MRI and TMS assessment during visit 1 and visit 2.&#xD;
Outcome is reported as the number of adverse events recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated Individualized Electric Fields</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)/diffusion tensor imaging (DTI) will be performed and, using computational modeling, electrical field characteristics will be determined. Outcome is reported in units of volts/meter.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gross Motor Function Classification System</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The GMFCS is a five-level classification system to describe the gross motor function of children with cerebral palsy. Measure is collected remotely via Zoom.&#xD;
Distinctions between levels are based on functional abilities, assistive technology use, and quality of movement. Outcome is reported as a score on a scale with a range from 1 to 5. Higher scores indicate greater impairment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mini-MACS Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The Mini-MACS is a classification system to describe how children with cerebral palsy aged 1-4 years use their hands in daily activities. Measure is collected remotely via Zoom. Ability is ranked on five levels based on the child's self-initiate activity and their need for assistance/adaptation when handling objects. Outcome is reported as a score on a score with a range from 1 to 5 with higher scores indicating greater impairment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pediatric Evaluation of Disability Inventory Computer Adaptive Test</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The PEDI-CAT uses Item Response Theory statistical models to estimate a child's ability from a minimal number of items. Three functional domains will be assessed. The PEDI-CAT software provides normative standard scores presented as T scores and age percentile ranges to assess daily activities, mobility, and social/cognitive function. Outcome is reported as the mean score generated by the PEDI-CAT software.&#xD;
Scores are based on t-test values and do not have a unit of measure or a defined range.&#xD;
Higher scores indicate greater deviation from the standardized mean score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Hemiparesis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All Infants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Each infant will receive an Magnetic Resonance Imaging, then Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation Cortical Excitability testing, and General Movement Assessment. These 3 different components of the one arm in which all infants are involved will be collectively assessed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</intervention_name>
    <description>Anatomical and Diffusion Tensor Imaging Analysis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>All Infants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Assessment of brain (cortical) excitability</description>
    <arm_group_label>All Infants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>General Movement Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Spontaneous movement assessment of infant while lying in unperturbed state.</description>
    <arm_group_label>All Infants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The pilot study portion will recruit infants with unilateral perinatal stroke between 3 to&#xD;
        5 months of corrected age to understand their brain reorganization after stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The follow-up study portion will recruit children aged 5 years or younger who have been&#xD;
        diagnosed with perinatal stroke and who participated in the pilot study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria for Pilot Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Birth diagnosis of unilateral perinatal stroke by cranial ultrasound, computer&#xD;
             tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corrected gestational age between 3 and 24 months of age for both infants with stroke&#xD;
             and typically developing infants&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for Pilot Study :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metabolic Disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neoplasm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disorders of Cellular Migration and Proliferation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acquired Traumatic Brain Injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received surgeries that may constraint current spontaneous movements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indwelling metal or incompatible medical devices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received surgeries that may constraint current spontaneous movements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other neurologic disorders unrelated to stroke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Small for gestational age (SGA): Infants are smaller in size than normal for the&#xD;
             gestational age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Apneic episodes and syncope (known heart defects) for the safety of participants in&#xD;
             the stud.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Genetic disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Inclusion Criteria for Follow-up Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Previous participation in pilot study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Exclusion Criteria for Follow-up Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Lack of wireless internet access or computer to participate in virtual Zoom call&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bernadette T Gillick, PhD, MSPT, PT</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Minnesota</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Minnesota</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55455</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lehman LL, Rivkin MJ. Perinatal arterial ischemic stroke: presentation, risk factors, evaluation, and outcome. Pediatr Neurol. 2014 Dec;51(6):760-8. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2014.07.031. Epub 2014 Aug 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25444092</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eyre JA, Taylor JP, Villagra F, Smith M, Miller S. Evidence of activity-dependent withdrawal of corticospinal projections during human development. Neurology. 2001 Nov 13;57(9):1543-54.</citation>
    <PMID>11706088</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen CY, Tafone S, Lo W, Heathcock JC. Perinatal stroke causes abnormal trajectory and laterality in reaching during early infancy. Res Dev Disabil. 2015 Mar;38:301-8. doi: 10.1016/j.ridd.2014.11.014. Epub 2015 Jan 9.</citation>
    <PMID>25577180</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thelen E, Corbetta D, Spencer JP. Development of reaching during the first year: role of movement speed. J Exp Psychol Hum Percept Perform. 1996 Oct;22(5):1059-76.</citation>
    <PMID>8865616</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Einspieler C, Prechtl HF. Prechtl's assessment of general movements: a diagnostic tool for the functional assessment of the young nervous system. Ment Retard Dev Disabil Res Rev. 2005;11(1):61-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15856440</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eyre JA, Miller S, Clowry GJ, Conway EA, Watts C. Functional corticospinal projections are established prenatally in the human foetus permitting involvement in the development of spinal motor centres. Brain. 2000 Jan;123 ( Pt 1):51-64.</citation>
    <PMID>10611120</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eyre JA, Smith M, Dabydeen L, Clowry GJ, Petacchi E, Battini R, Guzzetta A, Cioni G. Is hemiplegic cerebral palsy equivalent to amblyopia of the corticospinal system? Ann Neurol. 2007 Nov;62(5):493-503.</citation>
    <PMID>17444535</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gillick BT, Krach LE, Feyma T, Rich TL, Moberg K, Menk J, Cassidy J, Kimberley T, Carey JR. Safety of primed repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation and modified constraint-induced movement therapy in a randomized controlled trial in pediatric hemiparesis. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2015 Apr;96(4 Suppl):S104-13. doi: 10.1016/j.apmr.2014.09.012. Epub 2014 Oct 2.</citation>
    <PMID>25283350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gillick BT, Krach LE, Feyma T, Rich TL, Moberg K, Thomas W, Cassidy JM, Menk J, Carey JR. Primed low-frequency repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation and constraint-induced movement therapy in pediatric hemiparesis: a randomized controlled trial. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2014 Jan;56(1):44-52. doi: 10.1111/dmcn.12243. Epub 2013 Aug 21.</citation>
    <PMID>23962321</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kirton A, Chen R, Friefeld S, Gunraj C, Pontigon AM, Deveber G. Contralesional repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation for chronic hemiparesis in subcortical paediatric stroke: a randomised trial. Lancet Neurol. 2008 Jun;7(6):507-13. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(08)70096-6. Epub 2008 May 1.</citation>
    <PMID>18455961</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Narayana S, Rezaie R, McAfee SS, Choudhri AF, Babajani-Feremi A, Fulton S, Boop FA, Wheless JW, Papanicolaou AC. Assessing motor function in young children with transcranial magnetic stimulation. Pediatr Neurol. 2015 Jan;52(1):94-103. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2014.08.031. Epub 2014 Sep 18.</citation>
    <PMID>25439485</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van de Ruit M, Perenboom MJ, Grey MJ. TMS brain mapping in less than two minutes. Brain Stimul. 2015 Mar-Apr;8(2):231-9. doi: 10.1016/j.brs.2014.10.020. Epub 2014 Nov 8.</citation>
    <PMID>25556004</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 19, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 14, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 19, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>perinatal stroke</keyword>
  <keyword>transcranial magnetic stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>magnetic resonance imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>diffusion tensor imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>non-invasive brain stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>infant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paresis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

