<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04895917</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AC-016-IT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04895917</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Daratumumab and Pomalidomide in Previously Treated Patients With AL Amyloidosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>DarPAL</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multi-center Open Label Phase II Study of Daratumumab and Pomalidomide in Previously Treated Patients With AL Amyloidosis.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>IRCCS Policlinico S. Matteo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>IRCCS Policlinico S. Matteo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims at establishing a new powerful combination of daratumumab and pomalidomide as&#xD;
      rescue treatment for patients with R/R AL amyloidosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite recent advance in understanding the biology of the amyloidogenic clone and despite&#xD;
      the availability of different therapeutic options, there are still patients who fail to&#xD;
      respond to fist line therapy and experience relapse after response to first line regimens.&#xD;
      The toxicity profile of daratumumab resulted favorable in the setting of advanced AL&#xD;
      amyloidosis patients with severe organ damage. Pomalidomide has proven to be effective as a&#xD;
      single agent in R/R AL amyloidosis with a better safety profile over lenalidomide because of&#xD;
      relevant renal toxicity of the latter drug in presence of nephrotic proteinuria. Daratumumab&#xD;
      is a recently released mAb that has shown deep hematological responses in R/R multiple&#xD;
      myeloma with a favorable toxicity. Up-to-date clinical data have further demonstrated the&#xD;
      high efficacy of combination regimens including an ImiD/Daratumumab combination in R/R&#xD;
      multiple myeloma reaching unprecedented results in terms of response rate, progression free&#xD;
      survival (PFS) and minimal residual disease (MRD) negativity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On these bases, the present study aims to explore the doublet Daratumumab/pomalidomide in R/R&#xD;
      AL amyloidosis. The goal of the study is to obtain rapid, durable and deep hematological&#xD;
      responses with a low toxicity profile. The expectation is to attain a very favorable&#xD;
      benefit/risk ratio from this combination as these patients should experience a low rate of&#xD;
      treatment discontinuation, hospitalization due AEs and/or disease progression and/or organ&#xD;
      failures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 23, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of good quality (i.e. CR+VGPR) hematologic response.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the rate of good quality (i.e. CR+VGPR) hematologic response at the completion of 6 cycles of Daratumumab plus pomalidomide in patients with relapsed/refractory AL amyloidosis not in VGPR or better after any previous therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients according to their disease history the overall Hematologic Response Rate (CR, VGPR, LowdFLC partial response and PR) at the completion of 1st and 3rd cycles.</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of Cycle 1 and Cycle 3 (each cycle is 28 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients the overall Hematologic Response Rate including PR at the completion of 6 cycles.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients duration of hematologic response. After treatment discontinuation, follow-up will be made to the patient every 3 months for at least 1 year.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients the rate of organ response (i.e. cardiac response: NT-proBNB measurement; renal response: proteinuria measurement) and organ improvement, according to standard criteria (Palladini et al JCO 2012, Palladini et al Blood 2014).</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients the time from the screening to hematologic and organ response.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients the hematologic disease progression free survival (PFS) from screening and 1-year PFS from screening (months).</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients the overall survival (OS) from screening and 1-year OS from screening (months).</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess in all patients the MRD negativity rate according to next generation flow cytometry.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess quality of life (QoL) using EQ5D-5L.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after treatment discontinuation</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>AL Amyloidosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pomalidomide and daratumumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>daratumumab and pomalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient eligible to enter the study will receive 6 cycles of 28 days of subcutaneous Daratumumab (1800 mg SC) and oral pomalidomide 4 mg from day 1 to day 21. During cycle 1 and 2, Daratumumab will be administered weekly at days 1, 8, 15, and 22 then from cycle 3 to 6, Daratumumab will be administered every other week at days 1 and 15.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pomalidomide and daratumumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histologic diagnosis of AL amyloidosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients should have received at least one line(and no more than 3 lines)with an&#xD;
             alkylating agent and/or a PIn and dexamethasone and not be in VGPR or CR at the time&#xD;
             of inclusion (patients who did not reach VGPR or patients in VGPR or better but with&#xD;
             an hematological relapse can be included);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Measurable hematologic disease: difference between involved and uninvolved FLC &gt; 20&#xD;
             mg/L with an abnormal k/l ratio;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Symptomatic organ involvement (heart, kidney, liver/GI tract, peripheral nervous&#xD;
             system);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Wash-out period of at least 4 weeks from previous antitumor therapy or any&#xD;
             investigational treatment or 5 half-lives from previous antibodies, whichever is&#xD;
             longer. Treatment from previous therapy should be in accordance to the local clinical&#xD;
             practice in which a 4 weeks period is required for the evaluation of response;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Adequate bone marrow function prior to 1st drug intake (C1D1), without transfusion or&#xD;
             growth factor support within 5 days prior to 1st drug intake, defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophils ≥ 1000/mm3,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 50000/mm3,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 9.0 g/dL,&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate organ function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum SGOT/AST or SGPT/ALT &lt; 3.0 X Upper Limit of the normal range (ULN),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total bilirubin level&lt;1.5x ULN, unless for subjects with Gilbert's syndrome&#xD;
                  where the direct bilirubin should then be ≤2.0 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Female patients who are postmenopausal for at least 1 year before the screening visit,&#xD;
             or are surgically sterile, or if they are of childbearing potential, agree to practice&#xD;
             effective methods of contraception from the time of signing the informed consent&#xD;
             through 30 days after the last dose of study drug, or agree to completely abstain from&#xD;
             intercourse (serum pregnancy test has to be performed for all women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential at the beginning of each cycle during the study. In addition, a pregnancy&#xD;
             test may be done at any time during the study at the discretion of the investigator if&#xD;
             a subject miss a period or has unusual menstrual bleeding);&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Voluntary written consent must be given before performance of any study-related&#xD;
             procedure not part of standard medical care with the understanding that consent may be&#xD;
             withdrawn by the patient at any time without prejudice to future medical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of non-AL amyloidosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. AL amyloidosis with isolated soft tissue involvement;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Bone marrow plasma cells &gt;30% and clinically symptomatic multiple myeloma with lytic&#xD;
             bone lesions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. NT-proBNP &gt;8500 ng/L and hs-troponin I &gt;100 ng/L (cardiac stage IIIb patients);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Repetitive ventricular arrhythmias on 24h Holter ECG despite anti-arrhythmic&#xD;
             treatment, except if a pacemaker has been implanted;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Chronic atrial fibrillation with uncontrolled heart rate;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Supine systolic blood pressure &lt;100 mmHg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject is a woman who is pregnant, or breast-feeding, or planning to become pregnant;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subjects with known chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or persistent asthma ;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Previous anti-CD38 or pomalidomide therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Presence of other active malignancy with the exception of non-melanoma skin cancer,&#xD;
             cervical cancer, treated early-stage prostate cancer provided that prostate specific&#xD;
             antigen is within normal limit, or any completely resected carcinoma in situ;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects with known/underlying medical conditions that, in the investigator's opinion&#xD;
             would make the administration of the study drug hazardous (ie: uncontrolled diabetes&#xD;
             oruncontrolled coronary artery disease);&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject is:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  (Known to be) seropositive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  seropositive for hepatitis B (defined by a positive test for hepatitis B surface&#xD;
                  antigen [HBsAg]).Subjects with resolved infection (ie, subjects who are HBsAg&#xD;
                  negative but positive for antibodies to hepatitis B core antigen [anti-HBc]&#xD;
                  and/or antibodies to hepatitis B surface antigen [anti-HBs]) must be screened&#xD;
                  using real-time polymerase chain reaction (PCR) measurement of hepatitis B virus&#xD;
                  (HBV) DNA levels. Those who are PCR positive will be excluded. EXCEPTION:&#xD;
                  Subjects with serologic findings suggestive of HBV vaccination (anti- HBs&#xD;
                  positivity as the only serologic marker) AND a known history of prior HBV&#xD;
                  vaccination, do not need to be tested for HBV DNA by PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  (Known to be) seropositive for hepatitis C (except in the setting of a sustained&#xD;
                  virologic response [SVR], defined as aviremia at least 12 weeks after completion&#xD;
                  of antiviral therapy).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Paolo Milani, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00390382502994</phone>
    <email>p.milani@smatteo.pv.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Anna Carnevale Baraglia</last_name>
    <phone>00390382502967</phone>
    <email>a.carnevalebaraglia@smatteo.pv.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Policlinico Universitario &quot;Mater Domini&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catanzaro</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marco Rossi, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Foundation IRCCS Policlinico San Matteo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pavia</city>
        <zip>27100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paolo Milani</last_name>
      <phone>+390382502967</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paolo Milani, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Università Campus Biomedico</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rome</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ombretta Annibali, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>IRCCS Policlinico S. Matteo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Paolo Milani</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>AL Amyloidosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Daratumumab</keyword>
  <keyword>Pomalidomide</keyword>
  <keyword>relapsed/refractory AL Amyloidosis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulin Light-chain Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pomalidomide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Daratumumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

