<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04898764</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AGO/2019/005</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-003254-91</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04898764</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Research on Underlying Causes of Long-term Use of Nasal Decongestants and the Structured Withdrawal of the Decongestant</brief_title>
  <official_title>Characterisation and Intervention Study in Patients With Long-term Use of Nasal Decongestants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Ghent</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Ghent</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rhinitis medicamentosa (RM) is a form of non-allergic medication-induced rhinitis&#xD;
      characterised by nasal congestion. This nasal congestion is the result of the overuse of&#xD;
      intranasal decongestants which leads to rebound congestion when the medication wears off.&#xD;
      This prompts the user of the nasal decongestant to administer more in order to obtain relief&#xD;
      from the feeling of a blocked nose. Therefore, the patient ends up in a vicious cycle caused&#xD;
      and temporarily relieved by the use of medication.The diagnosis of rhinitis medicamentosa&#xD;
      depends greatly on the history of prolonged use of the nasal decongestant, since real&#xD;
      diagnostic criteria have not yet been established. It is unclear if these patients suffer&#xD;
      from an underlying (undetected and/or untreated) nasal condition which might have caused the&#xD;
      patient to start using the nasal decongestant in the first place. Therefore, the aim of the&#xD;
      first part of this study (Part A) is to characterize patients with long-term use of nasal&#xD;
      decongestants to examine if an underlying nasal condition is present. The investigators will&#xD;
      include healthy volunteers in part A of the study to be able to compare their test results&#xD;
      with those of patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants and hence be able to detect&#xD;
      differences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus far, the treatment of RM has been the topic of debate. Several treatment regimens have&#xD;
      been proposed in literature, but most study authors agree that it is essential to stop the&#xD;
      overuse of the nasal decongestant either immediately or gradually to limit withdrawal&#xD;
      symptoms. For this part of the study (Part B: intervention study), the investigators aim to&#xD;
      reduce the long-term use of nasal decongestants based on a structured withdrawal programme&#xD;
      comprising medication (nasal corticosteroid spray) and motivational interviewing. Only&#xD;
      patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants are eligible to participate in this part&#xD;
      of the study. They will be rescreened prior to inclusion into this part of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study comprises two parts:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Part A: Characterisation study (both healthy volunteers and patients with long-term use&#xD;
           of nasal decongestants)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Part B: Intervention study (only patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants).&#xD;
           Patients will be rescreened prior to inclusion into part B of the study. Participants&#xD;
           will receive the intervention (Mometasone furoate nasal spray) during a 12-week period&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part A (characterisation study) consists of three study-related contact moments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Telephone contact&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Ear-, nose- and throat examination (actual characterisation study)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part B (intervention study) consists of five contact moments:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Start-up of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Telephone contact (during follow-up 1 period)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Follow-up 1 (After 6 weeks of intervention*)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Follow-up 2 (After 12 weeks of intervention*)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Telephone follow-up (6 months post start-up of the intervention*) * Study windows&#xD;
           foreseen in the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures performed during part A of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Peak Nasal Inspiratory Flow (PNIF) measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal endoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of blood samples&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of patient diary&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of data regarding medication use&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Skin prick testing&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of patient diary&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Telephone follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures performed during part B of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of data regarding medication use&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Counselling conversations with the researchers&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of questionnaires&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of patient diary&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Drug accountability&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Daily administration of Mometasone furoate (by the patients themselves, during a 12 week&#xD;
           period)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PNIF measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal endoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of blood samples&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Telephone follow-up&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, the study had to be temporarily halted due to a shortage in study&#xD;
    site personnel and local hospital guidelines. We anticipate to resume the study when the&#xD;
    COVID-19 pandemic is better controlled.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of study subjects with long-term use of nasal decongestants able to completely withdraw the use of the nasal decongestant after 12 weeks of intervention.</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the effectiveness of a standardized, structured withdrawal plan based on Mometasone furoate combined with motivational interviewing to reduce the overuse of nasal decongestants.&#xD;
For this study, complete withdrawal is defined as at least 7 consecutive days without any use of a nasal decongestant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of study subjects who were able to completely withdraw the long-term use of nasal decongestants at follow-up 2 (after 12 weeks of intervention) who relapsed by the time of follow-up 3 (6 months after the start-up of the intervention).</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at follow-up 3 (6 months post start-up of the intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the relapse rates of patients with former nasal decongestant overuse. For this study, relapse is defined as daily use of a nasal decongestant for more than 7 consecutive days after prior full withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in Rhinitis Control Assessment Test (RCAT) score (RCAT scores range from 6 to 30, with higher scores indicating greater rhinitis symptom control)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at intervention baseline, follow-up 1 (6 weeks post start-up intervention), and follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start-up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in rhinitis control due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in home measured PNIF as captured in diary on a fixed day every week</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during screening period (2 weeks) and intervention period (12 weeks post start up intervention) on a weekly basis</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in nasal patency due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in hospital measured Peak Nasal Inspiratory Flow (PNIF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at intervention baseline, follow-up 1 (6 weeks post start-up intervention), and follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start-up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in nasal patency due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) for nasal obstruction. Range 0mm - 100mm with higher values indicating worse outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at intervention baseline, follow-up 1 (6 weeks post start-up intervention), and follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start-up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in nasal patency due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) for nasal symptoms (nasal obstruction, runny nose, sneezing) as captured in the daily diary. Range 0mm-100mm with higher values indicating worse outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during screening period (2 weeks) and intervention period (12 weeks) on a daily basis</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in nasal patency due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in Mini Rhinoconjunctivitis Quality of Life Questionnaire (miniRQLQ) (14 items, 0= no impairment to 6= severely impaired; higher scores indicate greater impairment of QoL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at intervention baseline, follow-up 1 (6 weeks post start-up intervention), and follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in disease specific health-related quality of life (HRQoL) due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from intervention baseline (part B) to week 12 of intervention in PROMIS Sleep Disturbance Short form 8b scores (Raw scores range from 8 to 40, with higher scores indicating greater sleep disturbance)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at intervention baseline, follow-up 1 (6 weeks post start-up intervention), and follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start-up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in sleep disturbance due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline (part A) to week 12 of intervention in nasal endoscopy outcomes, assessed with our newly developed nasal endoscopy scoring sheet (containing Visual Analogue Scales (0-100mm), a colour scale and a nasal polyp scoring system)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline (characterisation study) and at follow-up 2 (12 weeks post start-up intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the change in nasal endoscopy outcomes due to the withdrawal of the nasal decongestant</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline (part A) to week 12 of intervention in exploratory biomarkers of inflammation and immune response in blood samples (multiplex analysis of cytokines)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at baseline (characterisation study) and at follow-up 2 (12 weeks of intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the effect of withdrawal on exploratory biomarkers of inflammation and immune response in blood samples</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">125</enrollment>
  <condition>Rhinitis Medicamentosa</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>This study arm will only participate in part A of the study (Characterisation study) and thus will not receive the study drug. A maximum of 25 healthy volunteers will be included in this study arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A maximum of 100 patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants will be included in this study arm, for part A of the study (Characterisation study).&#xD;
The investigators will consecutively recruit patients from part A (Characterisation study) into part B of the study (Intervention study) until a total of 25 patients completed all study-related visits of part B. During the intervention study, patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants will administer Mometasone furoate intranasally, two doses (50µg/actuation) in each nostril, twice daily (total daily dose of 400µg) during a 12 week period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mometasone Furoate</intervention_name>
    <description>Mometasone furoate nasal spray suspension, 50µg/actuation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria Healthy Volunteers (only included in part A of the study):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient knowledge of the Dutch language&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria Healthy Volunteers (only included in part A of the study):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjective presence of nasal disease (i.e. the study subject indicates to experience&#xD;
             any nasal symptoms, an occasional common cold not taken into account)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Established diagnosis of a nasal disorder (e.g. allergy, nasal polyps, …) or a&#xD;
             positive allergy test (skin prick test or blood test)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior nasal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an oral corticosteroid in the month prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant disease(s) that might interfere with the study, based on the judgement of&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of a nasal decongestant, more than two episodes of 7 days use of a nasal&#xD;
             decongestant in the previous year or less than two episodes of 7 days use (in the&#xD;
             previous year) but last use less than a month prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other medication used to treat nasal symptoms (intranasal corticosteroids, oral or&#xD;
             intranasal antihistamines, oral decongestants …)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of rhinitis medicamentosa (either patient-reported long-term use of a nasal&#xD;
             decongestant or a diagnosis of rhinitis medicamentosa)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, trying to become pregnant (during the duration of the study) or&#xD;
             breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants: part A:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Daily use of a nasal decongestant for at least 6 months. Following ATC-codes are&#xD;
             considered, when the spray or drops contain a nasal decongestant and the drug is thus&#xD;
             intended for short-term use only: R01AA, R01AB, R01AD52, R01AD53&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient knowledge of the Dutch language&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants: part A:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, trying to become pregnant (during the duration of the study) or&#xD;
             breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an oral corticosteroid in the month prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an oral decongestant in the week prior to the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant disease(s) that might interfere with the study, based on the judgement of&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants: part B:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Daily use of a nasal decongestant for at least 6 months.Following ATC-codes are&#xD;
             considered, when the spray or drops contain a nasal decongestant and the drug is thus&#xD;
             intended for short-term use only: R01AA, R01AB, R01AD52, R01AD53&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sufficient knowledge of the Dutch language&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria patients with long-term use of nasal decongestants: part B:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, trying to become pregnant (during the duration of the study) or&#xD;
             breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glaucoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an oral corticosteroid in the month prior to the start of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an oral decongestant in the week prior to the start of the intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant disease(s) that might interfere with the study, based on the judgement of&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Philippe Gevaert, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ghent University Hospital, Ghent, Belgium</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ghent University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ghent</city>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>non-allergic drug-induced rhinitis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mometasone Furoate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

