<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04897867</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MED-MA-PLS-0647</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04897867</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>CoolSculpting® Elite for Non-Invasive Fat Reduction</brief_title>
  <official_title>CoolSculpting® Elite: Multi-Country Study to Evaluate Patient Satisfaction for Non-Invasive Fat Reduction in Abdomen, Flanks, Upper Arms, Inner Thighs, Outer Thighs and Submental Area</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Allergan</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Allergan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to generate data that conveys participant's experiences such as their&#xD;
      satisfaction with treatment delivered by the redesigned CoolSculpting® Elite system for&#xD;
      non-invasive fat reduction in the midsection area (abdomen and flanks) in addition to&#xD;
      optional body areas of upper arms, inner thighs, outer thighs and/or submental area. By doing&#xD;
      this, the study will provide insights for doctors to better inform participants about the&#xD;
      expected outcomes when one or more body areas are considered for treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 4, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 4, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants with \&quot;satisfied\&quot; or \&quot;very satisfied\&quot; on Item #1 for the CSQ (Cryolipolysis Satisfaction Questionnaire)- Midsection</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after the final treatment session (measured at Week 12 for participants who received only one 1 treatment session or Week 20 for participants who received 2 treatment sessions)</time_frame>
    <description>The CSQ-Midsection is a 2-item Patient-reported Outcome (PRO) instrument that measures participant's satisfaction with CoolSculpting® treatment of the midsection (abdomen and flanks). Participants rate their satisfaction by answering CSQ Item 1 =&quot;\Rate your overall satisfaction with the results of the fat reduction procedure on the treated area\&quot; using the following scale: Very satisfied, Satisfied, Neither satisfied nor dissatisfied, Dissatisfied or Very dissatisfied.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate safety of the CoolSculpting Elite System using CoolSculpting Elite applicators for non-invasive subcutaneous fat reduction of the abdomen and flanks, and optional additional body areas .</measure>
    <time_frame>First treatment to Follow-up/Exit Visit (Week 12 + 14 days for those participants who received only 1 treatment session and Week 20 + 14 days for those participants who received 2 treatment sessions)</time_frame>
    <description>The numbers and proportions of participants with adverse events (AEs) and adverse device effects (ADEs); serious adverse events (SAEs), serious adverse device effects (SADEs), and unanticipated AEs or ADEs will be determined.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who received treatment to abdomen and flank and one or more additional body areas for treatment with &quot;satisfied&quot; or &quot;very satisfied&quot; on CSQ-Overall Item 1</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after the final treatment session (measured at Week 12 for participants who received only one 1 treatment session or Week 20 for participants who received 2 treatment sessions)</time_frame>
    <description>The CSQ-Overall is a 1-item Patient-reported Outcome (PRO) instrument that measures the participant's satisfaction with CoolSculpting® Elite treatment when more than one body area has been selected for treatment. Participants rate their satisfaction by answering CSQ-Overall Item 1=&quot;\Rate your overall satisfaction with the results of the fat reduction procedure on the treated areas\&quot; using the following scale: Very satisfied, Satisfied, Neither satisfied nor dissatisfied, Dissatisfied or Very dissatisfied.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants with &quot;satisfied&quot; or &quot;very satisfied&quot; on individual treated body area (upper arms, inner thighs, outer thighs, fat under chin) CSQ Item 1</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after the final treatment session (measured at Week 12 for participants who received only one 1 treatment session or Week 20 for participants who received 2 treatment sessions)</time_frame>
    <description>The CSQ- Upper Arms, CSQ-Inner Thighs, CSQ-Outer Thighs, CSQ-Fat Under Chin are 1-item Patient-reported Outcome (PRO) instruments that measure participant's satisfaction with CoolSculpting® Elite treatment for the optional additional invididual body areas treated. Participants rate their satisfaction by answering CSQ Item 1 =&quot;\Rate your overall satisfaction with the results of the fat reduction procedure on the [treated area]\&quot; using the following scale: Very satisfied, Satisfied, Neither satisfied nor dissatisfied, Dissatisfied or Very dissatisfied.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correct identification of baseline vs 12-week post-final treatment images of the treated body area(s) by at least two out of three blinded, independent reviewers.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after the final treatment session (measured at Week 12 for participants who received only one 1 treatment session or Week 20 for participants who received 2 treatment sessions)</time_frame>
    <description>Success will be defined as at least 70% correct identification of the pre-treatment images.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-invasive Fat Reduction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CoolSculpting® Elite System</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants received up to two CoolSculpting® Elite treatment sessions for the abdomen and flanks plus optional additional body areas 8 weeks apart. At the investigator's discretion, per treatment session, up to 8 treatment cycles were performed for the midsection, and if applicable, up to 2 treatment cycles for the submental area, up to 4 cycles to upper arms, and up to 4 cycles each to inner and/or outer thighs.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CoolSculpting® Elite System with CoolSculpting® Elite applicators</intervention_name>
    <description>A treatment session is comprised of timed segments of cooling (treatment cycles) followed by 2 minutes of manual massage.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CoolSculpting® Elite System</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be in good health as determined by medical history, physical&#xD;
             examination, vital signs, and investigator's judgment, including no known active&#xD;
             pandemic infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has clearly visible and palpable fat in the abdomen and flanks, and&#xD;
             participant may also be assessed for visible and palpable fat in one or more of the&#xD;
             following body areas: left and right lower aspects of the upper arms, left and right&#xD;
             inner thigh, left and right outer thigh, or submental area, which in the&#xD;
             investigator's opinion is appropriate for and may benefit from treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a BMI of ≥ 18.5 and &lt; 30. BMI is defined as weight in kilograms&#xD;
             divided by height in meters squared (kg/m2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agrees to maintain weight (ie, within 5% of body weight) by not making any&#xD;
             changes in diet or exercise routine during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agrees to have photographs taken of the treatment area(s) during the&#xD;
             scheduled time periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of an invasive fat reduction procedure (eg, liposuction,&#xD;
             surgery, lipolytic agents, etc) within or adjacent to the area being considered for&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has implants (eg, breast implants) in or immediately adjacent to the area&#xD;
             of intended treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of prior surgery or scar tissue related to the area being&#xD;
             considered for treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known history of cryoglobulinemia, cold urticaria, cold agglutinin&#xD;
             disease, or paroxysmal cold hemoglobinuria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known sensitivity to cold or has any condition with a known response&#xD;
             to cold exposure that limits blood flow to the skin, such as cold urticaria, Raynaud's&#xD;
             disease, or chilblains (pernio).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with a clinically significant bleeding disorder, or concomitant use of&#xD;
             blood thinners, or is taking any medication that, in the investigator's opinion, may&#xD;
             significantly increase the participant's risk of bruising or bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of carpal tunnel syndrome, compartment syndrome, or deep&#xD;
             vein thrombosis in the upper or lower extremities (only applicable for participants&#xD;
             receiving treatment to the upper arms or thighs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is currently taking or has taken diet pills or weight control supplements&#xD;
             within the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any skin conditions, such as moderate to excessive skin laxity, open&#xD;
             wound, or scars, and active infection, eczema, dermatitis or rashes in the location of&#xD;
             the treatment sites that may interfere with the treatment or evaluation (stretch marks&#xD;
             are not an exclusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has an active implanted device such as a pacemaker, defibrillator, drug&#xD;
             delivery system, or any other metal-containing implant, within or adjacent to the area&#xD;
             being considered for treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant (WOCBP- woman of childbearing potential) is pregnant or intending to&#xD;
             become pregnant in the next 3 to 6 months and does not agree to use reliable&#xD;
             contraception during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is lactating or has been lactating in the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is unable or unwilling to comply with the study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is currently enrolled in a clinical study of any unapproved&#xD;
             investigational device, investigational product, or any other type of medical research&#xD;
             judged not to be scientifically or medically compatible with this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any other condition or laboratory value that would, in the&#xD;
             professional opinion of the investigator, potentially affect the participant's&#xD;
             response or the integrity of the data or would pose an unacceptable risk to the&#xD;
             participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had a non-invasive fat reduction and/or body contouring procedure in&#xD;
             the area(s) of intended treatment within the past 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant needs to administer, or has a known history of subcutaneous injections,&#xD;
             into the area(s) of intended treatment (eg, cortisone, heparin, insulin) within the&#xD;
             past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with known sensitivity or allergy to fructose, glycerin, isopropyl&#xD;
             alcohol, or propylene glycol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has impaired peripheral circulation in the area to be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has neuropathic disorders such as post-herpetic neuralgia or diabetic&#xD;
             neuropathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has impaired skin sensation in or immediately adjacent to the treatment&#xD;
             area(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of hernia in or immediately adjacent to the treatment&#xD;
             area(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant diagnosed with a systemic fibrosing disease or fibrosis in the area&#xD;
             intended or adjacent to the area to be treated.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>ALLERGAN INC.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Allergan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laser &amp; Skin Surgery Center of Northern California</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95816</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laser &amp; Skin Surgery Center of New York</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10016</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Fat Reduction Non-invasive</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>AbbVie is committed to responsible data sharing regarding the clinical trials we sponsor. This includes access to anonymized, individual and trial-level data (analysis data sets), as well as other information (e.g., protocols and clinical study reports), as long as the trials are not part of an ongoing or planned regulatory submission. This includes requests for clinical trial data for unlicensed products and indications.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>For details on when studies are available for sharing, please refer to the link below</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Access to this clinical trial data can be requested by any qualified researchers who engage in rigorous, independent scientific research, and will be provided following review and approval of a research proposal and Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP) and execution of a Data Use Agreement (DUA). For more information on the process, or to submit a request, visit the following link.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://vivli.org/ourmember/abbvie/</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

