<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04896190</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>merveyilmaz</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04896190</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Relationship Between Q Angle and Quadriceps Muscle Activation on Dynamic Balance in Women</brief_title>
  <acronym>Quadriceps</acronym>
  <official_title>The Relationship Between Q Angle and Quadriceps Muscle Activation on Dynamic Balance in Women</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The quadriceps angle (Q angle) is significant for the lower extremity alignment. Anatomical&#xD;
      alignment of Q angle is related to Quadriceps muscle strength. Women have consistently been&#xD;
      found to have larger Q angles than men and are more often affected due to patellofemoral&#xD;
      problems. Quadriceps muscle activation and lower extremity alignment affect musculoskeletal&#xD;
      health in women.The aim of this study wa s to determine the relationship between Q angle and&#xD;
      quadriceps muscle activation on dynamic balance in women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective: To determine the relationship between Q angle and quadriceps muscle activation on&#xD;
      dynamic balance in women. Design: Correlational Study. Setting: University. Participants:&#xD;
      Forth women will be included in the study. Interventions: Q angle in standing and supine&#xD;
      positions, quadriceps muscle activation, static and dynamic balance and functionality were&#xD;
      measured. Main Outcome Measurements: Q angle will measured with a tape measure; muscle&#xD;
      activation will measured with Surface Electromyography (EMG) static balance will measured&#xD;
      with Flamingo Balance Test (FBT); dynamic balance will measured with ProKin 252 Techno Body&#xD;
      device; and, functionality will measured with Short Form Musculoskeletal Assessment (SFMA).&#xD;
      Before the evaluation of EMG amplitude on dynamic balance position, the Q angle will measured&#xD;
      in supine and standing positions. The EMG signals collected by measuring the muscle&#xD;
      activation of the Vastus Medialis and Vastus Lateralis during dynamic balance position on the&#xD;
      ProKin device will recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 13, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Q angle evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The Q angle was measured with a standard universal goniometer. It was measured by drawing a line from the Anterior Superior Iliac Spine to the center of the patella and a second line from the center of the tibial tubercle to the center of the patella.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Electromyographic (EMG) measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>EMG biofeedback is a device that detects neuromuscular contractions and provides feedback signals to the subject. During the ProKin 252 Techno Body balance system, Vastus Medialis and Vastus Lateralis muscles activity levels were recorded at 1000-Hz sample data-regulating Surface EMG device and analyzed using the Biometrics Datalog (UK) system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamic Balance Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Dynamic balance was evaluated by ProKin 252 Techno Body balance device. The participants were taken to the balance platform on the right foot with their eyes open, after determining the reference interval and setting the test time as 30 seconds.They were instructed to stay balanced on the platform</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Static Balance Evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Static balance was assessed with Flamingo Balance Test (FBT) in open and closed eyes conditions.The subjects stood on the beam which was 50 cm long, 5 cm in height and 3 cm wide. Then the instructor started the stopwatch and the subjects tried to stand in this position for one minute. When the time was over, the subjects' attempts after they fell were counted and this score was recorded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functionality Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The functional status of subjects was evaluated with the Short Musculoskeletal Function Assessment Questionnaire (SMFA).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Before the evaluation of EMG amplitude on dynamic balance position, the Q angle was measured in supine and standing positions. The EMG signals collected by measuring the muscle activation of the Vastus Medialis and Vastus Lateralis during dynamic balance position on the ProKin device were recorded. Q angle evaluations, static and dynamic balance and functional status of all participants were evaluated.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Evaluation of Q angle and Quadriceps muscle activation on dynamic balance position</intervention_name>
    <description>Evaluation of Q angle, Quadriceps muscle activation, static and dynamic balance and functionality of all individuals was done.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The inclusion criteria were being women, being aged 19-25, and not having&#xD;
             musculoskeletal or neurological problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusion criteria were having an operation in the past year, taking medicine related&#xD;
             to lower limb problems, persistent pain and discomfort of the lower extremity.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul Medipol University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nguyen AD, Boling MC, Levine B, Shultz SJ. Relationships between lower extremity alignment and the quadriceps angle. Clin J Sport Med. 2009 May;19(3):201-6. doi: 10.1097/JSM.0b013e3181a38fb1.</citation>
    <PMID>19423972</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>merve yilmaz menek</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Q angle</keyword>
  <keyword>Quadriceps muscle activation</keyword>
  <keyword>EMG</keyword>
  <keyword>Balance</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>I will publish my manuscript about this study, so researchers can access my individual participant's daha with this way.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

