<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04709315</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>southvu7</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04709315</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rapid Sequence Induction: Succinyl Choline vs Rocuronium After Pretreatment With Dexmedetomidine</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison Between Standalone Succinyl Choline and Rocuronium After Pretreatment With Dexmedetomidine, in Rapid Sequence Induction.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>South Valley University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>South Valley University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Rapid sequence induction is a well-established anesthetic procedure used in&#xD;
      trauma setting and patients with full stomach. Succinyl choline has the been the drug of&#xD;
      choice, however, it carries potential risk and sometimes fatal outcome. Aim of the study: to&#xD;
      compare rocuronium after pre-treatment with Dexmedetomidine, to succinyl choline in providing&#xD;
      excellent intubating conditions. Material and method: Patients were randomly allocated to one&#xD;
      of two groups, of 120 each. Control (SS) group, patients received pretreatment with 10 ml&#xD;
      0.9% saline over 10 minutes, and succinyl choline 1mg/ kg was on induction. Experimental (DR)&#xD;
      group, received pretreatment with Dex 1 µg / kg in 10 ml 0.9% saline over 10 minutes and&#xD;
      rocuronium 0.6 mg/kg on induction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rapid sequence induction (RSI) is a well-established anesthetic procedure routinely used in&#xD;
      emergency and trauma setting, and in elective situations when there is high risk of&#xD;
      regurgitation/aspiration The ideal neuromuscular relaxant agent used for RSI should have a&#xD;
      quick onset of action, which is a major advantage in trauma setting as it mitigates the risk&#xD;
      of aspiration and desaturation when endotracheal intubation should be performed as early as&#xD;
      possible. It also should have a quick offset to ensure that if trials at endotracheal&#xD;
      intubation were unsuccessful, there would be quick neuromuscular recovery, with return to&#xD;
      spontaneous breathing before the patient start desaturation. Moreover, it should have minimal&#xD;
      cardiovascular or systemic side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Typically, succinyl choline has been the neuromuscular agent of choice for RSI as it has the&#xD;
      quickest onset and offset of action compared to other muscle relaxants. However, it has&#xD;
      potentially risky- sometimes fatal- side effects that make it far from being ideal&#xD;
      neuromuscular blocking agent in RSI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Owing to its fast onset of action and stable hemodynamics Rocuronium, a non-depolarizing&#xD;
      muscle blocker, has been suggested as possible alternative to succinyl choline in RSI. The&#xD;
      standard rocuronium intubating dose of during routine anesthesia is 0.6 mg/ kg, which results&#xD;
      in adequate intubation conditions within 60 seconds in nearly all patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The recommended rocuronium intubating dose during RSI anesthesia is 1.0-1.2 mg/kg, after&#xD;
      which optimum tracheal intubation conditions are also achieved within 60 seconds in nearly&#xD;
      all patients. If the standard dose of 0.6 mg/ kg is given on RSI of anesthesia, it is advised&#xD;
      to wait 90 seconds before attempting to intubate the trachea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nevertheless, this high dose has long duration of action and may pose a risk in patients with&#xD;
      unpredictable difficult intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dexmedetomidine (DEX), is a selective centrally acting α 2-adrenergic receptors agonist that&#xD;
      has been used successfully as procedural adjuvant, e.g., to minimize the stress response to&#xD;
      laryngoscopy during endotracheal intubation and has gained popularity in the peri-operative&#xD;
      period, due to its unique action as anxiolytic, sedative with no respiratory depression,&#xD;
      analgesic, opioid sparing effect, and Its ability to decrease overall anesthetic&#xD;
      requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of our study is to compare a combination of standard intubating dose of DEX and&#xD;
      rocuronium (0.6 mg /kg) to succinyl choline as regard endotracheal intubation condition&#xD;
      during RSI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and method&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomly allocated to one of two groups, of 120 each. The Dex pretreatment/&#xD;
      rocuronium group (DR group), and saline pretreatment/succinyl group (SS group). In the DR&#xD;
      group, patients shall receive pretreatment with Dex 1 µg / kg in 10 ml 0.9% saline over 10&#xD;
      minutes and rocuronium 0.6 mg/kg is the intubating muscle relaxant. In the SS group, patients&#xD;
      receive pretreatment with 10 ml 0.9% saline over 10 minutes, and succinyl choline 1mg/ kg is&#xD;
      the intubating muscle relaxant. Pretreatments will be given over 10 minutes using infusion&#xD;
      pump.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As soon as the pretreatment is completed, intravenous (IV) fentanyl 0.1 μg / kg and&#xD;
      preoxygenation for 3 minutes with a facemask, after which anesthesia is induced with IV&#xD;
      propofol 2 mg/ kg. Standardized intubating procedure is carried out that on loss of&#xD;
      consciousness, the neuromuscular relaxant drug is given per protocol, and 45 seconds later&#xD;
      the intubating anesthetist will be called in the operating room, at 50 seconds laryngoscopy&#xD;
      is introduced and at 60 seconds, the trachea would be expectedly successfully intubated. To&#xD;
      minimize interobserver bias, all intubations will be conducted by two designated senior&#xD;
      consultants. No ventilation will be carried out before orotracheal intubation. No cricoid&#xD;
      pressure shall be performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>that the anesthetist who prepared the experimented drugs was different from the one who was responsible for administration of all medications during induction and maintenance and was responsible for the patient throughout the surgery till patient was ready to transfer to PACU. An independent third anesthetist blinded to the experimental drug administration, carried out intubation and scored intubating conditions. This independent anesthetist, was summoned to enter the operating room 45 seconds after neuromuscular relaxant was administered, when the patient was ready for intubation.&#xD;
Moreover,All drugs administered in control group (saline 0.9%- succinyl; 1mg/kg) and experimental group (Dex; 1 µg/kg- rocuronium; 0.6mg/kg), were prepared in 10 mL syringe and were given via infusion pump. Saline and Dex were given over 10 minutes immediately prior to induction.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>number of patients with excellent intubating conditions</measure>
    <time_frame>60 seconds after muscle relaxant has been given</time_frame>
    <description>This score is based on triad of signs: how easy to insert the laryngoscope, the anatomical position of the vocal cords, and how patients react to the introduction of the laryngoscope</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>at induction of anesthesia, 4 and 5 minutes after intubation.</time_frame>
    <description>heart rate (beats/minute) were non invasively recorded</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mean blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>at induction, 4 and 5 minutes after intubation</time_frame>
    <description>mean blood pressure were non invasively recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">240</enrollment>
  <condition>Rapid Sequence Induction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>saline pretreatment/succinyl group (SS group).</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients receive pretreatment with 10 ml 0.9% saline over 10 minutes, and succinyl choline 1mg/ kg is the intubating muscle relaxant.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dex pretreatment/ rocuronium group (DR group),</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients receive pretreatment with Dex 1 µg / kg in 10 ml 0.9% saline over 10 minutes and rocuronium 0.6 mg/kg is the intubating muscle relaxant.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>dexemedetomidine and rocuronium</intervention_name>
    <description>In the DR group, patients received pretreatment with Dex 1 µg / kg in 10 ml 0.9% saline over 10 minutes and rocuronium 0.6 mg/kg was the intubating muscle relaxant</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dex pretreatment/ rocuronium group (DR group),</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>0.9% saline and succinyl choline 1mg/ kg</intervention_name>
    <description>0.9% saline over 10 minutes, and succinyl choline 1mg/ kg</description>
    <arm_group_label>saline pretreatment/succinyl group (SS group).</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status I or II&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. scheduled for elective surgery of more than 60 minutes duration. -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Mallampati score of III or IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Neuromuscular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of allergy to the studied drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Malignant hyperthermia&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients taking anticonvulsants or aminoglycoside antibiotic&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Hepatic dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Renal dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Cardiovascular dysfunction;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Electrolyte imbalance&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Morbidly obese with a body mass index (BMI) more than 30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pregnant or nursing mothers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>ossama salman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>South Valley University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>South Valley University Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Qinā</city>
        <state>Qina</state>
        <zip>85203</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>South Valley University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ossama Hamdy Salman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Choline</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rocuronium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Succinylcholine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

