<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04706494</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19LSHE</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04706494</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Investigate the Efficacy of AlphaWave® L-Theanine on Stress</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Cross-over Study to Investigate the Efficacy of an Acute Dose of AlphaWave® LTheanine on Stress in a Healthy Adult Population</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ethical Naturals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ethical Naturals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      AlphaWave® L-theanine will be compared against placebo to evaluate how the investigational&#xD;
      study product effects on salivary cortisol, EEG readings, blood pressure, and heart rate in a&#xD;
      moderately stressed and otherwise healthy adult population. It is hypothesized that&#xD;
      participants taking the AlphaWave® L-theanine will have reduced stress levels as assessed by&#xD;
      the parameters stated. Participants will be consuming the investigational study product or&#xD;
      placebo in the clinic only.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 25, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 25, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in salivary cortisol levels from pre- to post-tests between AlphaWave® LTheanine versus placebo.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by analysis of saliva sample at baseline and end of study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in EEG total alpha wave readings from pre- to post-tests between AlphaWave® LTheanine versus placebo.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured and analyzed at baseline and end of study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in EEG frontal alpha wave readings from pre- to post-tests between AlphaWave® LTheanine versus placebo.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured and analyzed at baseline and end of study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in EEG midline theta wave readings from pre- to post-tests between AlphaWave® LTheanine versus placebo.</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured and analyzed at baseline and end of study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in heart rate from pre-to post-test between the investigational product versus placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured at baseline and end of study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in blood pressure from pre- to post-test between the investigational product versus placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Measured at baseline and end of study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in State-Trait Anxiety Inventory (STAI) from pre- to post-test between the investigational product versus placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the participants' answers to the questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The change in Visual Analog Scale (VAS) from pre- to post-tests between the investigational product versus placebo</measure>
    <time_frame>9 days</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the participants' answers to the questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Stress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AlphaWave® LTheanine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AlphaWave® LTheanine</intervention_name>
    <description>200 mg of AlphaWave® LTheanine</description>
    <arm_group_label>AlphaWave® LTheanine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>microcrystalline cellulose</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females between 18 and 65 years of age, inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI between 18.5 to 29.9 kg/m2, inclusive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant is not of child-bearing potential, defined as females who have&#xD;
             undergone a sterilization procedure (e.g. hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy,&#xD;
             bilateral tubal ligation, total endometrial ablation) or have been post-menopausal for&#xD;
             at least 1 year prior to screening OR,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of child-bearing potential must have a negative baseline urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             and agree to use a medically approved method of birth control for the duration of the&#xD;
             study. All hormonal birth control must have been in use for a minimum of three months.&#xD;
             Acceptable methods of birth control include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hormonal contraceptives including oral contraceptives, hormone birth control&#xD;
                  patch (Ortho Evra), vaginal contraceptive ring (NuvaRing), injectable&#xD;
                  contraceptives (Depo-Provera, Lunelle), or hormone implant (Norplant System)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Double-barrier method&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Intrauterine devices&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-heterosexual lifestyle or agrees to use contraception if planning on changing&#xD;
                  to heterosexual partner(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vasectomy of partner at least 6 months prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with moderate stress as determined by the Perceived Stress Scale (scores&#xD;
             ranging from 14 - 26 are considered moderate stress)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have a regular sleep-wake cycle with a bedtime between 9:00 pm and 12:00 am and&#xD;
             receive between 7 and 9 hours of sleep for at least 3 weeks prior to baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to maintain current sleep schedule throughout study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to maintain current levels of diet, supplements, and exercise until the end of&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to refrain from exercising 24-hours prior to the visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to abstain from using hair products on the day of visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to complete questionnaires, records, diaries associated with the study,&#xD;
             and to complete all clinic visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy as determined by medical history, laboratory results, and physical exam as&#xD;
             assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             course of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant abnormal laboratory results at screening as assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have a known allergy to the test material's active or inactive&#xD;
             ingredients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current employment that calls for rotating shift work or shift work that will disrupt&#xD;
             normal circadian rhythm or have worked shift work in the last 3 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Travelled across 1 or more time zones in the last 3 weeks and/or is anticipating more&#xD;
             travel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self reported epilepsy and/or seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type I or Type II Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable metabolic disease or chronic diseases as assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or history of any significant disease of the gastrointestinal tract&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypertension treated with medication or supplements or untreated hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self reported anxiety or depression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant cardiovascular event in the past 6 months as assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery in the past 3 months or individuals who have planned surgery during the&#xD;
             course of the trial. Participants with minor surgery will be considered on a&#xD;
             case-by-case basis by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with an autoimmune disease or are immune-compromised&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of or current diagnosis with kidney and/or liver diseases as assessed by the&#xD;
             QI on a case-by-case basis, with the exception of history of kidney stones&#xD;
             symptom-free for 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self reported current or pre-existing thyroid condition. Treatment on a stable dose of&#xD;
             medication for at least 3 months will be considered by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self reported confirmation of medical or neuropsychological condition and/or cognitive&#xD;
             impairment that, in the QI's opinion, could interfere with study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self reported blood/bleeding disorders that will have an effect on safety outcomes as&#xD;
             assessed by the QI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alcohol or drug abuse within the last 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High alcohol intake (&gt;2 standard drinks per day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medicinal cannabinoid products&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic use of cannabinoid products (&gt;2 times/week). Occasional use to be assessed by&#xD;
             the QI on a case by case basis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of tobacco and nicotine-containing products within 60 days of baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prescribed medications listed: antibiotics, antiepileptics, antiseizure&#xD;
             medications, sedatives, hypnotics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of over-the-counter medications, supplements, foods, and/or drinks listed:&#xD;
             caffeine, green tea, L-theanine supplements, melatonin supplements, valerian root&#xD;
             supplements, GABA supplements, tart cherries/drinks/supplements, amla, ashwagandha,&#xD;
             rhodiola, shatavari, ginseng&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood donation 30 days prior to screening or a planned donation 30-days of the last&#xD;
             study visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants in a clinical research trial within 30 days of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are unable to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition that, in the opinion of the QI, may adversely affect the&#xD;
             participant's ability to complete the study or its measures or pose significant risk&#xD;
             to the participant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mal Evans, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>KGK Science Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>KGK Science Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A5R8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

