<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04708808</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020.0503</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04708808</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Music Therapy Under Ultrasound Guided Manual Vacuum Aspiration</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Efficacy of Music as an Adjunct Analgesic in Reducing Pain and Anxiety During Ultrasound-guided Manual Vacuum Aspiration (USG-MVA): A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chinese University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Manual vacuum aspiration (MVA) is one of the surgical treatment options for managing early&#xD;
      pregnancy loss. When compared to traditional surgical method; MVA is safer, more&#xD;
      cost-effective, due to its shorter hospitalisation period and not undergo the risk of general&#xD;
      anaesthesia. The MVA procedure is performed under local anaesthesia and analgesics is given&#xD;
      prior the procedure. However, majority of patients still complaint significant pain during&#xD;
      the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In our previous study, the investigator found women had high anxiety and stress levels when&#xD;
      undergo miscarriage and the operation. Pain perception may further be affected by one's&#xD;
      psychological state at the time of the procedure. Therefore reducing the patient's anxiety&#xD;
      during the USG-MVA may further improve the patient's pain control and overall acceptance of&#xD;
      the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Music can act as a distracter and has a calming effect which turn the patient's attention&#xD;
      away from negative stimuli. Yet, there has been no RCTs to investigate the beneficial effect&#xD;
      of music therapy in pain control or reducing anxiety levels during USG-MVA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator hypothesis the intervention of music therapy to our current pain control&#xD;
      will reduce the pain and anxiety levels experienced by our patients during USG-MVA. Thus,&#xD;
      there is a need to conduct an RCT to test our hypothesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is conducted in an university affilated hospital for women undergo the USG-MVA&#xD;
      procedure. The primary outcome is to evaluate in between group difference in the pain&#xD;
      intensity after the USG-guided MVA procedure. The secondary outcome is to evaluate the&#xD;
      difference in anxiety level . Case is randomized to music and non music group, Bluetooth&#xD;
      headphone are provided during the procedure and case can choose their favourite songs. The&#xD;
      outcome are measured by the self rated instrument: Visual analogue scale and the STAI trait&#xD;
      anxiety score and the physiological measure salivary alpha amylase (sAA )score. The pain&#xD;
      score and the anxiety level is measured pre operatively, immediate after the procedure and 2&#xD;
      hours post operatively. The SPSS-26 will be used for statistics analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Title: The efficacy of music as an adjunct analgesic in reducing pain and anxiety during&#xD;
      ultrasound-guided manual vacuum aspiration (USG-MVA): A randomized controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately one in four women will experience an early pregnancy loss in her lifetime.&#xD;
      Manual vacuum aspiration (MVA) is one of the treatment options for managing early pregnancy&#xD;
      loss. USG-MVA is safer, more cost-effective, and is associated with shorter hospital stay and&#xD;
      cost than traditional surgical method. However, majority of patients experience significant&#xD;
      pain during the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At present, there is no consensus on the optimal pain control regimen for USG-MVA. The pain&#xD;
      generated from USG-MVA may be due to the dilatation of the cervix or insertion of the&#xD;
      catheter or due to uterine contraction. Various analgesic methods have been used to reduce&#xD;
      the pain including the use of paracervical block (PCB), non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs&#xD;
      (NSAIDs), lidocaine gel and conscious sedation but the procedure is still not absolutely&#xD;
      painless. Pain management remains an important factor in its success and patient acceptance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In our previous study, the investigator evaluated the effectiveness of adding Buscopan速, an&#xD;
      anti-spasmodic agent, as pain control regimen for women undergone the USG-MVA. Result found&#xD;
      that the intervention group were more satisfied to the procedure than the placebo group. They&#xD;
      had 15% and 21% lower pain score immediately after the operation as well as two hours post&#xD;
      operatively. The investigator postulated the women receiving Buscopan速 is being relieved from&#xD;
      experiencing uterine spasms. However, the investigator found that the women had higher&#xD;
      anxiety levels as reflected by the high anxiety scores in their Hospital Anxiety Depression&#xD;
      Scale. Pain perception maybe affected by one's psychological state at the time of the&#xD;
      procedure. And undergo a surgical procedure plus the diagnosis of miscarriage further&#xD;
      increases their anxiety and stress levels. Therefore to reduce the patient's anxiety during&#xD;
      the USG-MVA may further improve the patient's pain control and overall acceptance of the&#xD;
      procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Music is known to have a calming effect; previous studies have postulated that music can act&#xD;
      as a distracter which turns the patient's attention away from negative stimuli. Another&#xD;
      theory is that music activates brain as rewarding region which is responsible for pleasant&#xD;
      experiences and happiness and induces dopamine release in striatal system. A systematic&#xD;
      review of 42 randomized controlled trials of music interventions in the preoperative setting&#xD;
      found music significantly reduced anxiety and pain. Previous studies also showed music as an&#xD;
      auxiliary analgesic during first trimester surgical abortion but only with small sample size&#xD;
      and mixed results. There has not been any RCTs to investigate the beneficial effect of music&#xD;
      therapy in pain control or reducing anxiety levels during USG-MVA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      we hypothesis the addition of music to our current pain control can reduce pain and anxiety&#xD;
      levels experienced by our patients during USG-MVA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Primary outcome is to evaluate the difference in pain score immediate postoperative and 2&#xD;
      hours after the USG-guided MVA procedure between the intervention and control groups. The&#xD;
      Secondary outcome is to evaluate the difference in their anxiety levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Plan of Investigation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects All women undergoing USG- MVA for the treatment of early pregnancy loss with&#xD;
      gestation less than 12 weeks; size of the gestation product is less than 5 cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women 18 years old or above Women with miscarriage who are feasible for USG-MVA&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Not feasible for MVA procedure Partial or total hearing impairment on analgesic or anxiolytic&#xD;
      before admission to hospital. Patient refusal&#xD;
&#xD;
      (ii) Methods The patient is recruited in the Department of Obstetrics and Gynaecology in a&#xD;
      university base hospital. The participates consented for the USG-MVA procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization For those who consented to the study, they will randomly assign to receive&#xD;
      music therapy or not, according to a computer generated random number series in 1:1 ratio.&#xD;
      Each number will be placed in an opaque envelope labelled serially: (i) intervention group:&#xD;
      routine USG-MVA procedure plus music given via headphone (ii) control group- routine USG-MVA&#xD;
      procedure with no music given, with no headphone is given either. Given the audible and&#xD;
      physical features of the intervention, it is impossible to blind the participant and&#xD;
      physicians, staff and research assistant in the process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      USG-MVA procedure (Routine care)&#xD;
&#xD;
      USG-MVA will carry out in an outpatient day ward. Women will be given oral Misoprostol tablet&#xD;
      2-3 hours before the procedure for cervical priming. All patients will be given naproxen (500&#xD;
      mg) orally an hour and an intravenous injection of Buscopan速 (20mg) 5 minutes before the&#xD;
      procedure. If the woman is allergic to NSAIDs, paracetamol or codeine will be used instead.&#xD;
      The women will be asked to have full bladder for the abdominal USG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the USG-MVA procedure, the women are placed in the lithotomy position and aseptically&#xD;
      dressed. Speculum will be put to visualize the cervix. 5 ml 2% xylocaine local anaesthetic&#xD;
      will be injected at the cervical-vaginal juncture at 4, 5,7, 8 o'clock position. The anterior&#xD;
      lip of cervix is held with a volsellum and cervical dilation is performed if required. A 60ml&#xD;
      charged syringe will attach to the curette (size 4 to 7mm). 5ml 2% Xylocaine gel will be&#xD;
      applied to the cervical canal and over the end of the curette tip during the insertion. And&#xD;
      abdominal USG will be performed during the procedure to ensure complete evacuation and&#xD;
      prevent perforation of organs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The USG-MVA will stop as soon as USG confirm that the uterine cavity was empty. Any&#xD;
      post-operative complications including significant bleeding requiring blood transfusion,&#xD;
      uterine perforation and infection will be recorded. Women will be discharged after two hours&#xD;
      if they were stable. And they are asked to return 3 weeks later for a pregnancy test to&#xD;
      evaluate the completeness of evacuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention group (Music therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
      In additional to the standard routine care, the patients are asked to select their favourite&#xD;
      music; they will start to hear the music when they are placed in lithotomy position and end&#xD;
      when procedure completed (removal speculum). They are asked not to hear any music before and&#xD;
      after the procedure. A bluetooth headphone fitted with sanitary covers is offered. The volume&#xD;
      of the media player is preset so instructions from the staff or clinicians could still be&#xD;
      heard. The genre of music chosen will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control group (No Music) In the control group, neither music nor headphones will be offered.&#xD;
      The participants are also asked not to listen to any music before; during or after the&#xD;
      USG-MVA and they will undergo the routine USG-MVA procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pain assessment Participants are asked to rate their pain intensity by the visual analog&#xD;
      scale (VAS). The scores ranged from 0 to 100, where 0 indicated no pain and 100 indicated the&#xD;
      worst pain imaginable. The pain score will be assessed when participants enter the&#xD;
      department, 30 minutes after administration of misoprostol, at the end of the procedure and 2&#xD;
      hours after the procedure. The need for additional postoperative analgesics were recorded&#xD;
      (yes or no).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stress and Anxiety levels The participants anxiety and stress level are assessed by the&#xD;
      Chinese version of the General Health Questionnaire-12 (GHQ-12), Hospital Anxiety and&#xD;
      Depression Scale (HADS) and State anxiety (STAI-S) of the State-trait Anxiety Inventory and&#xD;
      the salivary alpha amylase level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General health questionnaire (GHQ-12) The participants preoperative anxiety level are&#xD;
      assessed by the GHQ-12. It consists a 4-point Likert ranging from 1 to 4; The total score&#xD;
      ranges from 12-48, score greater than 27 indicate a higher level of psychological distress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) The HADS aims to evaluate the participants their&#xD;
      state of anxiety and depression. It is a 4-point Likert ranging from 0 to 3. The total score&#xD;
      ranges from 0 to 21. The cut-off point is 8 for higher state of anxiety or depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      State-trait anxiety inventory- State Anxiety Subscale (STAI-S) The STAI-S aims to evaluate&#xD;
      the current state of anxiety. Participants are asked to answer the questionnaires during&#xD;
      admission, after 30 minutes of cytotec administration, immediate and 2 hours after the&#xD;
      USG-MVA. It consists of 20 questions with 4 points Likert scale. The total scores range from&#xD;
      20 to 80, with higher scores correlating with greater anxiety.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stress biomarker assessment -Salivary alpha amylase (SAA) The Salivary alpha-amylase (sAA)&#xD;
      levels measures the physiological stress, they are collected by a dedicated SaliCap速&#xD;
      collection device via the passive drooling method before; immediately and at 30 minutes after&#xD;
      MVA procedure. All patients were asked not to eat or drink at least an hour before&#xD;
      collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Client satisfaction assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Client Satisfaction Questionnaire (CSQ) It is a self-administered questionnaire to assess&#xD;
      client satisfaction and acceptance. It consists of eight items with 4-point Likert Scale,&#xD;
      from &quot;Very satisfied&quot; to &quot;Quite dissatisfied&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      (iv) Data processing and analysis Statistical Analysis All statistical analyses will be&#xD;
      performed using SPSS 22.0 based on intention-to-treat. A two-tailed probability value of p&lt;&#xD;
      0.05 will be considered statistically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size Previous studies in women undergoing gynaecological procedures reported that&#xD;
      music therapy could reduce pain scores by between 35% to 50%. Assuming an alpha of 0.05,&#xD;
      power of 90% , estimated that 73 participants will be recruited in each group to detect a 1-&#xD;
      sided medium effect size of 0.5 due to music therapy. To allow for 20% drop-out rate, the&#xD;
      planned sample size will be increased to 88 per group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Duration of study Aim to conduct for 18 months, followed by 6 months for data collection and&#xD;
      analysis. Patients' recruitment will start after ethics approval.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>First trimester miscarriage case undergo the manual vaccum procedure.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>For those who consented to the study, they will be randomly assigned to receive music therapy or no according to a computer generated random number series. Each number will be placed in an opaque envelope labelled serially: (i) intervention group: routine care plus music given via headphone (ii) control group- routine care with no music or headphones.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the change in post operatively pain score with or without MT at different time points</measure>
    <time_frame>During one day</time_frame>
    <description>The case self rated the VAS score, VAS scores ranged from 0 to 100, where 0 indicated no pain and 100 indicated the worst pain imaginable.&#xD;
(T0) when entering the department, (T1) 30 minutes after administration of misoprostol, (T2) during the procedure, (T3) at the end of the procedure and (T4) 2 hours after the procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the impact of MT on anxiety level</measure>
    <time_frame>During one day</time_frame>
    <description>The client self rated the Chinese version of STAI-S subscore. It is a 20 item scale with a 4 point likert ranging from almost never to almost always. the total scores range from 20 to 80, with higher scores correlate with greater anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the psychological distress during the past few weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour before the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The client self rated the Chinese version General Health Questionnaire, it consists of 12 questions with 4 likert point rating. It aims to evaluate whether there are any baseline psychological distress, higher score indicates a higher level of psychological morbidity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the patient's satisfaction and acceptance</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The client self rated the Client Satisfaction Questionnaire, it consists of 12 questions with 4 likert point rating. Higher score indicates greater acceptance and satisfaction</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To measure the patient's physiological stress level.</measure>
    <time_frame>Saliva samples were collected 1 hour before the procedure and 30 minutes after MVA procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Saliva samples were collected via the passive drooling method , using a dedicated SaliCap collection device. All patients were asked not to eat or drink 1 hour before collection. The level is determined using the Indiko (Thermo Fisher Scientific) random access analyser to measure the physiological stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>To assess any post operative physical discomfort</measure>
    <time_frame>immediate after post operative and 2 hours post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>The case will complete the questionnaire of 4-likert point, with no, mild, moderate and severe for symptoms of nausea, vomiting, dizziness, tiredness, shortness of breath</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">176</enrollment>
  <condition>First Trimester Abortion</condition>
  <condition>Surgical Abortion</condition>
  <condition>Music Intervention</condition>
  <condition>Local Anesthesia</condition>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MVA case undergone music therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>case undergone manual vacuum aspiration are randomised to receive music therapy during the procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Routine Care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>music therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>cases will randomly assigned to receive music therapy group with routine care, plus music given via headphone, or assign to control group with no music given.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MVA case undergone music therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>No music therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Routine Care</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women 18 years old or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hospitalized for termination of first trimester pregnancy under local anaesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  being a minor or adult protected by law&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  not feasible for MVA procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partial or total hearing impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  on anxiolytics and analgesics before arriving at the hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  refusal to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>First trimester miscarriage women.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pui Wah Jacqueline Chung, MBBS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hiu Tan Margaret Lee</last_name>
    <phone>(852)35051764</phone>
    <email>margaretlee@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pui Wah Jacqueline Chung, MBBS</last_name>
    <phone>(852)35051764</phone>
    <email>jacquelinechung@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chinese University of Hong Kong</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hong Kong</city>
        <state>Shatin</state>
        <country>Hong Kong</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Margaret Lee</last_name>
      <phone>35053199</phone>
      <email>margaretlee@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Pui Wah Chung</last_name>
      <phone>35053199</phone>
      <email>jacquelinechung@cuhk.edu.hk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tin Chui Li, MBBS, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tracy Law, MBBS</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Hong Kong</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chinese University of Hong Kong</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Chung Pui Wah Jacqueline</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>music</keyword>
  <keyword>termination of pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>suction curettage</keyword>
  <keyword>evacuation of gestational product</keyword>
  <keyword>anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>abortion</keyword>
  <keyword>pain</keyword>
  <keyword>surgical abortion</keyword>
  <keyword>aspiration abortion</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

