<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04707456</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COA. MURA2020/303</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04707456</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparative Study of Learning Curve for First Trimester Fetal Anomaly Scan</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Comparative Study of Learning Curve Between Two Different Levels of Proficiency for First Trimester Fetal Anomaly Scan Using ISUOG Guidelines</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mahidol University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mahidol University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ultrasound scans during first trimester are more difficult than routine mid-trimester&#xD;
      ultrasound scans. Practice guidelines for first trimester fetal ultrasound scans have been&#xD;
      provided by the International Society of Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology (ISUOG)&#xD;
      since 2013. Using this guidelines, different levels of proficiency operators might have equal&#xD;
      ability to complete first trimester ultrasound scans.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Nowadays, high-resolution transabdominal ultrasounds are widely used, and ultrasound scans&#xD;
      for fetal structural abnormalities at the first trimester are indeed possible. First&#xD;
      trimester ultrasound scans are important and essential for detecting fetal structural&#xD;
      anomalies, and they help provide optimized early antenatal management. However, ultrasound&#xD;
      scans, during this period, are more difficult than routine mid-trimester ultrasound scans, as&#xD;
      fetal organs are small and experienced operators are needed to use the transducer to obtain&#xD;
      informative pictures. Practice guidelines for first trimester fetal ultrasound scans have&#xD;
      been provided by the International Society of Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology (ISUOG)&#xD;
      since 2013. Since then, the percentage of complete scans and the high detection rate of fetal&#xD;
      structural abnormalities during first trimester ultrasound scans have been reported. From our&#xD;
      perspective, ultrasound operators who have different experiences in mid-trimester ultrasound&#xD;
      scanning might have equal ability to complete first trimester ultrasound scans using the&#xD;
      ISUOG guidelines. The objective of this study is to compare the rate of completed scans&#xD;
      regarding fetal structures at the first trimester ultrasound scan between two different&#xD;
      levels of proficiency operators.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of completed scans of fetal structural abnormality between two different levels of proficiency operators</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the percentage of completed scans of each organ during the first trimester scan between two different levels of proficiency</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Screening time for first trimester ultrasound scans between two different levels of proficiency operators</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To compare screening time for first trimester ultrasound scans between two different levels of proficiency operators</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Learning curve of first trimester ultrasound scans between two different levels of proficiency operators</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the learning curve between two different levels of proficiency operators</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection rate of fetal structural abnormality in first trimester ultrasound scans between two different levels of proficiency operators</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the detection rate of fetal structural abnormality between two different levels of proficiency operators</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">210</enrollment>
  <condition>First Trimester Pregnancy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MFM staff-level operator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MFM fellowship trainee-level operator</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Training operator</intervention_name>
    <description>After recruitment, the participants were divided into two groups to perform first-trimester ultrasound scan by two different levels of proficiency.&#xD;
First group : operator has experience more than 3 years in NT scan and second trimester ultrasound scan Second group : operator has experience less than 3 years in NT scan and second trimester ultrasound scan</description>
    <arm_group_label>MFM fellowship trainee-level operator</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Singleton pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Maternal age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gestational age between 11-13 + 6 weeks by last menstrual date or ultrasound report if&#xD;
             uncertain date&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multifetal gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Miscarriage before first trimester ultrasound&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Loss to follow up at mid-trimester ultrasound scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Loss to follow up after birth&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Faculty of Medicine Ramathibodi hospital, Mahidol university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bangkok</city>
        <zip>10400</zip>
        <country>Thailand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Thailand</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Update on overall prevalence of major birth defects--Atlanta, Georgia, 1978-2005. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2008 Jan 11;57(1):1-5.</citation>
    <PMID>18185492</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pangkanon S, Sawasdivorn S, Kuptanon C, Chotigeat U, Vandepitte W. Establishing of National Birth Defects Registry in Thailand. J Med Assoc Thai. 2014 Jun;97 Suppl 6:S182-8.</citation>
    <PMID>25391192</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karim JN, Roberts NW, Salomon LJ, Papageorghiou AT. Systematic review of first-trimester ultrasound screening for detection of fetal structural anomalies and factors that affect screening performance. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2017 Oct;50(4):429-441. doi: 10.1002/uog.17246. Epub 2017 Sep 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27546497</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Taipale P, Ammälä M, Salonen R, Hiilesmaa V. Learning curve in ultrasonographic screening for selected fetal structural anomalies in early pregnancy. Obstet Gynecol. 2003 Feb;101(2):273-8.</citation>
    <PMID>12576250</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salomon LJ, Alfirevic Z, Bilardo CM, Chalouhi GE, Ghi T, Kagan KO, Lau TK, Papageorghiou AT, Raine-Fenning NJ, Stirnemann J, Suresh S, Tabor A, Timor-Tritsch IE, Toi A, Yeo G. ISUOG practice guidelines: performance of first-trimester fetal ultrasound scan. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2013 Jan;41(1):102-13. doi: 10.1002/uog.12342. Erratum in: Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2013 Feb;41(2):240.</citation>
    <PMID>23280739</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Srisupundit K, Tongsong T, Sirichotiyakul S, Chanprapaph P. Fetal structural anomaly screening at 11-14 weeks of gestation at Maharaj Nakorn Chiang Mai Hospital. J Med Assoc Thai. 2006 May;89(5):588-93.</citation>
    <PMID>16756041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Petousis S, Sotiriadis A, Margioula-Siarkou C, Tsakiridis I, Christidis P, Kyriakakis M, Mamopoulos A, Athanasiadis A, Dagklis T. Detection of structural abnormalities in fetuses with normal karyotype at 11-13 weeks using the anatomic examination protocol of the International Society of Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology (ISUOG). J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2020 Aug;33(15):2581-2587. doi: 10.1080/14767058.2018.1555807. Epub 2019 Jan 7.</citation>
    <PMID>30612473</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nicolaides KH. Nuchal translucency and other first-trimester sonographic markers of chromosomal abnormalities. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2004 Jul;191(1):45-67. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15295343</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salvesen K, Lees C, Abramowicz J, Brezinka C, Ter Haar G, Maršál K; Board of International Society of Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology (ISUOG). ISUOG statement on the safe use of Doppler in the 11 to 13 +6-week fetal ultrasound examination. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Jun;37(6):628. doi: 10.1002/uog.9026.</citation>
    <PMID>21618313</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mahidol University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Saranthorn Sripilaipong</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>First trimester ultrasound scan</keyword>
  <keyword>Learning curve</keyword>
  <keyword>ISUOG practice guidelines</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Congenital Abnormalities</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

