<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04703569</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>16087119.2.0000.5327</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04703569</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Compressive Therapies on the Healing of Venous Ulcers</brief_title>
  <acronym>VENOS</acronym>
  <official_title>Effect of Compressive Therapies on the Healing of Venous Ulcers in Primary Health Services: Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospital de Clinicas de Porto Alegre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Casex Innovation in Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Conselho Nacional de Desenvolvimento Científico e Tecnológico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospital de Clinicas de Porto Alegre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of the study is to compare the effect of two treatments on the healing of&#xD;
      venous ulcers in follow-up people in two Primary Health Services, in a city in southern&#xD;
      Brazil. The two treatments that will be tested are: (1) the high compression elastic bandage&#xD;
      and (2) Unna boot. The two treatments are indicated for the treatment of people with venous&#xD;
      insufficiency and who have an active ulcer. The treatment will last 26 weeks (6 months). Once&#xD;
      a week, during 26 weeks, a nurse will perform the dressing and will apply the therapy high&#xD;
      compression elastic bandage or Unna boot according to a drawing and in every two weeks an&#xD;
      evaluator will assess the characteristics of the ulcers and the size.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to compare the effect of two compressive therapies, high compression&#xD;
      elastic bandage and Unna boot, on time and on the healing characteristics of venous ulcers in&#xD;
      Primary Health Care and the secondary objectives are to verify the effects of the therapies&#xD;
      in tissue integrity and at the level of pain, to identify quality of life of the participants&#xD;
      and to evaluate the cost-effectiveness of the two therapies from the perspective of the&#xD;
      Unified Health System. A randomized clinical trial is being carried out in two Primary Health&#xD;
      Services in Porto Alegre city, with people with active venous ulcer. 126 venous ulcers, 63 in&#xD;
      each group will be followed. The A group receives elastic compressive therapy (high&#xD;
      compression elastic bandage) and the B group receives inelastic compressive therapy (Unna&#xD;
      boot) by randomization. Once a week, during 26 weeks, a nurse applies the therapy according&#xD;
      to the randomization group. And a blind evaluator for therapies will assess the&#xD;
      characteristics of the ulcers and the size, on the first day and in every two weeks until 26ª&#xD;
      week.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 29, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of the therapies on time and on the healing characteristics of venous ulcers</measure>
    <time_frame>On first day and in every two weeks, during 26 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>A blind evaluator for therapies will assess the characteristics of the ulcers using a Likert scale, being 1 the worst score and 5 best score, proposed to Nursing Outcomes Classification (NOC), in the outcome Wound Healing: Secondary Intention. This outcome has indicators to assess the healing characteristics, such as granulation tissue; necrosis; epithelial tissue; exsudate; erythema; oedema; macerated skin; odor and planimetry.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The effects of the therapies at the level of pain</measure>
    <time_frame>On first day and in every two weeks, during 26 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>A blind evaluator for therapies will ask about of the pain on the first day and in every two weeks.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-effectiveness of the therapies</measure>
    <time_frame>26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Direct costs to perform the dressing will be measured through a tool built by the researches. Every week, the nurses will take notes of all products they used and the time spent to perform the dressing (using a stopwatch). This will be converted into monetary value. Besides that, a blind evaluator for therapies will assess the effectiveness through the wound planimetry. In the end, the relationship between cost-effectiveness will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>On first day, on the 12ª week and on the 26ª week.</time_frame>
    <description>The SF-6D Questionnaire will be applied to the participants to identify the quality of life, on the first day, on the 12ª week and on the 26ª week. The Short Form-6 Dimension (SF-6D) is a widely used preference-based generic health-related quality of life measure with a multiattribute classification system consisting of six dimensions: physical functioning, role functioning, social functioning, pain, mental health, and vitality. Each dimension is composed of three to five levels. The SF-6D values range from 0.315 to 1, with higher scores indicating better health-related quality of life anchoring on the 0 (dead) to 1 (full health) scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The effects of the therapies at the tissue integrity</measure>
    <time_frame>On first day and in every two weeks, during 26 weeks.</time_frame>
    <description>A blind evaluator for therapies will assess the tissue integrity using a Likert scale, being 1 the worst score and 5 best score, proposed to Nursing Outcomes Classification (NOC), in the outcome Tissue Integrity: Skin and Mucous Membranes. This outcome has indicators to assess the tissue integrity, such as necrosis; skin hydration and skin pigmentation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>Venous Ulcers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Monolayer high compression elastic bandage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An elastic bandage of cotton, viscose, nylon and elastane</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Unna boot</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>A wet bandage with zinc oxide</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dressing with monolayer high compression elastic bandage</intervention_name>
    <description>The nurse will be apply the therapy high compression elastic bandage once a week, during 26 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Monolayer high compression elastic bandage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dressing with Unna boot</intervention_name>
    <description>The nurse will be apply the therapy Unna Boot once a week, during 26 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Unna boot</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  people with diagnosis of chronic venous insufficiency recorded in medical records,&#xD;
             with active venous ulcer;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with indication of compressive therapy, who are not using any of the therapies used in&#xD;
             the study and who have not used them within 30 days of the initial moment of data&#xD;
             collection;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years old or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with Ankle-Brachial Index (ABI) between 0.8 and 1.2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with pulses present on palpation in lower limbs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  walking people;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with Body Mass Index (BMI) between ≥ 18.5 kg/m2 and 39.9 kg/m2 (for elderly people: ≥&#xD;
             22 kg/m2 and 39.9 kg/m2);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with ankle circumference greater than 18cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  people with mixed, infected or in the epithelialization phase UV (with epithelial&#xD;
             tissue in 90% of the UV area);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncontrolled diabetics (with Glycated Hemoglobin greater than 7% in the last six&#xD;
             months);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  people with medical diagnosis of dermatological, rheumatological and oncological&#xD;
             diseases in the member of the active UV or immunosuppressive diseases (for influencing&#xD;
             the healing process);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  with allergy to any f the components of the compressive therapies used in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  people using immunosuppressants and/or corticosteroids for more than 21 days (for&#xD;
             influencing the healing process).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lisiane Paskulin, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisiane Paskulin, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>55 51 3308-5226</phone>
    <email>paskulin@orion.ufrgs.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Unidade de Saúde Modelo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto Alegre</city>
        <state>Rio Grande Do Sul</state>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lisiane Paskulin, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 51 999150237</phone>
      <email>pesquisa-venos@hcpa.edu.br</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Unidade de Saúde Santa Cecília</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto Alegre</city>
        <state>Rio Grande Do Sul</state>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lisiane Paskulin, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 51 999150237</phone>
      <email>pesquisa-venos@hcpa.edu.br</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Unidade de Saúde Santa Marta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto Alegre</city>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lisiane Paskulin, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 51 999150237</phone>
      <email>pesquisa-venos@hcpa.edu.br</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Varicose Ulcer</keyword>
  <keyword>Compression Bandages</keyword>
  <keyword>Wound Healing</keyword>
  <keyword>Nursing</keyword>
  <keyword>Primary Health Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Intervention study</keyword>
  <keyword>Cost-effectiveness</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Varicose Ulcer</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ulcer</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

