<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04705597</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BGE-175-201</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04705597</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, and Efficacy of BGE-175 in Hospitalized Adults With Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) That Are Not in Respiratory Failure</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Phase 2 Study to Investigate the Efficacy and Safety of BGE-175 in Hospitalized Adults With COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>BioAge Labs, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>BioAge Labs, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objectives of this study are to evaluate the safety, tolerability, and efficacy&#xD;
      of BGE-175 in participants ≥ 50 years of age hospitalized with documented COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter, double-blind study of&#xD;
      BGE-175 administered PO or NG in participants ≥ 50 years of age and hospitalized with&#xD;
      documented COVID-19 who are not yet in respiratory failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After signing informed consent, participants will be screened upon presentation at the&#xD;
      hospital. Screening will include full physical examination, vital signs, safety laboratory&#xD;
      evaluation, oxygen saturation, pre-diagnostics to measure prostaglandin D2 (PGD2) status, and&#xD;
      baseline assessment of World Health Organization (WHO) Ordinal Scale for COVID-19. If&#xD;
      confirmed that the participant qualifies for this protocol according to listed inclusion and&#xD;
      exclusion criteria, participants will receive the first dose of study medication, PO. The&#xD;
      participant will then receive study medication PO or NG (if intubated or unable to swallow&#xD;
      medication) once daily, at approximately the same time each day for up to 13 additional days.&#xD;
      Study medication will be administered in addition to standard of care deemed appropriate by&#xD;
      the treating physician(s). Participants will be randomized to receive BGE-175 or placebo.&#xD;
      Participants will be monitored daily for all relevant efficacy outcomes, oxygen saturation,&#xD;
      and adverse events. Blood will be drawn periodically for safety laboratory measurements,&#xD;
      plasma kinetics, lymphocyte subsets, C-reactive protein, and cytokines. Nasopharyngeal swabs&#xD;
      will be collected to measure viral load. Participants will be monitored for 14 days after&#xD;
      administration of the last dose (Day 28) and followed through Day 57.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Multicenter, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-blind</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants who have died or progressed to respiratory failure</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants who have died or progressed to respiratory failure as defined by progressing to the need for high-flow nasal cannula O2 delivery, noninvasive ventilation, mechanical ventilation, or extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO) at Day 28.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants experiencing treatment-emergent adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants experiencing treatment-emergent adverse events as measured by the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v 5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14, Day 28, Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants surviving at</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects who survive without progression to respiratory failure</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14, Day 28, Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of subjects who survive without progression to respiratory failure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Viral load</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Time to two successive negative viral titers in nasopharyngeal swab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical worsening on a 9-point ordinal scale</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Time to clinical worsening from baseline value (defined by time to ≥ 1-point worsening on WHO Ordinal Scale for COVID-19). The ordinal scale is an assessment of the clinical status at a given day. Each day, the worst score from the previous day will be recorded. The scale is as follows: 0.) Uninfected 1.) Ambulatory with no limitation of activities 2.) Ambulatory with limitation of activities 3.) Hospitalized, mild disease with no oxygen therapy 4.) Hospitalized, mild disease with oxygen by mask or nasal prongs 5.) Hospitalized, severe disease with noninvasive ventilation or high-flow oxygen 6.) Hospitalized, severe disease with intubation and mechanical ventilation 7.) Hospitalized, severe disease with ventilation and additional organ support (pressors, renal retention therapy, extracorporeal membrane oxygenation) 8.) Death.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Defined by time to ≥ 1-point improvement on WHO Ordinal Scale for COVID-19 - must be maintained through Day 28.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14/End of Treatment, Day 28, Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change from baseline in WHO Ordinal Scale for COVID-19 score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to extubation</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Time from dressing complete to the recorded time of endotracheal tube removal</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to discharge from hospital intensive care unit</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Time from intensive care unit admission to the recorded time of intensive care unit discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of supplemental oxygen administration</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of participants receiving supplemental oxygen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of supplemental oxygen administration</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of participants receiving supplemental oxygen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of noninvasive ventilation by nonrebreather mask or high-flow nasal cannula</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of participants receiving noninvasive ventilation by nonrebreather mask or high-flow nasal cannula</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of noninvasive ventilation by nonrebreather mask or high-flow nasal cannula</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of participants receiving noninvasive ventilation by nonrebreather mask or high-flow nasal cannula</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of mechanical ventilation plus additional organ support using vasopressors, and/or renal replacement therapy and/or ECMO</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of participants receiving mechanical ventilation plus additional organ support using vasopressors, and/or renal replacement therapy and/or ECMO</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of mechanical ventilation plus additional organ support using vasopressors, and/or renal replacement therapy and/or ECMO</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of participants receiving mechanical ventilation plus additional organ support using vasopressors, and/or renal replacement therapy and/or ECMO</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily ratio of oxygen saturation (SpO2) to fractional inspired O2 (SpO2/FiO2)</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Daily ratio of participants' oxygen saturation (SpO2) to fractional inspired O2 (SpO2/FiO2)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to discharge from the hospital</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Length (in days) of the time of hospitalization until medical discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to re-hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Length (in days) of the time from medical discharge from hospital to rehospitalization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants requiring intensive care unit admission</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants admitted to hospital intensive care unit post randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker IL-6</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker CRP</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker IL-10</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker TNF-α</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker IFN-γ</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker IFN-α</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker IP-10</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker MCP-1</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker CD4+ T cells</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammation marker CD8+ T cells</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Inflammation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute lymphocyte count</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of BGE-175</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Assess peak and trough concentrations of BGE-175 at steady-state</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Activity of prostaglandin D2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Assess prostaglandin D2 pre-diagnostic to assess correlation with response to treatment for COVID-19 based on change in the WHO Ordinal Scale for COVID-19 score</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants experiencing any treatment-emergent adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants experiencing any treatment-emergent adverse events as measured by the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v 5.0</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants experiencing any adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants experiencing any adverse events as measured by the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v 5.0</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants experiencing any treatment-emergent graded laboratory abnormalities</measure>
    <time_frame>First dose date up to Day 57</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants experiencing any treatment-emergent graded laboratory abnormalities as defined by laboratory parameters/reference ranges</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">312</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BGE-175</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>BGE-175 tablet to be taken by mouth once a day for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo tablet to be taken by mouth once a day for 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BGE-175</intervention_name>
    <description>Drug</description>
    <arm_group_label>BGE-175</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to voluntarily provide informed consent that is documented per local&#xD;
             requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An understanding, ability, and willingness to fully comply with study procedures and&#xD;
             restrictions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalized subjects with a confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory (polymerase chain reaction [PCR]) confirmed infection with SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 50 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 illness of any duration, and oxygen saturation measurements ≤ 94% over 5&#xD;
             minutes on room air (Note: low flow oxygen is permitted, but room air oxygen&#xD;
             saturation must be ≤ 94%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not in respiratory failure as defined by at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Respiratory failure defined by requiring at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Endotracheal intubation and mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Oxygen delivered by high-flow nasal cannula at flow rates &gt; 20 L/min with&#xD;
                       fraction of delivered oxygen ≥ 0.5)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  NIPPV&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  ECMO&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Clinical diagnosis of respiratory failure (i.e., need for one of the&#xD;
                       preceding therapies, but preceding therapies are not being administered&#xD;
                       because it is unavailable in the current setting)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Hemodynamic compromise (defined by systolic blood pressure &lt; 90 mm Hg, or&#xD;
                  diastolic blood pressure &lt; 60 mm Hg) or requiring vasopressors&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Multi-organ dysfunction/failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test at&#xD;
             screening or pre-treatment on Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use methods of&#xD;
             contraception that are consistent with local regulations for those participating in&#xD;
             clinical studies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in any other randomized, controlled clinical trial of an experimental&#xD;
             treatment for COVID-19 (uncontrolled, compassionate use trials are allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the opinion of the investigator, progression to death is imminent and inevitable&#xD;
             within the next 24 hours, irrespective of the provision of treatments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently participating in a vaccination trial for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known positive test for influenza A or influenza B at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) that is not controlled with current&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B surface antigen, or Hepatitis C positive at the time of screening.&#xD;
             Subjects who are positive for Hepatitis C but have Hepatitis C virus (HCV) RNA below&#xD;
             the limit of quantitation may be enrolled. Subjects with Hepatitis B, but with&#xD;
             undetectable viral load, may be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt; 5 × the upper&#xD;
             limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stage 4 severe chronic kidney disease (i.e., estimated glomerular filtration rate&#xD;
             [eGFR] &lt; 30 mL/min) or acute renal failure resulting in eGFR &lt; 30 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious comorbidity, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Myocardial infarction (within the last month)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Moderate or severe heart failure (New York Heart Association [NYHA] class III or&#xD;
                  IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Acute stroke (within the last month)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Uncontrolled malignancy. Uncontrolled malignancy would include cancers that are&#xD;
                  not considered in remission, or solid tumor or hematological malignancies with&#xD;
                  evidence of disease progression in the past 3 months (i.e., there is evidence of&#xD;
                  disease progression by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours [RECIST] or&#xD;
                  equivalent relevant criterion for the type of malignancy), and are not considered&#xD;
                  effectively managed with ongoing treatment as determined by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Recent severe thromboembolic disease or evidence of severe thromboembolic disease&#xD;
                  defined as a current large vessel thromboembolic event or a thromboembolic event&#xD;
                  within the past 3 months (e.g., deep vein thrombosis [DVT], pulmonary embolism,&#xD;
                  ischemic stroke, transient ischemic attack) requiring interventional treatment.&#xD;
                  This exclusion does not prohibit prophylaxis for thromboembolic events, including&#xD;
                  those considered possible with concurrent SARS-CoV-2 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions or hypersensitivity to the study&#xD;
             drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consideration by the investigator, for any reason, that the subject is an unsuitable&#xD;
             candidate to receive study treatment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard G Wilkerson, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Maryland, College Park</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patrick Martin, MD</last_name>
    <phone>510-806-1502</phone>
    <email>patrick@bioagelabs.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Banner Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mesa</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stephanie Blythe</last_name>
      <phone>480-412-5561</phone>
      <email>stephanie.blythe@bannerhealth.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Zachariah, DO</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Velocity Clinical Research, Chula Vista</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chula Vista</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91911</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rosalynn Landazuri</last_name>
      <phone>619-955-5246</phone>
      <email>RLandazuri@velocityclinical.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Waters, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Long Beach Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Long Beach</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90806</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Fady Youssef, MD</last_name>
      <phone>562-933-2000</phone>
      <email>fady.a.youssef@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fady Youssef, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCI Center for Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rosie Magallon</last_name>
      <phone>714-509-6082</phone>
      <email>rmagallo@hs.uci.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alpesh Amin, MD, MBA</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sharp Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92123</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Katie Hong</last_name>
      <phone>858-939-7162</phone>
      <email>Kathryn.Hong@sharp.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Roland El Ghazal, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stamford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stamford</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06904</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adrienne Scott</last_name>
      <phone>203-358-8879</phone>
      <email>OfficeofResearch@stamhealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul Sachs, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baptist Health, Lexington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jamie Wilder</last_name>
      <phone>859-260-3197</phone>
      <email>jamie.wilder@bhsi.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Dougherty, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Maryland Medical System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dana Beach, RN BSN CCRC</last_name>
      <phone>410-328-7635</phone>
      <email>dbeach3@som.umaryland.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Richard G Wilkerson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica Privada Independencia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ciudad Autonoma de Buenos Aires</city>
        <state>Buenos Aires</state>
        <zip>C1426ABP</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pablo A Doreski, MD, MBA</last_name>
      <phone>+54 0 11-4781-5331</phone>
      <email>respiramos@yahoo.com.ar</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pablo A Doreski, MD, MBA</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanatorio De La Trinidad Mitre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buenos Aires</city>
        <state>Ciudad Autonoma De Buenos Aires</state>
        <zip>C1039AAO</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Victoria Diaz, MD</last_name>
      <phone>54 11 4954 7070</phone>
      <phone_ext>494</phone_ext>
      <email>avictoria.diaz@yahoo.com.ar</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <phone>54 11 5371 3200</phone>
      <phone_ext>494</phone_ext>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica Adventista Belgrano (CAB)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buenos Aires</city>
        <state>Ciudad Autónoma De Buenos Aires</state>
        <zip>C1430EGF</zip>
        <country>Argentina</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Estefanía Aloisi</last_name>
      <phone>4014-1500</phone>
      <phone_ext>1818</phone_ext>
      <email>estefaniaaloisi@arsema.com.ar</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marcelo Casas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitário Cassiano Antônio de Moraes</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vitória</city>
        <state>Espiritu Santo</state>
        <zip>29043-260</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ingrid Segal</last_name>
      <phone>55 27 3335-7120</phone>
      <email>digsegal@yahoo.com.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tania Q Reuter Motta, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Felicio Rocho (HFR)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belo Horizonte</city>
        <state>Minas Gerais</state>
        <zip>30180-080</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aline P Gomes</last_name>
      <phone>55 31 3514-7195</phone>
      <email>pesquisarocho@feliciorocho.org.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ana Carolina Nazaré de Mendonça Procópio, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro de Pesquisa Hospital Ana Nery Santa Cruz do Sul</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santa Cruz Do Sul</city>
        <state>Rio Grande Do Sol</state>
        <zip>96835-090</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gabriella P Remedi</last_name>
      <phone>55 51 99159-1861</phone>
      <email>gpremedi@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eduardo Chaida Sonda, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica Supera Oncologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapecó</city>
        <state>Santa Catarina</state>
        <zip>89801-355</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maiara Cantarelli</last_name>
      <phone>55 49 9 9921-7878</phone>
      <email>maiara.cantarelli@bioservsmo.com.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cristiano Devenci Vendrame, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Unidade de Pesquisa Clinica da Fundação Pio XII - Hospital de Amor de Barretos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barretos</city>
        <state>Sao Paulo</state>
        <zip>14784-400</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bruna R Souza</last_name>
      <email>bruna.roberti@hcancerbarretos.com.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cesar Mauricio da Silva, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital das Clínicas da Faculdade de Medicina de Botucatu UNESP (HC-FMB/UNESP)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Botucatu</city>
        <state>Sao Paulo</state>
        <zip>18618-687</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paula Balin</last_name>
      <phone>55 14 3880 1663</phone>
      <email>paolasilvabalin@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Diego A Rios Queiroz, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pontificia Universidade Catolica de Campinas (PUC-CAMP) - Hospital e Maternidade Celso Pierro (HMCP) - Centro de Pesquisa São Lucas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Campinas</city>
        <state>Sao Paulo</state>
        <zip>13060-904</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carolina Sanchez</last_name>
      <phone>55 19 3343-8511</phone>
      <email>carolina-sanchez@uol.com.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria Patelli Juliani Souza Lima, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica de Alergia Martti Antila</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sorocaba</city>
        <state>Sao Paulo</state>
        <zip>18040-425</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Simone Rosa</last_name>
      <phone>55 15-99735-5812</phone>
      <email>simone.fernandes@cmpc.med.br</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Martti Anton Antila, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Conjunto Hospitalar de Mandaqui</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <state>Sao Paulo</state>
        <zip>02432</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Karine De Amicis Lima</last_name>
      <phone>55-11-972749399</phone>
      <email>karineamicis@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ana Marinho, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fundação Faculdade Regional de Medicina de São José do Rio Preto</name>
      <address>
        <city>São José do Rio Preto</city>
        <state>São Paulo</state>
        <zip>15090-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Osvaldo L da Silva Júnior, NP PgD MHSc</last_name>
      <phone>+55 17 3201-5054</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lilia N Maia, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Nacional de Infectologia Evandro Chagas / Fundação Oswaldo Cruz (FIOCRUZ)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rio De Janeiro</city>
        <zip>21040-360</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jessica B Felix</last_name>
      <phone>55 21 3865 9666</phone>
      <email>jessica.felix@ini.fiocruz.br</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Tania Krstic</last_name>
      <email>tania.krstic@ini.fiocruz.br</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Beatriz Grinsztejn, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Argentina</country>
    <country>Brazil</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>BGE-175</keyword>
  <keyword>BioAge</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiratory failure</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

