<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04700579</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>N19/09/126</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04700579</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pre- and Post-treatment Lung Microbiota, Metabolome and Immune Signatures at the Site of Disease in Patients With Active Pulmonary Tuberculosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>TB-LUNG</acronym>
  <official_title>Pre- and Post-treatment Lung Microbiota, Metabolome and Immune Signatures at the Site of Disease in Patients With Active Pulmonary Tuberculosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Stellenbosch</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>New York University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Stellenbosch</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The diverse microbial communities in different parts of the human body (microbiome) are&#xD;
      important for health but understudied in pulmonary tuberculosis (TB), which is the single&#xD;
      biggest infectious cause of death in the world. The investigators will study the&#xD;
      site-of-disease microbiome (in the lung bronchoalveolar space) in TB cases to investigate&#xD;
      how, before TB treatment, metabolic compounds made by microbes affect host biomarkers&#xD;
      important for TB control. The investigators will ask this question again at the&#xD;
      end-of-treatment and one year later. Specifically, the investigators will sample the lung at&#xD;
      the active TB hotspot identified by imaging and compare this to a non-involved lung segment&#xD;
      usually in the opposite lung. The investigators will compare the lung microbiome to other&#xD;
      sites in the body (i.e. oral cavity, nasopharynx, supraglottis, and gut). A small amount of&#xD;
      blood (~15 ml) will be collected to assess peripheral immunological correlates of the host&#xD;
      microbiome. Protected specimen brushings of the lung will be used to explore transcriptomic&#xD;
      signatures and how these relate to the lung microbiome. The investigators will also apply&#xD;
      these questions to the same number of controls (healthy patients and patients with an&#xD;
      alternative diagnoses). This will lay the foundation for clinical trials to evaluate if&#xD;
      specific bacteria have diagnostic (e.g., PCR) or therapeutic potential (e.g., antibiotics,&#xD;
      prebiotics, probiotics, vaccines) where targeting the microbiome could improve clinical&#xD;
      outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The human body is host to complex microbial communities at different anatomical sites such as&#xD;
      the gut, oral cavity, vagina, skin, and the lower respiratory tract - a site previously&#xD;
      thought to be sterile. Growing evidence has implicated the role of the human microbiome in&#xD;
      various diseases for example, Prevotella-enriched lung communities in HIV-positive pneumonia&#xD;
      patients independently predict 70-day mortality, and Lactobacillus enriched murine gut&#xD;
      microbiome alleviates asthma-like symptoms. However, despite the scale and severity of TB,&#xD;
      there are limited studies on the microbiome in TB cases, the site of disease, and the effect&#xD;
      of treatment, especially in the context of HIV. These key knowledge gaps preclude the design&#xD;
      and evaluation of interventions that could target the microbiome and avert poor treatment&#xD;
      outcomes in TB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date the few microbiome studies in TB have focused on the upper respiratory tract (using&#xD;
      specimens such as sputum) and gut rather than the site of disease which, in TB, is typically&#xD;
      the lung. These studies have shown associations between the microbiome and state of disease.&#xD;
      For example, mice colonized with Helicobacter hepaticus in the gut demonstrate poor control&#xD;
      of mycobacterial growth, heightened inflammation, and severe tissue pathology in the lungs.&#xD;
      The lung which is the site of disease in pulmonary TB has been widely considered sterile&#xD;
      until recently and the lung microbiome remains widely understudied in TB regardless of the&#xD;
      potential impact it might have in TB pathogenesis. One of the major reasons why the lung is&#xD;
      understudied is the difficult in sampling the lung. The investigators will implement a&#xD;
      modified bronchoscopy procedure to avoid microbial cross-contamination from neighbouring&#xD;
      anatomical sites (including from diseased to healthy parts of the lungs) and to accurately&#xD;
      sample the low biomass in the bronchoalveolar space. The investigators hypothesize that TB&#xD;
      cases have a distinct site-of-disease lung microbiota compared to non-diseased contralateral&#xD;
      tissue, characterized by an enrichment of oral anaerobic fermenters, SCFAs, and impaired&#xD;
      inflammation and tissue repair biomarkers. They also expect microbial and host biomarkers to&#xD;
      be altered by TB treatment. A study by one of the investigators has already demonstrated lung&#xD;
      microbiomes enriched with anaerobic oral taxa are associated with lung inflammation of the&#xD;
      Th17 phenotype. The products of microbial anaerobic metabolism have also been shown to&#xD;
      modulate immune response to diseases. The investigators will correlate the complex microbial&#xD;
      communities at the site-of-disease in TB with the microbial and host biomarkers at the&#xD;
      site-of-disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will recruit self-reporting patients with their first TB episode and Xpert MTB/RIF&#xD;
      Ultra-confirmed TB from Scottsdene and Wallacedene primary care clinics in Cape Town. A total&#xD;
      of 50 TB cases equally stratified by HIV status and 50 healthy household contacts (HHC) also&#xD;
      stratified by HIV will be recruited. In addition to HIV-negatives, the study is recruiting an&#xD;
      equal number of ART-treated HIV-positive TB cases, because there an epidemiologically&#xD;
      important subpopulation with impaired pulmonary immunity. An additional 50 sick controls with&#xD;
      other pulmonary diseases (Asthma, Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), Cancer,&#xD;
      Bronchiectasis (including post-TB) and Pneumonia) will recruited as comparator groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>18 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of changes in microbiota in diseased vs. non-diseased lung segments, stratified by HIV status.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Lung microbiome in diseased and non-diseased segments determined by 16S rRNA gene sequencing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of specific microbial taxa in diseased segments with elevated SCFAs and impaired host inflammation and tissue repair biomarkers.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation analysis of specific cytokines profiled using commercial multiplexed Luminex panels and SCFAs measured using Gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) assays.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of treatment on the lung microbiome.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Characterize bacterial community resilience alongside changes in microbial and host biomarkers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>TB - Tuberculosis</condition>
  <condition>HIV/AIDS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TB Cases</arm_group_label>
    <description>n= 50 (25 HIV positive and 25 HIV negative)&#xD;
Xpert MTB/RIF Ultra-confirmed TB</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Household Contacts</arm_group_label>
    <description>n= (25 HIV positive and 25 HIV negative)&#xD;
Culture negative TB result</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sick controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>n=50&#xD;
Diseases: Asthma, Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), Cancer, Bronchiectasis (including post-TB) and Pneumonia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, Protected specimen brushings, Sputum, Oro- Nasopharyngeal&#xD;
      swabs, Urine, Blood and Stool.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Self-presenting patients with Xpert MTB/RIF Ultra-confirmed TB (n=50, equally stratified by&#xD;
        HIV) and culture negative HHCs (n=50, equally stratified by HIV) will be recruited from&#xD;
        primary care clinics (Scottsdene and Wallacedene) in Cape Town, South Africa. An additional&#xD;
        50 sick controls with other lung diseases will be referred from Tygerberg Academic&#xD;
        Hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18-60 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to undergo CXR and/or CT scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has unilateral TB disease defined as one lung with extensive evidence of TB disease&#xD;
             (non-applicable to healthy controls; sick controls will require an alternative&#xD;
             diagnosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No evidence of prior TB treatment and/or CXR/CT does not have obvious evidence of&#xD;
             prior TB.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to undergo a research bronchoscopy at baseline, 6 months and 18 months and&#xD;
             likely to remain in the area for the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If HIV-positive, must be stable on antiretroviral therapy (ART) for ≥1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to return for follow-up visits, with no plans to move in the near&#xD;
             future.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to comply with study requirements i.e. provision of contact details and&#xD;
             written, informed consent prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 18 years or older than 60 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has already initiated TB treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rifampicin resistant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a previous history of TB.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilateral TB disease defined as both lungs with extensive TB disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received probiotics, antibiotics or inhaled steroids within three months prior to&#xD;
             enrolment (not applicable to sick controls)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has diabetes mellitus, which affects TB disease, treatment response, and the&#xD;
             microbiome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a contraindication for bronchoscopy (e.g., FEV1 &lt;70%), as determined by&#xD;
             bronchoscopists according to best practice guidelines&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a daily alcohol intake of more than 6 beers or 4 mixed drinks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is pregnant (a commercial human chorionic gonadotropin determination assay will be&#xD;
             performed in accordance with manufacturer's guidance on urine) or pregnancy planned&#xD;
             for follow-up period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent hospitalization for any reason&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Grant Theron, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Stellenbosch</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Grant Theron, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(+27) 021 938 9693</phone>
    <email>gtheron@sun.ac.za</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Charissa Naidoo, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(+27) 0219389955</phone>
    <email>ccnaidoo@sun.ac.za</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kraaifontein Community Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cape Town</city>
        <state>Western Cape</state>
        <zip>7570</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Grant Theron, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(+27) 21 938 9693</phone>
      <phone_ext>9693</phone_ext>
      <email>gtheron@sun.ac.za</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Byron WP Reeve, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(+27) 21 938 9954</phone>
      <phone_ext>9954</phone_ext>
      <email>byronreeve@sun.ac.za</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Scottsdene Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cape Town</city>
        <state>Western Cape</state>
        <zip>7570</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Grant Theron, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(+27) 21 938 9693</phone>
      <phone_ext>9693</phone_ext>
      <email>gtheron@sun.ac.za</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Byron WP Reeve, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(+27) 21 938 9954</phone>
      <phone_ext>9954</phone_ext>
      <email>byronreeve@sun.ac.za</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wallacedene Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cape Town</city>
        <state>Western Cape</state>
        <zip>7570</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Grant Theron, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(+27) 21 938 9693</phone>
      <phone_ext>9693</phone_ext>
      <email>gtheron@sun.ac.za</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Byron WP Reeve, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>(+27) 21 938 9954</phone>
      <phone_ext>9954</phone_ext>
      <email>byronreeve@sun.ac.za</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>South Africa</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yatsunenko T, Rey FE, Manary MJ, Trehan I, Dominguez-Bello MG, Contreras M, Magris M, Hidalgo G, Baldassano RN, Anokhin AP, Heath AC, Warner B, Reeder J, Kuczynski J, Caporaso JG, Lozupone CA, Lauber C, Clemente JC, Knights D, Knight R, Gordon JI. Human gut microbiome viewed across age and geography. Nature. 2012 May 9;486(7402):222-7. doi: 10.1038/nature11053.</citation>
    <PMID>22699611</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wade WG. The oral microbiome in health and disease. Pharmacol Res. 2013 Mar;69(1):137-43. doi: 10.1016/j.phrs.2012.11.006. Epub 2012 Nov 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23201354</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weiner J 3rd, Parida SK, Maertzdorf J, Black GF, Repsilber D, Telaar A, Mohney RP, Arndt-Sullivan C, Ganoza CA, Faé KC, Walzl G, Kaufmann SH. Biomarkers of inflammation, immunosuppression and stress with active disease are revealed by metabolomic profiling of tuberculosis patients. PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e40221. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0040221. Epub 2012 Jul 23. Erratum in: PLoS One. 2016;11(3):e0153050.</citation>
    <PMID>22844400</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grice EA, Kong HH, Renaud G, Young AC; NISC Comparative Sequencing Program, Bouffard GG, Blakesley RW, Wolfsberg TG, Turner ML, Segre JA. A diversity profile of the human skin microbiota. Genome Res. 2008 Jul;18(7):1043-50. doi: 10.1101/gr.075549.107. Epub 2008 May 23.</citation>
    <PMID>18502944</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shenoy MK, Iwai S, Lin DL, Worodria W, Ayakaka I, Byanyima P, Kaswabuli S, Fong S, Stone S, Chang E, Davis JL, Faruqi AA, Segal MR, Huang L, Lynch SV. Immune Response and Mortality Risk Relate to Distinct Lung Microbiomes in Patients with HIV and Pneumonia. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2017 Jan 1;195(1):104-114. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201603-0523OC.</citation>
    <PMID>27447987</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wipperman MF, Fitzgerald DW, Juste MAJ, Taur Y, Namasivayam S, Sher A, Bean JM, Bucci V, Glickman MS. Antibiotic treatment for Tuberculosis induces a profound dysbiosis of the microbiome that persists long after therapy is completed. Sci Rep. 2017 Sep 7;7(1):10767. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-10346-6.</citation>
    <PMID>28883399</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Botero LE, Delgado-Serrano L, Cepeda ML, Bustos JR, Anzola JM, Del Portillo P, Robledo J, Zambrano MM. Respiratory tract clinical sample selection for microbiota analysis in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. Microbiome. 2014 Aug 25;2:29. doi: 10.1186/2049-2618-2-29. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>25225609</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cheung MK, Lam WY, Fung WY, Law PT, Au CH, Nong W, Kam KM, Kwan HS, Tsui SK. Sputum microbiota in tuberculosis as revealed by 16S rRNA pyrosequencing. PLoS One. 2013;8(1):e54574. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0054574. Epub 2013 Jan 24.</citation>
    <PMID>23365674</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cui Z, Zhou Y, Li H, Zhang Y, Zhang S, Tang S, Guo X. Complex sputum microbial composition in patients with pulmonary tuberculosis. BMC Microbiol. 2012 Nov 23;12:276. doi: 10.1186/1471-2180-12-276.</citation>
    <PMID>23176186</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Segal LN, Clemente JC, Tsay JC, Koralov SB, Keller BC, Wu BG, Li Y, Shen N, Ghedin E, Morris A, Diaz P, Huang L, Wikoff WR, Ubeda C, Artacho A, Rom WN, Sterman DH, Collman RG, Blaser MJ, Weiden MD. Enrichment of the lung microbiome with oral taxa is associated with lung inflammation of a Th17 phenotype. Nat Microbiol. 2016 Apr 4;1:16031. doi: 10.1038/nmicrobiol.2016.31.</citation>
    <PMID>27572644</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Segal LN, Alekseyenko AV, Clemente JC, Kulkarni R, Wu B, Gao Z, Chen H, Berger KI, Goldring RM, Rom WN, Blaser MJ, Weiden MD. Enrichment of lung microbiome with supraglottic taxa is associated with increased pulmonary inflammation. Microbiome. 2013 Jul 1;1(1):19. doi: 10.1186/2049-2618-1-19. Erratum in: Microbiome. 2014;2:21. Gao, Zhan [added].</citation>
    <PMID>24450871</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Naidoo CC, Nyawo GR, Wu BG, Walzl G, Warren RM, Segal LN, Theron G. The microbiome and tuberculosis: state of the art, potential applications, and defining the clinical research agenda. Lancet Respir Med. 2019 Oct;7(10):892-906. doi: 10.1016/S2213-2600(18)30501-0. Epub 2019 Mar 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30910543</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Stellenbosch</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Grant Theron</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>Short Chain Fatty Acids</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunological Biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Collaborators will have access to de-identified IPD data. Other researchers wishing to access the data will be required to sign a data sharing agreement as per institutional policies.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be available once the findings are published.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data access will be granted to interested collaborators and parties through sharing of data files or login information for the study's secure RedCap electronic database during the course of patient recruitment.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

