<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04700371</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1.0-2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04700371</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vessel Deformations and Restenosis After Stenting of the Popliteal Artery</brief_title>
  <acronym>FIRESTEP</acronym>
  <official_title>Flexion-Induced Vessel Deformations and Restenosis After Stenting of the Popliteal Artery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kantonsspital Aarau</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kantonsspital Aarau</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The femoro-popliteal (FP) artery is the most frequently treated vascular segment in patients&#xD;
      with symptomatic peripheral artery disease (PAD), for which endovascular therapy became an&#xD;
      established treatment option during the last decades. However, loss of primary patency and&#xD;
      consecutive clinically driven target lesion revascularization (TLR) limit this procedure.&#xD;
      Moreover, in the popliteal artery (PA), evidence about the best treatment strategy to prevent&#xD;
      loss of patency and TLR is limited to only a few randomized controlled trials (RCT). Arterial&#xD;
      deformations of the PA with its unique anatomical properties during leg flexion might explain&#xD;
      the poor technical and clinical outcomes in this segment. Generally, a &quot;leave nothing behind&quot;&#xD;
      strategy in the PA is preferred, but cannot be avoided in all cases due to e.g. flow limiting&#xD;
      dissections or re-coil after balloon angioplasty. Basically two different self-expandable&#xD;
      nitinol-based stent designs are available on the market. An interwoven nitinol and laser-cut&#xD;
      nitinol stent. The interwoven nitinol stent has a higher radial force in comparison to the&#xD;
      laser-cut stent and reveals higher patency rates in the FP arteries. However, a head-to-head&#xD;
      comparison of these stents is missing and it remains unknown in which way different stent&#xD;
      designs affect the deformation and hemodynamic behaviors of the PA during knee flexion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Randomized trial to investigate the impact of different stent designs on the target lesion&#xD;
      restenosis rate in femoro-popliteal arteries. Immediately after stent implantation, sets of&#xD;
      three orthogonal angiographic views (separated by an angle of &gt; 25째) of the stented region&#xD;
      (TL) will be obtained with the leg in supine position. This will be followed by&#xD;
      intra-arterial imaging using Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT). OCT images (one pullback if&#xD;
      the lesion length is &lt; 75 mm, 2 pullbacks otherwise) of the TL will be acquired using the&#xD;
      Dragonfly catheter. In addition, duplex ultrasound (DU) of the TL will be performed,&#xD;
      including the arterial segments 10cm at proximal and distal edge of the TL. Thereafter, a&#xD;
      bending cast will be used to obtain a knee/hip flexion of approximately 70째/20째. In this&#xD;
      position the angiographic, OCT, and DU measurements will be repeated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The OCT images will provide the shapes of the arterial lumen which will be used to generate&#xD;
      3D surface models (in .stl format). The X-ray images will be utilized to construct the 3D&#xD;
      arterial centerline for the supine and flexed leg positions. These arterial centerlines will&#xD;
      be used to quantify the axial deformation (in mm), twisting (in 째), and curvature changes (in&#xD;
      mm-1) along the length of the investigated segment. Additionally, the lumen profiles obtained&#xD;
      from OCT images will be used to accurately estimate the radial deformations (in mm) in the&#xD;
      lumen and define instances of arterial pinching during leg flexion (as the difference in&#xD;
      lumen diameters between straight and flexed leg positions).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The geometries of the arterial lumens will be combined with their corresponding 3D arterial&#xD;
      centerlines to generate patient-specific arterial models. Along with patient-specific&#xD;
      boundary conditions obtained from DU measurements, these models will be transferred to a&#xD;
      commercial software, to perform Computational Fluid Dynamics analyses. The changes in these&#xD;
      parameters due to leg flexion, as well as due to different stent designs, will be quantified.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary patency</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year post index procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Primary patency of the target lesion measured by duplex ultrasound</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in arterial flow within the target lesion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 6 months, and 1 year post index procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in blood flow/hemodynamics caused by the different stent designs measured by Computational Fluid Dynamics</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Arterial Disease</condition>
  <condition>Popliteal Artery Stenosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interwoven stent</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of an interwoven nitinol stent to treat patients with arteriosclerotic lesions of the distal portion of the superficial artery and/or the popliteal artery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Laser-cut stent</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Use of a laser-cut nitinol stent to treat patients with arteriosclerotic lesions of the distal portion of the superficial artery and/or the popliteal artery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Interwoven stent</intervention_name>
    <description>Interwoven nitinol stent placement in patients with arteriosclerotic lesions of the distal portion of the superficial artery and/or the popliteal artery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interwoven stent</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laser-cut stent</intervention_name>
    <description>Laser-cut nitinol stent placement in patients with arteriosclerotic lesions of the distal portion of the superficial artery and/or the popliteal artery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Laser-cut stent</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent prior to any study procedure,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of PAD (2 - 3 Rutherford-Becker class),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Atherosclerotic de-novo lesion (stenosis &gt;70% or occlusion) of the distal part of the&#xD;
             superficial femoral artery and/or any part of the popliteal artery,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Target lesion-length: 4cm to 12cm,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Target vessel diameter: 5mm to 7mm,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Guidewire must cross target lesion and located intraluminally before randomization,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one (1) patent below-the knee artery (=with no stenosis &gt;50%),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Possibility to treat the target lesion with one (1) study stent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Interventions in TASC A and B lesions to restore adequate blood flow, in the same&#xD;
             index procedure, are allowed. This intervention must be prior to the treatment of the&#xD;
             study lesion(s) and successful.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Angiographic evidence of thrombus within the target lesion,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with acute critical limb ischemia (Rutherford-Becker class 4-6),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Restenosis of the target lesion,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-atherosclerotic obstructions of the target lesion,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aneurysm of the target lesion,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal failure, defined as GFR, &lt;40 mL/min/1.73m2,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's inability to follow the study procedures e.g. psychological disorders,&#xD;
             dementia, etc.,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous enrolment into an ongoing study,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected allergies or contraindications to aspirin and/or clopidogrel,&#xD;
             heparin,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Coagulation disorders, or general refusal of the patient to receive blood&#xD;
             transfusions,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contrast allergy that cannot be treated,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thrombolysis therapy including 72 hours before the planned index procedure,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myocardial infarction or stroke &lt;30 days prior to index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Equipment is unavailable to fulfill study treatments.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aljoscha Rastan</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Kantonsspital Aarau</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aljoscha Rastan</last_name>
    <phone>0041628386458</phone>
    <email>aljoscha.rastan@ksa.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Christoph Thalhammer</last_name>
    <phone>0041628384703</phone>
    <email>christoph.thalhammer@ksa.ch</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 7, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kantonsspital Aarau</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aljoscha Rastan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Endovascular Therapy, Angiology, Kantonsspital Aarau</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

