<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04704375</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>25-154</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04704375</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Osteopathic Manipulative Treatment (OMT) and Bio Electro-Magnetic Regulation (BEMER) Therapy on Low Back Pain in Adults.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Osteopathic Manipulative Treatment (OMT) and Bio Electro-Magnetic Regulation (BEMER) Therapy on Low Back Pain in Adults.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is clear that low back pain (LBP) is a major challenge in our society, which can lead to&#xD;
      severe disability in many individuals. Although there are several different treatments and&#xD;
      approaches to help individuals with LBP, the number affected by this condition has been&#xD;
      steadily increasing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OMT has been shown to be helpful in the treatment of LBP. In fact, the use of OMT has been&#xD;
      shown to increase mobility of the lumbar myofascial tissues, visceral motion and decrease&#xD;
      pain in patients with LBP. Bio Electro-Magnetic Regulation (BEMER) Therapy is a therapeutic&#xD;
      modality that deploys a biorhythmically defined stimulus through a Pulsed Electromagnetic&#xD;
      Field (PEMF), which leads to an increase in blood flow. The positive effects of BEMER on the&#xD;
      circulation has been shown to result in significant increases in arteriovenous oxygen&#xD;
      difference, number of open capillaries, arteriolar and venular flow volume, and flow rate of&#xD;
      red blood cells in the microvasculature. Therefore, BEMER can potentially be used in the&#xD;
      treatment of LBP by improving microcirculation in muscular tissue. In fact, BEMER with&#xD;
      physiotherapy showed reductions in pain and fatigue acutely in patients with chronic low back&#xD;
      pain. A systemic review of randomized controlled trials that investigated whether PEMF was&#xD;
      effective in low back pain showed there was decrease in pain intensity and improved&#xD;
      functionality in individuals with different low back pain conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, it is plausible that the combination of OMT and BEMER therapy may help increase&#xD;
      circulation to myofascial structures that influence low back restriction and pain. The&#xD;
      purpose of this study is to investigate the individual and combined effects of OMT and BEMER&#xD;
      therapy on low back pain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 13, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 9, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 9, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Low back pain rating</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 1 week of completion of 3-week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by questionnaire rating, compared with pre-intervention rating</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life rating</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 1 week of completion of 3-week intervention period</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by questionnaire rating, compared with pre-intervention rating</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Musculoskeletal Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BEMER</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects in the BEMER group received treatment 5 times per week for a period of 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OMT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each subject in the OMT group received treatment 3 times per week for a period of 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BEMER + OMT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each subject in the BEMER + OMT group received treatment 3 times per week for a period of 3 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Finally, subjects in the Placebo group will receive the light touch and BEMER sham treatments at same intervals as the corresponding experimental groups.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bio Electro-Magnetic Regulation (BEMER) Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>BEMER is a therapeutic modality that deploys a biorhythmically defined stimulus through Pulsed Electromagnetic Field (PEMF). This stimulus has a targeted effect on the microvasculature, and the primary effect is an improvement in tissue microcirculation. The positive effects of vasomotion on the microcirculation has been shown to result in significant increases in arteriovenous oxygen difference, number of open capillaries, arteriolar and venular flow volume, and flow rate of red blood cells in the microvasculature. Therefore, BEMER can potentially be used in the treatment of LBP by improving microcirculation in muscular tissue.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BEMER</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>BEMER + OMT</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OMT (osteopathic manipulative treatment)</intervention_name>
    <description>i. OMT Myofascial release (MFR), soft tissue (ST) release, muscle energy (ME), counterstrain (CS), and balanced ligamentous tension (BLT) technique.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BEMER + OMT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>OMT</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Light touch</intervention_name>
    <description>Treaters will place their hands lightly on the subject's lumbar paraspinal muscles in the supine and prone positions in the same area as where one would place your hands for lumbar MFR technique for the same amount of time as it would take to perform MFR in this area (approximately 5 minutes). However, no lifting or action will be done. In addition, the subject will lie down on the BEMER mat (as they would do during a BEMER session), but the device will not be activated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        LECOM-Bradenton faculty, staff and Students currently enrolled in LECOM-Bradenton's&#xD;
        osteopathic medical program, pharmacy program, dental program, and master's program who are&#xD;
        currently experiencing low back pain will be approached for recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects will be excluded if they are unable to provide informed consent, are currently&#xD;
        pregnant, or have a known medical history of current psychiatric conditions, skin disorders&#xD;
        or open wounds precluding skin contact, fasciitis of fascial tears, myositis, neurological&#xD;
        symptoms such as numbness, tingling, weakness in lower extremities, neoplasia, cancer, bone&#xD;
        fracture, osteomyelitis, or osteoporosis, coagulation problem, deep vein thrombosis,&#xD;
        adrenal diseases/syndromes, acute upper or lower respiratory infection, immunosuppressive&#xD;
        syndromes, radiation or chemotherapy within the past 3 years, lupus, osteopenia, congestive&#xD;
        heart failure, BMI greater than 30, any other autoimmune disease not stated above,&#xD;
        medication changes within the last 4 weeks, asthma exacerbations within the last 4 weeks,&#xD;
        immunosuppressive therapy as a consequence of organ transplantation, immunosuppressive&#xD;
        therapy as a consequence of allogeneic cellular transplantations or bone marrow stem cell&#xD;
        transplantation, other conditions often requiring immunosuppressive therapy, anticoagulant&#xD;
        therapy, or known sensitivity to the carotid sinus reflex.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LECOM-Bradenton</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bradenton</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>34211</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Lake Erie College of Osteopathic Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Diana Speelman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>OMM</keyword>
  <keyword>BEMER</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Back Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

