<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04709380</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCC2509</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04709380</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase III RCT of Radiotherapy Plus Toripalimab Versus Sorafenib in Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma With PVTT</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase III Randomized Clinical Trial of Radiotherapy Plus Toripalimab Versus Sorafenib in Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma With Portal Vein Tumor Thrombosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To explore the efficacy of radiotherapy plus toripalimab Versus standard treatment of&#xD;
      sorafenib in advanced hepatocellular carcinoma with Portal Vein/Hepatic vein Tumor&#xD;
      Thrombosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an single-center, open, randomized study, which is going to enroll patients filtered&#xD;
      to meet the standard of advanced hepatocellular carcinoma, in a 2: 1-proportional randomly&#xD;
      assigned to the test group and control group. Patients in the experimental group will be&#xD;
      given local vein tumor thrombus/hepatic vein tumor thrombus +/- intrahepatic large lesions&#xD;
      with hypofractionated intensity-modulated radiotherapy (tumor area dose 40-60Gy/10-20f),&#xD;
      concurrent with and followed by 240mg Q3W of toripalimab within 1 week of radiotherapy&#xD;
      started. Patients in the control group will be treated with sorafenib (400mg, twice a day).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 2, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>TTP</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Time to Progression (TTP) was defined as the duration from the date of patient recruited to the first progress at any site or the date of death.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Response Rate (ORR) was defined as the total of CR (Complete Response) and PR (Partial Response). CR and PR were assessed by independent reviewers according to the Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>OS</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival (OS) was defined as the duration from the date of patient recruited to the date of death with any reason.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of grade 3 and above adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events was evaluated during received protocol therapy according to CTCAE 4.03.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">85</enrollment>
  <condition>Radiotherapy</condition>
  <condition>Toripalimab</condition>
  <condition>Sorafenib</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Radiotherapy plus Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the experimental group will be given local vein tumor thrombus/hepatic vein tumor thrombus +/- intrahepatic large lesions with hypofractionated intensity modulated radiotherapy (tumor area dose 40-60Gy/10-20f), concurrent with and followed by 240mg Q3W of teriprizumab within 1 week of radiotherapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sorafenib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in the control group will be treated with sorafenib (400mg, twice a day).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiotherapy plus Toripalimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Intensity modulated radiotherapy has shown important role in the treatment of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), especially for advanced disease with portal vein tumor thrombosis (PVTT), or hepatic vein tumor thrombosis. Toripalimab is a recombinant, humanized programmed death receptor-1 (PD-1) monoclonal antibody that binds to PD-1 and prevents binding of PD-1 with programmed death ligands 1 (PD-L1) and 2 (PD-L2).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Radiotherapy plus Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sorafenib</intervention_name>
    <description>Sorafenib is a multi-targeted oral drug for the treatment of cancer.Treatment of inoperable advanced renal cell carcinoma ,inoperable or distant metastatic primary hepatocellular carcinoma and so on.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sorafenib</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical or histologic diagnosis of Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) according to the&#xD;
             2019 version of liver cancer diagnosis and treatment guideline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged between 18 and 80 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ECOG 0-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The left volume of liver-GTV which is received less than dose of 5Gy is more than&#xD;
             250ml after the portal vein/hepatic vein tumor thrombosis and its connected primary&#xD;
             main lesion is received treatment dose of 40-60Gy/10-20f.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients may have a history of treatments for hepatocellular carcinoma such as TACE,&#xD;
             radiofrequency, surgery, chemotherapy, and Chinese herbal medicine, but all patients&#xD;
             must have not been received targeted therapy and Immunotherapy, such as anti-PD-1,&#xD;
             anti-PD-L1 or anti-PD-L2 drug therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. BCLC Stage C, HCC combined with portal vein or hepatic vein tumor thrombosis. If it is&#xD;
             a portal vein tumor thrombosis, it must involve the left or right portal trunk at&#xD;
             least. If it is a hepatic vein tumor thrombosis, it must involve the left or middle or&#xD;
             right main hepatic veins at least. At the same time, eligible patients have to meet&#xD;
             one of the following conditions. (1) There are distant metastases (except for central&#xD;
             nervous system and meningeal metastases); (2) Both hepatic lobes are showed multiple&#xD;
             lesions which are unable to be fully covered within the target area&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The expected lifetime is more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Child A5, A6, B7.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Virus conditions: HBV DNA &lt;2000 IU/mL, if ≥ 2000 IU/mL, need to accept antiviral&#xD;
             treatment until&lt;2000 IU/mL; patients with a positive HCV antibody must have a negative&#xD;
             polymerase chain reaction (PCR) test result of HCV RNA;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Liver function: ALT is within 2.5 times of the upper limit of normal. AST can be&#xD;
             within 6 times of the upper limit of normal if ALT is within 1.5 times of the upper&#xD;
             limit of normal and cardiac infarction is excluded. If ALT is 1.5 to 2.5 times the&#xD;
             upper limit of normal, AST must be within 1.5 times the upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. There is no obvious abnormality in the electrocardiography, and no obvious cardiac&#xD;
             dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Renal function: CRE and BUN are within 1.5 times the upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Blood routine test: Hb≥80g/L, ANC≥1.0×10 9/L, PLT≥40×10 9/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Coagulation function: no bleeding tendency.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Willingness to voluntarily participate in the clinical trial and sign informed&#xD;
             consent..&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those who are participating in other clinical trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Had prior abdominal irradiation, or had prior liver transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with chronic, serious diseases such as cardiac, pulmonary, and renal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Suspected or true alcohol, drug abuse history.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. May be allergic to treatment with sorafenib or toripalimab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have received immunotherapy in the past, such as anti-PD-1, anti-PD-L1, anti-PD-L2&#xD;
             drugs, and other drugs that stimulate or co-inhibitory T cell receptors (such as&#xD;
             CTLA-4, OX- 40 or CD137) treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Severe mental or nervous system disorders that affect informed consent and/or&#xD;
             expression or perception of adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Previous clinical diagnosis of hepatic encephalopathy in the past 6 months. Patients&#xD;
             with hepatic encephalopathy which are controlled by rifaximin or lactulose are not&#xD;
             allowed to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Moderate to severe ascitic fluid with obvious symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Concomitant secondary malignant tumors or other tumors (except superficial skin&#xD;
             cancer, localized low-grade malignant tumors and carcinoma in situ) within 3 years&#xD;
             before the start of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of gastrointestinal hemorrhage within 6 months before the start of the study,&#xD;
             or was diagnosed by ERCP/CT/DSA as a high risk of rupture and bleeding of esophageal&#xD;
             gastric varices.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Suffer from serious unhealed wounds, ulcers or fractures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Active central nervous system metastasis or cancerous meningitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Active tuberculosis (TB), who are receiving anti-tuberculosis treatment or have&#xD;
             received anti-tuberculosis treatment within 1 year before the first medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of biliary fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, and intra-abdominal abscess&#xD;
             within 4 weeks before the start of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of unstable angina, myocardial infarction, coronary artery bypass grafting,&#xD;
             congestive heart failure, cerebrovascular accident (including transient ischemic&#xD;
             attack, pulmonary embolism) within 3 months before the start of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. NCI-CTCAE v.4 grade ≥2 cardiac arrhythmia, atrial fibrillation, or QT interval&#xD;
             prolongation of any NCI-CTCAE v.4 grade (male &gt; 450ms, female &gt; 470ms).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Uncontrollable hypertension treated with best antihypertensive drugs (&gt; 150/90mmHg&#xD;
             after rational medication).&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. History of HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Females who are pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Live vaccines were vaccinated within 30 days before the first dose of study drug. Live&#xD;
             vaccines include but are not limited to the following: measles, mumps, rubella,&#xD;
             varicella/shingles (chickenpox), yellow fever, rabies, BCG (BCG) and typhoid vaccines.&#xD;
             Since seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are usually inactivated virus&#xD;
             vaccines, their use is allowed; however, intranasal influenza vaccines (for example,&#xD;
             FluMist) are live attenuated vaccines, so they are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Have an active autoimmune disease that requires systemic treatment in the past 2 years&#xD;
             (for example, immunomodulatory drugs, corticosteroids, or immunosuppressive drugs.&#xD;
             Autoimmune diseases such as autoimmune hepatitis, interstitial pneumonia, uveal&#xD;
             Inflammation, systemic lupus erythematosus, rheumatoid arthritis, inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             disease, antiphospholipid syndrome related vascular thrombosis, Wegener's&#xD;
             granulomatosis, Sjogren's syndrome, Guillain-Barré syndrome, multiple sclerosis,&#xD;
             vasculitis, Glomerulonephritis, etc., hyperthyroidism or hypothyroidism, asthma that&#xD;
             requires bronchodilator treatment, etc.). Replacement therapy (for example, thyroxine,&#xD;
             insulin, or physiological corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary&#xD;
             insufficiency) is not considered systemic therapy and is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Combined with medical contraindications that cannot accept any contrast-enhanced&#xD;
             imaging examinations (CT or MRI).&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Severely allergic to research intervention and/or any of its excipients (≥Grade 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Uncontrolled metabolic disorders or other non-malignant tumor organs or systemic&#xD;
             diseases or cancer secondary reactions, which can lead to higher medical risks and/or&#xD;
             uncertainty in survival evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Patients who have received allogeneic tissue/solid organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Patients with other acute or chronic diseases, mental illnesses, or abnormal&#xD;
             laboratory test values that may cause the following results: increase the risk related&#xD;
             to study participation or study drug administration, or interfere with the&#xD;
             interpretation of the study results, and the patients shall be treated according to&#xD;
             the judgment of the investigator classified as not eligible to participate in this&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bo Chen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>008613240000876</phone>
    <email>cbchinese@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bo Chen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <state>Beijing</state>
        <zip>100021</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Bo Chen, MD</last_name>
      <phone>008613240000876</phone>
      <email>chenboo@outlook.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bo Chen, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Huiying Zeng, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Liming Wang, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cancer Institute and Hospital, Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bo Chen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Radiotherpay</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-PD-1 antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced Hepatocellular Carcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sorafenib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

