<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04704154</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21136</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-003359-13</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04704154</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial to Learn Whether Regorafenib in Combination With Nivolumab Can Improve Tumor Responses and How Safe it is for Participants With Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multi-indication, Single-treatment Arm, Open-label Phase 2 Study of Regorafenib and Nivolumab in Combination in Patients With Recurrent or Metastatic Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bayer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol Myers Squibb Co. and Ono Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bayer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Researchers are looking for a better way to treat people with solid tumors. Before a&#xD;
      treatment can be approved for people to take, researchers do clinical trials to better&#xD;
      understand its safety and how it works.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this trial, the researchers want to learn about regorafenib taken together with nivolumab&#xD;
      in a small number of participants with different types of tumors. These include tumors in the&#xD;
      head and neck, the esophagus, the pancreas, the brain, and the biliary tract. The biliary&#xD;
      tract includes gall bladder and bile ducts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will include about 200 participants who are at least 18 years old. All of the&#xD;
      participants will take 90 mg of regorafenib as a tablet by mouth. The dose of regorafenib can&#xD;
      be adjusted up to 120 mg or down to 60 mg by the doctor based on how well a participant&#xD;
      tolerates treatment. All of the participants will receive 480 milligrams (mg) of nivolumab&#xD;
      through a needle put into a vein (IV infusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants will take treatments in 4-week periods called cycles. They will take&#xD;
      regorafenib once a day for 3 weeks, then stop for 1 week. In each cycle, the participants&#xD;
      will receive nivolumab one time. These 4-week cycles will be repeated throughout the trial.&#xD;
      The participants can take nivolumab and regorafenib until their cancer gets worse, until they&#xD;
      have medical problems, or until they leave the trial. The longest nivolumab can be given is&#xD;
      up to 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the trial, the doctors will take pictures of the participants' tumors using CT or MRI&#xD;
      and will take blood and urine samples. The doctors will also do physical examinations and&#xD;
      check the participants' heart health using an electrocardiogram (ECG). They will ask&#xD;
      questions about how the participants are feeling and if they have any medical problems.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 21, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 13, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to the last participant having been followed for approximately 10 months, summing up to approximately 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Per Response evaluation criteria in solid tumors 1.1 (RECIST 1.1) by local assessment for all solid tumors except GBM/AA (Glioblastoma multiforme/Anaplastic astrocytoma)&#xD;
Per Response assessment in neuro-oncology (RANO) by local assessment for GBM/AA</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing up to the end of the study (LPLV), summing up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate (DCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing up to the end of the study (LPLV), summing up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing up to the end of the study (LPLV), summing up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6 months PFS</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing up to the end of the study (LPLV), summing up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1 year OS</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of AEs (adverse events) per CTCAE v 5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing up to the end of the study (LPLV), summing up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>CTCAE: Common terminology criteria for adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From first dosing up to the end of the study (LPLV), summing up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Regorafenib+Nivolumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Parallel-cohort in adult participants with selected recurrent or metastatic tumors (HNSCC, ESCC, PDAC, BTC, and GBM/AA) who have been previously treated with one or more systemic therapy for the selected tumor indication.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Regorafenib, (Stivarga, BAY73-4506)</intervention_name>
    <description>Intake orally, starting with 3x 30 mg tablets every day (once daily.) for 21 days of every 28-day cycle (21 days on, 7 days off).&#xD;
If the starting dose is well tolerated dose can be escalated to 120 mg (4x30 mg tablets).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Regorafenib+Nivolumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab (Opdivo)</intervention_name>
    <description>480 mg administered on Day 1 of each treatment cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Regorafenib+Nivolumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed selected recurrent or metastatic solid tumor types that have&#xD;
             progressed after treatment with standard therapies and for which there are no curative&#xD;
             intent surgery or chemoradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 1: subjects with HNSCC (Head and neck squamous-cell carcinoma) who have not&#xD;
             received prior PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitor therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 2: subjects with HNSCC who have progressed on or after prior systemic therapy,&#xD;
             at least one of which included a PD-1/PD-L1 inhibitor alone or in combination with&#xD;
             chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 3: subjects with ESCC (Esophageal Squamous Cell Carcinoma) who progressed on or&#xD;
             after platinum and/or fluoropyrimidine based regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 4: subjects with PDAC (Pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma) who have progressed on&#xD;
             or after gemcitabine or fluoropyrimidine based regimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 5: subjects with BTC (Biliary tract carcinoma) (intrahepatic or extrahepatic&#xD;
             cholangiocarcinoma or gall bladder cancer) who have progressed on gemcitabine or&#xD;
             fluoropyrimidine or platinum therapy or a combination of these agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 6: subjects with Grade IV GBM (Glioblastoma multiforme) or Grade III AA&#xD;
             (Anaplastic astrocytoma) (World Health Organization [WHO] criteria) with unequivocal&#xD;
             first progression after surgery followed by radiotherapy and temozolomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented HPV (Human papilloma virus) / p16 status for oropharyngeal cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of giving signed informed consent, including compliance with the requirements&#xD;
             and restrictions listed in the informed consent form (ICF) and in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult participants of legal maturity (18 years or older).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status (PS) 0 to 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate hematologic and organ function as assessed by the following laboratory tests&#xD;
             performed within 7 d before start of study treatment including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤1.5 x the upper limit of normal (ULN). Total bilirubin (≤3 x&#xD;
                  ULN) is allowed if Gilbert's syndrome is documented&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine transaminase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) ≤3 x ULN (≤5 x&#xD;
                  ULN for participants with liver involvement of their cancer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease by baseline CT or MRI per RECIST 1.1 or RANO.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must consent to provide recent biopsy/tumor tissue of a primary tumor&#xD;
             lesion or from metastases (e.g. liver, lung) for HNSCC (IO treated) for Stage 1 and 2&#xD;
             and in HNSCC (IO naïve) cohort for Stage 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticipated life expectancy greater than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to swallow and absorb oral tablets.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of symptomatic central nervous system (CNS) metastases, leptomeningeal&#xD;
             metastases or spinal cord compression. Previously-treated lesions should be stable for&#xD;
             at least 6 weeks prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a condition requiring systemic treatment with either corticosteroids&#xD;
             (&gt;10 mg daily prednisone equivalent) or other immunosuppressive medications within 14&#xD;
             days of start of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy with PD-1/PD-L1 or cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-associated protein 4 (CTLA-4)&#xD;
             inhibitors, or any form of immunotherapy to treat cancer (except cohort 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cohort 2: More than one prior therapy with PD-1/PD-L1 or CTLA-4 inhibitors, or any&#xD;
             other form of immunotherapy to treat cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ESCC:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  patients with apparent tumor invasion on organs located adjacent to the&#xD;
                  esophageal disease (e.g., the aorta or respiratory tract).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  patients who have previously received taxane agents for recurrent/metastatic&#xD;
                  cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GBM/AA&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Primary tumors localized to the brainstem or spinal cord.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of diffuse leptomeningeal disease or extracranial disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants requiring &gt; 4 mg of dexamethasone or biologic equivalent per day to&#xD;
                  control symptoms related to brain tumor and cerebral edema within 21 days of&#xD;
                  starting study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have known dMMR/MSI-H cancers or NTRK (tropomyosin receptor kinase)&#xD;
             fusions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy with regorafenib.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic anti-cancer treatment within 14 days or less than 5 half-lives (whichever is&#xD;
             shorter) of the first dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have permanent discontinuation of PD-1/PD-L1 therapy due to toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arterial thrombotic or embolic events such as cerebrovascular accident (including&#xD;
             transient ischemic attacks) within 6 months before the start of study treatment.&#xD;
             Active pulmonary emboli or deep vein thrombosis that are significant or not adequately&#xD;
             controlled on anticoagulation regimen as per investigator's judgement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiac disorders as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congestive heart failure ≥ New York Heart Association (NYHA) class 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina (angina symptoms at rest), new-onset angina (begun within the&#xD;
                  last 3 months), myocardial infarction less than 6 months before start of study&#xD;
                  drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmias.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poorly controlled hypertension, defined as a blood pressure consistently above 140/90&#xD;
             mmHg despite optimal medical management.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with an active, known or suspected autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids, current pneumonitis or&#xD;
             interstitial lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection &gt; NCI-CTCAE Grade 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test (from historical data or tested during screening) for human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or known acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any positive test result for hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV)&#xD;
             indicating presence of virus, e.g. Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg, Australia&#xD;
             antigen) positive (except for participants on anti-viral therapy for HBV with a viral&#xD;
             load &lt; 100 IU/mL), or Hepatitis C antibody (anti-HCV) positive (except if&#xD;
             HCV-ribonucleic acid [RNA] negative).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs, study drug classes, or excipients in&#xD;
             the formulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory abnormality that&#xD;
             might confound the results of the trial or interfere with the participation for the&#xD;
             full duration of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a current or past history of interstitial lung disease or pulmonary&#xD;
             fibrosis diagnosed based on imaging or clinical findings.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bayer Clinical Trials Contact</last_name>
    <phone>(+)1-888-84 22937</phone>
    <email>clinical-trials-contact@bayer.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope National Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rocky Mountain Cancer Centers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center &amp; Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114-2696</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115-6013</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Henry Ford Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48202</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oncology Associates of Oregon</name>
      <address>
        <city>Eugene</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarah Cannon Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor Charles A. Sammons Cancer Center at Dallas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75246</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Erasme/Erasmus Ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bruxelles - Brussel</city>
        <zip>1070</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Antwerpen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edegem</city>
        <zip>2650</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU de Liège</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liege</city>
        <zip>4000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Bergonié - Unicancer Nouvelle Aquitaine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux Cedex</city>
        <zip>33076</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Léon Bérard</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon Cedex</city>
        <zip>69008</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital de la Pitié-Salpétrière</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75651</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut de Cancérologie de l'Ouest - Saint Herblain</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Herblain</city>
        <zip>44805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Claudius Regaud - iUCT Oncopole</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse Cedex 9</city>
        <zip>31059</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Gustave Roussy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif Cedex</city>
        <zip>94805</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AUSL di Bologna - IRCCS Istituto Scienze Neurologiche</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <state>Emilia-Romagna</state>
        <zip>40139</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Clinico Humanitas - Humanitas Mirasole S.p.A.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <state>Lombardia</state>
        <zip>20089</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione IRCCS Istituto Neurologico Carlo Besta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <state>Lombardia</state>
        <zip>20133</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ASST Grande Ospedale Metropolitano Niguarda</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <state>Lombardia</state>
        <zip>20162</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Oncologico Veneto IRCCS (IOV)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Padova</city>
        <state>Veneto</state>
        <zip>35128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aichi Cancer Center Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nagoya</city>
        <state>Aichi</state>
        <zip>464-8681</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kobe University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kobe</city>
        <state>Hyogo</state>
        <zip>650-0017</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tohoku University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sendai</city>
        <state>Miyagi</state>
        <zip>980-8574</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saitama Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kita-Adachigun</city>
        <state>Saitama</state>
        <zip>362-0806</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cancer Center Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chuo-ku</city>
        <state>Tokyo</state>
        <zip>104-0045</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Cancer Institute Hospital of JFCR</name>
      <address>
        <city>Koto-ku</city>
        <state>Tokyo</state>
        <zip>135-8550</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <state>Seoul Teugbyeolsi</state>
        <zip>03080</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Severance Hospital, Yonsei University Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>03722</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>China Medical University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung</city>
        <zip>40447</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chi-Mei Medical Center, Liouyine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tainan</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taipei Veterans General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>11217</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Marsden NHS Trust (Surrey)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <zip>SM2 5PT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospitals Coventry and Warwickshire NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Coventry</city>
        <state>West Midlands</state>
        <zip>CV2 2DX</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beatson West of Scotland Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <zip>G12 0YN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Marsden Hospital (London)</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SW3 6JJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Japan</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pancreatic Ductal Adenocarcinoma (PDAC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma (HNSCC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Esophageal Squamous Cell Carcinoma (ESSC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM)</keyword>
  <keyword>Anaplastic Astrocytoma (AA)</keyword>
  <keyword>Biliary Tract Carcinoma (BTC)</keyword>
  <keyword>PD-1 inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>nivolumab</keyword>
  <keyword>regorafenib</keyword>
  <keyword>multi-kinase inhibitor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Availability of this study's data will be determined according to Bayer's commitment to the EFPIA/PhRMA &quot;Principles for responsible clinical trial data sharing&quot;. This pertains to scope, timepoint and process of data access. As such, Bayer commits to sharing upon request from qualified researchers patient-level clinical trial data, study-level clinical trial data, and protocols from clinical trials in patients for medicines and indications approved in the US and EU as necessary for conducting legitimate research. This applies to data on new medicines and indications that have been approved by the EU and US regulatory agencies on or after January 01, 2014. Interested researchers can use www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com to request access to anonymized patient-level data and supporting documents from clinical studies to conduct research. Information on the Bayer criteria for listing studies and other relevant information is provided in the Study sponsors section of the portal.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

