<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04705571</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DO609885A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04705571</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Evaluation of Fractional Bi-Polar RF for Symptoms of SUI and Vulvovaginal Atrophy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Evaluation of Fractional Bi-Polar Radio-Frequency for Symptoms of Stress Urinary Incontinence and Vulvovaginal Atrophy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>InMode MD Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>InMode MD Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Clinical Evaluation of Fractional Bi-Polar Radio-Frequency for Symptoms of Stress Urinary&#xD;
      Incontinence and Vulvovaginal Atrophy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this trial is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of the MorpheusV&#xD;
      Applicator for Symptoms of Stress Urinary Incontinence and Vulvovaginal Atrophy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Eligible subjects will receive 1 treatment with the MorpheusV Applicator according to the study protocol.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>An objective change as measured by standardized cough stress test</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>An objective change as measured by standardized cough stress test performed in standing position before treatment and at 6 months (6M FU) after the treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>An objective evaluation of vaginal atrophy/estrogenization</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, month 6</time_frame>
    <description>An objective evaluation of vaginal atrophy/estrogenization measured by the globally validated &quot;Vaginal Health Index&quot; (VHI) score at 6M FU compared to Baseline.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms and quality of life by means of the Incontinence Quality of Life (IQOL) Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, month 6</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms and quality of life by means of the Incontinence Quality of Life (IQOL) Questionnaire. Administered at baseline and at 6M FU.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms by means of Urogenital Distress Inventory 6 Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>day 0, month 6</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms by means of Urogenital Distress Inventory 6 Questionnaire. Administered at baseline and at 6M FU.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms by means of Bladder voiding diary after the treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, month 6</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms by means of Bladder voiding diary after the treatment, and at 6M FU versus baseline.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms by means of Medical, Epidemiologic, and Social Aspects of Aging Urinary Incontinence (MESA) Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, month 6</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the treatment on urinary symptoms by means of Medical, Epidemiologic, and Social Aspects of Aging Urinary Incontinence (MESA) Questionnaire at 6M FU versus baseline.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of histological changes to vaginal canal tissue</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0, month 3</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of histological changes to vaginal canal tissue taken immediately post treatment and at 3M FU versus baseline. (for 5 subjects)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of expected post treatment immediate response</measure>
    <time_frame>day 0, through study completion, on average 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of expected post treatment immediate response including erythema and edema and during all study period based on predefined scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Discomfort scale</measure>
    <time_frame>day 0</time_frame>
    <description>A 10cm visual analog scale from 0 (no discomfort) to 10 (worst possible discomfort) to measure discomfort associated with probe insertion, and RF energy application</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number, severity and type of any adverse event recorded throughout the course of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Stress Urinary Incontinence</condition>
  <condition>Vulvovaginal Signs and Symptoms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MorpheusV Applicator (active)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MorpheusV Applicator</intervention_name>
    <description>1 treatment with the MorpheusV Applicator</description>
    <arm_group_label>MorpheusV Applicator (active)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female subjects, 35 and 75 years of age at the time of enrolment with primary and&#xD;
                  moderate to severe symptoms of SUI, who had scored at least 6 out of 12 according&#xD;
                  to severity index developed by Sandvik&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  She has produced a leak during the bladder &quot;cough&quot; stress test.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  18 out of 27 for the Stress Incontinence Questions and were confirmed as having&#xD;
                  predominant SUI on the Medical, Epidemiologic, and Social Aspects of Aging&#xD;
                  Urinary Incontinence (MESA) Questionnaire completed at the screening assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  General good health confirmed by medical history and skin examination of the&#xD;
                  treated area.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The patients should be willing to comply with the study procedure and schedule,&#xD;
                  including the follow up visit, and will refrain from using any other aesthetic&#xD;
                  treatment methods for the last 6 months and during the entire study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  - Pacemaker or internal defibrillator, or any other active electrical implant anywhere&#xD;
             in the body.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent implant in the treated area such as metal plates and screws, silicone&#xD;
             implants or an injected chemical substance, unless deep enough in the periostal plane.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or history of cancer, or premalignant condition in the treatment area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe concurrent conditions, such as cardiac disorders, epilepsy, uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension, and liver or kidney diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy and nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired immune system due to immunosuppressive diseases such as AIDS and HIV, or use&#xD;
             of immunosuppressive medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of diseases stimulated by heat, such as recurrent Herpes Simplex&#xD;
             in the treatment area, may be treated only following a prophylactic regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poorly controlled endocrine disorders, such as diabetes or thyroid dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active condition in the treatment area, such as sores, psoriasis, eczema, and&#xD;
             rash.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of skin disorders, keloids, abnormal wound healing, as well as very dry and&#xD;
             fragile skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bleeding coagulopathies or use of anticoagulants in the last 10 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any surgery in treated area within 3 months prior to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Simultaneous participation in another investigator drug or device study or completion&#xD;
             of the follow-up phase for the primary endpoint of any previous study less than 30&#xD;
             days prior to the first evaluation in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Six months delay is required if other recent treatments like light, CO2 laser or RF&#xD;
             were performed on the same area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Isotretinoin (Accutane®) within 6 months prior to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  As per the practitioner's discretion, refrain from treating any condition that might&#xD;
             make it unsafe for the patient&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tracy Blusewicz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Advanced Women's Care of the Lowcountry, PC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maria Shusterman</last_name>
    <phone>905-707-6787</phone>
    <email>maria.shusterman@inmodemd.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Leon Grach</last_name>
    <phone>905-707-6787</phone>
    <email>Leon.Grach@inmodemd.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Advanced Women's Care of the Lowcountry, PC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bluffton</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29910</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tracy Blusewicz, MD</last_name>
      <phone>843-341-3996</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Enuresis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence, Stress</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

