<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01861496</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LiPlaCis/P1/002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>SMR-3338</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01861496</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase I/II Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of LiPlaCis in Patients With Advanced or Refractory Tumours</brief_title>
  <acronym>LiPlaCis</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase I/II Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of LiPlaCis (Liposomal Cisplatin Formulation) in Patients With Advanced or Refractory Tumours</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Allarity Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Allarity Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Liposomal formulations are frequently used today in the treatment of cancer. LiPlaCis is the&#xD;
      first targeted liposomal formulation with a tumour triggered release mechanism to undergo&#xD;
      clinical development in oncology and it is expected that LiPlaCis will improve the&#xD;
      therapeutic index of cisplatin compared to conventional cisplatin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cisplatin is one of the most widely used drugs in the treatment of cancer due to its&#xD;
      documented efficacy in a number of tumour types. Furthermore, it seems highly likely that&#xD;
      cisplatin will remain an important drug in the future treatment of cancer. However, the drug&#xD;
      is associated with a number of serious toxicities that complicates or necessitates&#xD;
      discontinuation of therapy - e.g. need for pre-hydration, neurotoxicity, nausea and vomiting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, there is a well-established need for improving cisplatin therapy in cancer patients.&#xD;
      One option here is improving the formulation of the drug, so that a more selective up-take of&#xD;
      cisplatin administered takes place at the tumour sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the results of the pre-clinical studies of LiPlaCis, it seems clear that LiPlaCis&#xD;
      offers the potential to improve cisplatin therapy to the benefits of cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a prematurely stopped Phase I Dutch study a Recommended Dose (RD) for a Phase II study was&#xD;
      never reached which was the aim of the finished Phase I dose escalating part of this study&#xD;
      for advanced or refractory solid tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the Phase 2 part of this study, patients with advanced breast cancer with a biopsy&#xD;
      examination showing a pattern compatible with sensitivity to LiPlaCis or patients with skin&#xD;
      cancer will be included.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and recommended dose (RD) by evaluating the safety and tolerability</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
    <description>Primary Objective:&#xD;
Assessment of adverse events and laboratory abnormalities</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Observed Plasma Concentrations of platinum (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to the initial dose on day 1, day 8 and 15 and 5 min before end of infusion, 5 min, 0,5, 1, 3, 7, 24, 48, 72 hours post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples are obtained and plasma concentrations of total LiPlaCis-derived platinum are determined using a validated atomic absorption spectrometry method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of platinum (Pt-DNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to the initial dose on day 1and 24 hours after</time_frame>
    <description>Tumor and normal tissue biopsies are obtained concentrations of platinum are determined using a validated method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Plasma - Time Concentration Curve (AUC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to the initial dose on day 1, day 8 and 15 and 5 min before end of infusion, 5 min, 0,5, 1, 3, 7, 24, 48, 72 hours post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples are obtained and plasma concentrations of total LiPlaCis-derived platinum are determined using a validated atomic absorption spectrometry method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination half-life of platinum (T½)</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to the initial dose on day 1, day 8 and 15 and 5 min before end of infusion, 5 min, 0,5, 1, 3, 7, 24, 48, 72 hours post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples are obtained and plasma concentrations of total LiPlaCis-derived platinum are determined using a validated atomic absorption spectrometry method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total body clearance of platinum (Cl)</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to the initial dose on day 1, day 8 and 15 and 5 min before end of infusion, 5 min, 0,5, 1, 3, 7, 24, 48, 72 hours post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples are obtained and plasma concentrations of total LiPlaCis-derived platinum are determined using a validated atomic absorption spectrometry method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Volume of distribution of platinum at steady state (Vss)</measure>
    <time_frame>Prior to the initial dose on day 1, day 8 and 15 and 5 min before end of infusion, 5 min, 0,5, 1, 3, 7, 24, 48, 72 hours post dose</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples are obtained and plasma concentrations of total LiPlaCis-derived platinum are determined using a validated atomic absorption spectrometry method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Therapeutic efficacy of LiPlaCis (Efficacy Endpoint)</measure>
    <time_frame>Tumor Assessed every 6 weeks until and at end of treatment, with an expected average of 3 treatment cycles (9 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Response and progression is evaluated using internationally accepted response criteria and definitions proposed by the RECIST criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>one year after end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>PFS for patients at dose step 5 and up by Response and progression evaluated using internationally accepted response criteria and definitions proposed by the RECIST criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Phase 1: Advanced or Refractory Solid Tumours</condition>
  <condition>Phase 2 Part: Metastatic Breast Cancer, Prostate Cancer and Skin Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LiPlaCis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of LiPlaCis - a liposomal formulation of cisplatin will be administered intravenously in cycles every 3 weeks on day 1, day 8. Upon the investigator's judgement the patient may continue treatment for more than 3 cycles when benefiting from the study drug.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LiPlaCis</intervention_name>
    <description>LiPlaCis IV every 3 weeks on day 1, day 8</description>
    <arm_group_label>LiPlaCis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Liposomal formulation of Cisplatinum</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological or cytological documented locally advanced or metastatic solid tumour&#xD;
             relapsed on 2 or more different prior therapies. From step 5 and extension phase,&#xD;
             population limited to Skin Cancer patients (non screened) or metastatic Breast Cancer&#xD;
             patients or metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer patients screened&#xD;
             sensitive to LiPlaCis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;= 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy &gt;= 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status of 0 - 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recovered to Grade 1 or less from acute toxicities of prior treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;= 6 months must have elapsed since patient received cisplatin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;= 4 weeks must have elapsed since patient received any investigational medicinal&#xD;
             product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;= 4 weeks must have elapsed since patient received any radiotherapy(except for&#xD;
             palliative radiotherapy on non-target lesions), or treatment with cytotoxic or&#xD;
             biologic agents (&gt;=6 weeks for mitomycin or nitrosoureas). No hormonal treatment is&#xD;
             allowed except treatment with corticosteroids at physiological dose and hormonal&#xD;
             treatment with LHRH agonists for prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt;=2 weeks must have elapsed since any prior surgery or therapy with G-CSF and GM-CSF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate condition as evidenced by the following clinical laboratory values:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1,5 x 10E9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Haemoglobin is at least 4,6 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &gt;= 75 x 10E9/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) and aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt;= 2,5 x ULN,&#xD;
                  in case of known liver metastases ALT and AST &lt;= 5 x ULN. Patients who does not&#xD;
                  conform to the transaminase inclusion criteria, but who by the PI are considered&#xD;
                  in good PS and otherwise eligible for inclusion, and where the transaminase&#xD;
                  levels are considered elevated due to other reasons than deteriorated liver&#xD;
                  capacity, may be considered for inclusion based on conferred agreement between PI&#xD;
                  and Sponsor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum bilirubin &lt;= 1,5 ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase &lt;= 2,5 x ULN, in case of known liver metastases &lt;= 5 x ULN.&#xD;
                  Patients who does not conform to the Alkaline phosphatase inclusion criteria, but&#xD;
                  who by the PI are considered in good PS and otherwise eligible for inclusion, and&#xD;
                  where the Alkaline phosphatase levels are considered elevated due to other&#xD;
                  reasons than deteriorated liver capacity, may be considered for inclusion based&#xD;
                  on conferred agreement between PI and Sponsor&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Blood urea within normal limits, creatinine below upper normal limits and&#xD;
                  creatinine clearance within normal limits (&gt;= 60 mL/min Cr-EDTA clearance).In the&#xD;
                  case of hydronephrosis, renography must be considered prior to treatment with&#xD;
                  LiPlaCis. For signs of drainage obstacle, well-functioning renal excretion/effect&#xD;
                  and normal diuresis must be ensured, e.g. via a double-J catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males and females of child-producing potential, must use adequate&#xD;
             contraception (oral contraceptives, intrauterine device or barrier method of&#xD;
             contraception) for the study duration and at least six months afterwards.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must understand the investigational nature of this study and sign an&#xD;
             independent ethical committee (IEC) approved written informed consent form prior to&#xD;
             any study related activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active uncontrolled bleeding or bleeding diathesis (e.g., active peptic ulcer&#xD;
             disease).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active infection requiring parenteral or oral antibiotic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known infection with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or hepatitis virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing renal insufficiency. Please refer to inclusion criteria no. 10g.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active heart disease including myocardial infarction or congestive heart failure&#xD;
             within the previous 6 months, symptomatic coronary artery disease, or symptomatic&#xD;
             arrhythmias currently requiring medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected active central nervous system (CNS metastasis). (Patients stable 8&#xD;
             weeks after completion of treatment for CNS metastasis are eligible).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impending or symptomatic spinal cord compression or carcinomatous meningitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing neuropathy, i.e., Grade &gt;1 neuromotor or neurosensory toxicity (as&#xD;
             defined by National Cancer Institute Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI&#xD;
             CTCAE) v4,0), except for abnormalities due to cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to cisplatin or liposomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requiring immediate palliative treatment of any kind including surgery and/or&#xD;
             radiotherapy(except for palliative radiotherapy on non-target lesions).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant or breast-feeding (pregnancy test with a positive&#xD;
             result before study entry).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to follow protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous progression on a platinum containing therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ulrik Lassen, Professor MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rigshospitalet, Finsen Centre, Oncology Department, Phase 1 Unit</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dorte Nielsen, Professor MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Herlev&amp;Gentofte Hospital, Oncology Department</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Phase One Unit, The Finsen Centre, Rigshospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>DK-2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Herlev &amp; Gentofte Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Herlev</city>
        <zip>2730</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nordsjællands Hospital Hillerød</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hillerod</city>
        <zip>3400</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vejle Sygehus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vejle</city>
        <zip>7100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 1, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 21, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 23, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cisplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Liposomal formulation</keyword>
  <keyword>DRP (Drug Response Prediction)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Skin Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

