<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04935814</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CORVaso / RBHP 2021 GODET 2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04935814</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cardiac Output Response to Vasopressin Infusion In Abdominal Surgery Patients Under Mechanical Ventilation</brief_title>
  <acronym>CORVaso</acronym>
  <official_title>Cardiac Output Response to Vasopressin Infusion In Abdominal Surgery Patients Under Mechanical Ventilation: A Clinical Pharmacodynamics Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the investigators propose to explore the hemodynamic variations induced by&#xD;
      vasopressin and its influence on cardiac output, mean systemic pressure, and venous return&#xD;
      resistance measured through cardiopulmonary interactions, according to the approach proposed&#xD;
      by Guyton, in patients undergoing major abdominal surgeries.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Maintaining hemodynamic stability is one of the main objectives of the anesthesiologist or&#xD;
      the intensivist, either in the ICU or the OR. This consists of optimizing cardiac output to&#xD;
      ensure satisfactory systemic perfusion during the peri-operative period or the ICU stay. The&#xD;
      occurrence of oxygen debt (mismatch between oxygen consumption and transport) and/or tissue&#xD;
      hypoperfusion are key factors in the development of organ failure. Numerous studies have&#xD;
      shown in recent years that individualized hemodynamic optimization (cardiac output and organ&#xD;
      perfusion pressure) reduces the risk of postoperative and ICU morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring of cardiac output and stroke volume is a valuable and essential aid in determining&#xD;
      the therapies to be used for this optimization, whether it involves volume expansion or the&#xD;
      use of a vasopressor or even inotropic agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several vasopressor therapies have been available to date. Norepinephrine is currently the&#xD;
      reference in the treatment of vasoplegic shock states, but also in the operating room during&#xD;
      major surgery or in fragile patients. Other molecules are currently available and are used in&#xD;
      a disparate manner, according to the habits of each practitioner, sometimes outside&#xD;
      regulatory rules, not following international recommendations concerning the pathology in&#xD;
      question: adrenaline, dopamine, phenylephrine, terlipressin...&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vasopressin (D-arginine-D-vasopressin) is an endogenous hormone synthesized by the&#xD;
      hypothalamus (peptide composed of 9 amino acids) which has an antidiuretic renal action&#xD;
      through its V2 receptor but also a vasoconstriction activity through its V1a receptor, at the&#xD;
      level of the smooth muscles of the vascular wall. It also participates in the stimulation of&#xD;
      catecholamine secretion by the adrenal medulla. Vasopressin is commercially available under&#xD;
      the name &quot;argipressin&quot;. It is currently indicated as an adjunct to other vasopressors such as&#xD;
      norepinephrine in refractory septic shock to maintain satisfactory hemodynamic stability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, its vasoconstrictive and hemodynamic effects, including its influence on cardiac&#xD;
      output, have never been studied to date and to the knowledge of investigators. In particular,&#xD;
      there are no studies showing the influence of this molecule on mean systemic pressure and&#xD;
      venous return resistance, which are fundamental determinants of its impact on left heart&#xD;
      function and thus on cardiac output.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, the investigators propose to explore the hemodynamic variations induced by&#xD;
      vasopressin and its influence on cardiac output, mean systemic pressure, and venous return&#xD;
      resistance measured through cardiopulmonary interactions, according to the approach proposed&#xD;
      by Guyton.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 10, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>CORVaso is a pharmacological trial which aims to determine the variations of cardiac output during vasopressin infusion in major abdominal surgery patients.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Patients are under general anesthesia and outcomes assessor (statistician) will be blinded of patients positions orders.&#xD;
Sequential positions of patients will be randomized.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Variation of cardiac output after an infusion of vasopressin at different levels of cardiac preload</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes after position change</time_frame>
    <description>Using a thermodilution method, cardiac output will be measured and recorded at different levels of cardiac preload obtained by changing patient's position (Trendelenburg, anti-Trendelenburg and supine position).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Variation of mean systemic filling pressure and venous return after an infusion of vasopressin at different levels of cardiac preload</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes after position change</time_frame>
    <description>Mean systemic filling pressure will be determined by plotting the venous return curve using the cardiopulmonary interaction described by Guyton, by changing patient's position (Trendelenburg, anti-Trendelenburg and supine position).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Variation of central venous pressure after an infusion of vasopressin at different levels of cardiac preload</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes after position change</time_frame>
    <description>Using a central venous catheter, the central venous pressure will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Abdominal Surgery</condition>
  <condition>General Anesthesia</condition>
  <condition>Mechanical Ventilation</condition>
  <condition>Vasopressin Infusion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous vasopressin infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After general anesthesia, patients will receive a continuous infusion of vasopressin in order to improve mean arterial pressure by 20 mmHg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vasopressin, Arginine</intervention_name>
    <description>Once vasopressin infusion started, patients positions will be randomized: Trendelenburg (-30°), anti Trendelenburg (+30°) and supine position (0°).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous vasopressin infusion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults above 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned for a major abdominal surgery under general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of a central venous and arterial lines allowing transpulmonary thermodilution&#xD;
             cardiac output measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's consent with a social insurance&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not consent to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of heart attack, arteriopathy or aneurysm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to use transpulmonary thermodilution to measure cardiac output :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cardiac arrythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of pace-maker or defibrillator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe valvulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (according to Berlin criteria)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of arterial hypertension (treated or not)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of seizure, chronic headache, asthma or heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF) &lt; 45% or right ventricular dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pulmonary lobectomy or surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of restrictive or obstructive pulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body Mass Index (BMI) &lt; 15 or &gt; 40 kg/m²&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to vasopressin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under protection of justice (guardianship, curators...)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas Godet</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Clermont-Ferrand</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lise Laclautre</last_name>
    <phone>+33 4 73 754963</phone>
    <email>promo_interne_drci@chu-clermontferrand.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clermont-Ferrand</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Thomas Godet</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Vasopressin</keyword>
  <keyword>Argipressin</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiac Output</keyword>
  <keyword>General Anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>Mechanical Ventilation</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vasopressins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arginine Vasopressin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

