<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04939181</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NESABarça</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04939181</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Non-invasive Neuromodulation NESA in Neuroefficiency in Basketball Players</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Non-invasive Neuromodulation NESA in Neuroefficiency in Basketball Players on the Field</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Competitive team sports calendars are becoming increasingly compressed, generating changes in&#xD;
      the effort-recovery cycle. Given this new situation, it seems necessary to analyze how it&#xD;
      affects the physiological and performance level of semi-professional players, as well as how&#xD;
      to observe if the non-invasive neuromodulation technique NESA helps the neuroefficiency and&#xD;
      concentration values of said players.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The design of this study is a randomised, triple blind clinical trial with placebo control.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The general configuration of the study consists of capturing the second basketball team of FC&#xD;
      BARCELONA. For this, a double-blind capture system will be available (neither the specialist&#xD;
      nor those responsible for recovery will know which patients are entering the complementary&#xD;
      treatment) and two NESA XSIGNAL® devices operating in double-blind (due to the imperceptivity&#xD;
      of the stimulation performed, there will be a placebo machine and another that applies the&#xD;
      treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study, the results obtained between the different groups of patients will&#xD;
      be able to be compared; those additionally treated with a device, those treated with a&#xD;
      placebo device and those in the standard rehabilitation procedure without a device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The variables of the study will be collected at three time points: before the intervention,&#xD;
      during the intervention and at the end of the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The statistical analysis will be an intention-to-treat analysis. For the main outcomes&#xD;
      variables a two factor ANOVA will-be performed (intervention-time) with a post-hoc analysis&#xD;
      with kruskal wallis correction correction. Statistical significance will be defined as p&#xD;
      &lt;0.05&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 18, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in creatinine kinase level</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours before the first match, immediately after the match and 48 hours after the match</time_frame>
    <description>For the analysis of these biomarkers, a saliva sample, collected with Salivette containers will be necessary. Once the sample is obtained, it will be kept following the necessary security protocols and sent to a laboratory for further analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kinematic demand parameters (external load) I</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Total distance traveled (meters minute)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kinematic demand parameters (external load) II</measure>
    <time_frame>During the match and all the intervention ( 6 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Player Load (vector magnitude expressed as the square root of the sum of the squared instantaneous rates of change in acceleration in each of the 3 planes divided by 100) in arbitrary units (&gt;0.02 AU; m·min-1)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kinematic demand parameters (external load) III</measure>
    <time_frame>During all the intervention ( 6 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>High-speed running absolute (HSR distance covered above 18 km·h -1; m·min-1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Kinematic demand parameters (external load) IV</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Relative high-speed running (RHSR, distance covered above 85% of individual maximum speed recorded in training sessions or matches; m·min-1)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular parameters: heart rate variability (VHR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It is proposed to observe the changes or adaptations presented by the player once the sporting activity has ceased, by quantifying the modulation between the sympathetic and parasympathetic systems</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceptual parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>A Wellness questionnaire consisting of four questions on the level of fatigue, stress, sleep and muscle pain before the game. Each question is scored individually with scores ranging from 1 (&quot;Very, very low or good&quot;) to 7 (&quot;Very, very high or bad&quot;). The higher the score, the worse the results. The largest value would be 49, while the smallest would be 4</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceptual parameters II</measure>
    <time_frame>During all the intervention. Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Perception of Effort questionnaire to value perceived by the athlete will be recorded during the days of the intervention.also known as the Borg scale of perceived exertion measures the entire range of exertion that the individual perceives when exercising. The instrument consists of a table with numbers between 20 and 6, placed vertically and accompanied by qualitative evaluations between very, very strong and very, very light.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Basketball free throw efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Variable analyzed by counting the number of free throws taken and the number of shots that enter the ring. To measure this type of throw during training, a protocolized Task will be carried out where each player shoots between 4 and 6 free throws (in series of 2) each training in a pressure context.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Basketball Player</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-invasive Neuromodulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention with microcurrents: application of 6 electrodes per extremity and an adhesive electrode at C7 level.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Non-invasive Neuromodulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo microcurrents Intervention with microcurrents: application of 6 electrodes per extremity and an adhesive electrode at C7 level.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-invasive Neuromodulation</intervention_name>
    <description>The electrodes will be placed with the help of gloves and adapted socks for 1 hour, twice a week, until 10 intervention sessions are completed. In addition, depending on the session, an adhesive electrode will be placed at the level of C7. Characteristics of microcurrents:&#xD;
pulsed monophasic rectangular wave with a pulse of 1.3 s and pause of 300 ms, voltage 3 mV and intensity 0.5 μA.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Non-invasive Neuromodulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Non-invasive Neuromodulation</intervention_name>
    <description>The same protocol described for the experimental group will be applied, but microcurrents device which will be previously manipulated and tested with an oscilloscope so that they do not emit electrical currents.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Non-invasive Neuromodulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Belonging to the team&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants do not present injury or pathology during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In normal conditions and mentally competent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In condition to complete the study questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present some of the contraindications for a treatment with non-invasive&#xD;
             neuromodulation: pacemakers, internal bleeding, do not apply electrodes on skin in&#xD;
             poor condition, with ulcerations or wounds, acute febrile processes, acute&#xD;
             thrombophlebitis and / or electricity phobia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not having signed the informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present any injury or pathology during the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>A men's basketball team will be evaluated</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>24 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aníbal Báez-Suárez, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aníbal Báez-Suárez, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+34 652077692</phone>
    <email>anibal.baez@ulpgc.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Aníbal Báez-Suárez, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+34652077692</phone>
    <email>anibal.baez@ulpgc.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aníbal Báez-Suárez</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</city>
        <state>Las Palmas</state>
        <zip>35016</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aníbal Báez-Suárez, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+34652077692</phone>
      <email>anibal.baez@ulpgc.es</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Impellizzeri FM, Marcora SM, Coutts AJ. Internal and External Training Load: 15 Years On. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2019 Feb 1;14(2):270-273. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2018-0935. Epub 2019 Jan 6.</citation>
    <PMID>30614348</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vanrenterghem J, Nedergaard NJ, Robinson MA, Drust B. Training Load Monitoring in Team Sports: A Novel Framework Separating Physiological and Biomechanical Load-Adaptation Pathways. Sports Med. 2017 Nov;47(11):2135-2142. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0714-2.</citation>
    <PMID>28283992</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kellmann M, Bertollo M, Bosquet L, Brink M, Coutts AJ, Duffield R, Erlacher D, Halson SL, Hecksteden A, Heidari J, Kallus KW, Meeusen R, Mujika I, Robazza C, Skorski S, Venter R, Beckmann J. Recovery and Performance in Sport: Consensus Statement. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2018 Feb 1;13(2):240-245. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2017-0759. Epub 2018 Feb 19.</citation>
    <PMID>29345524</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bragazzi NL, Khoramipour K, Chaouachi A, Chamari K. Toward Sportomics: Shifting From Sport Genomics to Sport Postgenomics and Metabolomics Specialties. Promises, Challenges, and Future Perspectives. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2020 Sep 22. pii: ijspp.2020-0648. doi: 10.1123/ijspp.2020-0648. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32963119</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Fernández D, Varo F, Carmona G, Reche X. Quantification of external load of elite rink hockey players in official matches. J Sports Med Phys Fitness. 2020 Dec;60(12):1520-1525. doi: 10.23736/S0022-4707.20.11097-1. Epub 2020 Jun 30.</citation>
    <PMID>32608935</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Torreño N, Munguía-Izquierdo D, Coutts A, de Villarreal ES, Asian-Clemente J, Suarez-Arrones L. Relationship Between External and Internal Loads of Professional Soccer Players During Full Matches in Official Games Using Global Positioning Systems and Heart-Rate Technology. Int J Sports Physiol Perform. 2016 Oct;11(7):940-946. Epub 2016 Aug 24.</citation>
    <PMID>26816391</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rabbani A, Clemente FM, Kargarfard M, Chamari K. Match Fatigue Time-Course Assessment Over Four Days: Usefulness of the Hooper Index and Heart Rate Variability in Professional Soccer Players. Front Physiol. 2019 Feb 19;10:109. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2019.00109. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>30837890</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dong JG. The role of heart rate variability in sports physiology. Exp Ther Med. 2016 May;11(5):1531-1536. Epub 2016 Feb 23.</citation>
    <PMID>27168768</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ravé G, Zouhal H, Boullosa D, Doyle-Baker PK, Saeidi A, Abderrahman AB, Fortrat JO. Heart Rate Variability is Correlated with Perceived Physical Fitness in Elite Soccer Players. J Hum Kinet. 2020 Mar 31;72:141-150. doi: 10.2478/hukin-2019-0103. eCollection 2020 Mar.</citation>
    <PMID>32269655</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Castro-Sepulveda M, Cancino J, Fernández-Verdejo R, Pérez-Luco C, Jannas-Vela S, Ramirez-Campillo R, Del Coso J, Zbinden-Foncea H. Basal Serum Cortisol and Testosterone/Cortisol Ratio Are Related to Rate of Na+ Lost During Exercise in Elite Soccer Players. Int J Sport Nutr Exerc Metab. 2019 Nov 1;29(6):658-663. doi: 10.1123/ijsnem.2019-0129.</citation>
    <PMID>31629352</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aníbal Báez Suárez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>physical therapy modality</keyword>
  <keyword>Electric Stimulation Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>basketball</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

