<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04931355</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00006761-M2020443</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04931355</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acupuncture in the Freeze-all IVF Cycle</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Controlled Study on the Short-term Intervention of Acupuncture in the Freeze-all IVF Cycle to Improve Pregnancy Rate</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Peking University Third Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Peking University Third Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the early stage, our team found that Acupuncture intervention in freeze-all IVF cycles can&#xD;
      improve the clinical pregnancy rate. In order to further study the role of Acupuncture in&#xD;
      improving the pregnancy outcome of IVF-ET in infertility. A randomized controlled clinical&#xD;
      trial will be used in this study. 90 infertile patients are randomly divided into two groups.&#xD;
      The control group will be treated with conventional modern medicine, and the treatment group&#xD;
      will be treated with Acupuncture on the basis of conventional modern medicine. The&#xD;
      intervention starts from the 5th day of the menstrual cycle and lasts to the day before&#xD;
      IVF-ET. The number of oocytes, antral follicles, AMH, serum FSH, and clinical pregnancy rate&#xD;
      will be observed to evaluate the effect of Acupuncture on the improvement of pregnancy&#xD;
      outcome. In addition, all of the participants will be asked to complete the self-evaluation&#xD;
      of the anxiety/depression scale on the 7th day of the menstrual cycle, before and after&#xD;
      transplantation, to analyze the emotional changes of the subjects during the study. We&#xD;
      observe the safety and health economic indicators of Acupuncture treatment, so as to improve&#xD;
      the overall efficacy of TCM Combined Application in assisted reproductive technology in the&#xD;
      future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study will be conducted on patients with DOR attending our reproductive medicine center&#xD;
      for proposed IVF-ET between June 2021and December 2022.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial is designed as a randomized, controlled clinical trial with two groups established&#xD;
      by 1:1 equal allocation, a treatment group with interventions using acupuncture to tonify the&#xD;
      kidneys and regulate blood and a control group treated using conventional Western medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Random numbers will be prepared by an independent third-party statistician who prepared a&#xD;
      list of random group codes for this study. Enrolled subjects will be given a subject number&#xD;
      during the screening process and, upon formal enrolment, will be randomly assigned to either&#xD;
      the test or control group with a corresponding random number.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The acupoints used will be:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Zhongwan (RN12) ：The needle should be punctured for 1-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qihai(RN6): The needle should be punctured for 1-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Guanyuan(RN4): The needle should be punctured for 0.8-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Zhongji(RN3): The needle should be punctured for 0.8-1.0 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Guilai(ST29): The needle should be punctured for 0.8-1.0 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Shenshu(BL23): The needle should be punctured for 0.8-1.0 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ciliao(BL28): The needle should be punctured for 1-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Xuehai(SP10): The needle should be punctured for 1-1.5 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Zusanli(ST36): The needle should be punctured for 1-1.5 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diji(SP8): The needle should be punctured for 1-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sanyinjiao(SP6): The needle should be punctured for 1-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Taixi(KI6): The needle should be punctured for 0.8-1.2 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baihui(DU20): The needle should be punctured for 0.5-1.0 inches and retained for 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Yintang(EX-HN3): The needle should be punctured for 0.5-1.0 inches and retained for 30&#xD;
      minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Acupuncture intervention will start on the 5th day of the menstruation cycle, which will&#xD;
      be carried out 1 time per day,at least 5 times a week, lasts for 10-15days. All operations&#xD;
      were performed by experienced acupuncturists. After ET, both the control group and the&#xD;
      treatment group will be treated with conventionally with no TCM intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Serum human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) will be measured, and an hCG&gt;30 IU will be&#xD;
      considered to indicate biochemical pregnancy. Ultrasound monitoring will be performed 30 days&#xD;
      after ET to calculate the clinical pregnancy rate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical pregnancy rate (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks from enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Follow up by telephone calls 14days after the IVF-ET</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Concentration of β-human Choriogonadotropin(β-HCG)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 weeks from enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Obtained by blood sampling 14 days after the proposed IVF-ET</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from Baseline concentration of Self rating Anxiety Scale (SAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The 5th day of menstruation、 Baseline the proposed IVF-ET、14 days after the IVF-ET</time_frame>
    <description>They were completed on the 5th day of menstruation, before transplantation and the 14th day after transplantation.The score of 20 items is added to get the rough score (x), and after the formula is converted, that is, the whole part is taken after multiplying the rough score by 1.25, and then the standard score (y) will be obtained.According to the results of Chinese norm, the cut-off value of SAS standard deviation was 50 points, of which 50-59 points were mild anxiety, 60-69 points were moderate anxiety, and more than 69 points were severe anxiety.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes from Baseline concentration of Self rating Depression Scale (SDS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The 5th day of menstruation、 Baseline the proposed IVF-ET、14 days after the IVF-ET</time_frame>
    <description>They were completed on the 5th day of menstruation, before transplantation and the 14th day after transplantation.The normal upper limit of SDS gross score is 41, and the lower the score, the better the state. The standard is divided into the integral part of the total rough score multiplied by 1.25. In China, SDS score ≥ 50 is regarded as depressive symptom.Severity of depression = cumulative score of each item / 80. Results: no depression was found in patients below 0.5; 5-0. 59 for mild to mild depression; 6-0. 69, moderate to severe; More than 0.7 was severe depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Acupuncture</condition>
  <condition>Female Infertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Method: Acupuncture at Zhongwan、Qihai、Guanyuan、Zhongji、Guilai、Shenshu、Ciliao、Xuehai、Sanyinjiao、Taixi. The acupuncture treatment starts on the 5th day of the menstrual cycle and lasts to the days before IVF-ET</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Western medicine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The western medicine group will be treated with conventional western medicine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acupuncture</intervention_name>
    <description>The Acupuncture intervention（Zhongwan、Qihai、Guanyuan、Zhongji、Guilai、Shenshu、Ciliao、Xuehai、Sanyinjiao、Taixi.） will start on the 5th day of menstruation cycle, which will be carried out 1 time per day, at least 5 times a week, lasts for 10-15days. All operations were performed by experienced acupuncturists. After ET, both the control group and the treatment group will be treated with conventionally with no TCM intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>conventional western medicine(Recombinant Human Follitropin Alfa for Injection、Fructose Injection、Tetyacycline Hydrochloride Capsules、Cetrorelix Acetate Powder for Injection )</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Western medicine</intervention_name>
    <description>Western medicine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Western medicine group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Meet the diagnostic criteria for infertility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Meet the criteria for identifying kidney deficiency in TCM.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who Planning to undergo IVF-ET for pregnancy in our center, Age ≤40 years and&#xD;
             ≥25 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous embryo transfer failure ≥ 2 times.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Menstrual cycle is basically normal, and normal ovulation has been monitored in the&#xD;
             past.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. There were more than 1 blastocyst /more than 2 high-quality embryos with more than 6&#xD;
             cells on day 3/more than 2 high-quality embryos with more than 4 cells on day 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Consent to participate in this clinical trial and sign an informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with endometritis, acute pelvic inflammatory disease, mycotic vaginitis,&#xD;
             bacterial vaginitis, adnexitis or other systemic infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. It has been confirmed that there are obvious and serious other organic lesions in the&#xD;
             reproductive organs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with allergic constitution&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Infertility caused by genetic factors&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with serious primary diseases such as cardio cerebrovascular, kidney, liver&#xD;
             and hematopoietic system and psychosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. A person who is unable to cooperate (such as a combination of neurological or mental&#xD;
             illness, or a reluctance to cooperate)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. The endometrial thickness on the day of hCG was less than 6 mm or the endometrial&#xD;
             morphology on the day of hCG was type C&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Those who did not agree to participate in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Acupuncture</keyword>
  <keyword>Traditional chinese medicine</keyword>
  <keyword>freeze-all IVF cycle</keyword>
  <keyword>Embryo Transfer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infertility, Female</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cetrorelix</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

