<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04935567</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PRECISE-21</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04935567</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PRediction of Vagal Nerve Stimulation EfficaCy In Drug-reSistant Epilepsy</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRECISE</acronym>
  <official_title>PRediction of Vagal Nerve Stimulation EfficaCy In Drug-reSistant Epilepsy: Prospective Study for Pre-implantation Prediction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Masaryk University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>St. Anne's University Hospital Brno, Czech Republic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospital, Motol</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Na Homolce Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Masaryk University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Vagal nerve stimulation (VNS) can be indicated in patients with drug-resistant epilepsy who&#xD;
      are not eligible for resective epilepsy surgery with responders rates about 50% (≥50% seizure&#xD;
      reduction). At the moment, there is not a widely-accepted possibility to predict VNS efficacy&#xD;
      in a given patient based on pre-implantation data, which can lead to unnecessary surgery and&#xD;
      improper allocation of financial resources. The principal aim of PRECISE (PRediction of vagal&#xD;
      nerve stimulation EfficaCcy In drug-reSistant Epilepsy) study is to verify the predictability&#xD;
      of VNS efficacy by analysis of pre-implantation routine EEG. The PRECISE relies on the&#xD;
      results of our previous work, which developed a statistical classifier for VNS response&#xD;
      (responders vs. non-responders) based on differences in EEG power spectra dynamics&#xD;
      (Pre-X-Stim). PRECISE is designed as a prospective multicentre study in which patients&#xD;
      indicated to VNS therapy will be recruited. Patients will be classified as predicted&#xD;
      responders vs. predicted non-responders using pre-implantation EEG analyses. After the first&#xD;
      and the second year of the study, the real-life outcome (responder vs. non-responder) will be&#xD;
      determined. The real-life outcome and predicted outcome will be compared in terms of&#xD;
      accuracy, specificity, and sensitivity. In the meantime, the patients will be managed&#xD;
      according to the best clinical practice to obtain the best therapeutical response.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The patients will be recruited within cooperating epilepsy centres. The recruitment limited&#xD;
      to cooperating centres will ensure the correct indication for VNS therapy and the adjustment&#xD;
      of VNS parameters according to the best medical practice, which are not part of the study&#xD;
      protocol itself, but are crucial for the study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The VNS will be indicated in a given patient based on a clinical decision as a standard of&#xD;
      patient´s therapy (i.e., the indication of VNS is not a part of the proposed project). The&#xD;
      patient will be informed about the study on a pre-implantation visit or by a phone call,&#xD;
      during which initial eligibility for the study will be determined, and study protocol and&#xD;
      design will be explained by research staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      G. Assessment 0 - pre-implantation assessment Assessment 0 includes screening for eligibility&#xD;
      criteria and obtaining baseline data on subjects participating in the study. After the&#xD;
      signature of informed consent, the patient will be given a unique code by which all data will&#xD;
      be labelled. The demographic information, health history, including psychiatric disease and&#xD;
      type of epilepsy, concomitant medication (AEDs and other drugs), and seizure frequency will&#xD;
      be collected. The seizure frequency will be analysed based on the patient diary. Standard EEG&#xD;
      will be recorded according to the protocol described below.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol for EEG recording The EEG will be recorded on the EEG recording system with a&#xD;
      sampling frequency of 250 Hz or higher, with electrodes placed on the scalp according to&#xD;
      10-20 system (electrodes names as follows: Fp1, Fp2, F7, F3, Fz, F4, F8, T3, C3, Cz, C4, T4,&#xD;
      T5, P3, Pz, P4, T6, O1, and O2). Different electrodes names are allowed, but their position&#xD;
      must correspond with the position of previously defined electrodes. Additional electrodes are&#xD;
      also allowed, but will not be evaluated within the study. EEGs with lower numbers or&#xD;
      different positions of electrodes are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The EEG is recorded in a supine position with eyes closed except for periods with eyes&#xD;
      opening. The recorded EEG will have a duration of 20 minutes or more and must contain defined&#xD;
      segments in the following order (Figure 1):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Segment 1 - Rest 1 - duration at least 2 min Segment 2 - Eyes opening/closing - duration at&#xD;
      least 10 s Segment 3 - Rest 2 - duration at least 10 s; immediately after eye closure Segment&#xD;
      4 - Photic stimulation - stimulation frequencies: 5 Hz (10 s) - 10 Hz (10 s) - 15 Hz (10s) -&#xD;
      20 Hz (10 s) - 25 Hz (10 s) - 30 Hz (10 s) - 25 Hz (5 s) - 20 Hz (5 s) - 15 Hz (5 s) - 10 Hz&#xD;
      (5 s) - 5 Hz (5 s); light intensity at least 0.7 Joule Segment 5 - Hyperventilation -&#xD;
      duration at least 4 min (2 minutes hyperventilation by nose + 2 minutes hyperventilation by&#xD;
      mouth) Segment 6 - Eyes opening/closing - duration at least 10 s Segment 7 - Rest 3 -&#xD;
      duration at least 10 s, immediately after eye closure Segment 8 - Rest 4 - duration at least&#xD;
      2 minutes The recorded EEG will be anonymized and labelled by a unique code previously&#xD;
      attributed to a patient. In the next step, the EEG will be sent for mathematical/statistical&#xD;
      processing. Based on this processing, the patients´ predicted response to VNS will be&#xD;
      determined in terms of predicted responders (seizure reduction ≥ 50%) vs. predicted&#xD;
      non-responders (seizure reduction &lt; 50%). Neither the patient nor the physician will be&#xD;
      informed about the classification results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up assessments - Assessments 1, 2 Two assessments are designed in patients´ follow-up:&#xD;
      Assessment 1 - 1 year after stimulation initialization and Assessment 2 - 2 years after&#xD;
      stimulation initialization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment 1, 2 The patients will be evaluated 1 and 2 years after stimulation&#xD;
      initialization. The patient will be asked about changes in health history, including&#xD;
      psychiatric disease, concomitant medication (AEDs and other drugs), VNS parameters setting,&#xD;
      and seizure frequency. The seizure frequency will be collected by reviewing patients 'diary.&#xD;
      The reported seizure frequency will be compared with pre-implantation seizure frequency, and&#xD;
      real-life response will be calculated in terms of real-life responders (seizure reduction ≥&#xD;
      50%) or real-life non-responder (seizure reduction &lt; 50%). If the patient does not tolerate&#xD;
      at least the minimal VNS setting (0.75 mA) because of serious adverse events, he/she will be&#xD;
      excluded from further analysis (the patient´s data will be reported separately).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The information collected in Assessment 1 and 2, including real-life response to VNS, will be&#xD;
      labelled by the patient´s unique code and will be sent to the coordinating centre, where it&#xD;
      will be compared with the patient´s predicted response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of Assessment 2, the patient will be asked if he/she is interested in the&#xD;
      predicted response to VNS. If yes, the study physician will contact the coordinating centre,&#xD;
      where the predicted response for a given patient will be conveyed. The patient will be&#xD;
      informed about the predicted response by a phone call or during a regular visit (not a part&#xD;
      of the study protocol, described below).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is concerned with the verification of the real-life validity of our statistic&#xD;
      classifier for the prediction of VNS response based on pre-implantation EEG. The patients&#xD;
      based on the pre-implantation EEG will be classified based on their predicted response as&#xD;
      predicted responders (≥50% seizure reduction) vs. predicted non-responders (&lt;50% seizure&#xD;
      reduction). In Assessment 1 a 2, respectively, the patients´ real-life response will be&#xD;
      determined: real-life responders (≥50% seizure reduction) vs. real-life non-responder (&lt; 50%&#xD;
      seizure-reduction). The predicted and real-life responses will be statistically compared in&#xD;
      terms of accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The individual patients´ groups (predicted responders vs. predicted non-responders, real-life&#xD;
      responders vs. real-life non-responders) will be compared based on their demographic data,&#xD;
      health history, AEDs, and VNS parameter. A suitable statistical test will be chosen&#xD;
      concerning the data´s characteristics (Pearson´s Chi-squared test for categorical variables,&#xD;
      Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney test for continuous variables).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>PRECISE is a prospective multicentre study for prediction VNS efficacy based on pre-implantation EEG data. The patients with drug-resistant epilepsy will undergo standard VNS implantation based on a clinical decision. Before implantation, the scalp EEG, according to the study protocol, will be recorded. The EEG will be mathematically processed, and the patient´s predicted outcome in terms of predicted responder vs. predicted non-responders will be statistically determined. The stimulation parameters and AEDs therapy will be modified according to the best clinical practice. The real-life outcome will be determined by percent seizure reduction. Subsequently, the real-life and predicted outcome will be compared in terms of accuracy, sensitivity, and specificity. The main goal is to validate Pre-X-Stim in a real-life prospective study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of statistic model for prediction of response to VNS therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of statistic model for prediction of response to VNS therapy in terms of responders and non-responders in drug-resistant epilepsy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The quantification of differences in EEG power spectra</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The quantification of differences in EEG power spectra (Relative Mean Power, %) between real-life responders and real-life non-responders to VNS therapy in drug-resistant epilepsy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prediction of patients' response to VNS therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Prediction of patients' response to VNS therapy in terms of responders (≥ 50% seizure reduction from baseline) and non-responders (&lt;50% seizure reduction from baseline)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Predicted responders</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients indicated VNS therapy as their standard for clinical care and are concerned about the prediction of VNS efficacy based on pre-implantation EEG, (≥50% seizure reduction).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Predicted non-responders</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients indicated VNS therapy as their standard for clinical care and are concerned about the prediction of VNS efficacy based on pre-implantation EEG, (&lt;50% seizure reduction).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Statistical model for the prediction of VNS efficacy</intervention_name>
    <description>statistical model for the prediction of VNS efficacy based on a mathematical and statistical analysis of scalp EEG data</description>
    <arm_group_label>Predicted non-responders</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Predicted responders</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>the verification of the real-life validity of the statistic classifier for prediction of VNS response based on pre-implantation EEG</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug-resistant epilepsy indicated to VNS based on clinical decision.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drug-resistant epilepsy is defined as a failure of adequate trials of two tolerated,&#xD;
             appropriately chosen, and used antiepileptic drug schedules (whether as monotherapy or&#xD;
             in combination) to achieve sustained seizure freedom (Kwan et al., 2010).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability to record 20 minutes of EEG with photic stimulation, hyperventilation,&#xD;
             and eye-opening/closing according to the pre-defined protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Availability of seizure diaries at least three months before VNS implantation OR&#xD;
             reliable information about seizure frequency at least three months before VNS&#xD;
             implantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The ability of a patient/family member/caregiver to record seizures precisely into&#xD;
             seizure diaries OR the ability of a patient/family member/caregiver to report seizures&#xD;
             precisely different ways.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In cases with very high seizure frequency (several seizures per day), it is acceptable&#xD;
             to report only the days without any seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The indication and planning of resection brain surgery as a treatment option for&#xD;
             drug-resistant epilepsy. If a patient clearly demonstrates his refusal of resection&#xD;
             surgery, he/she can be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of psychogenic non-epileptic seizures which cannot be reliably&#xD;
             distinguished from epileptic seizures by a patient/family member/caregiver.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of other condition which can resemble epileptic seizures which cannot be&#xD;
             reliably distinguished from epileptic seizures by a patient/family member/caregiver.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metabolic condition or other diseases, in which the increase of seizure frequency is&#xD;
             expectable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The inability of a patient to take regular visits which are required for VNS&#xD;
             parameters settings or the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy shorter than two years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Milan Brazdil, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital st. Anne´s Brno</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Milan Brazdil, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+420 543 182 684</phone>
    <email>milan.brazdil@fnusa.cz</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Irena Doležalová, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+420 543 182 654</phone>
    <email>irena.dolezalova@fnusa.cz</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital St. Anne´s Brno</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brno</city>
        <zip>654 91</zip>
        <country>Czechia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Milan Brazdil, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+420543182654</phone>
      <email>milan.brazdil@fnusa.cz</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Irena Doležalová, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+420543183324</phone>
      <email>irena.dolezalova@fnusa.cz</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Milan Brazdil, Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Irena Doležalová, Assoc. Prof.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Czechia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug-resistant epilepsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Vagal nerve stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Efficacy predictability</keyword>
  <keyword>Responders</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-responders</keyword>
  <keyword>EEG</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

