<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04939220</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB202101097</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04939220</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SGA for TEE: Safe Alternative to Deep Sedation for Patients With High-risk Cardiopulmonary Disease.</brief_title>
  <acronym>SGA-TEE</acronym>
  <official_title>Supraglottic Airway Use for Transesophageal Echocardiography: a Safe Alternative to Deep Sedation for Patients With High-risk Cardiopulmonary Disease. (SGA-TEE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Florida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Florida</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Increasingly, transesophageal echos (TEEs) are being done on high risk patients. A TEE is a&#xD;
      short procedure done with deep sedation, but poses an increased risk of apnea/ hypoxemia in&#xD;
      those with pulmonary disease. It is desirable to avoid intubation, which adds risk. Use of&#xD;
      supraglottic airway (SGA) may offer an alternative. The investigators hypothesize that TEEs&#xD;
      can be done successfully with an SGA in place. The investigators propose a prospective RCT to&#xD;
      compare TEE exams done with deep sedation to those done with an SGA.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Increasingly, non-operating room anesthesia (NORA) cases are being performed on patients with&#xD;
      high risk for needing advanced airway management, ie patients with morbid obesity, chronic&#xD;
      hypoxemic lung disease, obstructive sleep apnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Transesophageal echocardiography (TEE) exams are one example of this. While a TEE is&#xD;
      typically a short, diagnostic procedure done with deep sedation, deep sedation poses an&#xD;
      increased risk of hypoventilation and hypoxemia in patients with cardiopulmonary disease. It&#xD;
      is desirable to avoid endotracheal intubation for TEE exams, as the procedure is short and&#xD;
      can easily be done without muscle relaxation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover, securing the airway with an endotracheal tube (ETT) is not without significant&#xD;
      risk. The use of a supraglottic airway (SGA) may offer an alternative for patients receiving&#xD;
      a TEE who are high risk candidates for deep sedation with a natural airway.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesize that the TEE procedure can be done successfully, without&#xD;
      interruption, with an SGA in place. Our secondary hypothesis is that SGA use in high-risk&#xD;
      patients may be safer than deep sedation, as there may be less episodes of hypoventilation&#xD;
      and hypoxemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose a prospective randomized control trial to compare TEE exams done&#xD;
      with deep sedation (control group) to those done with SGA (intervention group). Our primary&#xD;
      outcome will be TEE study completion, and secondary outcomes will focus on the safety profile&#xD;
      of the two groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, randomized control trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Randomization to control group- deep sedation with propofol and natural airway or Experimental group-SGA Placement and maintenance with inhalational anesthetic or propofol.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of successfully completed TEE examinations with the assigned airway intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome is a binary data point (yes/no) defined as the success of using the assigned LMA or natural airway successfully for a TEE procedure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ease of Placement of LMA</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Defined by placement of LMA on first attempt, with good chest rise on positive pressure assisted ventilation, no audible leak on assisted ventilation with cuff pressure &lt;32 cm H2O, and sustained, square waveform capnography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alternative Airway device</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>this secondary outcome is a binary data point (yes/no) on the use of an endotracheal tube for rescue from failure of assigned airway type for the procedure (LMA vs natural airway with sedation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dislocation of LMA</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>this secondary outcome is a binary data point (yes/no) for any form of dislocation of the LMA during the endoscopic procedure necessitating repositioning of the LMA.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chin Lift or Jaw Thrust</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Procedure</time_frame>
    <description>this secondary outcome is a binary data point (yes/no) for the need to perform chin lift or jaw thrust to maintain a patent airway.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharyngeal Bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Procedure</time_frame>
    <description>the incidence of pharyngeal bleeding during placement or after the procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypoxia</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Hypoxia during the procedure will be defined as an oxygen saturation (SpO2) &lt;92% for more than 5 minutes.&#xD;
Regurgitation defined by visualized gastric contents requiring suctioning Aspiration defined by desaturation after regurgitation with suspicion of the anesthesiologist or CRNA that aspiration occurred.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aspiration</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Aspiration will be defined by desaturation (SpO2 &lt;92) after regurgitation and inhalation of the gastric contents.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of the endoscopic procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of Procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Insertion to removal of TEE probe</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sore throat</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of procedure up to 24 hours after the procedure ends.</time_frame>
    <description>As described on a numerical rating scale, and at time 0, 2, and 24 hours 0= no sore throat , 1= mild sore throat, 2= moderate sore throat, 3= severe sore throat</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ease and comfort of advancing and operating the Endoscope by attending endoscopist</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>The comfort of advancing and operating the endoscope rated by the attending endoscopist after the procedure via a 5 point Likert-type scale (0 = not at all satisfied, 1=slightly satisfied, 2=moderately satisfied, 3=very satisfied, 4 = completely satisfied).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiopulmonary Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Deep sedation with propofol and natural airway</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SGA Placement and maintenance with inhalational anesthetic or propofol</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TEE with SGA</intervention_name>
    <description>SGA Placement and maintenance with inhalational anesthetic or propofol</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TEE with Deep Sedation</intervention_name>
    <description>Deep sedation with propofol and natural airway</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults presenting for elective outpatient TEE examinations at UF Shands hospital&#xD;
             during the study duration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected difficult airway, patient refusal or inability to consent, patients&#xD;
             to have emergent or urgent TEE exams, patients considered to have full stomach ie&#xD;
             gastroparesis or achalasia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stefan Braunecker, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Florida</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Stefan Braunecker, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>904-244-5431</phone>
    <email>stefan.braunecker@jax.ufl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kelly N Flynn, MS</last_name>
    <phone>904-244-4378</phone>
    <email>kelly.flynn@jax.ufl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UF Health Jacksonville</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jacksonville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32209</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul D Mongan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kerri Lydon, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.sealedenvelope.com/power/binary-noninferior/</url>
    <description>Power calculator for binary outcome non-inferiority trial. Sealed Envelope Ltd. 2012. Power calculator for binary outcome non-inferiority trial. [Online] [Accessed Sat Apr 03 2021].</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chiew WA, Chen Q, Tan LZ. Use of LMAⓇ GastroTM in esophagogastroduodenoscopy and endoscopy. Korean J Anesthesiol. 2019 Dec;72(6):618-619. doi: 10.4097/kja.19163. Epub 2019 Jul 1.</citation>
    <PMID>31257818</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Terblanche NCS, Middleton C, Choi-Lundberg DL, Skinner M. Efficacy of a new dual channel laryngeal mask airway, the LMA(®)Gastro™ Airway, for upper gastrointestinal endoscopy: a prospective observational study. Br J Anaesth. 2018 Feb;120(2):353-360. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2017.11.075. Epub 2017 Dec 1.</citation>
    <PMID>29406183</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tran A, Thiruvenkatarajan V, Wahba M, Currie J, Rajbhoj A, van Wijk R, Teo E, Lorenzetti M, Ludbrook G. LMA® Gastro™ Airway for endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography: a retrospective observational analysis. BMC Anesthesiol. 2020 May 13;20(1):113. doi: 10.1186/s12871-020-01019-5.</citation>
    <PMID>32404136</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schmutz A, Loeffler T, Schmidt A, Goebel U. LMA Gastro™ airway is feasible during upper gastrointestinal interventional endoscopic procedures in high risk patients: a single-center observational study. BMC Anesthesiol. 2020 Feb 8;20(1):40. doi: 10.1186/s12871-020-0938-9.</citation>
    <PMID>32035477</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hakim M, Bryant J, Miketic R, Williams K, Erdman SH, Shafy SZ, Kim SS, Tobias JD. Clinical Outcomes of a Modified Laryngeal Mask Airway (LMA(®) Gastro™ Airway) During Esophagogastroduodenoscopy in Children and Adolescents: A Randomized Study. Med Devices (Auckl). 2020 Sep 21;13:277-282. doi: 10.2147/MDER.S272557. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>33061677</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Waruingi D, Mung'ayi V, Gisore E, Wanyonyi S. A randomised controlled trial of the effect of laryngeal mask airway manometry on postoperative sore throat in spontaneously breathing adult patients presenting for surgery at a university teaching hospital. Afr Health Sci. 2019 Mar;19(1):1705-1715. doi: 10.4314/ahs.v19i1.47.</citation>
    <PMID>31149001</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Seet E, Yousaf F, Gupta S, Subramanyam R, Wong DT, Chung F. Use of manometry for laryngeal mask airway reduces postoperative pharyngolaryngeal adverse events: a prospective, randomized trial. Anesthesiology. 2010 Mar;112(3):652-7. doi: 10.1097/ALN.0b013e3181cf4346.</citation>
    <PMID>20179502</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Balmforth D, Smith A, Nagore D, Schilling R, O'Brien B. Can Transesophageal Echocardiography Be Performed Safely Using a Laryngeal Mask Airway During Atrial Fibrillation Ablation? J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2018 Apr;32(2):790-795. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2017.10.040. Epub 2017 Nov 2.</citation>
    <PMID>29229253</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Salvi L, Pepi M. Pressure-assisted breathing through a laryngeal mask airway during transesophageal echocardiography. Anesth Analg. 1999 Dec;89(6):1591-2.</citation>
    <PMID>10589667</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferson D, Thakar D, Swafford J, Sinha A, Sapire K, Arens J. Use of deep intravenous sedation with propofol and the laryngeal mask airway during transesophageal echocardiography. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2003 Aug;17(4):443-6.</citation>
    <PMID>12968230</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Patrick Mayr N, Michel J, Wiesner G, Rumpf PM. Supraglottic airway device use for transoesophageal echocardiography during left atrial appendage occlusion. Anaesthesia. 2019 Mar;74(3):405-406. doi: 10.1111/anae.14597.</citation>
    <PMID>30734949</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saxena S, Aminian A, Nahrwold DA, Daper A. LMA Gastro Airway Seen Through the Eyes of a Cardiac Anesthesiologist. J Cardiothorac Vasc Anesth. 2019 Aug;33(8):2365-2366. doi: 10.1053/j.jvca.2019.04.014. Epub 2019 Apr 20.</citation>
    <PMID>31101507</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>TEE</keyword>
  <keyword>SGA</keyword>
  <keyword>Anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>sedation</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Hypoxemic lung Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Obstructive Sleep Apnea</keyword>
  <keyword>Morbid Obesity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Heart Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

