<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04933539</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210024</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>21-C-0024</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04933539</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Subcutaneous Daratumumab, Once Weekly Carfilzomib, and Dexamethasone (DKd) in Patients With High-Risk Smoldering Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Adaptive Study of Subcutaneous Daratumumab, Once Weekly Carfilzomib, and Dexamethasone (DKd) in Patients With High-Risk Smoldering Multiple Myeloma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multiple myeloma (MM) is a tumor in which malignant plasma cells accumulate in the bone&#xD;
      marrow. It can cause organ damage and is not curable. Researchers want to see if a&#xD;
      combination drug treatment can help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To try to prevent or slow down developing MM and its associated organ damage by treating it&#xD;
      while still in the smoldering phase with a mix of drugs known as DKd.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 18 and older with smoldering MM that is at high risk of converting to symptomatic&#xD;
      MM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical history&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bone survey (x-rays of their bones)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Spinal magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bone marrow biopsy (a needle is used to remove bone marrow from their hipbone)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electrocardiogram (to check heart function)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lung function tests&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment will be given in 28-day cycles. Participants will get daratumumab by injection&#xD;
      under the skin. They will get carfilzomib intravenously (IV) through a tube inserted in a&#xD;
      vein. They will get dexamethasone as oral tablets or as an IV. They will get all 3 drugs for&#xD;
      8 or 12 cycles. Then they will get daratumumab alone for up to 24 cycles. They may have stem&#xD;
      cells collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have frequent study visits. At these visits, they will repeat some&#xD;
      screening tests. They will complete questionnaires. They will have imaging scans. For these&#xD;
      scans, they may receive an oral or IV contrast.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a follow-up visit 30 days after treatment ends. Then they will have&#xD;
      visits every 3-12 months. They will be followed on this study for life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Smoldering multiple myeloma (SMM) is a precursor condition to MM defined by the clinical&#xD;
      parameters of M-protein &gt;=3.0 g/dL or bone marrow plasma cells &gt;=10%, and absence of end&#xD;
      organ disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with high-risk SMM have a risk of progression to MM of 72-75% in 5 years with median&#xD;
      time to progression of &lt;2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current standard of care for SMM is close follow-up without treatment, until symptomatic&#xD;
      MM develops. However, International Myeloma Working Group (IMWG) recommends Preventive&#xD;
      clinical trials need to be considered for patients with high risk smoldering myeloma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Carfilzomib is a proteasome inhibitor and daratumumab is an anti-CD38 monoclonal antibody,&#xD;
      both with potent anti-MM effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the remission rate of daratumumab, carfilzomib, and dexamethasone (DKd) in patients&#xD;
      with high-risk (HR) smoldering multiple myeloma (SMM) by determining the minimal residual&#xD;
      disease (MRD) negative complete response (CR) rate by up to 12 cycles of induction therapy&#xD;
      using flow cytometry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      SMM according to the IMWG definition; i.e.:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Serum M-protein &gt;=3 g/dl and/or bone marrow plasma cells &gt;=10 % and &lt;60%&#xD;
&#xD;
      Absence of anemia: Hemoglobin &gt;10 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
      Absence of renal failure: serum creatinine &lt;2.0 mg/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Absence of hypercalcemia: Ca &lt;10.5 mg/dl or 2.65 mmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
      Absence of lytic bone lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
      &lt;=1 focal lesion on MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
      Involved/un-involved light chain ratio &lt;100&#xD;
&#xD;
      High-risk SMM per Mayo Clinic, Spanish PETHEMA, or the Rajkumar, Landgren, Mateos criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age &gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adequate laboratory parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Single arm trial of combination therapy (daratumumab, carfilzomib, and dexamethasone)&#xD;
      followed by daratumumab maintenance monotherapy (DKd-D) for high-risk SMM&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will receive 8 cycles of DKd induction combination therapy. After 8 cycles,&#xD;
      participants who have not attained an MRD negative remission will receive 4 additional cycles&#xD;
      of DKd. Each cycle consists of 28-days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 4 cycles of induction therapy, transplant eligible participants may choose to undergo&#xD;
      stem cell collection for storage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After induction with DKd, participants will receive daratumumab maintenance therapy for 24&#xD;
      cycles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have routine blood work with SPEP and free light chains at the start of&#xD;
      each cycle during the induction phase. Laboratory evaluations may be spread out to every 3-6&#xD;
      months during the maintenance and follow-up phases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-treatment, post-treatment and follow-up bone marrow biopsies will be obtained for&#xD;
      confirmation of diagnosis, response and correlative studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will also undergo evaluation for MRD at regular interval time points, using&#xD;
      multi-parametric flow cytometry, FDG PET-CT, and Diffusion Weighted Whole Body (DW-MRI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The statistical analysis of the primary endpoint, MRD negativity, will be performed at the&#xD;
      end of induction therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 cycles</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the remission rate of DKd in participants with high-risk (HR) SMM by determining the minimal residual disease (MRD) negative complete response (CR) by flow cytometry (10-5 sensitivity) rate after 12 cycles of therapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6-8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The fraction of participants who experience a PR, VGPR, CR or sCR after DKd determined by dividing the number of responders by the total evaluable patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6-8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Time from PR or better until the time of PD. Kaplan-Meier will be utilized</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochemical and Symptomatic progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>every 6-8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Using Kaplan-Meier method, considering those who biochemically progress or die and those who clinically progress or die, and censoring those who do not</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Durability of MRD negative complete response (CR)</measure>
    <time_frame>through 3 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Sustained negative CR rate 1, 2, 3 years.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity evaluation of DKd</measure>
    <time_frame>through 30 days post treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Descriptive statistics to determine safety of receiving KRd with daratumumab maintenance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>Determined using the Kaplan-Meier method</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">59</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Daratumumab SC (Cycles 1-2: Days 1, 8, 15, 22; Cycles 3-6: Days 1, 15; Cycles =7: Days 1 of the 28-day cycle); Carfilzomib IV (Days 1, 8, 15 of the 28-day cycle); Dexamethasone PO/IV (Days 1, 8, 15, 22 of the 28-day cycle)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexamethasone PO/IV (for Cycles 1-4: Dexamethasone 40 mg IV/PO on days 1, 8, 15, 22; for Cycles =5: Dexamethasone 20 mg IV/PO on days 1, 8, 15, 22); for up to 12 cycles</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carfilzomib</intervention_name>
    <description>Carfilzomib IV (for Cycles 1-2: 20 mg/m2 IV on day 1, 56 mg/m2 IV on days 8, 15; Cycles =2: 56/m2 IV on days 1, 8, 15); for up to 12 cycles</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Daratumumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Daratumumab SC 1800 mg (Cycles 1-2: Days 1, 8, 15, 22; Cycles 3-6: Days 1, 15; Cycles =7: Days 1 of the 28-day cycle); up to 36 cycles total</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed smoldering multiple&#xD;
             myeloma (SMM) based on the International Myeloma Working Group Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum M-protein &gt;=3 g/dl and/or bone marrow plasma cells &gt;=10 % and &lt;60%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of anemia: hemoglobin &gt;10 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of renal failure: serum creatinine &lt;2.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of hypercalcemia: Ca &lt;10.5 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of lytic bone lesion on X-ray, CT, or PET/CT and not more than 1 lesion&#xD;
                  on spinal MRI (NOTE: At the discretion of the investigator, PET/CT may replace&#xD;
                  MRI in patients who have a contraindication to MRI.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Involved/un-involved light chain ratio must be &lt; 100 (unless involved light chain&#xD;
                  is &lt;=10 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease within the past 4 weeks defined by any one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum monoclonal protein &gt;= 0.5 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Urine monoclonal protein &gt;200 mg/24 hour&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum immunoglobulin free light chain &gt;10 mg/dL AND abnormal kappa/lambda serum&#xD;
                  free light chain ratio (reference 0.26-1.65)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Because the primary endpoint is MRD (-) remission rate, per the discretion of the&#xD;
                  Principal Investigator, patients without measurable disease in the serum (e.g.,&#xD;
                  Mspike &lt;0.5 g/dL) may also be enrolled. This is in line with the most recent IMWG&#xD;
                  MM response criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;=18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status &lt;=2 (Karnofsky &gt;=60%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;=1.0 K/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: At the discretion of the investigator, patients with an ANC of 0.5 K/uL -1.0 K/uL may&#xD;
        also be enrolled if clinically appropriate (e.g., patients with a baseline neutropenia that&#xD;
        is chronic and that does not cause complications).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  platelets &gt;=75 K/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hemoglobin &gt; =8 g/dL, for anemia not due to MM (transfusions are permissible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  total bilirubin = &lt;1.5 X institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT) =&lt;3.0 X institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  creatinine within normal institutional limits, OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If creatinine is outside of the normal limits, then creatinine Clearance (CrCl) or&#xD;
             Egfr (estimated glomerular filtration Rate) &gt;=40 ml/min calculated by Cockcroft-Gault&#xD;
             method, modification of diet in renal disease (MDRD), or the chronic kidney disease&#xD;
             (CKD)-epidemiology collaboration (EPI) (institutional standard) equations.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -In addition to having SMM, patients must also be classified as high-risk SMM per at&#xD;
             least one of three criteria below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria 1: Mayo Clinic, high-risk defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bone marrow plasmacytosis &gt;=10%,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum monoclonal protein &gt;=3 g/dL, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum free light chain ratio of &gt;=8 or &lt;=0.125&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria 2: Spanish PETHEMA, high-risk defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunoparesis (depression of one of the uninvolved immunoglobulin isotypes in the&#xD;
                  total serum immunoglobulin assay, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  &gt;=95% aberrant plasma cells on bone marrow aspirate flow cytometry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Criteria 3: Rajkumar, Landgren, Mateos may also be used to define high risk disease,&#xD;
             namely clonal bone marrow plasma cells &gt;=10% AND any one or more of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum M protein &gt;=30g/L,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  IgA SMM,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunoparesis with reduction of 2 uninvolved immunoglobulin isotypes,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum involved/uninvolved FLC ratio &gt;=8 (but &lt;100),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Progressive increase in M protein level (evolving type of SMM; increase in serum&#xD;
                  M protein by &gt;=25% on 2 successive evaluations within a 6-month period),&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clonal BMPCs 50%-60%,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Abnormal PC immunophenotype (&gt;=95% of BMPCs are clonal) and reduction of &gt;=1&#xD;
                  uninvolved immunoglobulin isotypes,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  t(4;14) or del(17p) or 1q gain,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Increased circulating PCs,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MRI with diffuse abnormalities or 1 focal lesion, AND/OR PET-CT with focal lesion&#xD;
                  with increased uptake without underlying osteolytic bone destruction&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  The effects of carfilzomib and daratumumab on the developing human fetus are&#xD;
                       unknown. For this reason, women of child-bearing potential (WOCBP) and men&#xD;
                       must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method of&#xD;
                       birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for 3 months after&#xD;
                       daratumumab and/or 6 months after the last dose of carfilzomib, whichever is&#xD;
                       longer. Males with female partners of reproductive potential must use&#xD;
                       adequate contraception during treatment and for 3 months after stopping&#xD;
                       daratumumab and/or carfilzomib. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect&#xD;
                       she is pregnant while she or her partner is participating in this study, she&#xD;
                       should inform her treating physician immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Negative serum or urine pregnancy test at screening for WOCBP.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Ability of subject to understand and the willingness to sign a written&#xD;
                       informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving any other investigational agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior therapy for SMM. At the discretion of the investigator, exceptions might be made&#xD;
             depending on prior treatments received and response to those treatments, provided that&#xD;
             by the start of protocol therapy, there will be a 4-week washout period. Exceptions&#xD;
             will not be made for patients who have received the current DKd with daratumumab&#xD;
             maintenance regimen nor any other regimen consisting of daratumumab and a proteasome&#xD;
             inhibitor (e.g., bortezomib, ixazomib). Treatment with corticosteroids for other&#xD;
             indications is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to any concomitant medication, including support/prophylaxis for&#xD;
             infusion reaction, antiviral, antibacterial, anticoagulation or tumor lysis given&#xD;
             prior to therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has either of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Known chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) with a forced expiratory volume&#xD;
             in 1 second (FEV1) &lt;50% of predicted normal. NOTE: FEV1 testing is required for&#xD;
             patients suspected of having COPD and subjects must be excluded if FEV1 is &lt;50% of&#xD;
             predicted normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
             ---Known moderate or severe persistent asthma within the past 2 years, or uncontrolled&#xD;
             asthma of any classification. NOTE: Subjects who currently have controlled&#xD;
             intermittent asthma or controlled mild persistent asthma are allowed to participate in&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Seropositive for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV). HIV-infected patients on&#xD;
             effective anti-retroviral therapy with undetectable viral load for at least the 3&#xD;
             months prior to enrollment are eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis B infection. NOTE: Patients who are hepatitis B surface antigen&#xD;
             (HbcsAg) or hepatitis B core antibody (HbcAb) positive will need to have a negative&#xD;
             HBV PCR result before enrollment. Those with a positive PCR for hepatitis B are&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Seropositive for hepatitis C (except in the setting of a sustained virologic response&#xD;
             [SVR], defined as aviremia at least 12 weeks after completion of antiviral therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripheral neuropathy of any cause that is Grade 2 or higher&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of inflammatory bowel disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to carfilzomib or daratumumab or other agents used in study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current uncontrolled hypertension (chronic systolic blood pressures &gt;160 mm Hg) or&#xD;
             diabetes (chronic clinical signs/symptoms of hyperglycemia and/or an A1c value &gt;9%).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant cardiovascular disease with NYHA Class II, III or IV symptoms, or&#xD;
             hypertrophic cardiomegaly, or restrictive cardiomegaly, or myocardial infarction&#xD;
             within 3 months prior to enrollment, or unstable angina, or unstable arrhythmia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No studies of carfilzomib or daratumumab have been conducted on breast feeding women&#xD;
             and it is not known if it is excreted in milk. Because there is an unknown but&#xD;
             potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the&#xD;
             mother, breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated with&#xD;
             carfilzomib/daratumumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, venous thromboembolic&#xD;
             disease, hemorrhage, pulmonary fibrosis, pneumonitis, or psychiatric illness/social&#xD;
             situations that would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark J Roschewski, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>NCI Medical Oncology Referral Office</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 760-6050</phone>
    <email>ncimo_referrals@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>888-624-1937</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2021-C-0024.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 7, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anti-CD38 monoclonal antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Proteasome Inhibitor</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-Myeloma Activity</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunomodulatory Agents</keyword>
  <keyword>Combination Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Smoldering Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Daratumumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

