<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04936139</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CEI 20/69</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04936139</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Art Therapy Effectiveness in the Level of Anxiety and Depression of Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>ATANDEC</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Art Therapy in the Level of Anxiety and Depression of Cancer Patients. Multicentric Random Clinical Trial (ATANDEC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Elisenda Campreciós Suñol</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fundació privada Nous Cims</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Althaia Xarxa Assistencial Universitària de Manresa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Althaia Xarxa Assistencial Universitària de Manresa</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Having a diagnosis of cancer leaves a great emotional impact when it comes to strategies for&#xD;
      coping with illness and life after illness. Participation in an art therapy program to forge&#xD;
      and improve the emotional well-being is considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Art therapy can be an effective intervention to help cancer patients lower their levels of&#xD;
      anxiety and depression and in return improve their quality of life and their ability to cope&#xD;
      with the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: The passage of a cancer through a person leaves a great emotional impact when&#xD;
      it comes to strategies for coping with illness and life after illness. Participation in an&#xD;
      art therapy program to forge and improve your emotional well-being is considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Project Hypothesis: Art therapy can be an effective intervention to help cancer&#xD;
      patients lower their levels of anxiety and depression and in return improve their quality of&#xD;
      life and their ability to cope with the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: To evaluate the effectiveness of art therapy in reducing the levels of anxiety&#xD;
      and depression in cancer patients, as well as in improving the quality of life and coping&#xD;
      strategies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology: Randomized, controlled, parallel and multi-centric non-pharmacological clinical&#xD;
      trial. Eight centers will participate in the study with an N of 423 patients. Patients older&#xD;
      than 18 years of age who are diagnosed with cancer at any stage of treatment with the&#xD;
      intention of radical treatment or palliative treatment with a life expectancy of more than 12&#xD;
      months will be included. If it is carried out in an online format, the person must have&#xD;
      access to the internet. Patients who suffer from a current or previous serious psychological&#xD;
      / psychiatric illness or those who have participated in an art therapy program structured in&#xD;
      the context of oncological process will be excluded. Patients will be assigned to the control&#xD;
      group (they will receive the usual follow-up from the center) or to the intervention group&#xD;
      (art therapy program). Patients assigned to the intervention group will participate in an art&#xD;
      therapy workshop once a week for 12 weeks, which will be done in person / online depending on&#xD;
      the epidemiological situation of covid-19 and the needs of each center, The group will&#xD;
      maintain the format (online / face-to-face) with which it has started throughout all the&#xD;
      sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Art therapy is a discipline that offers a space to meet with oneself, where one can dialogue&#xD;
      with different artistic languages, with the aim of promoting emotional integration and&#xD;
      looking for new ways to integrate difficult experiences through creative language.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessing anxiety and depression with the HAD scale, coping strategies with the Mini-MAC&#xD;
      scale, and WHOQOL-BREF for quality of life will be used. Statistical analysis will be for&#xD;
      treatment purposes. IBM SPSS Statistics v.24 and STATA v.14 will be used.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 21, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized, controlled, parallel and multi-centric non-pharmacological clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HAD scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The scale consists of 14 items that assess symptoms of anxiety and depression on a Likert scale of 4 response options. Scores between 0 and 7 are considered normal; between 8 and 10 doubtful, and scores above 11 for clinical problem of depression or anxiety.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HAD scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The scale consists of 14 items that assess symptoms of anxiety and depression on a Likert scale of 4 response options. Scores between 0 and 7 are considered normal; between 8 and 10 doubtful, and scores above 11 for clinical problem of depression or anxiety.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>World Health Organization Quality of Life (WHOQOL-BREF scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The questionnaire contains a total of 26 questions, two global quality of life and general health questions, and one question from each of the 24 facets contained in the WHOQOL-100. It also consists of 4 areas or dimensions: physical health, psychological, social relationships and environment. Each item has 5 ordinary Likert-type response options and the time it takes is two weeks. Higher scores indicate better quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>World Health Organization Quality of Life (WHOQOL-BREF scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The questionnaire contains a total of 26 questions, two global quality of life and general health questions, and one question from each of the 24 facets contained in the WHOQOL-100. It also consists of 4 areas or dimensions: physical health, psychological, social relationships and environment. Each item has 5 ordinary Likert-type response options and the time it takes is two weeks. Higher scores indicate better quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mini-Mental Adjustment to Cancer Scale (MINI-MAC)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>MINI-MAC is a 29-item instrument on a 4-choice Likert scale that assesses cognitive and behavioral responses to cancer. Differentiate 5 modes of coping: helplessness / hopelessness (ID), anxious worry (PA), cognitive avoidance (EN), fighting spirit (EL), and fatalism (FAE). Results are calculated for each of the examined strategies. Each strategy includes seven relevant statements. Every analysed subscale result range may be from 7 to 28. The higher the score, the stronger the behaviour typical for a given strategy of coping with càncer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mini-Mental Adjustment to Cancer Scale (MINI-MAC)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>MINI-MAC is a 29-item instrument on a 4-choice Likert scale that assesses cognitive and behavioral responses to cancer. Differentiate 5 modes of coping: helplessness / hopelessness (ID), anxious worry (PA), cognitive avoidance (EN), fighting spirit (EL), and fatalism (FAE). Results are calculated for each of the examined strategies. Each strategy includes seven relevant statements. Every analysed subscale result range may be from 7 to 28. The higher the score, the stronger the behaviour typical for a given strategy of coping with càncer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">432</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Art Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients assigned to the intervention group will participate in 12 weekly group therapy workshop sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients assigned to the control group will receive the usual follow-up care of each center provided for the cancer patient and will not perform art therapy workshops.&#xD;
They will be offered the opportunity to participate in the workshops once they have completed their participation in the study, putting them on a waiting list.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Art Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>During the 12 planned sessions, different artistic disciplines will be used: visual arts, music, play, narrative, dramatization, movement and body expression.&#xD;
Each session is structured in 3 phases:&#xD;
i. A first part of encounter and contextualization, to make contact with oneself, with the art therapist and with the group through a relaxation or meditation activity (35 minutes).&#xD;
ii. A second part, where the session continues with the work of artistic elaboration and production with the different materials and the different artistic languages (50 minutes).&#xD;
iii. A third part where the participants will be invited to make a closing, a moment to welcome and share whoever wishes, the experiences that have been experienced. A dialogue is created between Work-Patient-Art Therapist (35 minutes).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Art Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intention for radical treatment or palliative treatment with a life expectancy of more&#xD;
             than 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have internet access in case the intervention is done online&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to participate and sign informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with active diagnosis or personal history of severe psychological /&#xD;
             psychiatric illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who has participated in an art therapy program structured in the context of&#xD;
             the oncological process&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pau Gomes, MsC</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Fundació Nou Cims</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elisenda Campreciós, Bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>+3493 875 93 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>3140</phone_ext>
    <email>ecamprec@althaia.cat</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Anna Arnau, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+3493 875 93 00</phone>
    <phone_ext>3414</phone_ext>
    <email>aarnau@althaia.cat</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Althaia Xarxa Assistencial Universitària de Manresa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manresa</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08243</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elisenda Campreciós, Bachelor, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+34 93 875 93 00</phone>
      <phone_ext>3140</phone_ext>
      <email>ecamprec@althaia.cat</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Anna Arnau, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+34 93 875 9 300</phone>
      <phone_ext>3414</phone_ext>
      <email>aarnau@althaia.cat</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elisenda Campreciós, Bachelor, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gemma Cuberas, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Arnau, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elisabet Roldan, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Begoña Mellado</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jessica Gonzalez</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Gonzalez</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sara Garcia</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Rodriguez</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sonia Albenia</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Milagros Barez</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maria Marin</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carolina Martinez</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gemma Riera</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Imma Brao</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Laura Puntí</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Iolanda Pujol</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sally Schofield</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nereida Jimenez</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ana Manzano</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sybille Cseri</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Archer S, Buxton S, Sheffield D. The effect of creative psychological interventions on psychological outcomes for adult cancer patients: a systematic review of randomised controlled trials. Psychooncology. 2015 Jan;24(1):1-10. doi: 10.1002/pon.3607. Epub 2014 Jun 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24953449</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Andreu Vaillo Y, Murgui Pérez S, Martínez López P, Romero Retes R. Mini-Mental Adjustment to Cancer Scale: Construct validation in Spanish breast cancer patients. J Psychosom Res. 2018 Nov;114:38-44. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2018.09.004. Epub 2018 Sep 15.</citation>
    <PMID>30314577</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Oster I, Svensk AC, Magnusson E, Thyme KE, Sjõdin M, Aström S, Lindh J. Art therapy improves coping resources: a randomized, controlled study among women with breast cancer. Palliat Support Care. 2006 Mar;4(1):57-64.</citation>
    <PMID>16889324</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Krikorian A, Limonero JT, Maté J. Suffering and distress at the end-of-life. Psychooncology. 2012 Aug;21(8):799-808. doi: 10.1002/pon.2087. Epub 2011 Oct 11.</citation>
    <PMID>21990213</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Monti DA, Peterson C, Kunkel EJ, Hauck WW, Pequignot E, Rhodes L, Brainard GC. A randomized, controlled trial of mindfulness-based art therapy (MBAT) for women with cancer. Psychooncology. 2006 May;15(5):363-73.</citation>
    <PMID>16288447</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Puetz TW, Morley CA, Herring MP. Effects of creative arts therapies on psychological symptoms and quality of life in patients with cancer. JAMA Intern Med. 2013 Jun 10;173(11):960-9. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2013.836. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23699646</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Svensk AC, Oster I, Thyme KE, Magnusson E, Sjödin M, Eisemann M, Aström S, Lindh J. Art therapy improves experienced quality of life among women undergoing treatment for breast cancer: a randomized controlled study. Eur J Cancer Care (Engl). 2009 Jan;18(1):69-77. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2354.2008.00952.x.</citation>
    <PMID>19473224</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Thyme KE, Sundin EC, Wiberg B, Oster I, Aström S, Lindh J. Individual brief art therapy can be helpful for women with breast cancer: a randomized controlled clinical study. Palliat Support Care. 2009 Mar;7(1):87-95. doi: 10.1017/S147895150900011X.</citation>
    <PMID>19619378</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Xu L, Cheng P, Wu Y, Zhang J, Zhu J, Cui J, Yu R. The effects of art therapy on anxiety and depression in breast cancer patients: An updated meta-analysis. Eur J Cancer Care (Engl). 2020 Sep;29(5):e13266. doi: 10.1111/ecc.13266. Epub 2020 May 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32452121</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zhang MF, Wen YS, Liu WY, Peng LF, Wu XD, Liu QW. Effectiveness of Mindfulness-based Therapy for Reducing Anxiety and Depression in Patients With Cancer: A Meta-analysis. Medicine (Baltimore). 2015 Nov;94(45):e0897-0. doi: 10.1097/MD.0000000000000897. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26559246</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Zigmond AS, Snaith RP. The hospital anxiety and depression scale. Acta Psychiatr Scand. 1983 Jun;67(6):361-70.</citation>
    <PMID>6880820</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Althaia Xarxa Assistencial Universitària de Manresa</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elisenda Campreciós Suñol</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator (Bachelor's in Nursing, MSc)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Art Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of Life</keyword>
  <keyword>Coping Skills</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

