<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04933448</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00009115</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04933448</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ketogenic Diet Following Moderate to Severe Pediatric Traumatic Brain Injury</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ketogenic Diet Following Moderate to Severe Pediatric Traumatic Brain Injury: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Gillette Children's Specialty Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>State of Minnesota Spinal Cord Injury and Traumatic Brain Injury Research Grant Program</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Gillette Children's Specialty Healthcare</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to evaluate the feasibility and safety of using the&#xD;
      ketogenic diet (KD) in children who sustained moderate to severe traumatic brain injury&#xD;
      (TBI). The secondary objective is a preliminary evaluation of the outcomes of children who&#xD;
      have had the standard of care plus the KD, compared to those with standard of care alone.&#xD;
      Outcome measures for the secondary objective will include: need for ventriculoperitoneal&#xD;
      shunt, duration of unconsciousness, need for any type of craniotomy, duration of&#xD;
      post-traumatic amnesia, acute hospitalization length of stay, and cognitive and motor&#xD;
      function at 12 months after injury. If this study demonstrates feasibility and safety, the&#xD;
      information related to outcomes will be used to inform the planning of a future, larger,&#xD;
      randomized study of the efficacy of the KD in children and adolescents with TBI.&#xD;
      Specifically, this information will be used to assist with sample size calculations for this&#xD;
      future study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The KD is an alternative feeding regimen that has been in use since 1921. It is a high fat,&#xD;
      low carbohydrate and moderate protein diet. There are various forms of the KD. The classic KD&#xD;
      consists of long-chain triglycerides with a fat-to-combined-protein-and-carbohydrate ratio&#xD;
      that can vary. At our institution, it is standard of care to initiate a ketogenic diet at a&#xD;
      ratio of 2:1, and to increase the ratio to 3:1 or 4:1 as needed to achieve ketosis.&#xD;
      Clinically, the KD has been proven to be an effective therapy in children and adolescents&#xD;
      with refractory epilepsy, as well as for those with type II diabetes. In addition, an&#xD;
      international consensus was published in 2009 that recommended the use of the KD to treat&#xD;
      epilepsy refractory as an alternative to at least two antiepileptic medications. Before&#xD;
      initiating the KD for epilepsy management, labs such as urine and blood ketones, blood&#xD;
      glucose and a basic metabolic panel including magnesium are commonly recommended. Risks for&#xD;
      long-term use of the KD include but are not limited to the following: hypercholesterolemia,&#xD;
      mineral deficiencies, acidosis, constipation, weight loss and nephrolithiasis. However,&#xD;
      short-term use should significantly limit the occurrence of these potential complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ability to complete a course of the ketogenic diet (KD)</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and feasibility will be determined by the ability to complete a 14-day course of the KD after TBI without needing to terminate the diet due to intolerance resulting from gastrointestinal side effects (for example, nausea and vomiting, diarrhea, or acidosis), or due to abnormal findings on laboratory tests. Outcome is reported as the number of participants who complete the 14-day keto diet treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Unconsciousness</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the length of time (in hours) a participant is unconscious following their injury.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for Surgeries</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the number of surgeries required in each group following injury.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Acute Hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the length (in days) of acute hospitalization following injury.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Post-traumatic Amnesia</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Outcome is reported as the length of time (in days) that a participant experiences amnesia following their injury.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Traumatic Brain Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive standard of care for acute management of moderate to severe traumatic brain injury, together with a weight-based ketogenic diet added for up to fourteen days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Historical Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Medical records of past TBI patients will be used as controls matched for age, gender, socioeconomic status (type of health care coverage including private insurance vs. government-funded coverage), lowest first 24 hour post-injury Glasgow Coma Score (GCS) (&lt;8 or 8-12), and pre-injury school program (regular or special education).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketogenic Diet</intervention_name>
    <description>The ketogenic diet (KD) is an alternative feeding regimen that has been in use since 1921. It is a high-fat, low carbohydrate, and moderate protein diet. There are various forms of the KD. The classic KD consists of long-chain triglycerides with a fat-to-combined-protein-and-carbohydrate ratio that can vary. At the investigating institution, it is standard of care to initiate a ketogenic diet at a ratio of 2:1, and to increase the ratio to 3:1 or 4:1 as needed to achieve ketosis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prospective Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keto</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age limits met at the time of injury and admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with moderate to severe traumatic brain injury defined as a Glasgow Coma&#xD;
             Scale Score of 3-12 (lowest score in the first 24 hours after injury). Individuals&#xD;
             requiring craniotomy and/or evacuation of intracranial hemorrhage may be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anoxia/ischemia as a significant portion of injury, including near-drowning&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-accidental traumatic brain injury (i.e., assault, abuse)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Penetrating injury including gunshot wounds&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that in the opinion of the Pediatric Intensive Care Unit or neurosurgery&#xD;
             medical staff warrants exclusion from the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Linda Krach, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Angela Sinner, DO</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Linda Krach, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(651)-229-3873</phone>
    <email>LKrach@gillettechildrens.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Angela Sinner, DO</last_name>
    <phone>(651)-325-2317</phone>
    <email>ASinner@gillettechildrens.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gillette Children's Specialty Healthcare</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Linda Krach, MD</last_name>
      <phone>651-229-3873</phone>
      <email>LKrach@gillettechildrens.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Injuries, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

