<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04935580</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GC012F-32</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04935580</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of FasT CAR-T GC012F Injection in High Risk TE NDMM Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Frontline Therapy of GC012F Injection in Transplant Eligible Newly Diagnosed Multiple Myeloma Patients With High-Risk Profile</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shanghai Changzheng Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Gracell Biotechnology Shanghai Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shanghai Changzheng Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a single arm, open label, single-center prospective study to evaluate the safety and&#xD;
      efficacy of GC012F as frontline therapy for transplant eligible multiple myeloma(MM) patients&#xD;
      with high-risk profile. Patients enrolled will be newly diagnosed treatment naïve patients&#xD;
      who are eligible for transplant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients will be leukapheresed prior to receiving up to 2 cycles of standard induction&#xD;
      therapy optional at physicians' choice. After the optional induction therapy, patients will&#xD;
      receive standard lymphodepleting therapy with fludarabine and cyclophosphamide prior to&#xD;
      GC012F infusion. After a single infusion of GC012F, patients will be assessed for Response&#xD;
      Rate and depth of response at month 1. In case CR/sCR not achieved, patients will be&#xD;
      re-asssesd for depth of Response at month 3 post CART infusion. If at month 3 response is&#xD;
      less than CR/sCR, patients can proceed to transplant/anti-tumor therapy according to clinical&#xD;
      practice. In case CR/sCR is achieved at either month 1 or month 3, MRD will be assessed. In&#xD;
      case MRD positive, patient may receive a hematological stem cell transplant (HSCT) optional&#xD;
      or other anti-tumor therapy. Patients who obtain a CR/sCR at month 1 or month 3 according to&#xD;
      the IMWG criteria and are assessed MRD negative response will be confirmed by PET-CT scan and&#xD;
      they will continue to be observed. If patients obtain a MRD negative CR/sCR at month 1 then&#xD;
      additional assessment at month 3 is not necessary. MRD will be tested when CR/sCR is&#xD;
      achieved. At month 6 an additional response assessment will be conducted-maintenance therapy&#xD;
      can be given post month 6 at physicians' choice. Patients will continue to be followed and&#xD;
      assessed for duration of response at fixed timepoints at months 12, 18 and 24. Safety and&#xD;
      efficacy will be analyzed throughout the study at timepoints as per schedule of assessment&#xD;
      until the end of study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events (AE) after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>An assessment of severity grade will be made according to the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (NCI CTCAE), with the exception of cytokine release syndrome (CRS), and immune effector cell-associated neurotoxicity syndrome (ICANS). CRS and ICANS should be evaluated according to the American Society for Transplantation and Cellular Therapy (ASTCT) consensus grading</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) as measured by International Myeloma Working Group (IMWG) criteria after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>ORR defined as proportion of patients achieving PR or better based on IMWG defined response criteria</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with minimal residual disease (MRD) negative(tested by NGF at sensitivity of 10e-5 to 10e-4) at landmark analysis of 1/3/6/12/18/24 months post GC012F infusion (Measured once achieving CR/sCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>MRD negative rate is defined as the proportion of participants who achieve MRD negative status by the respective time point</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progress free survival (PFS) at 6 months, 12 months and 24 months after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>PFS defined as time from date of GC012F infusion to date of first documented disease progression, or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first. DOR defined as time form Month 1 after GC012F infusion to date of 1st documented PD if patients' response deeper or keeping sCR after CAR-T infusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response (DOR) at 6 months, 12 months and 24 months after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>DOR defined as time form Month 1 after GC012F infusion to date of 1st documented PD if patients' response deeper or keeping sCR after CAR-T infusion.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS) after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Response is defined as participant has met all criteria for PR or better according to IMWG criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first response (TTR) after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Response is defined as participant has met all criteria for PR or better according to IMWG criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to best response (TBR) after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Response is defined as participant has met all criteria for PR or better according to IMWG criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Health-related Quality of Life (HRQoL) as Measured by EORTC QLQ-C30</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to study completion ( 2 years after GC012F Infusion on Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HRQoL will be assessed by the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC) Quality of Life Questionnaire Core-30 (QLQC30) items. Subscale and single item scores are reported on a 0-100 scale with higher scores representing better global health status, better functioning, and worst symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in HRQoL as Measured by EORTC QLQ-MY20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to study completion ( 2 years after GC012F Infusion on Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HRQoL will be assessed by the EORTC QLQ-Multiple Myeloma ((MY20) module items. Subscale and single item scores are reported on a 0-100 scale with higher scores representing better global health status, better functioning, and worst symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Participant-reported Health Status Measured by EQ-5D- 5L</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to study completion ( 2 years after GC012F Infusion on Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Participant-reported health status measured by the EuroQol Group 5-dimension, 5-level (EQ-5D-5L) questionnaire. A total utility score is reported based on the health status, ranging from 0 to 1, where higher values indicate better health utility. The visual analog scale ranges from 0 to 100 where higher values indicate better overall health status.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline in Pain Measured by PGIS Scale [Time Frame: Baseline up to study completion</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to study completion ( 2 years after GC012F Infusion on Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Participant reported pain measured by Patient Global Impression of Severity (PGIS) Scale. The PGIS is a single item to assess pain severity. The 5-point verbal rating scale ranged from 1 (none) to 5 (very severe).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of CAR-T Cell Expansion (proliferation), and Persistence</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of GC012F cell expansion (proliferation), and persistence via monitoring CAR-T positive cell counts and CAR transgene level will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokines in the peripheral blood after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Serum concentrations of Granulocyte-macrophage Colony Stimulating Factor (GM-CSF), interleukin (IL)-6, IL-10, interferon-gamma (IFN-γ), soluble BCMA (sBCMA) and TNF-α after GC012F infusion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum concentrations of C-reaction protein (CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Serum concentrations of C-reaction protein (CRP)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with Anti-GC012F Antibodies, replication-competent lentivirus (RCL) after GC012F infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years after patients infused with GC012F injection</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients exhibiting anti-drug antibodies for GC012F and RCL will be reported</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>GC012F treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>GC012F will be infused at a dose of 3 x 10^5 CAR+ T cells/kg after receiving lymphodepleting chemotherapy. Lenalidomide maintenance therapy will be given post month 6 at physicians' choice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>GC012F injection</intervention_name>
    <description>GC012F injection is an autologous dual CAR-T targeted BCMA and CD19. A single infusion of CAR-T cells will be administered intravenously.</description>
    <arm_group_label>GC012F treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. ≥18 years of age at the time of signing informed consent-upper age limit 65;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Newly diagnosed Multiple Myeloma-transplant eligible patients-patients must be&#xD;
                  treatment naïve to any anti-Myeloma therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. High-risk defined as meet one or more of the following criteria at screen:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. R-ISS stage II or III;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. LDH &gt; the upper limit of normal;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Meet one or more of cytogenetic high risk defined by: del 17p, t(4:14),&#xD;
                       t(14:16); Gain 1q21≥ 4 copies;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    4. Patients with extramedullary disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    5. IgD or IgE subtype;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    6. Meet one or more high-risk definition of mSMART3.0;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Documented evidence of multiple myeloma at diagnosis as defined by IMWG&#xD;
                  guidelines CRAB (calcium elevation, renal insufficiency, anemia, and bone&#xD;
                  abnormalities)/SLiM criteria, monoclonal plasma cells in the bone marrow ≥10% or&#xD;
                  presence of a biopsy proven plasmacytomas, and measurable secretory disease&#xD;
                  according to IMWG criteria meet one or more of the following criteria at&#xD;
                  screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Serum M protein ≥ 1 g/dL;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Urine M protein ≥ 200 mg/24h;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Serum free light chain sFLC ≥ 10 mg/dL with abnormal serum immunoglobulin&#xD;
                       κ/λ free light chain ratio.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. ECOG score was 0-2 at screen;&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Estimated life expectancy ≥3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5×10^9/L without use of growth factors;&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Platelet count ≥ 75×10^9/L without transfusion support within 7 days before the&#xD;
                  screen;&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Hemoglobin≥ 80 g/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Adequate functional reserve of organs:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. ALT/AST ≤ 2.5× UNL (upper normal limit);&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Creatinine clearance ≥ 40mL/min, or serum creatinine level ≤177μmol/L，may be&#xD;
                       calculated or measured according to local practice;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Serum total bilirubin ≤ 1.5× UNL, except in subjects with congenital&#xD;
                       bilirubinemia, such as Gilbert syndrome, then direct bilirubin ≤ 1.5× UNL;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    4. The left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF)≥50%, and no clinically&#xD;
                       significant ecg abnormalities were found;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    5. Basic oxygen saturation in natural indoor air: SPO2&gt;92%.&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Adequate venous access for apheresis collection, and no other contraindications&#xD;
                  to apheresis;&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Subjects and sexual partner with fertility are willing to use effective and&#xD;
                  reliable method of contraception for at least 1 year after CART cell infusion,&#xD;
                  serum HCG should be negative in females with fertility both at screening&#xD;
                  andbaseline;&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Subjects must sign a written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be excluded if they meet any one of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with purely non-secretory MM;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subject has had radiation therapy within 14 days of screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subjects has plasma cell leukemia or POEMS syndrome (polyneuropathy,&#xD;
                  organomegaly, endocrinopathy, monoclonal protein, and skin changes);&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Subjects has a diagnosis of primary amyloidosis, Waldenstroem's disease,&#xD;
                  monoclonal gammopathy of undetermined significance, or smoldering multiple&#xD;
                  myeloma;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Having other tumors (excluding non-melanoma skin cancer and cervical cancer in&#xD;
                  situ bladder cancer and breast cancer that have been disease-free for more than 5&#xD;
                  years);&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Overt clinical evidence of dementia or altered mental status; any history of&#xD;
                  central nervous system (CNS) disease or neurodegenerative disorder, such as&#xD;
                  epilepsy, seizures, paralysis, aphasia, stroke, severe brain damage, dementia,&#xD;
                  Parkinson's disease, psychosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. History of hereditary diseases such as Fanconi anemia, Schrader syndrome,&#xD;
                  Costerman syndrome, or any other known bone marrow failure syndrome;&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Clinically significant cardiac disease including: uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
                  or clinically significant ECG abnormalities, grade III-IV heart failure or&#xD;
                  myocardial infarction cardiac angioplasty or stenting unstable angina or other&#xD;
                  clinically significant cardiac conditions within one year prior to enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Presence of any indwelling catheter or drainage tube (e.g., percutaneous&#xD;
                  nephrostomy catheter indwelling catheter bile drainage tube or&#xD;
                  pleural/peritoneal/pericardial catheter) permits the use of a dedicated central&#xD;
                  venous catheter;&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Subjects is exhibiting clinical signs of meningeal involvement of multiple&#xD;
                  myeloma;&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. A positive virological result for any of the following: HIV, HCV, HBsAg, TPPA;&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Other severe viral or bacterial infections or uncontrolled systemic fungal&#xD;
                  infections are present;&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Subjects with a history of severe hypersensitivity;&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. There is a history of an autoimmune disease (e.g., Crohn's disease, rheumatoid&#xD;
                  arthritis, systemic lupus erythematosus) that has resulted in terminal organ&#xD;
                  damage or requires systemic immunosuppressive/disease modulating drugs in the&#xD;
                  past 2 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. Presence of lung disease (such as pulmonary fibrosis);&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Subjects has had major surgery within 2 weeks before screen or has not fully&#xD;
                  recovered from surgery, or has surgery planned during the time the subject is&#xD;
                  expected to participate in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
              17. Poor compliance due to factors such as physiological family, social geography,&#xD;
                  etc., and inability to comply with the research program and follow-up plan;&#xD;
&#xD;
              18. Pregnant or lactating women, or men who are planned to have babies during the&#xD;
                  period of participation in the study or within 1 year of receiving treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
              19. Investigator assessment deemed to be ineligible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan Du, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Shanghai Changzheng Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Weijun Fu, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Shanghai Changzheng Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Juan Du, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+86-21-81885423</phone>
    <email>changzheng_pg@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Weijun Fu, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+86-21-81885424</phone>
    <email>fuweijun@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Shanghai Changzheng Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Juan Du</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Hematology Department</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

