<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04931407</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>153665</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04931407</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Feasibility Study in Chronically Fatigued Cancer Survivors</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Feasibility Study in Chronically Fatigued Cancer Survivors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oslo University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oslo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Diakonhjemmet Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Norwegian School of Sport Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Norwegian University of Science and Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UiT The Arctic University of Norway</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oslo University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Improved cancer survival has led to increased attention on long-term health and quality of&#xD;
      life (QoL) among the survivors. Both the cancer diagnosis and intensive treatments increase&#xD;
      the risk of late effects which may interfere with daily physical, psychological and social&#xD;
      functioning, and thereby negatively affect their QoL. Well-documented late-effects among&#xD;
      cancer survivors are second cancer, cardio-vascular disease, pain, hormone disturbances,&#xD;
      mental distress and chronic fatigue (CF).&#xD;
&#xD;
      CF is a subjective experience of substantial lack of energy, exhaustion and cognitive&#xD;
      difficulties lasting for six months or longer. CF is one of the most common and distressing&#xD;
      late effects after cancer, affecting 15-35 % of survivors, often for years beyond treatment.&#xD;
      Despite the high prevalence and the huge negative consequences of CF on daily functioning and&#xD;
      QoL and the economic and societal costs, effective treatment of CF and standardized follow-up&#xD;
      care are currently lacking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CF is a complex condition best understood as a multifactorial phenomenon. Our and other&#xD;
      research groups have examined various cohorts of cancer survivors in order to identify&#xD;
      behavioral-, psychological-, and biological factors associated with CF, that can form the&#xD;
      basis for targeted interventions. So far, few treatable biological factors have been&#xD;
      identified, even though immune activation, flattened diurnal cortisol slopes and a blunted&#xD;
      cortisol response to stress have been demonstrated in small studies among cancer survivors&#xD;
      suffering from CF. On the other hand, several modifiable behavioral factors including&#xD;
      emotional distress, physical inactivity, sleep disturbances and unhealthy diets are found to&#xD;
      be associated with CF. So far, most of the interventions aiming to reduce fatigue during and&#xD;
      shortly after cancer treatment have targeted only one of these factors at a time, with small&#xD;
      to moderate effect sizes. No prior study has examined if CF in cancer survivors is better&#xD;
      treated by a complex intervention targeting combinations of these factors, an approach which&#xD;
      seems logical due to the complexity of the symptom.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Division of Cancer Medicine at Oslo University Hospital (OUH) presently offers limited&#xD;
      rehabilitation programs, including patient education, physical exercise, cognitive behavioral&#xD;
      program and nutrition counselling to cancer survivors with CF. However, these programs are&#xD;
      not offered as an interdisciplinary intervention integrated in a standardized patient care&#xD;
      pathway, and the effects of these interventions have not been assessed. Based on the&#xD;
      investigators clinical experience and published studies on single-targeted interventions, the&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that a complex intervention including psycho-educational elements,&#xD;
      physical exercise and nutrition counseling delivered as a standardized patient care pathway&#xD;
      is well-founded and doable, and will improve fatigue, functioning and QoL in cancer survivors&#xD;
      with CF.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the fall of 2021, the investigators will conduct a randomized controlled trial (RCT)&#xD;
      with the overall objective to improve fatigue in lymphoma survivors with CF. To uncover&#xD;
      strengths and weaknesses with the planned RCT, i.e. the inclusion procedures, the assessments&#xD;
      and the complex intervention, the investigators are now conducting a small one-armed&#xD;
      feasibility study before the RCT during spring 2021.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recruitment rate</measure>
    <time_frame>The week before the intervention period (week 0)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the number who consent to participate</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Inclusion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>The week before the intervention period (week 0)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the number of consenting participants who are included (i.e. have chronic fatigue according to the Fatigue Questionnaire, and are cleared for participation by oncologist after the medical screening).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>The week before the intervention period (week 0)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the number of consenting participants consenting patients who complete any measurement at the final assessment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Strengths and weaknesses with the inclusion procedure: participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by structured conversations with the participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Strengths and weaknesses with the inclusion procedure: study personnel</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by structured conversations with the study personnel</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the patient education session: participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths, weaknesses, and usefulness of the contents in the education session will be assessed by structured conversations with the participants after the patient education session.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the patient education session: presenters</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths, weaknesses, and usefulness of the contents in the education session will be assessed by structured conversations with the presenters after the patient education session.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the exercise program part one (week 1-3): participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the exercise program will be evaluated through structured conversations with the participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the exercise program part one (week 1-3): physiotherapists</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the exercise program will be evaluated through structured conversations with the physiotherapists</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the exercise program part two (week 4-7): participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the exercise program will be evaluated through structured conversations with the participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the exercise program part two (week 4-7): physiotherapists</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the exercise program will be evaluated through structured conversations with the physiotherapists</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to the cognitive behavioral therapy groups sessions</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Participation to the cognitive behavioral therapy groups sessions will be registered by the study coordinators/psychologists..</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the cognitive behavioral therapy groups sessions: participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths, weaknesses, and usefulness of the groups sessions will be assessed by structured conversations with the participants after the last group session</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the cognitive behavioral therapy groups sessions: psychologists</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths, weaknesses, and usefulness of the groups sessions will be assessed by structured conversations with the psychologists after the last group session</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to the nutrition counseling</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 11</time_frame>
    <description>Participation rate of the individual nutrition counseling sessions will be registered by the clinical dietitian.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the nutrition counseling: participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 11</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths, weaknesses, and usefulness of the contents in the sessions will be assessed by structured conversations with the participants after the last counseling session.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the nutrition counseling: clinical dietitian</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 11</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths, weaknesses, and usefulness of the contents in the sessions will be assessed by structured conversations with the clinical dietitian after the last counseling session.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to the exercise program: attendance</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Registered by the physiotherapists in an exercise log</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to the exercise program: intensity during the aerobic exercise intervals</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Registered by pulse sensors</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to the exercise program: implementation of the strength training exercises</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Registered by the physiotherapists in an exercise log</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the exercise program part three (week 8-12): participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the exercise program will be evaluated through structured conversations with the participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the exercise program part three (week 8-12): physiotherapists</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the exercise program will be evaluated through structured conversations with the physiotherapists</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the questionnaires</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the questionnaire will be evaluated through structured conversations with the participants.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the physical tests: participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the tests will be evaluated through structured conversations with the participants.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the physical tests: physiotherapists</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Strengths and weaknesses with the tests will be evaluated through structured conversations with the physiotherapists conducting the tests.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to the physical tests</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the completion rate of the physical tests (i.e. the number of participants who conduct the tests as planned).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Completeness of the questionnaires</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the completion rate of the questionnaire (i.e. proportion of missing).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by Chalder Fatigue Questionnaire. Total score range from 0 to 33, with increasing score implying more fatigue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by Chalder Fatigue Questionnaire. Total score range from 0 to 33, with increasing score implying more fatigue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of fatigue</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by Chalder Fatigue Questionnaire. Total score range from 0 to 33, with increasing score implying more fatigue.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in daily functioning and global quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Core Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC-QLQ-C30). Scores range fro 0 to 100, a higher score represents a higher (better) level of functioning or a higher (worse) level of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in daily functioning and global quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Core Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC-QLQ-C30). Scores range fro 0 to 100, a higher score represents a higher (better) level of functioning or a higher (worse) level of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in daily functioning and global quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Core Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC-QLQ-C30). Scores range fro 0 to 100, a higher score represents a higher (better) level of functioning or a higher (worse) level of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in subjective well-being</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Satisfaction with Life Scale. Total score range from 5 to 35, with increasing score implying higher subjective well-being.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in vitality</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Subjective Vitality Scale. The total score ranges from 6 to 36 with a higher score indicating a better condition</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in general health</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by European Quality of Life Five-dimension Scale Questionnaire (EQ-5D). Total score range from 5 (worst health) to 25 (best health).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in work ability</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by Work Ability Index. Total score range from 7 to 49 points, with higher score indicating better work ability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in work ability</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by Work Ability Index. Total score range from 7 to 49 points, with higher score indicating better work ability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in work ability</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by Work Ability Index. Total score range from 7 to 49 points, with higher score indicating better work ability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in anxiety symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the General Anxiety Disorder 7-items. Total score range from 0 to 21 with increasing score implying higher level of anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in anxiety symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the General Anxiety Disorder 7-items. Total score range from 0 to 21 with increasing score implying higher level of anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in anxiety symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the General Anxiety Disorder 7-items. Total score range from 0 to 21 with increasing score implying higher level of anxiety.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depressive symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Patient Health Questionnaire-9. Total score from 0 to 27, increasing score implying higher depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depressive symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Patient Health Questionnaire-9. Total score from 0 to 27, increasing score implying higher depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in depressive symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Patient Health Questionnaire-9. Total score from 0 to 27, increasing score implying higher depressive symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Godin Leisure Time Exercise Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Godin Leisure Time Exercise Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in level of physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Godin Leisure Time Exercise Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in exercise mastery</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Perceived Competence Scale. The scale consists of 4 items (statements). On each item, participants are asked to rate how true a statement is using a 7-point scale.Total score range from 4 to 28, with increasing score reflecting higher exercise mastery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in exercise mastery</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Perceived Competence Scale. The scale consists of 4 items (statements). On each item, participants are asked to rate how true a statement is using a 7-point scale.Total score range from 4 to 28, with increasing score reflecting higher exercise mastery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in exercise mastery</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Perceived Competence Scale. The scale consists of 4 items (statements). On each item, participants are asked to rate how true a statement is using a 7-point scale.Total score range from 4 to 28, with increasing score reflecting higher exercise mastery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dietary intake of the participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by a digital food frequency questionnaire (DIGIKOST-FFQ)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in meal pattern</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by the Meal Pattern Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated by measuring weight and height</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated by measuring weight and height</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Calculated by measuring weight and height</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep problems</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by questions from the Trøndelag Health Survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep problems</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by questions from the Trøndelag Health Survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sleep problems</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Measured by questions from the Trøndelag Health Survey</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiorespiratory fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by a submaximal and indirect treadmill test (modified Balke protocol)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiorespiratory fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by a submaximal and indirect treadmill test (modified Balke protocol)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiorespiratory fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by a submaximal and indirect treadmill test (modified Balke protocol)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lower body muscle strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by 30 second sit-to-stand test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lower body muscle strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by 30 second sit-to-stand test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lower body muscle strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by 30 second sit-to-stand test</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in upper body muscle strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by maximum repetitions of push-ups with various starting positions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in upper body muscle strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 4 months follow-up (week 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by maximum repetitions of push-ups with various starting positions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in upper body muscle strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) to 7 months follow-up (week 42)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by maximum repetitions of push-ups with various starting positions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life among relatives</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the Research and Development 36-item Short Form Survey (RAND SF-36).The eight scales are standardized with a scoring algorithm or by the SF-36v2 scoring software to obtain a score ranging from 0 to 100. Higher scores indicate better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in global health status among relatives</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from baseline (week 0) and to post-intervention (week 13)</time_frame>
    <description>The global health status / quality of life scale from the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Core Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC-QLQ-C30). Scores range from 0 to 100, a higher score represents a higher (better) level of functioning or a higher (worse) level of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Fatigue</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interdisciplinary complex intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention includes patient education, physical exercise, a group-based cognitive behavioral program and individual nutritional counseling</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>A 12-week interdisciplinary complex intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention will last for 12 weeks and includes four components; patient education, physical exercise, cognitive behavioral program and nutritional counseling.&#xD;
The patient education will include an online 2-hours group-based patient-education sessions in week 1.&#xD;
The physical exercise program includes two weekly exercise sessions, one supervised by a physiotherapist and one unsupervised, including aerobic exercise, resistance exercise and psychometric physiotherapy. Half of the intervention group (N=7) will perform the supervised exercise session individually with a physiotherapist in the municipality, while the other half (n=8) will exercise in online groups lead by physiotherapists.&#xD;
The cognitive behavioral program will begin in week 3 and include six group-based online sessions every week lead by a clinical psychologist.&#xD;
The nutritional counseling will include three individual digital nutrition counselling sessions in week 2, 6 and 10 by a clinical dietitian.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interdisciplinary complex intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Seven lymphoma survivors will be included, with the same inclusion criteria as in the&#xD;
        planned RCT:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Survivors of Hodgkin and aggressive non-Hodgkin lymphoma, diagnosed 2014 or 2019 (n=7)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18-65 years at diagnosis, and 19-67 years at participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CF measured by Chalder FQ.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Curatively treated, more than 2 years since last treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation approval from oncologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indolent non-Hodgkin lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fatigue more than one year before the cancer diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing cancer treatment, relapse or second cancer, somatic/physical conditions (i.e.&#xD;
             severe heart failure/disease, lung disease, use of wheelchair /crutches).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric disorders (i.e. severe depression, schizophrenia), substance abuse&#xD;
             disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition, eight cancer survivors with various diagnosis, will be included from a waiting&#xD;
        list for rehabilitation at the Cancer Rehabilitation Centre at Aker hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>67 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lene Thorsen</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Oslo University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oslo University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <zip>0379</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Norway</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oslo University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lene Thorsen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>chronic fatigue</keyword>
  <keyword>lymphoma</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer survivors</keyword>
  <keyword>nutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>cognitive therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>patient education</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

