<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04933045</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Syndesmotic Augmentation</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04933045</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Syndesmotic Disruption With Anatomic Distal Tibiofibular Ligament Augmentation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Syndesmotic Disruption With Anatomic Distal Tibiofibular Ligament Augmentation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Clair Orthopaedics</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Clair Orthopaedics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to evaluate indications and outcomes of operative fixation of&#xD;
      syndesmotic injuries, at least in part, with direct anatomic augmentation in acute and&#xD;
      subacute traumatic cases. The secondary objective of the study is to evaluate clinically the&#xD;
      InternalBraceTm to facilitate the direct syndesmotic fixation/augmentation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A syndesmosis is a slightly movable fibrous joint in which bones such as the tibia and fibula&#xD;
      are joined together by connnective tissue. Together, they form a bracket shaped socket,&#xD;
      covered in hyaline cartilage. This socket is known as the mortise. A syndesmotic or 'high&#xD;
      'ankle sprain is when the ligaments binding the distal tibia and fibula at the ankle joint&#xD;
      are injured or torn. This can lead to the ankle joint and syndesmoses to being malaligned,&#xD;
      subluxed or widened. Subsequently, this can lead to ankle arthritis and deformity with&#xD;
      persistent pain and swelling about the ankle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no generally accepted treatment guidelines. Thus, there still remains considerable&#xD;
      controversies regarding diagnosis, classification and treatment of syndesmotic injuries.&#xD;
      Syndesmotic malreduction is the most common indication for early re-operation after ankle&#xD;
      fracture surgery, and widening of the ankle mortise by only 1 mm decreases the contact area&#xD;
      of the tibiotalar joint by 42%. Outcome of ankle fractures with syndesmosis injury is worse&#xD;
      than without, even after surgical syndesmotic stabilization. This may be due to a high&#xD;
      incidence of syndesmotic malreduction revealed by increasing postoperative computed&#xD;
      tomography controls. Therefore, even open visualization of the syndesmosis during the&#xD;
      reduction maneuver has been recommended. Thus, the most important clinical predictor of&#xD;
      outcome is consistently reported as accuracy of anatomic reduction of the injured&#xD;
      syndesmosis. In 2017 a new syndesmotic InternalBraceTM technique for improved anatomic distal&#xD;
      tibiofibular ligament augmentation to protect healing of the injured native ligaments was&#xD;
      introduced. This technique involves direct surgical inspection of the syndesmoses for injury&#xD;
      and subsequent augmentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study hopes to evaluate the results of this direct syndesmotic&#xD;
      augmentation/stabilization to help determine if this is perhaps a safer, and possibly more&#xD;
      effective method.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This prospective study is designed to evaluate 32 consecutive patients that did have an acute&#xD;
      or subacute syndesmotic injury that necessitated surgical stabilization and used at least in&#xD;
      part the InternalBrace technique. There was not a restriction of age, gender, or race.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2 patients who were labeled as having severe syndesmotic disruption and had additional screw&#xD;
      fixation. Also, 5 patients had dynamic syndesmotic fixation in addition to direct&#xD;
      InternalBrace augmentation of the AITFL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patents will or had had plain radiographs and physical examination of injured ankle 1&#xD;
      week, 1 month, 3 months, 6 months and 12 months. Also, at minimum 12 months post operatively&#xD;
      a physical exam and plain radiograph contralateral uninjured ankle to be performed as&#xD;
      comparison/control. At minimum 12 months post operative additional patent report outcomes&#xD;
      such as AOFAS/VAS scores and return to pre-injury status recreationally/work level to be&#xD;
      evaluated. The ankle anatomic syndesomotic and mortise alignment has been associated with&#xD;
      long term outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Indications and outcomes of operative fixation of syndesmotic injuries</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate indicatinos and outcomes of operative fixation of syndesmotic injuries at least in part with direct anatomic augmentation in acute and subacute traumatic ankle fracture cases.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>InternalBrace</measure>
    <time_frame>1 yeaer</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate clinically the InternalBrace to facilitate the direct syndesmotic fixation/augmentation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Syndesmotic Injuries</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Syndesmotic Fixation Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Cohort of patients treated with anatomic ATFL reconstruction for syndesmotic ankle injury.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Arthrex InternalBrace</intervention_name>
    <description>Placement of Arthrex InternalBrace for anatomic distal tibiofibular ligament augmentation to stabilize the ankle syndesmosis during surgery.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Syndesmotic Fixation Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Skeletally mature patients that occurred an ankle syndesmotic injury necessitating surgical&#xD;
        stabilization/fixation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skeletally mature patients that occurred an ankle syndesmotic injury necessitating&#xD;
             surgical stabilization/fixation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Skeletally immature patients, patients with nonoperatively managed ankle injuries&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>105 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christopher Zingas, MD</last_name>
    <phone>313-689-7030</phone>
    <email>cmzingas@me.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Matthew Schuch, DO</last_name>
    <phone>616-848-9119</phone>
    <email>schuchm11@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Clair Orthopedics and Sports Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Clair Shores</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48080</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>St. Clair Orthopaedics</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christopher N Zingas</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Orthopedic Surgeon</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Syndesmosis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ankle Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

