<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04938596</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1211225</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04938596</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Airborne Preventive Measures to Reduce New TB Infections in Household Contacts</brief_title>
  <acronym>TBMask</acronym>
  <official_title>Strengthening of Airborne Preventive Measures Inside Households of Pulmonary TB Cases as a Tool to Reduce New Infections in Close Contacts. A Pilot, Controlled, Pre-post Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fondo Nacional de Desarrollo Científico y Tecnológico, Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Agencia Nacional de Investigación y Desarrollo, ANID</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis (TB) is currently one of the top 10 causes of death worldwide and the leading&#xD;
      cause of death from a single infectious agent (ranking above HIV/AIDS). The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that reducing respiratory exposure within the household, during the first weeks&#xD;
      of TB treatment initiation of the index case, can reduce new TB infections in close contacts.&#xD;
      For this purpose, a pilot, controlled, pre-post study will be set up, to evaluate the&#xD;
      feasibility of implementing a bundle of respiratory precautions to all household contacts of&#xD;
      new pulmonary TB cases, compared to standard of care, in primary health care in a high TB&#xD;
      incidence area in Santiago, Chile.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Tuberculosis (TB) is currently one of the top 10 causes of death worldwide and the leading&#xD;
      cause of death from a single infectious agent (ranking above HIV/AIDS). In 2018, an estimated&#xD;
      10 million people fell ill with TB worldwide, and more than 1.4 million people died from it,&#xD;
      making eradication of this disease in the next decades highly unlikely unless new&#xD;
      interventions are discovered. Mycobacterium tuberculosis (Mtb) transmission mainly occurs&#xD;
      when patients affected by laryngeal or pulmonary TB cough upon others and the mycobacteria&#xD;
      are spread in airborne droplets nuclei smaller than 5 μm that are subsequently inhaled by&#xD;
      close contacts. Although chemoprophylaxis once a new TB infection is detected is an effective&#xD;
      strategy to reduce the risk of contacts developing active TB, it does not prevent Mtb&#xD;
      acquisition; it only reduces the risk of developing active TB once infected. Currently, the&#xD;
      large majority of international guidelines recommend strict measures to reduce airborne&#xD;
      transmission in hospitalized patients with pulmonary TB, with a minimum of 2 weeks of&#xD;
      effective TB therapy to consider a patient no longer infectious and discontinue respiratory&#xD;
      isolation in healthcare settings. On the contrary, in the community, no special&#xD;
      recommendations regarding protection of household contacts are specified, assuming that most&#xD;
      of them are already infected and that the TB index case will stop infecting very quickly&#xD;
      under antimicrobial treatment. However, several studies show that median time to sputum Mtb&#xD;
      culture conversion under effective treatment takes 5-7 weeks, raising the potential for&#xD;
      continued transmission even despite effective treatment. Furthermore, a previous study has&#xD;
      shown that in Santiago, Chile, 55% of household contacts of TB cases have no evidence of TB&#xD;
      infection at the time of diagnosis of the index case - as categorized by negative latent TB&#xD;
      testing - yet under close follow-up, up to 21% of these show new evidence of having acquired&#xD;
      the infection based on latent TB test conversion after 12 weeks of follow-up. The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that reducing respiratory exposure within the household, during the&#xD;
      first weeks of TB treatment initiation of the index case, can reduce new TB infections in&#xD;
      close contacts. For this purpose, a pilot, controlled, pre-post study will be done to&#xD;
      evaluate the feasibility of implementing a bundle of respiratory precautions to all household&#xD;
      contacts of new pulmonary TB cases, compared to standard of care, in primary care in a high&#xD;
      TB incidence area in Santiago. The respiratory bundle in the intervention arm will be&#xD;
      implemented as soon as a new pulmonary TB case is diagnosed, will last 2 weeks and, will&#xD;
      include: (a) provision of N95 masks and strong recommendation of use to all household&#xD;
      contacts and the index case when sharing a room together, (b) recommendation to index case to&#xD;
      sleep in a room alone, with the door closed and avoid sharing room with others, (c) promotion&#xD;
      of strategies to improve house ventilation; and (d) education about TB transmission. The&#xD;
      investigators expect to show that this trial is feasible to proceed with a larger, definitive&#xD;
      cluster randomized controlled trial that will evaluate the intervention effectiveness in&#xD;
      reducing the incidence of new TB infections in household contacts. The results of this study&#xD;
      will help to answer a critical research gap in TB infection control and prevention and, it&#xD;
      will provide a key contribution to future policies regarding TB control and elimination&#xD;
      worldwide. Furthermore, in the new global context of rising infectious agents of pandemic&#xD;
      risk, this work may have an additional potential relevance with respect to the use,&#xD;
      acceptability and transmission prevention potential of a respiratory bundle in the household&#xD;
      setting regarding other respiratory pathogens such as SARS-Cov-2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Pre-post controlled study.&#xD;
Two different health care areas of Santiago (and their corresponding TB clinics) will be allocated to control or intervention arm; after a baseline pre-intervention period.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Participation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To document the proportion of TB cases and household contacts who agree to participate as measured by enrollment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Study compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To document participants compliance with the respiratory bundle as measured by a previously validated adherence questionnaire.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The number of participants assessable at end of follow-up.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of the intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Focus group evaluation (participants and TB nurses perspectives, qualitative outcome).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>New tuberculosis infections</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The number of participants converting from a negative to a positive latent TB test at follow-up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</condition>
  <condition>Household Contacts</condition>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Respiratory Bundle Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention consists of a bundle of measures for respiratory transmission prevention that will be provided during the first 2 weeks of TB treatment of index case.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Under current national guidelines, no systematic recommendation regarding respiratory protection is given for household contacts of TB cases.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Respiratory bundle</intervention_name>
    <description>Provision of N95 masks and strong recommendation of use to all household contacts and the index case when sharing a room together, for 2 weeks&#xD;
Recommendation to index case to sleep in a room alone, with the door closed and avoid sharing room with others during 2 weeks&#xD;
Promotion of strategies to improve house ventilation during 2 weeks&#xD;
Provision of a TB leaflet and nurse education about TB transmission.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Respiratory Bundle Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  all household contacts of a new case of pulmonary TB (smear, culture or PCR positive)&#xD;
             newly diagnosed at each clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  household contacts found to have co-prevalent active TB at enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  household contacts planning to leave the house at the time of enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  household contacts of index cases having already initiated TB treatment for &gt; 48h&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  household contacts of index cases that are currently hospitalized&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>María Elvira Balcells, MD; MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>School of Medicine. Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Romina Seguel, RN</last_name>
    <phone>+56223543508</phone>
    <email>rjseguel@uc.cl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago</city>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Chile</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis, Pulmonary</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

