<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04500119</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00000572</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04500119</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neuronal Mechanisms of Human Episodic Memory</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neuronal Mechanisms of Human Episodic Memory</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Colorado, Denver</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Health Network, Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Boston Children's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, Santa Barbara</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose the research is to better understand how the human brain accomplishes the basic&#xD;
      cognitive tasks of learning new information, recalling stored information, and making&#xD;
      decisions or choices about presented information. These investigations are critical to better&#xD;
      understand human cognition and to design treatments for disorders of learning and memory.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The rapid formation of new memories and the recall of old memories to inform decisions is&#xD;
      essential for human cognition, but the underlying neural mechanisms remain poorly understood.&#xD;
      The long-term goal of this research is a circuit-level understanding of human memory to&#xD;
      enable the development of new treatments for the devastating effects of memory disorders. The&#xD;
      study experiments utilize the rare opportunity to record in-vivo from human single neurons&#xD;
      simultaneously in multiple brain areas in patients undergoing treatment for drug resistant&#xD;
      epilepsy. The overall objective is to continue and expand a multi-institutional (Cedars&#xD;
      Sinai/Caltech, Johns Hopkins, U Toronto, Children's/Harvard, UC Denver, UCSB), integrated,&#xD;
      and multi-disciplinary team. Jointly, the investigators have the expertise and patient volume&#xD;
      to test key predictions on the neural substrate of human memory. The study will utilize a&#xD;
      combination of (i) in-vivo recordings in awake behaving humans assessing memory strength&#xD;
      through confidence ratings, (ii) focal electrical stimulation to test causality, and (iii)&#xD;
      computational analysis and modeling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These techniques will be applied to investigate three overarching hypotheses on the&#xD;
      mechanisms of episodic memory. First, to determine the role of persistent neuronal activity&#xD;
      in translating working memories into longterm declarative memories (Aim 1). Second, to&#xD;
      determine how declarative memories are translated into decisions (Aim 2). Third, to&#xD;
      investigate how event segmentation, temporal binding and reinstatement during temporally&#xD;
      extended experience facilitate episodic memory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The expected outcomes of this work are an unprecedented characterization of how episodic&#xD;
      memories are formed, retrieved and used for decisions, and how temporally extended&#xD;
      experiences are segmented to form distinct but linked episodes. This work is significant&#xD;
      because it moves beyond a &quot;parts list&quot; of neurons and brain areas by testing circuit-based&#xD;
      hypotheses by simultaneously recording single-neurons from multiple frontal cortical and&#xD;
      subcortical temporal lobe areas in humans who are forming, declaring and describing their&#xD;
      memories. The proposed work is unusually innovative because it combines single-neuron&#xD;
      recordings in multiple areas in behaving humans, develops new methods for non-invasive&#xD;
      localization of implanted electrodes and electrical stimulation and directly test&#xD;
      long-standing theoretical predictions on the role of evidence accumulation in memory&#xD;
      retrieval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A second significant innovation is the study team, which combines the patient volume and&#xD;
      expertise of several major centers to maximally utilize the rare neurosurgical opportunities&#xD;
      available to directly study the human nervous system. This innovative approach permits&#xD;
      investigation of circuit-level mechanisms of human memory that cannot be studied&#xD;
      non-invasively in humans nor in animal models. This integrated multi-disciplinary combination&#xD;
      of human in-vivo single-neuron physiology, behavior, and modeling will contribute&#xD;
      significantly to the understanding of the circuits and patterns of neural activity that give&#xD;
      rise to human memory, which is a central goal of human neuroscience in general and the BRAIN&#xD;
      initiative in particular.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 12, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Persistent Neuronal Activity (Firing Rates)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Neuronal firing rates (measured in spike rates per second) of cells in the frontal and temporal lobes during working memory.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Persistent Neuronal Activity (Power)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Power of local field potential bandwidths (measured in amplitude across frequency of the bandwidths) in the frontal and temporal lobes during working memory.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decision Making (Firing Rates)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Neuronal firing rates of cells (measured in spike rates per second) in the frontal and temporal lobes during a decision-making process.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decision Making (Power)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Power of local field potential bandwidths (measured in amplitude across frequency of the bandwidths) in the frontal and temporal lobes during a decision-making process.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decision Making (Timing)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Timing of neuronal discharges (measured in spike rates per second) across the frontal and temporal lobes during a decision-making process.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disruption of learning and memory via electrical stimulation (firing rates)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Measure the change in firing rates of neurons (measured in amplitude across frequency of the bandwidths) after applying small pulse of electrical activity during a learning task.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disruption of learning and memory via electrical stimulation (memory)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Measure the change in memory (measured in spike rates per second) observed after applying small pulse of electrical activity during a learning task.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Epilepsy Intractable</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Behavioral Testing</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Behavioral and Neuronal Recordings</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cedrus RB-844 response pad; Adtech Behnke-Fried micro-electrodes; Neurolynx electrophysiology system; Blackrock Cerestim stimulator</intervention_name>
    <description>Devices listed are components of a single intervention that includes: Record patient responses (Cedrus RB-844), record neuronal activity (Neurolynx) from electrodes (Adtech Behnke-Fried), apply intermittent electrical stimulation (Blackrock Cerestim)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Behavioral Testing</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intractable epilepsy, undergoing invasive monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥13&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full Scale Intelligence Quotient &gt; 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to comprehend and perform simple behavioral tasks by pressing buttons on&#xD;
             laptop computer in response to questions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Determination by clinicians and investigators that a patient is unable to complete the&#xD;
             behavioral tasks required for the protocol due to either cognitive limits,&#xD;
             psychological limits, or pain.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>13 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ueli Rutishauser, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adam Mamelak, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 5, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Adam Mamelak, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Neurosurgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Epilepsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Decision-making</keyword>
  <keyword>Memory</keyword>
  <keyword>Depth Electrode</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

