<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04509180</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0120-161/2020/4</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04509180</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of Treatment Outcomes Between Convergent Procedure and Catheter Ablation for Persistent and Longstanding Persistent Atrial Fibrillation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of Treatment Outcomes Between Convergent Procedure and Catheter Ablation for Persistent and Longstanding Persistent Atrial Fibrillation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Medical Centre Ljubljana</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Medical Centre Ljubljana</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the last 20 years, atrial fibrillation has become one of the leading healthcare burden in&#xD;
      Europe and other developed countries. With an ever-increasing prevalence and incidence,&#xD;
      atrial fibrillation is expected to remain a significant problem in the near future. Due to&#xD;
      numerous detrimental effects atrial fibrillation has on the patient's health, having an&#xD;
      efficient and safe treatment is crucial for managing the problem.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The gold standard for an atrial fibrillation treatment is a catheter ablation. In typical&#xD;
      catheter ablation procedure, triggers in pulmonary veins are addressed with a pulmonary vein&#xD;
      isolation- offering a high long-term success rate in patients with paroxysmal atrial&#xD;
      fibrillation. However, the same cannot be said for persistent and longstanding persistent&#xD;
      atrial fibrillation. Studies have shown that efficiency of catheter ablation for persistent&#xD;
      and longstanding persistent atrial fibrillation, including multiple procedures per patient,&#xD;
      ranges around 50 %. It is postulated that extrapulmonary vein triggers, such as foci located&#xD;
      in the posterior wall of the left atrium, play an important role in initiating and&#xD;
      maintaining persistent and longstanding persistent atrial fibrillation. In the past, to&#xD;
      address this issue, a convergent procedure was developed. In convergent procedure an&#xD;
      epicardial ablation of posterior wall is performed through a subxyphoid window. Next, an&#xD;
      endocardial ablation with an ablation catheter is performed to isolate pulmonary veins.&#xD;
      Because the epicardial lesions are applied in the opposite direction and not towards the&#xD;
      esophagus, ablation of posterior wall can safely be performed. The procedure offers a high&#xD;
      long-term success rate (85%) in patients with persistent and longstanding persistent atrial&#xD;
      fibrillation. However, due to higher associated invasiveness, the convergent procedure&#xD;
      carries a higher risk of complications compared with catheter ablation (4 % vs 9 %).&#xD;
&#xD;
      With advancements in ablation catheter technology, such as continuous force measurement at&#xD;
      the tip of the catheter, the depth and volume of the lesion can be estimated. This&#xD;
      information greatly increases the reliability of lesion formation. The operator can thus&#xD;
      effectively apply lesions to the posterior wall of the left atrium more safely in regards to&#xD;
      the collateral damage to the esophagus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives of the study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare procedural, safety and efficiency profile of convergent procedure with&#xD;
           catheter ablation procedure, both targeting pulmonary veins triggers and triggers&#xD;
           located in the posterior wall of the left atrium.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare long-term success rate of convergent procedure with catheter ablation&#xD;
           procedure, both targeting pulmonary veins triggers and triggers located in the posterior&#xD;
           wall of the left atrium.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Noninferiority of catheter ablation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>arrhythmia-free survival registered with an implantable loop recorder</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in AF burden</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>registered with an implantable loop recorder</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in acute success rate of posterior wall isolation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>registered with voltage and activation mapping during the index procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in complication rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>procedure related complications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Persistent Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <condition>Longstanding Persistent Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Catheter ablation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergoing catheter procedure will be put under conscious sedation and local anesthesia. Pulmonary vein isolation and posterior wall isolation will be performed with a radiofrequency ablation catheter (20-45W, open-tip irrigation). Ablation index will be used for the lesion formation guidance (450-500 on anterior aspects; 350-400 on the posterior aspects). A wide antral circumferential ablation will be performed for pulmonary veins and a box lesion set for the posterior left atrial wall. Voltage mapping and signal analysis performed by the operator will be used to assess electrical isolation of the pulmonary veins and posterior wall and to identify gaps in ablation lines. At the end of procedure, an implantable loop recorder will be inserted in the left parasternal region.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Convergent group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients undergoing convergent procedure will be put under general anesthesia. A minimally invasive epicardial radiofrequency ablation (30W, 90s) of posterior wall will be performed through a subxiphoid window. Monitoring of the esophageal temperature will be performed with an esophageal temperature probe set at 38°C. Next, an endocardial radiofrequency ablation (20-40W, open-tip irrigation; ablation index 450-500 anteriorly and 350-400 posteriorly) of pulmonary veins in a wide antral circumferential fashion will be performed. Voltage mapping and signal analysis performed by the operator will be used to assess the electrical isolation of the pulmonary veins and posterior wall and to identify the gaps in ablation lines. At the end of procedure, an implantable loop recorder will be inserted in the left parasternal region.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Catheter ablation</intervention_name>
    <description>Endovascular approach</description>
    <arm_group_label>Catheter ablation group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Convergent procedure</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical and endovascular approach</description>
    <arm_group_label>Convergent group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed persistent and/or long-term&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failed medical therapy with antiarrhythmic drug therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected life expectancy of less than one year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous heart operation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous ablation procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Left ventricular ejection fraction below 30 %&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe valvular heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute coronary syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diminished functional capacity due to non-cardiac co-morbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jus Ksela, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+386 1 522 8251</phone>
    <email>jus.ksela@kclj.si</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Matevz Jan, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+386 1 522 8238</phone>
    <email>matevz.jan@kclj.so</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UMC Ljubljana</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ljubljana</city>
        <zip>1000</zip>
        <country>Slovenia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matevž Jan, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0038615228238</phone>
      <email>matevz.jan@kclj.si</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Tine Prolič Kalinšek, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0038615228238</phone>
      <email>tine.prolic.kalinsek@icloud.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Slovenia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Medical Centre Ljubljana</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Matevz Jan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

