<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04505813</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NEXI-002-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04505813</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Antigen-specific T Cell Therapy for Patients With Relapsed Refractory Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 / 2 Study to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of Adoptively Transferred Autologous T Cells in Patients With Relapsed Refractory Multiple Myeloma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NexImmune Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NexImmune Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Research study is being done to characterize the safety, tolerability, and preliminary&#xD;
      antitumor activity of the NEXI-002 T cell product (a new experimental therapy), which&#xD;
      contains populations of CD8+ T cells targeting multiple Myeloma associated antigen peptides&#xD;
      in patients with relapsed refractory multiple myeloma (MM).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will enroll patients with MM who have relapsed or are refractory to standard lines&#xD;
      of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The enrolled patients will undergo bridging therapy for the purposes of disease control while&#xD;
      the NEXI-002 T cell product is being manufactured. Choice of bridging therapy administered&#xD;
      will be per the Investigator's discretion, but is limited to acceptable agents as specified&#xD;
      in the protocol. Bridging therapy will be administered prior to lymphodepleting (LD) therapy,&#xD;
      with the last dose of the bridging therapy administered ≥ 14 days prior to initiation of LD&#xD;
      therapy. Within 72 hours after completing LD therapy, patients will receive a single IV&#xD;
      infusion of the NEXI-002 T cell product.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The NEXI-002 is an adoptive cellular therapy product which contains populations of&#xD;
      antigen-specific CD8+ T cells. The antigen-specific CD8+ T cells in the NEXI-002 T cell&#xD;
      product are derived from Peripheral Blood Mononuclear Cells (PBMC) obtained from the original&#xD;
      stem cell donor. During the manufacturing process, these cells are primed and expanded ex&#xD;
      vivo using nano-size artificial Antigen Presenting Cells (aAPC) loaded with five leukemia&#xD;
      associated antigen peptides in combination with a proprietary T cell enrichment and expansion&#xD;
      process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The NEXI-002 T cell product is restricted to patients that are HLA-A2.01 allele positive for&#xD;
      this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are two parts to this study, a Safety Evaluation Phase and a Dose Expansion Phase. The&#xD;
      Safety Evaluation Phase will determine the safety and tolerability of a single dose of&#xD;
      NEXI-002 T cell product, and will consist of Dose Escalation at two dose levels - each with&#xD;
      cohorts of three patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When all three patients at Dose Level 1 have dosed and cleared the DLT period, three&#xD;
      additional patients will be enrolled at Dose Level 2. When three patients have cleared the&#xD;
      DLT period at the highest dose level, that dose will be advanced to the Dose Expansion Phase.&#xD;
      The Dose Expansion Phase will enroll up to 16 additional patients to further define the&#xD;
      safety and evaluate the initial anti-tumor efficacy of the NEXI- 002 T cell product at the&#xD;
      dose established from the Safety Evaluation Phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will enter a Post-Treatment Follow-Up period after infusion of the NEXI- 002 T&#xD;
      cell product. During this phase, all patients will be monitored for AEs and followed for&#xD;
      anti-leukemia response until the end of study visit is complete (up to one year).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional assessments for safety, disease status, and other secondary and exploratory&#xD;
      endpoints will also be monitored during the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be followed for overall survival (OS) from time of disease progression&#xD;
      until the last visit of the last patient. During this time, patients will be followed via&#xD;
      telephone or other electronic contact at 12 week intervals for monitoring of OS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs) events</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>1) Dose Limiting Toxicities (DLTs).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progressive Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Median Progressive free Survival (PFS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Survival (Rate)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival (OS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events (AEs) Reporting</measure>
    <time_frame>At year 1</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of TEAEs leading to study withdrawal</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs) events (AEs) Reporting</measure>
    <time_frame>at year 1</time_frame>
    <description>Cytokine Release Syndrome (CRS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs)events (AEs) Reporting (ICANS)</measure>
    <time_frame>at year 1</time_frame>
    <description>Immune effector Cell-Associated Neurotoxicity Syndrome (ICANS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs)events (AEs) Reporting-TEAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>At year 1</time_frame>
    <description>For Incidence of TEAEs and serious TEAEs (Treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) are defined as those AEs that started on or after LD therapy or that worsened after LD therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs)events (AEs) Reporting-Infusion Reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>At year 1</time_frame>
    <description>Infusion Related Reactions (IRR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">22</enrollment>
  <condition>Relapsed Refractory Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Evaluation Phase</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment with NEXI-002 T cells, derived from PBMCs of the patient</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Phase</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose Expansion Phase to further define the safety, tolerability and initial anti-tumor efficacy of the NEXI- 002 T cell product at the dose established from the Safety Evaluation Phase.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>NEXI-002 T Cells</intervention_name>
    <description>The NEXI-001 T cell product will be administered as a single IV infusion to patients within 72 hours after completing LD therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose Expansion Phase</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Safety Evaluation Phase</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Ability to provide informed consent and documentation of informed consent prior to&#xD;
             initiation of any study-related tests or procedures that are not part of&#xD;
             standard-of-care for the patient's disease. Patients must also be willing and able to&#xD;
             comply with study procedures, including the acquisition of specified research&#xD;
             specimens&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age ≥ 18 years old &amp; life expectancy &gt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Expression of HLA-A*0201 as determined by high resolution sequence-based typing method&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 or 1 with exception&#xD;
             of ECOG &gt; 1 if related to recent bone fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must have confirmed diagnosis of MM&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have identified relapsed/refractory disease which includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Previous therapy consisting of at least three (3) standard regimens, including a&#xD;
                  proteasome inhibitor, IMiD, or anti-CD38 targeting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Note: Induction therapy, autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT) &amp;&#xD;
                  maintenance therapy if given sequentially without intervening progressive disease&#xD;
                  (PD) are considered one 'regimen'&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Refractory MM may be defined as disease that is refractory to treatment while on&#xD;
                  therapy or that shows progression within 60 days of the last therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have measurable disease as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Serum M protein ≥ 0.5 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Urine M protein ≥ 200 mg/24hr&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum free light chains (FLC) ≥ 10 mg/dL with abnormal FLC ratio Note: Patients&#xD;
                  with IgA MM in whom serum protein electrophoresis (sPEP) is deemed unreliable,&#xD;
                  due to co-migration of normal serum proteins with the paraprotein in the β&#xD;
                  region, may be considered eligible as long as total serum IgA level is &gt; normal&#xD;
                  range.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Acceptable laboratory parameters as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. AST/ALT ≤ 2.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 × ULN, except patients with Gilbert's syndrome, who may&#xD;
                  enroll if the conjugated bilirubin is within normal limits&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum creatinine ≤ 2.5 mg/dL or estimated creatinine clearance (CL) ≥ 30 mL/min &amp;&#xD;
                  not dialysis-dependent&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. ALC &gt; 1000 cells/µL&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Recovery to Grade 1 or baseline of non-hematologic toxicities from prior treatments,&#xD;
             excluding alopecia &amp; Grade 2 peripheral neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Female patients of childbearing potential must test negative for pregnancy at&#xD;
             enrollment and during the study. Sexually active women of child-bearing potential,&#xD;
             unless surgically sterile, must be willing to use a highly effective method of birth&#xD;
             control defined as those which result in a low failure rate (i.e., less than 1% per&#xD;
             year) such as implants, injectables, combined oral contraceptives, intra-uterine&#xD;
             devices (IUDs) or vasectomized partner&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Male patients with partners of childbearing potential must be either vasectomized or&#xD;
             agree to use a condom in addition to having their partners use another method of&#xD;
             contraception resulting in a highly effective method of birth control defined as those&#xD;
             which result in a low failure rate (i.e., less than 1% per year) such as implants,&#xD;
             injectables, combined oral contraceptives, or IUDs. Patients should not have sexual&#xD;
             intercourse with females who are either pregnant or lactating without double-barrier&#xD;
             contraception • Is not pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father&#xD;
             children within the projected duration of the trial, starting with the prescreening or&#xD;
             screening visit through one year from administration of NEXI-002 T cells&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have active cerebral or meningeal disease related to the underlying malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have hemolytic anemia, plasma cell leukemia, Waldenstrom's macroglobulinemia, POEMS&#xD;
             syndrome, amyloidosis, plasmacytoma, significant autoimmune or other malignant disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have active or uncontrolled infections with positive cultures and/or requiring&#xD;
             treatment with IV anti-infective agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Echocardiogram or MUGA with left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 45%&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of clinically significant cardiovascular disease including but not limited to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Myocardial infarction or unstable angina within the 6 months prior to the&#xD;
                  initiation of study&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months prior to initiation of study&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Clinically significant cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Uncontrolled hypertension: systolic blood pressure (SBP) &gt; 180 mmHg, diastolic&#xD;
                  blood pressure (DBP) &gt; 100 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association [NYHA] class III-IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Pericarditis or clinically significant pericardial effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Myocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Clinically significant pulmonary compromise, including a requirement for supplemental&#xD;
             oxygen use to maintain adequate oxygenation&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Eligible patients will not be on any steroids ≥10 mg per day prednisone or equivalent&#xD;
             or other immunosuppressants such as tacrolimus, cyclosporine, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Intermittent topical, inhaled or intranasal corticosteroids are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of symptomatic deep vein thrombosis (DVT) or pulmonary embolism (PE) requiring&#xD;
             systemic anticoagulation within 6 months before enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of autoimmune disease (e.g., Crohn's, rheumatoid arthritis, systemic lupus&#xD;
             erythematosus, etc.) resulting in end organ injury or requiring systemic&#xD;
             immunosuppression / systemic disease modifying agents within the last 2 year prior to&#xD;
             enrollment. Subjects with a history of autoimmune-related hypothyroidism on a stable&#xD;
             dose of thyroid replacement hormone and subjects with controlled Type 1 diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus on a stable insulin regimen may be eligible for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) seropositive; HIV testing within 2 years of&#xD;
             enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Seropositive for and with evidence of active viral infection with hepatitis B virus&#xD;
             (HBV). Patients who are hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) negative and HBV viral DNA&#xD;
             negative are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients who had HBV but have received an antiviral treatment and show&#xD;
                  non-detectable viral DNA for 6 months are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients who are seropositive because of HBV vaccine are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Seropositive for and with active viral infection with hepatitis C virus (HCV)&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Patients who had HCV but have received an antiviral treatment and show no&#xD;
             detectable HCV viral DNA for 6 months are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Second primary invasive malignancy that has not been in remission for more than 2&#xD;
             years. Exceptions that do not require a 2-year remission include: non-melanoma skin&#xD;
             cancer; carcinoma in situ (cervix, bladder, breast, etc.) or squamous intraepithelial&#xD;
             lesion on Pap smear; localized prostate cancer (Gleason score &lt; 6); or resected&#xD;
             melanoma in situ&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of trauma or major surgery within 4 weeks prior to the initiation of study&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Any serious underlying medical or psychiatric condition that would impair the ability&#xD;
             of the patient to receive or tolerate the planned treatment and follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Known hypersensitivity to any component of NEXI-002 T cells, cyclophosphamide,&#xD;
             fludarabine or tocilizumab&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Vaccination with any live virus vaccine within 6 weeks prior to the initiation of&#xD;
             study treatment. Inactivated annual influenza vaccination is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Dementia or altered mental status that would preclude understanding and rendering of&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of seizures, aphasia, psychosis or other chronic clinically significant&#xD;
             neurologic disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Patients with remote history of seizures that are well controlled on anti-seizure&#xD;
             medications and without any seizure episode for 6 months are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Any issue that in the opinion of the investigator, would contraindicate the patient's&#xD;
             participation in the study or confound the results of the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan Varela, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Advent Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Han Myint, MD</last_name>
    <phone>3018259810</phone>
    <phone_ext>118</phone_ext>
    <email>hmyint@neximmune.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gloria Hoyah</last_name>
    <phone>3018259810</phone>
    <phone_ext>138</phone_ext>
    <email>ghoyah@neximmune.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>City of Hope Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duarte</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Myo Htut, MD</last_name>
      <phone>626-256-4673</phone>
      <phone_ext>82405</phone_ext>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Main Contain Number</last_name>
      <phone>626-256-4673</phone>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Myo Htut, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stephen Forman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>L. Elizabeth Budde, MD. PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Samer Khaled, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chatchada Karanes, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amirita Krishnan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nitya Nathwani, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Rosenzweig, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tanya Siddiqi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shirong Wang, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Advent Health Medical Group Blood &amp; Marrow Transplant</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orlando</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32804</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Juan Varela, MD</last_name>
      <phone>407-303-2070</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan Varela, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven C Goldstein, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rushang Dilipkumar Patel, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jason W Balls, PA</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Amy L Browning, ARNP</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cory M Edgar, PA</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Megan F Smith, ARNP</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicole Marsden, DNP, FNP-BC</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shahram Mori, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tori Smith, ARNP</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Courtney P McVey, PA</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Paul Richardson, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul Richardson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karmanos Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Detroit</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48201</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrew Kin, MD</last_name>
      <phone>313-576-8745</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Research Office</last_name>
      <phone>1-800-527-6266</phone>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dipenkumar Modi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Uberti, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Abdhinav Deol, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Asif Alavi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Melissa Runge-Morris, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erlene Seymour, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jeffrey Zonder, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dahlia Sano, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Charles Schiffer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>David H. Koch Center for Cancer Care at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10021</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Miguel-Angel Perales, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Miguel-Angel Perales, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David Marin, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Marin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 6, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 3, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

