<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04509115</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2000027561</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04509115</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Variation in Opioid Prescribing and Use for Acute Pain in Diverse Populations</brief_title>
  <official_title>Real-World Data to Assess Variation in Opioid Prescribing and Use for Acute Pain in Diverse Populations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Food and Drug Administration (FDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will characterize patient pain and opioid use after an initial opioid prescription&#xD;
      for acute pain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to characterize patient pain and opioid use after an initial&#xD;
      opioid prescription for acute pain. The investigators aim to enroll a total of 300 patients&#xD;
      receiving a prescription for an opioid in primary and urgent care, inpatient care (child&#xD;
      birth and total knee arthroplasty), and in the emergency department. Patients not currently&#xD;
      using opioids who receive a new short-acting opioid prescription for acute pain will be&#xD;
      recruited and followed prospectively for 180 days to assess pain trajectories, analgesic and&#xD;
      non-pharmacologic treatment use, activity, and health care service use. The patient-centered&#xD;
      health data sharing platform (Hugo) will be used to collect patient-reported outcomes and&#xD;
      structured data from pharmacy and electronic health records patient portals as well as&#xD;
      patient-generated data collected through personal digital devices (Fitbit).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific aims&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess patients' pain and opioid use patterns in episodes of acute pain for which&#xD;
           opioids were prescribed, characterizing pain severity and persistence, as well as other&#xD;
           prescription and over-the-counter pain medication use&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To examine associations between patient demographic, clinical and emotional&#xD;
           characteristics and outcomes of pain severity and persistence, opioid and non-opioid&#xD;
           treatment patterns, satisfaction with care, and barriers to care&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To assess how patients handled unused opioids&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid Pain medication use</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days using any opioid medications</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-Opioid pain medication and treatment use</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days using any non-opioid drugs/treatments</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain medication use concordant with directions for use</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of directions for use and actual use: For each day the person takes opioids, measure whether the number of pills taken falls within the range prescribed, below the prescribed range, or above the prescribed range. The overall proportion of days taking less than the prescribed range, within the prescribed range, and over the prescribed range will be calculated for each patient and the distribution of these measures will be plotted as histograms and reported as the median, 25th percentile and 75th percentile.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to opioid discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>From initial opioid use to the day on which the last opioid was taken, up to 180 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Discontinuation defined as 30 days with no opioid use. . If 30 days pass with no opioid use, but the participant takes an opioid on the 31st day, a new episode of opioid use will be considered to have started and the time to opioid discontinuation will again be measured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to pain resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Pain resolution will be defined as patient no longer indicating pain in the body area initially treated, as indicated by either a) an overall pain rating of 0 on the brief pain inventory scale from 0 to 10, with 0 being no pain and 10 the worst pain imaginable, or b) the patient no longer selects the body area initially treated when completing the body map of areas where patient is experiencing pain).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average activity levels</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Trajectory of the average steps per day registered by the Fitbit Inspire over time (decreasing, increasing, stable) for the periods between enrollment and stopping opioids, enrollment and pain resolution</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-reported satisfaction with health care received to treat pain: distribution of responses. &quot;Treatment satisfaction: In general, how satisfied are you with the health care you received to treat your pain? Very satisfied; Somewhat satisfied; Somewhat dissatisfied; Very dissatisfied&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Barriers to treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Reported barriers to accessing additional treatment: proportion reporting difficulty with one or more of the following: getting a refill, difficulty getting a pharmacy to fill, getting insurance to pay for treatment, being able to afford to pay for treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of pain medications used</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Use patterns of different pain medications (opioid and any combination ingredients), including the strength, and number of pills dispensed (in MME)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient opioid use progression</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients progressing to: long-term use of opioids (90+ days of use or 120+ days' supply filled)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient chronic pain progression</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients progressing to chronic pain (pain lasts 90+ days)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Prescription Pain Medication Misuse short-form; selected items</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>We will assess this outcome with 5 survey items drawn from the Patient-Reported Outcomes Measurement Information System (PROMIS) Prescription Pain Medication Misuse short-form. The total score for these 5 items ranges from 5 to 25 with 25 signaling greatest misuse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Storage and disposal guidance</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients that report receiving: information on how to properly dispose of medication, and/or on the importance of disposing of unused medication.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid Storage Methods</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients that report storing opioids in: a locked location (proportion reporting always or almost always), a latched location (proportion reporting always or almost always), in the original bottle (proportion reporting always or almost always)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Unused Opioids</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of opioids left over after opioid discontinuation and estimated amount used during study period Measured in absolute amounts-e.g., mg of oxycodone-as well as MME and tablets</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated Opioid Use</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Based on left over opioids, amount used during study period Measured in absolute amounts-e.g., mg of oxycodone-as well as MME and tablets</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid Disposal</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients reporting each disposal method including disposing of drug in garbage, flushed down toilet, returned to police, returned to pharmacy, passed on to someone else, kept for future use/did not dispose, used up all opioids. Motivations for disposing of or keeping leftover drugs, proportion reporting each survey response.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Motivations for disposing or keeping leftover drugs</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 180 days</time_frame>
    <description>We will assess this outcome with 16 survey items drawn from the University of South Florida and Purdue Pharma study of disposal. We will report on the proportion of participants endorsing each item. Representative items include inconvenience, risk of disposal, and potential need for opioids in the future</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1550</enrollment>
  <condition>Opioid Use</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Prescribing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients given short-acting opioid prescription</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients not currently using opioids who receive a new short-acting opioid prescription for acute pain will be recruited.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Short-acting opioid prescription for acute pain</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients not currently using opioids who receive a new short-acting opioid prescription as part of routine care for acute pain will be recruited and followed prospectively for 180 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients given short-acting opioid prescription</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators will recruit a total of 1,550 patients receiving primary and urgent care,&#xD;
        emergency department care, inpatient care (child birth and total knee arthroplasty), and&#xD;
        dental care in 5 healthcare systems. Participants must be 18 years or older, be English- or&#xD;
        Spanish-speaking, and be willing and able to consent for themselves.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English- or Spanish-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experiencing acute pain of less than 8 weeks duration at the time the opioid is&#xD;
             prescribed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received prescription for opioid analgesic at visit; opioids included in the study&#xD;
             will be all FDA-approved enteral, transdermal, and transmucosal opioid analgesics&#xD;
             including the most common: hydrocodone (except cough and anti-diarrheal medications),&#xD;
             oxycodone, codeine (except cough medications), tramadol, morphine, hydromorphone.&#xD;
             Receipt of a prescription for the following is not an exclusion: buprenorphine (as an&#xD;
             analgesic), butorphanol, dihydrocodeine, fentanyl, meperidine, methadone (as an&#xD;
             analgesic), oxymorphone, pentazocine, sufentanil, and tapentadol. All of these opioids&#xD;
             are included in any combinations with acetaminophen, aspirin, ibuprofen, naloxone,&#xD;
             etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-report of no opioid use (no use of prescribed opioids or illicit opioids,&#xD;
             including medical or non-medical use) in the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to give consent and participate in study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to access a device with web access (laptop, desktop, smartphone, or tablet) daily&#xD;
             to complete study surveys&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to connect Fitbit to a mobile device (smartphone or tablet) that can regularly&#xD;
             link to Hugo for data transfer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to use the health data sharing platform&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Released/discharged to home after their visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain thought to be caused by a systemic disease very likely to progress to chronic&#xD;
             pain (e.g., sickle cell disease, fibromyalgia, lupus, multiple sclerosis, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cancer or end-of-life pain;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to give consent and be enrolled within 3 days of their visit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joseph Ross, MD, MHS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Joseph Ross, MD, MHS</last_name>
    <phone>2037852987</phone>
    <email>joseph.ross@yale.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>CERSI</last_name>
    <email>cersi@yale.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35233</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gregg Gilbert, DDS, MBS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Page, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cedars Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Teryl Nuckols, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sam Torbati, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale-New Haven Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jessica Ritchie, MPH</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joseph Ross, MD, MHS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nilay Shah, PhD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Molly Jeffery, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Monument Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rapid City</city>
        <state>South Dakota</state>
        <zip>57701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Stephen Tamang, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Analgesics, Opioid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

