<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04502589</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HM20015846</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R21AA026681</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04502589</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open Label Pilot Study of Perampanel for the Treatment of Alcohol Use Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Open Label Pilot Study of Perampanel for the Treatment of Alcohol Use Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Virginia Commonwealth University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Virginia Commonwealth University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to test the safety, tolerability, and effectiveness of&#xD;
      the drug Perampanel when used in persons who drink and wish to stop drinking. Perampanel has&#xD;
      been approved by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) for the treatment of seizures&#xD;
      but has not yet been approved to treat alcohol use disorders. For this reason, it is&#xD;
      considered an investigational drug. Some people in this study will receive Perampanel alone&#xD;
      and some people will receive Perampanel and Disulfiram, this will be determined by the&#xD;
      pharmacy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants will be asked to take a medication (Perampanel or Perampanel + Disulfiram) every&#xD;
      day for approximately 8 weeks and have weekly study visits. At these visits, participants&#xD;
      will be asked questions about their medical history, drinking behavior and life events, have&#xD;
      bloodwork checked routinely, have regular medication counseling, and perform some computer&#xD;
      tasks. Throughout the study, there will be regular phone calls from staff. Participants will&#xD;
      also be asked to use a device called &quot;Soberlink&quot; which is like an at-home breathalyzer test&#xD;
      to help track progress throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly assigned (like the flip of a coin) to receive either Perampanel&#xD;
      alone or Peramanel and Disulfiram.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in this study will last up to 10 weeks. Approximately 20 individuals will&#xD;
      participate in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will sequence all or part of participant's DNA. This is a necessary part of the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before starting the study, participants may be referred to an alcohol detoxification program&#xD;
      (medical treatment of an alcoholic), if clinically indicated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>20 subjects with AUD will be randomized 1:1 to one of two groups; perampanel by itself, and perampanel combined with disulfiram.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent abstinent days</measure>
    <time_frame>End of treatment, up to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Participant will report the number of alcoholic drinks they consumed during the previous weeks period. Based on participant report, the percent of days the participant was abstinent will be calculated over the 8 week active treatment period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in alcohol craving</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to end of treatment, up to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Alcohol craving will be assess using the Alcohol Urge Questionnaire (AUG). The AUG is an 8-item survey asking participants to rate their craving for alcohol on a 1 to 7 scale. The answers are summed yielding a score ranging from 7 to 56 with higher scores indicated higher alcohol craving.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent heavy drinking days</measure>
    <time_frame>End of treatment, Up to 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Participant will report the number of alcoholic drinks they consumed during the previous weeks period. Based on participant report, the percent of days the participant drank heavily will be calculated over the 8 week active treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcohol Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>perampanel by itself</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Perapanel with Disulfiram</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Perampanel Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be titrated over 3 weeks to a target dose of 8mg perampanel daily in both groups</description>
    <arm_group_label>Perapanel with Disulfiram</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>perampanel by itself</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Disulfiram</intervention_name>
    <description>Disulfiram will be kept at 250mg daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Perapanel with Disulfiram</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Men and women ages 21-70 with DSM-5 AUD;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. regular heavy drinkers as defined by averaging ≥ 2 heavy drinking days per week over&#xD;
             the 60 days baseline pre-treatment TLFB, and recognize a need to completely stop&#xD;
             drinking;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. willingness to provide written, informed consent to participate in the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Individuals with LFTs that are no more than 2-3 times above the normal levels and with&#xD;
             a Child-Pugh score of no greater than 5 will be included and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. women of child-bearing potential (i.e., no hysterectomy, bilateral oophorectomy, or&#xD;
             tubal ligation or &lt;2 years postmenopausal), must be non-lactating, practicing a&#xD;
             reliable method of birth control, and have a negative serum pregnancy test prior to&#xD;
             initiation of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. a current, clinically significant physical disease [i.e., neurologic, renal,&#xD;
             pulmonary, cardiovascular, hepatic] on the basis of medical history, physical&#xD;
             examination, or routine laboratory evaluation that, in the context of the study would&#xD;
             represent a risk to the subject, or significant laboratory abnormalities related to&#xD;
             hepatic function such as marked elevations of hepatic aminotransferase levels (i.e.,&#xD;
             AST and ALT) or direct bilirubin;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. history of renal compromise or current renal disease (as evidenced by serum creatinine&#xD;
             above our laboratory's reference limit of 1.7 mg/dL;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. history of seizure disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. use of any of a number of medications that might prominently influence drinking&#xD;
             patterns or cause risk of harm or injury (e.g., other anticonvulsants, medications to&#xD;
             treat AUD, opioid pain medication), currently taking CNS depressants (e.g.&#xD;
             benzodiazepines, barbiturates, sedating antihistamines;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. schizophrenia, bipolar disorder, current major depressive episode, or substantial&#xD;
             suicide or violence risk on the basis of history or psychiatric examination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. currently dependent on stimulants, opioids or sedatives;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. subjects with any substantial alcohol withdrawal will be required to be detoxified by&#xD;
             regular clinical services prior to study entry;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. are currently taking any medication that is a moderate to strong CYP3A4 inhibitor or&#xD;
             inducer if participants are required to initiate these medications by an outside&#xD;
             provider during the course of this study, they will be tapered off the study regimen&#xD;
             and we will have them terminate early)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. are taking phenytoin or warfarin&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Albert Arias, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Virginia Commonwealth University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Commonwealth University Inst. for Drug and Alcohol Studies</name>
      <address>
        <city>Richmond</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mandy Adams, CRC</last_name>
      <phone>804-828-3784</phone>
      <email>msadams@vcu.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Albert Arias, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 4, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disulfiram</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

