<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04508699</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R21DC018865</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04508699</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Semantic Learning Deficits in School Age Children With Developmental Language Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Semantic Learning Deficits in School Age Children With Developmental Language Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>San Diego State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>San Diego State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      School age children with developmental language disorder (DLD) have known semantic learning&#xD;
      deficits but what is less well understood is why semantic learning is difficult for these&#xD;
      children. This project will combine behavioral and brain methods to investigate the cognitive&#xD;
      and linguistic processes underlying semantic learning in children with DLD compared to&#xD;
      typically developing peers. The outcomes will have implications for semantic learning&#xD;
      intervention approaches in DLD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This project will elucidate deficits in learning semantic information in developmental&#xD;
      language disorder (DLD, formerly referred to as specific language impairment) by combining&#xD;
      behavioral and neural measures to examine differences in the semantic learning process&#xD;
      between school-age children with and without DLD. Vocabulary knowledge, particularly semantic&#xD;
      knowledge, has a critical influence on reading comprehension and academic success. Despite&#xD;
      the strong association between vocabulary knowledge and academic success, vocabulary is an&#xD;
      under-recognized area of deficit in school-age children with DLD. Younger children with DLD&#xD;
      have well-established deficits in vocabulary and word learning and weaknesses in semantic&#xD;
      knowledge. Additionally, the rate of vocabulary growth in children with DLD decreases&#xD;
      compared to typically developing peers around age 10 and semantic representations of known&#xD;
      vocabulary items are sparse. Even with this knowledge, the field's ability to make progress&#xD;
      toward improved semantic learning in school age DLD is hindered by the lack of basic&#xD;
      information on the underlying nature of the semantic learning deficits in this population.&#xD;
      This project establishes how and why semantic learning differs between school-age children&#xD;
      with and without DLD, providing a much-needed theoretical foundation for clinical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Storkel, expanding on an adult word learning model by Leach and Samuel, provides a clearly&#xD;
      testable account of word learning that has been used with children with DLD. This account&#xD;
      involves three processes: 1) triggering, in which a new lexical encounter is compared to&#xD;
      existing lexical representations, 2) configuration, which adds information to the expanding&#xD;
      lexical representation, and 3) engagement, which examines how the new lexical representation&#xD;
      behaves dynamically with existing representations. The configuration process is arguably the&#xD;
      most critical for semantic development. Successful configuration requires the simultaneous&#xD;
      engagement of cognitive and linguistic processes, such as attention, inhibition, working&#xD;
      memory, and semantic and syntactic processing. While it is widely accepted that configuration&#xD;
      is the most affected word learning process in DLD, what is unknown is what underlies deficits&#xD;
      in configuration and whether these deficits vary across the DLD profile. These questions are&#xD;
      further compounded by difficulty measuring configuration and associated processes, given that&#xD;
      they are largely internal, and therefore invisible. Electroencephalography (EEG) addresses&#xD;
      this invisibility problem by allowing for a real-time examination of unconscious levels of&#xD;
      semantic learning and cognitive and linguistic processes. A combined EEG-behavioral methods&#xD;
      approach can illustrate how children with DLD are approaching configuration in terms of the&#xD;
      relative contribution of these processes. The central hypothesis of this research is that&#xD;
      children with DLD engage cognitive and linguistic processes at different points during&#xD;
      configuration compared to their typical peers, resulting in poorer semantic learning&#xD;
      outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test the central hypothesis, the investigators will record behavioral and EEG data from&#xD;
      10-12 year old children with DLD and typical-language peers as they complete a semantic&#xD;
      learning task. This age aligns with the point where vocabulary growth rates in DLD further&#xD;
      diverge from typical peers [6]. In the semantic learning task, children listen to sets of&#xD;
      three sentences that all end with the same nonword: half of the sentence triplets support&#xD;
      learning meaning of the nonword, half do not. The investigators will analyze EEG data for&#xD;
      event-related potentials (ERPs) as well as changes in neural oscillations (time frequency&#xD;
      analysis). The investigators will combine EEG and behavioral measures to examine the&#xD;
      following aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1. To investigate the cognitive and linguistic processes underlying configuration in&#xD;
      children with DLD and typical language (TL) peers. This aim will include data from the&#xD;
      semantic learning task. Based on the assessment of behavioral outcomes, the investigators&#xD;
      predict that the TL group will be more accurate in semantic learning than the DLD group. ERP&#xD;
      analyses will focus on the N400 component, associated with semantic processing. Time&#xD;
      frequency analysis will focus on changes in the theta (4-8 Hz) and alpha (8-12 Hz) frequency&#xD;
      bands, typically associated with lexical retrieval and attention/inhibition, respectively.&#xD;
      For both neural measures, the investigators predict engagement of the same components (N400,&#xD;
      theta, alpha) across groups but different patterns of change in those components during&#xD;
      configuration between groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2. To investigate individual differences in configuration in children with DLD and TL&#xD;
      peers. This aim will include data from the semantic learning task and a behavioral assessment&#xD;
      battery. Assessment of behavioral data will focus the types of errors children make during&#xD;
      semantic learning. The investigators expect that children with DLD will provide incorrect&#xD;
      meanings for the nonword that best fit with the first sentence in the triplet and that TL&#xD;
      children will provide incorrect meanings that best fit with the last sentence. The&#xD;
      investigators will also examine individual differences related to semantic learning outcomes&#xD;
      and fine-grained differences in N400 learning effects across groups. Here, the investigators&#xD;
      expect that individual differences in general language ability and semantic knowledge,&#xD;
      measured via the behavioral assessment battery, will be most predictive of both behavioral&#xD;
      semantic learning and N400 change during learning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Compare behavioral and EEG outcomes of semantic learning in children with and without developmental language disorder</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Some participants and care providers might not be aware of their child's language impairment</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>mean percent correct semantic meaning identification</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately following treatment, on the same day as treatment</time_frame>
    <description>accuracy on the semantic learning task (did they identify when there was a meaning and when there was not)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in the N400 mean amplitude at the word being learned across presentations of the new word</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately following treatment, on the same day as treatment</time_frame>
    <description>analysis of the N400 erp component related to attaching semantic meaning</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>change in the alpha and theta band power at the word being learned across presentations of the new word</measure>
    <time_frame>immediately following treatment, on the same day as treatment</time_frame>
    <description>analysis of the theta and alpha frequency bands related to attaching semantic meaning</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Evaluation of Language Fundamentals - 5th edition</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>standardized language omnibus measure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Test of Integrated Language and Literacy Skills, Vocabulary awareness subtest</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>standardized semantic knowledge measures</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children - 5th edition, nonverbal index</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>standardized nonverbal cognition assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nonword repetition task</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>experimental task gauging phonological memory, participants are asked to repeat made up words</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Flanker inhibitory control and attention task</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Experimental measure of inhibition and attention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Developmental Language Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Developmental language disorder</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Children with language impairment but in the absence of cognitive deficits</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Typical language</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Children with typical language development and typical cognitive development</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>semantic learning</intervention_name>
    <description>Experimental semantic learning from linguistic context task</description>
    <arm_group_label>Developmental language disorder</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Typical language</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of typical language development or history of language or literacy&#xD;
             difficulties&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  must be willing to wear EEG cap&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  must be able to sit still for 1.5 hours to complete experimental tasks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  must be literate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neurological disorders (i.e., ASD, ADHD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  significant neurological history (i.e., head injury, epilepsy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  left handedness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  primary language other than English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  medication other than over-the-counter allergy medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  and/or nonverbal IQ less than 70&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alyson Abel Mills, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>619-594-4694</phone>
    <email>alyson.abel@sdsu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>San Diego State University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alyson Abel Mills</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Semantic Learning</keyword>
  <keyword>ERP</keyword>
  <keyword>N400</keyword>
  <keyword>ERSP</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Language Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Language Development Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

