<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04503239</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PTL-904050</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04503239</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes Data Collection Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>T2Help</acronym>
  <official_title>Prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes Data Collection Study: T2Help</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>DexCom, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>DexCom, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To collect data in an observational study from Prediabetes (PD) and Type 2 Diabetes (T2D)&#xD;
      patients including time correlated CGM, medication and food intake approximately 80% of the&#xD;
      time for each subject that completes the entire active phase.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In addition, lifestyle and treatment already established for prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes&#xD;
      such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sleep&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Exercise/Physical activity/or lack of it&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Heart rate&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Five hours OGTT- 6 subjects in each group that have C-Peptide positive lab result at&#xD;
           screening and consent to the OGTT (Appendix 3) This data will address the sources and&#xD;
           nature of blood glucose variability across the progression of PD and T2D. The data&#xD;
           collected in this study will enable investigation into CGM-data artifacts that speak to&#xD;
           the state and management of PD and T2D. Possible applications enabled by these data sets&#xD;
           include: compliance with drug regimens and other lifestyle recommendations, drug&#xD;
           titration and/or escalation/de-escalation, and diagnosis and/or treatment throughout the&#xD;
           progression of the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 27, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 27, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Collect Device Data - CGM</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To collect data in an observational study from Prediabetes (PD) and Type 2 Diabetes (T2D) patients including time correlated CGM approximately 80% of the time for each subject that completes the entire active phase.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Collect Device Data - e-Diary</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To collect data in an observational study from Prediabetes (PD) and Type 2 Diabetes (T2D) patients including logging diabetic medication taken or not taken 80% of the time for each subject that completes the entire active phase.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Collect Device Data - e-Diary</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To collect data in an observational study from Prediabetes (PD) and Type 2 Diabetes (T2D) patients including logging food intake approximately 80% of the time for each subject that completes the entire active phase.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Collect Device Data - Activity Tracker</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To collect data in an observational study from Prediabetes (PD) and Type 2 Diabetes (T2D) patients including logging lifestyle by activity tracker approximately 80% of the time for each subject that completes the entire active phase.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Collect Current Subject Lifestyle and Treatment Regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 16 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Collect subjects current treatment already established for Prediabetes and Type 2 Diabetes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>9</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">306</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <condition>Pre-diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prediabetes (both IGT and IFG)</arm_group_label>
    <description>Device: G6 Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes on 1 OAD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes on 2 or more OAD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes using Basal insulin with or without OAD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes in GLP-1 with or without OAD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes using intense insulin treatment-Multiple Dail</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes in MDI or basal insulin plus GLP-1</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes on 0 OAD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High Risk to Develop Prediabetes / Type 2 Diabetes</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participant to wear G6 and activity tracker for 3 months and add meals and medications into e-diary daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>G6</intervention_name>
    <description>Wear 9 wear periods of the 10-day CGM</description>
    <arm_group_label>High Risk to Develop Prediabetes / Type 2 Diabetes</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prediabetes (both IGT and IFG)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes in GLP-1 with or without OAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes in MDI or basal insulin plus GLP-1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes on 0 OAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes on 1 OAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes on 2 or more OAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes using Basal insulin with or without OAD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Type 2 Diabetes using intense insulin treatment-Multiple Dail</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Pre-diabetics and Type 2 Diabetics 18 and over willing to wear 2 study devices and enter in&#xD;
        the daily medication and food intake.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects ages ≥18 years of age at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High Risk of developing PD or T2D with HbA1c ≤5.6%&#xD;
&#xD;
        With one or more of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Strong family history of T2D&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI ≥35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age and Race, Ethnicity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Polycistic Ovarian Syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  High Blood Pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal cholesterol and triglyceride levels&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinical Diagnosis of Prediabetes (PD) as defined by ADA to have an HbA1c&#xD;
                  ≥5.7%-6.4%. or clinical diagnosis of Type 2 Diabetes (T2D) with HbA1c between&#xD;
                  ≥6.5 % and ≤12.0%. Determined via medical record or source documentation by an&#xD;
                  individual qualified to make a medical diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Having no treatment, one or more of the combination of treatments for the disease&#xD;
                  in every spectrum such as exercise and diet for PD and no treatment, 1 or more&#xD;
                  methods of treatment for T2D and combination of treatments for the disease MDI or&#xD;
                  CSII alone, MDI or CSII plus OAD and MDI or CSII with or without GLP-1 with or&#xD;
                  without OAD.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No change in diabetic medication in the last three months for patients in&#xD;
                  treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness to use a study provided CGM, use of an activity tracker, and agree to&#xD;
                  record data related to food and medication intake in an e-diary (e.g. mobile&#xD;
                  app).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For a subset of subjects who agree to provide consent, an OGTT will be performed&#xD;
                  as explained on Appendix 3. OGTT will be performed on 6 subjects per group that&#xD;
                  have a lab result with positive c-peptide. Having a smartphone compatible with&#xD;
                  Dexcom G6 CGM, activity tracker &amp; e-Diary. (This could be provided by the study&#xD;
                  team if the qualified subject does not have smartphone compatible with apps. For&#xD;
                  users that do not use their personal smartphones for data collection purposes,&#xD;
                  the T2Help study will provide a commercially available smartphone. The&#xD;
                  smartphones will be modified so they are only capable of hosting and running the&#xD;
                  study applications required for data collection (Fitbit, Welldoc, G6). The&#xD;
                  modified smartphones will not be able to execute standard smartphone&#xD;
                  functionality such as internet browsing, texting, or making phone calls.&#xD;
                  Bluetooth functionality will remain intact as it is required for the approved&#xD;
                  applications to collect data.)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If using additional medication, such as thyroid, hypertension, and cholesterol&#xD;
                  lowering medication these have to be stable for at least 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospital admissions for diabetes ketoacidosis (DKA) or Hyperglycemic Hyperosmolar&#xD;
             Nonketotic Syndrome (HHNS) in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of 2 or more episodes of severe hypoglycemia, which resulted in any of the&#xD;
             following during the 6 months prior to screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical assistance by a third party (Caregiver needed to inject glucagon, ER visit,&#xD;
        hospitalization) Coma Seizures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a skin condition for which he/she is unable to tolerate tape adhesive in&#xD;
             the area of sensor placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy (as demonstrated by a positive test at study entry) at time of screening or&#xD;
             are planning to become pregnant during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has had any of the following cardiovascular events within 3 months of&#xD;
             screening: myocardial infarction, unstable angina, coronary artery bypass surgery,&#xD;
             coronary artery stenting, recent transient ischemic attack, cerebrovascular accident&#xD;
             with sequelae, unstable angina, unstable congestive heart failure, unstable&#xD;
             ventricular rhythm disturbances or thromboembolic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unstable thyroid disease. (changes in Thyroid medication in the last 90 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has taken any oral, injectable, or intravenous (IV) steroids within 8 weeks&#xD;
             from the time of screening visit, or plans to take any oral, injectable, or IV&#xD;
             steroids during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is actively participating in an investigational study (drug or device) wherein&#xD;
             he/she has received treatment from an investigational study drug or investigational&#xD;
             study device in the last 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is currently using illicit drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is currently abusing prescription drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is currently abusing alcohol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a history of visual impairment which would not allow him/her to&#xD;
             participate in the study and perform all study procedures safely, as determined by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has elective surgery planned that requires general anesthesia during the&#xD;
             course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a sickle cell disease, hemoglobinopathy, or has received red blood cell&#xD;
             transfusion or erythropoietin within 3 months prior to time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject plans to receive red blood cell transfusion or erythropoietin over the course&#xD;
             of study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject diagnosed with current eating disorder such as anorexia or bulimia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is on dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has eGFR &lt;45 confirmed by medical record.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent Pancreatitis. (&lt; 30 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cancer/malignancy in treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cystic fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other problem for which the investigator or the sponsor may believe that the&#xD;
             subject will not be able to comply with the study. (e.g. use of hydroxyurea)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>not pregnant or planning on becoming pregnant during study</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Danny Chernavvsky, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>DexCom, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Synergy San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lemon Grove</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>91945</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Palm Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89148</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oregon Health &amp; Science University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97239</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diabetes and Glandular Disease</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 4, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 7, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

