<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03288116</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2352</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03288116</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Objective and Subjective Diagnostic Parameters in the Fellow Eye of Unilateral Keratoconus</brief_title>
  <official_title>Literature in Mansoura Ophthalmic Center ,Mansoura University</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dar Al Shifa Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dar Al Shifa Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      patients with keratoconus in one eye and forme fruste keratoconus in the fellow eye compared&#xD;
      to normal subjects .the patients were examined by schemipflug imaging system (Pentacam)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This cross-sectional study was carried out on patients presenting keratoconus in one eye and&#xD;
      forme fruste keratoconus in the fellow eye; the patients attended the outpatient clinic of&#xD;
      Mansoura ophthalmic center between January 2014 and February 2015. This study was approved by&#xD;
      the institutional research board of the Mansoura faculty of medicine and was performed in&#xD;
      accordance with the ethical standards of the Declaration of Helsinki. All patients included&#xD;
      in the study provided informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ocular examinations were performed on all eyes included in the study. Clinical Keratoconus&#xD;
      was diagnosed if all the following criteria were found:1)asymmetric bow tie with skewed&#xD;
      radial axis (SRAX), inferior or central steepening on the topography map, 2)mean keratometry&#xD;
      (K)&gt;47diopters or an inferior-superior (I-S) value &gt;1.4diopters according to the Rabinowitz&#xD;
      and McDonnell criteria[8],and 3)at least one clinical symptom(i.e., stromal thinning, conical&#xD;
      protrusion of corneal apex,Fleischer ring, Vogt striae or anterior stromal scar). Forme&#xD;
      fruste keratoconus was diagnosed if all the following criteria were found: 1) normal&#xD;
      topography, 2) mean K&lt;47D and I-S ≤1.4,3) normal slit lamp, and 4)keratoconus in the fellow&#xD;
      eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The eyes with an evident keratoconus diagnosis were included in (Group A)and the fellow eyes&#xD;
      were included in (Group B).Control cases(Group C) were selected from the normal database of&#xD;
      candidates for refractive surgery with the following:1)normal topography, 2)negative rotating&#xD;
      Scheimpflug device indices and negative topographic keratoconus classification, 3)normal slit&#xD;
      lamp examination, and 4)no history of eye disease(only one eye of each normal candidate was&#xD;
      included in the study depending on a computer-based randomizing program).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exclusion criteria included previous ocular surgery or trauma, significant corneal&#xD;
      scarring or associated ocular pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All eyes were examined by rotating Scheimpflug corneal tomography (Pentacam, Oculus&#xD;
      Optikgerate GmbH).No patients in the study wore contact lenses. During the Scheimpflug&#xD;
      corneal tomography examination, the patient was properly positioned on the chin rest and&#xD;
      forehead strap. The patient was asked to blink several times then open both eyes and stare at&#xD;
      a fixed target. After obtaining proper alignment, the automatic release mode started the&#xD;
      scan; a total of25 single Scheimpflug images were captured within 2 sec for each eye. Three&#xD;
      consecutive scans were taken of each eye by the same examiner. The average of the results of&#xD;
      three acceptable measurements was included in the study. Each eye was required to have a&#xD;
      corneal map with at least 9 mm of corneal coverage and no extrapolated data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Pentacam maps were analyzed. The following anterior and posterior corneal surface&#xD;
      parameters were evaluated by the Scheimpflug system: corneal dioptric power at the flattest&#xD;
      meridian in the 3 mm-central zone(K1),corneal dioptric power in the steepest meridian in the&#xD;
      3mm-central zone (K2)and mean corneal power in the 3mm-zone (mean K).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The pachymetric map was analyzed, including the central corneal thickness (CCT) at the apex&#xD;
      of the geometric center and corneal thickness at the thinnest point (CTmin).The average&#xD;
      progression index (PPI avg) was calculated as the progression value at the different rings&#xD;
      referenced to the mean curve. The minimum (PPI min) and maximum (PPI max) progression indices&#xD;
      were recorded. The Ambrósior elational thickness (ART)was calculated as follows:&#xD;
      ARTavg=CTmin/PPIavg,ARTmin = CTmin/PPImin, ARTmax =CTmin/PPImax[9].&#xD;
&#xD;
      The posterior corneal elevation maps were evaluated; a reference best fit sphere was&#xD;
      calculated at a fixed optical zone of 8 mm, and the posterior corneal elevation values&#xD;
      relative to this reference were recorded. The back difference elevation and multimetric D&#xD;
      index values were extrapolated from the difference map of the Belin/Ambrósio-enhanced ectasia&#xD;
      display of the Pentacam system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Contrast and Glare sensitivity test:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The contract and glare tests were carried out with a Mesotest II (Oculus Optikgeräte GmbH,&#xD;
      Wetzlar, Germany), which consists of Landolt rings of different contrast levels presented in&#xD;
      front of a low-brightness background. There are 4 contrast levels, 1:23, 1:5, 1:2.7, and 1:2,&#xD;
      which represent the ratio between the light intensity of the optotypes and the background.&#xD;
      There were 8 tests, 4 without glare and 4 with glare. Test 1, with a contrast level of 1:23,&#xD;
      is the most easily recognized. For statistical purposes, each level of the contrast or glare&#xD;
      test was given a score ranging from 20% at the 1:23 level to 100% at the 1:2 level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 5, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 5, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>keratometric power of the corneal surface</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>in diopter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>corneal thickness(pachymetry)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>in micrometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>corneal elevations</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>in micrometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Keratoconus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>patient</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scheimplug imaging and contrast and sensitivity test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>early disease</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scheimplug imaging and contrast and sensitivity test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>normal</arm_group_label>
    <description>Scheimplug imaging and contrast and sensitivity test</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Scheimplug imaging and contrast and sensitivity test</intervention_name>
    <description>examination of the patients using the schemiplug imaging with evaluation of keratometric parametres ,pachymetric parametres ,elevation parameters.</description>
    <arm_group_label>early disease</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>normal</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>patient</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        unilateral keratoconus&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with clinically evident keratoconus in one eye and apparently normal in the&#xD;
             fellow eye&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous ocular surgery or truama,significant corneal scarring or associatedocular&#xD;
             pathology&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>44 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>September 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 30, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 19, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 19, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dar Al Shifa Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>magda torky</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>clinical professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Keratoconus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

