<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03963492</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro2019000453</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03963492</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intermittent vs Continuous Walking in People With Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intermittent vs. Continuous Walking Training in People With Multiple Sclerosis: a Comparison of Effectiveness</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mount Sinai Rehabilitation Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>City University of New York, School of Public Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will compare the effectiveness of a traditional, continuous walking rehabilitation&#xD;
      program for people with MS to the novel intervention of an intermittent or interval walking&#xD;
      rehabilitation program. Half of the participants will receive the continuous walking program&#xD;
      while the other half will receive the novel intermittent walking program.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The typical rehabilitation of walking difficulties for people with MS has included practice&#xD;
      walking. In general, this includes training to build walking endurance by having the person&#xD;
      with MS walk until he/she becomes tired and needs to stop. Although this model has been used&#xD;
      successfully to treat people with other diagnoses, it has limited effectiveness in improving&#xD;
      walking ability and endurance in people with MS because of fatigue. Recently, a different&#xD;
      model has been considered: intermittent or interval walking training. Interval walking&#xD;
      training is organized such that seated rest breaks are intentionally interspersed between&#xD;
      walking training bouts that end before the person with MS becomes too tired to continue.&#xD;
      Exploratory research has shown that people with MS can walk faster and farther when using&#xD;
      interval walking training, and may have more improvements in walking ability and endurance&#xD;
      after using interval walking training. This study will compare the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      traditional model of continuous walking training to the promising new model of interval&#xD;
      walking training. This will help to determine whether interval or continuous walking training&#xD;
      is superior in improving walking ability and endurance in people with MS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Suspended</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    COVID-19 Pandemic&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled pre-post study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Assessors blinded to experimental condition</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 6-minute Walk Test distance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>Is a measurement of the distance (in meters) walked at best pace in six minutes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 12-item Multiple Sclerosis Walking Scale score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>A survey that measures a participant's perception of how his/her walking ability is affected by multiple sclerosis. The scale ranges from 0-100 with lower scores representing a lesser impact of multiple sclerosis on the participant's walking ability. There are no subscales.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Fatigue Severity Scale score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>A survey that measures a participant's perception of the impact of the symptom of fatigue on a person's ability to participate in life roles. The scale ranges from from 9-63, with lower scores representing a lower impact of fatigue on the ability to perform the activities listed in the scale.There are no subscales.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Step Length</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>The distance (in centimeters) traversed in one step from initial contact of one foot to the initial contact of the opposite foot.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Step Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>The time (in seconds) taken to complete one step from initial contact of one foot to the initial contact of the opposite foot.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Stride Velocity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>The speed with which it takes a person to complete one stride from initial contact of one foot to the next initial contact of the same foot</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Cadence</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 weeks (after intervention), and 12 weeks (6-week follow-up)</time_frame>
    <description>The number of steps (the initial contact of one foot to the initial contact of the opposite foot taken per minute</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Walking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the Continuous Walking (CONT) arm will undergo training 2x/week for 6 weeks for a total plan of 12 training sessions. The intervention for the CONT group will be to complete a 6-minute long walk without rest breaks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interval Walking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in the Interval Walking (INT) arm will undergo training 2x/week for 6 weeks for a total plan of 12 training sessions. The intervention for the (INT) group will be to complete three 2-minute-long walks with 2-minute seated rest breaks between each walk</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Walking</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will undergo training in either the CONT or INT walking interventions 2x/week for 6 weeks for a total plan of 12 training sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Continuous Walking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Interval Walking</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-identified difficulty walking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Definitive diagnosis of multiple sclerosis from a neurologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed an approved consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to ambulate for unaided for 6-minutes continuously with or without an&#xD;
             assistive device (e.g. a cane or brace)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has not had a multiple sclerosis relapse in the past 6 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to complete assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or able to complete assessments and or intervention without the use of&#xD;
             portable functional electrical stimulation devices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of concomitant condition unrelated to multiple sclerosis which may&#xD;
             impact results including: other neurological conditions including stroke, Parkinson's&#xD;
             disease, or orthopedic, or cardiopulmonary conditions that affect walking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Had a major change in exercise habits in the past three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals reporting change in any disease modifying treatment or steroid use during&#xD;
             the past 6 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to walk for 6 minutes continuously without physical assistance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of unstable angina, uncontrolled cardiac dysrhythmias causing&#xD;
             symptoms, symptomatic severe aortic stenosis, uncontrolled symptomatic heart failure,&#xD;
             acute pulmonary embolus or pulmonary infarction, history of deep vein thrombosis,&#xD;
             acute myocarditis or pericarditis, acute systemic infection, uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension, and uncontrolled diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an abnormal response to exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cannot adhere to protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Determined to be unsafe at the discretion of the research team including individuals&#xD;
             unwilling to wear safety &quot;gait belt&quot; during testing or not willing to wear proper&#xD;
             footwear.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Evan T Cohen, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mandell Center for Multiple Sclerosis - Mount Sinai Rehabilitation Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hartford</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 16, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 23, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 24, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Evan T. Cohen, SHRP Department of Rehabilitation and Movemen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Walking</keyword>
  <keyword>Gait</keyword>
  <keyword>Fatigue</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

