<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03964337</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00101042</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03964337</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Immediate Prostatectomy vs. Cabozantinib Followed by Prostatectomy in Men With High-Risk Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>SPARC</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Open-Label Randomized Study of Immediate Prostatectomy vs. Cabozantinib Followed by Prostatectomy in Men With High-Risk Prostate Cancer (SPARC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Duke University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Exelixis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized, open-label, phase II trial of cabozantinib in subjects&#xD;
      with untreated, high risk prostate cancer undergoing radical prostatectomy. This multicenter&#xD;
      study will enroll 30 subjects. Duke is the lead site for this trial. There will be a second&#xD;
      site selected TBD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be assigned (first 9 subjects only) or randomized 2:1 to either: (1)&#xD;
      cabozantinib 40 mg by mouth daily for 4 weeks, followed by a 2 week drug washout period&#xD;
      before prostatectomy (n = 20), or (2) immediate prostatectomy within 12 weeks of registration&#xD;
      (n = 10). The first 9 subjects (6 subjects assigned to cabozantinib treatment, 3 subjects&#xD;
      assigned to immediate prostatectomy) will constitute the Safety Lead-In Cohort, which will be&#xD;
      only accrued at Duke. After six subjects have received cabozantinib and completed the 57-85&#xD;
      day safety visit without triggering a stopping rule, subjects may be accrued at the ex-Duke&#xD;
      site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary goal is to compare pathologic apoptotic indices (cleaved caspase-3) in&#xD;
      prostatectomy specimens from patients who undergo immediate prostatectomy (controls) versus&#xD;
      those who receive with cabozantinib followed by prostatectomy. The secondary objective is to&#xD;
      conduct immune phenotypic profiling on the peripheral blood and tumor microenvironment in&#xD;
      prostatectomy specimens from both groups. A statistical analysis will be used to compare the&#xD;
      apoptotic indices between the two groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apoptotic index in prostatectomy specimens from patients who undergo immediate prostatectomy (Arm B) versus those treated with cabozantinib followed by prostatectomy (Arm A)</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Apoptotic index as measured by cleaved caspase-3 levels in tumor tissue</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune phenotyping of Myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Arm A: Screening, Day 29, Day 43, Day 57-85; Arm B: Screening, Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of MDSCs in peripheral blood and tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune phenotyping of neutrophils</measure>
    <time_frame>Arm A: Screening, Day 29, Day 43, Day 57-85; Arm B: Screening, Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of neutrophils in peripheral blood and tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune phenotyping of M1 macrophages</measure>
    <time_frame>Arm A: Screening, Day 29, Day 43, Day 57-85; Arm B: Screening, Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of M1 macrophages in peripheral blood and tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immune phenotyping of M2 macrophages</measure>
    <time_frame>Arm A: Screening, Day 29, Day 43, Day 57-85; Arm B: Screening, Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of M2 macrophages in peripheral blood and tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunohistochemical (IHC) analysis of CD8+</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of CD8+ positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunohistochemical (IHC) analysis of programmed death ligand-1 (PD-L1)</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of PD-L1 positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunohistochemical (IHC) analysis of cytotoxic T-lymphocyte-associated protein 4 (CTLA-4)</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of CTLA-4 positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunohistochemical (IHC) analysis of interleukin-1 receptor antagonist (IL-1RA)</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of IL-1RA positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of the neutrophil chemotactic factor CXCL12</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of neutrophil chemotactic factor CXCL12 positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of the neutrophil chemotactic factor HMGB1</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of neutrophil chemotactic factor HMGB1 positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of the MDSC-promoting cytokine CCL5</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of MDSC-promoting cytokine CCL5 positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of the MDSC-promoting cytokine CCL12</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of MDSC-promoting cytokine CCL12 positive cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of the MDSC-promoting cytokine CD40</measure>
    <time_frame>At prostatectomy (Arm A: Day 43, Arm B: Day 1)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of MDSC-promoting cytokine CD40 cells in tumor tissue</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">33</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Non-Metastatic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cabozantinib Followed by Prostatectomy (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Experimental group will received cabozantinib for 4 weeks, followed by a 2 week drug washout before a prostatectomy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Immediate Prostatectomy (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group will receive an immediate prostatectomy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabozantinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Cabozantinib 40 mg by mouth daily for 4 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cabozantinib Followed by Prostatectomy (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cabometyx</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radical Prostatectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Radical prostatectomy as part of routine medical care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cabozantinib Followed by Prostatectomy (Arm A)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Immediate Prostatectomy (Arm B)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male, age ≥ 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ECOG performance status of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologic evidence of adenocarcinoma of the prostate who are deemed candidates for&#xD;
             curative radical prostatectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Planned robotic or laparoscopic prostatectomy technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Low risk for conversion to open prostatectomy, in the opinion of the treating surgeon.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Intermediate-high or high risk, clinically localized disease by the following&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prostate cancer in at least 2 cores with a Gleason score ≥ 7 (4+3 or 3+4) in at&#xD;
                  least 1 of those cores.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No definite evidence of metastasis, in the opinion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate organ function as defined by the following criteria within 14 days prior to&#xD;
             first dose of study treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT) ≤3 x local laboratory&#xD;
                  upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total serum bilirubin ≤1.5 x ULN, (for subjects with Gilbert's disease ≤ 3 x ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1500/L without granulocyte colony-stimulating&#xD;
                  factor support.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White blood cell count ≥ 2500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin ≥ 2.8 g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum calcium ≤12.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 2.0 x ULN or calculated creatinine clearance ≥ 30mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Urine protein/creatinine ratio (UPCR) ≤ 1 mg/mg (≤ 113.2 mg/mmol).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Written Authorization for Use and Release of Health and Research Study Information&#xD;
             (HIPAA authorization per institutional requirements)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that&#xD;
             the subject has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Willing/able to adhere to the prohibitions and restrictions specified in this&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Agrees to use a condom (even men with vasectomies) and another effective method of&#xD;
             birth control if subject is having sex with a woman who is pregnant or a woman of&#xD;
             childbearing potential while on study drug and for 4 months following the last dose of&#xD;
             study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Prior treatment for prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Major surgery or radiation therapy within 4 weeks of Day 1 on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Planned radiation therapy until at least 4 weeks after prostatectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. NCI CTCAE v4.0 grade 3 hemorrhage within 4 weeks of Day 1 on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Prothrombin time (PT)/INR or partial thromboplastin time (PTT) test ≥ 1.3 x the&#xD;
             laboratory ULN within 14 days before Day 1 on study (Arm A subjects only) or within 14&#xD;
             days of the completion of screening (Arm B subjects only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Concomitant anticoagulation with oral anticoagulants (e.g., warfarin, direct thrombin&#xD;
             and Factor Xa inhibitors) or platelet inhibitors (eg, clopidogrel). However, low-dose&#xD;
             aspirin for cardio protection is allowed (per local applicable guidelines).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of or known metastatic prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. QTcf interval &gt; 500 msec on baseline EKG.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The subject has uncontrolled, significant intercurrent or recent illness including,&#xD;
             but not limited to, the following conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Cardiovascular disorders:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Symptomatic congestive heart failure (CHF) New York Heart Association Class 3 or 4,&#xD;
             unstable angina pectoris, ongoing cardiac dysrhythmias of NCI CTCAE grade ≥2.&#xD;
             coronary/peripheral artery bypass graft (CABG), within 6 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. Stroke (including transient ischemic attack [TIA]), cerebrovascular accident&#xD;
             (CVA), myocardial infarction (MI), or other ischemic event, or thromboembolic event&#xD;
             (eg, deep venous thrombosis, pulmonary embolism (PE)) within 6 months prior to&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
             b. Gastrointestinal (GI) disorders including those associated with a high risk of&#xD;
             perforation or fistula formation:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Evidence of tumor invading the GI tract, active peptic ulcer disease, inflammatory&#xD;
             bowel disease (eg, Crohn's disease), diverticulitis, cholecystitis, symptomatic&#xD;
             cholangitis or appendicitis, acute pancreatitis, acute obstruction of the pancreatic&#xD;
             duct or common bile duct, or gastric outlet obstruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. Abdominal fistula, GI perforation, bowel obstruction, or intra-abdominal abscess&#xD;
             within 6 months before first dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Complete healing of an intra-abdominal abscess must be confirmed before first&#xD;
             dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
             c. Clinically significant hematuria, hematemesis, or hemoptysis of &gt; 0.5 teaspoon (2.5&#xD;
             ml) of red blood, or other history of significant bleeding (eg, pulmonary hemorrhage)&#xD;
             within 12 weeks before first dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
             d. Serious non-healing wound/ulcer/bone fracture. e. Other clinically significant&#xD;
             disorders that would preclude safe study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Hypertension that cannot be controlled by medications (&gt;140/90 mm Hg despite optimal&#xD;
             medical therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pre-existing thyroid abnormality with thyroid function that cannot be maintained in&#xD;
             the normal range with medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Concurrent treatment on another clinical trial. Supportive care trials or&#xD;
             non-treatment trials, e.g. QOL, are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that may increase the risk associated with study participation or study&#xD;
             drug administration, or may interfere with the interpretation of study results, and in&#xD;
             the judgment of the investigator would make the subject inappropriate for entry into&#xD;
             this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Inability to swallow tablets.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Diagnosis of another malignancy within 2 years before first dose of study treatment,&#xD;
             except for superficial skin cancers, or localized, low grade tumors deemed cured and&#xD;
             not treated with systemic therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Harrison, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julia Hurrelbrink, BA, BSN, RN</last_name>
    <phone>919-681-1030</phone>
    <email>julia.hurrelbrink@duke.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julia Hurrelbrink, BA, BSN, RN</last_name>
      <phone>919-681-1030</phone>
      <email>julia.hurrelbrink@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 23, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 23, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

