<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05117294</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0367-CL-1111</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-004042-38</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05117294</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of ASP0367 in People With Kidneys That do Not Work Well and in Healthy People</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Open Label Study to Evaluate the Pharmacokinetics, Safety and Tolerability of ASP0367 in Participants With Renal Impairment Compared to Healthy Participants With Normal Renal Function</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Astellas Pharma Global Development, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Astellas Pharma Inc</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is for adults whose kidneys do not work well (renal impairment) and adults whose&#xD;
      kidneys work normally. This study will provide more information on a potential new treatment,&#xD;
      called ASP0367. The main aim of the study is to learn how ASP0367 is processed by the body in&#xD;
      these different groups of people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be in 2 parts. Part 2 will only happen if the results between the 2 groups&#xD;
      are different in Part 1. In each part, people in the study will stay in a research unit for 6&#xD;
      days and 5 nights. Later, they will return to the research unit for 1 check-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Part 1, people whose kidneys work normally and people whose kidneys work very poorly&#xD;
      (severe renal impairment) can take part.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If Part 2 happens, people whose kidneys work normally and people whose kidneys do not work&#xD;
      well (mild or moderate renal impairment) can take part.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In both parts of the study, people who can take part will be admitted to the research unit.&#xD;
      The next day they will take tablets of ASP0367 just once. People will give blood and urine&#xD;
      samples at various times during their stay. They will have their vital signs (heart rate and&#xD;
      blood pressure) checked regularly. People will also have ECGs to check their heart rhythm.&#xD;
      They will be asked if they have any medical problems. After 6 days, provided all the checks&#xD;
      have been done and there are no medical problems, people in the study will leave the research&#xD;
      unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      People will return to the research unit for 1 check-up. This will be between 9 and 11 days&#xD;
      after their last blood sample was taken during their previous stay in the unit. The check-up&#xD;
      will include a physical exam, a check of people's vital signs (heart rate and blood&#xD;
      pressure), and blood tests. Also, people will have an ECG and be asked if they have had any&#xD;
      medical problems.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokentics (PK) of ASP0367 in Plasma: Area Under The Concentration-time Curve From Time of Dosing Extrapolated to Time Infinity (AUCinf)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>AUCinf will be recorded from PK plasma samples collected.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokentics (PK) of ASP0367 in Plasma: Area Under The Concentration-time Curve From The Time of Dosing to The Last Measurable Concentration (AUClast)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>AUClast will be recorded from PK plasma samples collected.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokentics (PK) of ASP0367 in Plasma: maximum concentration (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Cmax will be recorded from PK plasma samples collected.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokentics (PK) of ASP0367 in Plasma: apparent clearance (CL/F)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 days</time_frame>
    <description>CL/F will be recorded from PK plasma samples collected.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 16</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse Events (AEs) will be coded using MedDRA. An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant, temporally associated with the use of study IP, whether or not considered related to the study IP. An AE can therefore be any unfavorable and unintended sign (including an abnormal laboratory finding), symptom, or disease (new or exacerbated) temporally associated with the use of study IP. This includes events related to the comparator and events related to the (study) procedures.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Laboratory Value Abnormalities and/or AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 16</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with potentially clinically significant laboratory values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Vital Sign Abnormalities and/or AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 16</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with potentially clinically significant vital signs values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with 12-Lead Electrocariogram (ECG) Anormalities and/or AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to Day 16</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with potentially clinically significant 12-Lead ECG values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Renal Impairment</condition>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Severe Renal Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with severe renal impairment will receive a single dose of ASP0367 under fasting conditions on day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Moderate Renal Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with moderate renal impairment will receive a single dose of ASP0367 under fasting conditions on day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Mild Renal Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with mild renal impairment will receive a single dose of ASP0367 under fasting conditions on day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Normal Renal Function</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with normal renal function will receive a single dose of ASP0367 under fasting conditions on day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ASP0367</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral</description>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Mild Renal Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Moderate Renal Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Normal Renal Function</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>ASP0367: Severe Renal Impairment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MA-0211</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a body mass index range of 18.5 to 40.0 kg/m^2, inclusive and weighs&#xD;
             at least 50 kg at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant is not pregnant and at least 1 of the following conditions apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not a woman of child-bearing potential (WOCBP)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WOCBP who agrees to follow the contraceptive guidance from the time of informed&#xD;
                  consent through at least 28 days after Investigational Product (IP)&#xD;
                  administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant must agree not to breastfeed starting at screening and throughout&#xD;
             the study period and for 28 days after IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant must not donate ova starting at first dose of IP and throughout the&#xD;
             study period and for 28 days after IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participant with female partner(s) of childbearing potential (including&#xD;
             breastfeeding partner) must agree to use contraception throughout the treatment period&#xD;
             and for 28 days after IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participant must not donate sperm during the treatment period and for 28 days&#xD;
             after IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participant with pregnant partner(s) must agree to remain abstinent or use a&#xD;
             condom for the duration of the pregnancy throughout the study period and for 28 days&#xD;
             after IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agrees not to participate in another interventional study while&#xD;
             participating in the present study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has normal renal function as defined by estimated glomerular filtration&#xD;
             rate (eGFR) using Modification of Diet in Renal Disease formula ≥ 90 mL/min per 1.73&#xD;
             m^2 or participant has varying degrees of chronic kidney disease as defined by the&#xD;
             National Kidney Foundation and by eGFR:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  60 to &lt; 90 mL/min per 1.73 m^2 for participants with mild renal impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  30 to &lt; 60 mL/min per 1.73 m^2 for participants with moderate renal impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  &lt; 30 mL/min per 1.73 m^2 and not on hemodialysis, with approximately 50 percent&#xD;
                  of participants to have eGFR ≤ 20 mL/min per 1.73 m^2 for participants with&#xD;
                  severe renal impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has adequate venous access.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has received any investigational therapy within 28 days or 5 half-lives,&#xD;
             whichever is longer, prior to day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any condition, which makes the participant unsuitable for study&#xD;
             participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participant who has been pregnant within 6 months prior to screening or&#xD;
             breastfeeding within 3 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known or suspected hypersensitivity to ASP0367 or any components of&#xD;
             the formulation used.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had previous exposure with ASP0367.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used moderate or strong inducers of P450 (CYP)3A within the 3 months&#xD;
             prior to day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used a strong cytochrome CYP3A inhibitor within 5 half lives, prior to&#xD;
             day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used proton pump inhibitor within the 2 weeks prior to IP&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used histamine 2 blockers within 24 hours prior to IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any clinically significant history of allergic conditions (including&#xD;
             drug allergies, asthma, eczema or anaphylactic reactions, but excluding untreated,&#xD;
             asymptomatic, seasonal allergies) prior to IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has/had febrile illness or symptomatic, viral, bacterial (including upper&#xD;
             respiratory infection) or fungal (noncutaneous) infection within 1 week prior to day&#xD;
             -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any of the liver function tests (alkaline phosphatase, alanine&#xD;
             aminotransferase, aspartate aminotransferase and total bilirubin ≥ 1.5 × upper limit&#xD;
             of normal (ULN) on day -1. In such a case, the assessment may be repeated once.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had significant blood loss, donated ≥ 1 unit (450 mL) of whole blood&#xD;
             or donated plasma within 7 days prior to day -1 and/or received a transfusion of any&#xD;
             blood or blood products within 60 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is an employee of Astellas, the study related CROs or the clinical unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a positive result for SARS-CoV-2 polymerase chain reaction (PCR) test&#xD;
             at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has consumed grapefruit, Seville oranges, grapefruit containing products&#xD;
             or Seville orange containing products within 72 hours prior to day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of smoking &gt; 10 cigarettes (or equivalent amount of tobacco)&#xD;
             per day within 3 months prior to day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used any drugs of abuse (amphetamines, barbiturates, benzodiazepines,&#xD;
             cannabinoids, cocaine and/or opiates) within 3 months prior to day -1 or the&#xD;
             participant tests positive for drugs of abuse (amphetamines, barbiturates,&#xD;
             benzodiazepines, cannabinoids, cocaine and/or opiates) at screening or on day -1,&#xD;
             unless the positive result is due to an approved prescription medication (for&#xD;
             participants with renal impairment only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For US sites: Participant has a history of consuming &gt; 14 units for male participants&#xD;
             or &gt; 7 units for female participants of alcoholic beverages per week within 6 months&#xD;
             prior to screening or has a history of alcoholism or drug/chemical/substance abuse&#xD;
             within 2 years prior to screening (note: 1 unit = 12 ounces of beer, 4 ounces of wine,&#xD;
             1 ounce of spirits/hard liquor) or the participant tests positive for alcohol at&#xD;
             screening or on day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For EU sites: Participant has a history of consuming &gt; 21 units for male participants&#xD;
             or &gt; 14 units for female participants of alcohol per week within 3 months prior to day&#xD;
             -1 (note: 1 unit = 10 g pure alcohol, 250 mL of beer [5 percent], 35 mL of spirits [35&#xD;
             percent] or 100 mL of wine [12 percent]) or the participant tests positive for alcohol&#xD;
             at screening or on day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has received a COVID-19 vaccine within the 2 weeks prior to IP&#xD;
             administration or will have a COVID-19 vaccine dose before the ESV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a positive serology test for hepatitis A virus antibodies&#xD;
             (immunoglobulin M), hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C virus antibodies or&#xD;
             antibodies to human immunodeficiency virus type 1 and/or type 2 at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participant with renal impairment will be excluded from participation in the study if any&#xD;
        of the following apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of any clinically significant illness (other than renal&#xD;
             disease and conditions related to the renal disease, such as stable diabetes and&#xD;
             stable hypertension), medical condition or laboratory abnormality within 3 months&#xD;
             prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a mean pulse &lt; 40 or &gt; 90 bpm; mean systolic blood pressure (SBP) &lt; 90&#xD;
             or &gt; 160 mmHg; mean diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &lt; 50 or &gt; 100 mmHg (measurements&#xD;
             taken in triplicate after participant has been resting in a supine position for at&#xD;
             least 5 minutes; pulse will be measured automatically) on day -1. If the mean blood&#xD;
             pressure exceeds the limits above, 1 additional triplicate may be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a mean QT interval using Fridericia's correction (QTcF) of &gt; 450 msec&#xD;
             (for male participants) and &gt; 480 msec (for female participants) on day -1. If the&#xD;
             mean QTcF exceeds the limits above, 1 additional triplicate may be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who has had a change in dose regimen of medically required medication(s)&#xD;
             in the 2 weeks prior to screening (permitted concomitant medications) and/or&#xD;
             participant for whom dose changes are likely to occur during the study (minor dose&#xD;
             changes are allowed in agreement with the sponsor) and/or participant has used&#xD;
             nonpermitted concomitant medication(s) in the 3 weeks prior to admission to the&#xD;
             clinical unit (nonpermitted concomitant medications include vitamins and natural and&#xD;
             herbal remedies, e.g., St. John's Wort).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who has a renal disease secondary to malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who has a fluctuating or rapidly deteriorating renal function within 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to IP administration, as indicated by strongly varying or worsening of&#xD;
             clinical and/or laboratory signs of renal impairment within the screening period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a hemoglobin result of &lt; 9 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a functioning kidney transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has cardiac troponin I for a given manufacturer's assay being used that is&#xD;
             above the historical upper range or participants with chronic kidney injury (and also&#xD;
             without evidence of acute myocardial infarction) at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy participants with normal renal function will be excluded from participation in the&#xD;
        study if any of the following apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any history or evidence of any clinically significant cardiovascular,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal, endocrinologic, hematologic, hepatic, immunologic, metabolic,&#xD;
             urologic, pulmonary, neurologic, dermatologic, psychiatric, renal and/or other major&#xD;
             disease or malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has any clinically significant abnormality following the physical&#xD;
             examination, electrocardiogram (ECG) and protocol defined clinical laboratory tests at&#xD;
             screening or on day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a mean pulse &lt; 45 or &gt; 90 bpm; mean systolic blood pressure &gt; 140&#xD;
             mmHg; mean diastolic blood pressure &gt; 90 mmHg (measurements taken in triplicate after&#xD;
             participant has been resting in the supine position for at least 5 minutes; pulse will&#xD;
             be measured automatically) on day -1. If the mean blood pressure exceeds the limits&#xD;
             above, 1 additional triplicate may be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a mean QTcF of &gt; 430 msec (for male participants) and &gt; 450 msec (for&#xD;
             female participants) on day -1. If the mean QTcF exceeds the limits above, 1&#xD;
             additional triplicate ECG may be taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has used any prescribed or nonprescribed drugs (including vitamins and&#xD;
             natural and herbal remedies, e.g., St. John's Wort) in the 2 weeks prior to IP&#xD;
             administration, except for occasional use of acetaminophen (up to 2 g/day), topical&#xD;
             dermatological products (including corticosteroid products), hormonal contraceptives&#xD;
             and hormone replacement therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has creatinine level outside normal limits on day -1. In such a case, the&#xD;
             assessment may be repeated once.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has cardiac troponin (cTnI) &gt; Upper limit of normal (ULN) (or cardiac&#xD;
             troponin T [cTnT] &gt; ULN if cTnI is not available) at screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Executive Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Astellas Pharma Global Development, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Astellas Pharma Global Development, Inc.</last_name>
    <phone>800-888-7704</phone>
    <email>Astellas.registration@astellas.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Severe renal impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Moderate renal impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Mild renal impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>ASP0367</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteers</keyword>
  <keyword>MA-0211</keyword>
  <keyword>Kidney function</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Access to anonymized individual participant level data will not be provided for this trial as it meets one or more of the exceptions described on www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com under &quot;Sponsor Specific Details for Astellas.&quot;</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

