<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05119491</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>7039</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05119491</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Relation Between Pulmonary Function Tests and Ultrasonographic Chest Joints</brief_title>
  <acronym>Ultrasound</acronym>
  <official_title>Relation Between Pulmonary Function Tests and Ultrasonographic Changes of Asymptomatic Anterior Chest Wall Joints in Rheumatoid Arthritis Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Zagazig University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Zagazig University</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ultrasonography can detect different changes in anterior chest wall (ACW) joints in patients&#xD;
      with Rheumatoid arthritis (RA) even before being clinically manifested. Airways ,pleura, lung&#xD;
      parenchyma and vascular compartment all may be attacked by RA. This study was aiming at&#xD;
      detecting the relation between ultrasonographic changes of asymptomatic ACW joints and&#xD;
      pulmonary function tests (PFTs) in patients with RA.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Clinical assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Patients and controls were examined in supine position with elbows placed in contact&#xD;
           with the body. The anterior chest wall joints (CWJ) which include the right and left&#xD;
           sternoclavicular (SCJ) and manubriosternal (MSJ) joints were evaluated for&#xD;
           presence/absence of spontaneous pain, pain evoked by digital pressure, swelling, and&#xD;
           redness of skin.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Rheumatoid disease activity was assessed clinically using: disease activity score (DAS28&#xD;
           ESR)] and Functional status assessment by health assessment questionnaire (HAQ) .&#xD;
&#xD;
           Chest expansion was measured with a tape measure placed circumferentially around the&#xD;
           chest wall at the fourth intercostal space.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. US assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Ultrasonographic B examination (mode and Doppler power mode) of the 3 joints were&#xD;
           performed by an experienced rheumatologist. All patients were examined using B-mode&#xD;
           (gray scale) real-time MSUS (F37; Hitachi-Aloka, Japan) interfaced with a 10-18-MHz&#xD;
           linear array transducer. For each patient and control subject, US examination included a&#xD;
           longitudinal section of the left and right SCJ and the MSJ, followed by a cross-section&#xD;
           in case erosion was detected. During the examination, synovitis (hypo echoic&#xD;
           intracapsular incompressible area with or without Doppler flow), joint effusion&#xD;
           (compressible anechoic intracapsular area, absence of Doppler flow), erosion (disruption&#xD;
           of the cortical bone line displayed in 2 perpendicular axes), joint space narrowing&#xD;
           (reduction of the joint space), ankylosis (complete loss of joint space), or Doppler&#xD;
           signal (power Doppler signal) were investigated.&#xD;
&#xD;
           PD parameters were as follow: Pulse repetition frequency (PRF) was adjusted at the&#xD;
           lowest permissible value to maximize sensitivity. This setting resulted in PRF from 500&#xD;
           Hz to 750 Hz. Flow was additionally demonstrated in 2 planes and confirmed by pulsed&#xD;
           wave Doppler spectrum to exclude artifacts.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Computed Tomography (HRCT) was done on the chest to exclude any interstitial lung&#xD;
           disease that may affect chest expansion and restrictive PFTs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Pulmonary function tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
      PFTs was done with a Sensormedics Vmax229 system (Sensormedics, Yorba Linda, California, USA)&#xD;
      and included measurement of the forced expiratory volume in1 second (FEV1), forced vital&#xD;
      capacity (FVC), and the ratio of forced expiratory volume in 1 second to the forced vital&#xD;
      capacity(FEV1/FVC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was approved by the Institutional Review Board at the Faculty of Medicine, Zagazig&#xD;
      University Hospitals. It has been carried out in accordance with the code of ethics of the&#xD;
      world medical association (Declaration of Helsinki 1964) for studies involving humans. A&#xD;
      written informed consent was obtained from each participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim: To detect the relation between ultrasonographic changes of asymptomatic ACW joints and&#xD;
      pulmonary function tests (PFTs) in patients with RA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design and setting: An observational case control study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 21, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>2 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>This study is a trial to find correlation between US detected abnormalities in anterior chest wall joints and (FEV1,FVC,FEV1/FVC ) in Rh A patients</measure>
    <time_frame>about 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>observation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Restrictive Lung Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cases ultra sound and spirometry</arm_group_label>
    <description>observation by ultra sound and spirometry for cases</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>heathy subjects ultra sound and spirometry</arm_group_label>
    <description>observation ultra sound and spirometry for control heathy subjects</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>uitrasonography and spirometry</intervention_name>
    <description>chest uitrasonography and spirometry</description>
    <arm_group_label>cases ultra sound and spirometry</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>heathy subjects ultra sound and spirometry</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        rheumatoid arthritis patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  rheumatoid arthritis patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  other respiratory diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>zagazigU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zagazig</city>
        <zip>44519</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Zagazig University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Waleed Mansour</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Ass prof</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>research</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

