<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05112965</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>YO42713</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05112965</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Extension Study in Participants Previously Enrolled in a Genentech and/or F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd Sponsored Atezolizumab Study (IMbrella C)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-Label, Multicenter Extension Study in Participants Previously Enrolled in a Genentech and/or F. Hoffmann-La Roche Ltd Sponsored Atezolizumab Study (IMbrella C)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hoffmann-La Roche</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hoffmann-La Roche</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, multicenter, non-randomized extension study. Participants receiving&#xD;
      atezolizumab monotherapy or atezolizumab combined with other agent(s) or comparator agent(s)&#xD;
      in a Genentech or Roche-sponsored study (the parent study), who are eligible to continue&#xD;
      treatment and do not have access to the study treatment locally, continue to receive study&#xD;
      treatment in this extension study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 4, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 21, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 21, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Continued Access to Atezolizumab-based Therapy and/or Comparator Agent(s)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days after the final dose of study treatment (up to approximately 4 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants With Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 90 days after the final dose of study treatment (up to approximately 4 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will continue to receive atezolizumab monotherapy or atezolizumab with other agent(s) or comparator agent(s) as per parent protocol, until disease progression or beyond if the participant continues to derive clinical benefit as judged by the investigator and if allowed by the parent study or local prescribing information until death; withdrawal of study consent; unacceptable toxicity; pregnancy; participant non-compliance; or study termination by the Sponsor, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Atezolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Atezolizumab will be administered as a monotherapy or atezolizumab with other agent(s) or comparator agent(s) as per parent protocol. Dosing regimen will continue in accordance with the parent study or at equivalent dose (if applicable) and at the same schedule as the parent study at the time of participant discontinuation from the parent study closure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Atezolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Tecentriq</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible for continuing or crossing over to atezolizumab-based therapy at the time of&#xD;
             rollover from the parent study, as per the parent study protocol, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible for continuing the comparator agent(s) in a Genentech- or Roche-sponsored&#xD;
             study as per the parent study protocol, with no access to commercially available&#xD;
             comparator agent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First dose of study treatment in this extension study will be received within 7 days&#xD;
             of the treatment interruption window allowed by the parent study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continue to benefit from atezolizumab-based study treatment or from the comparator at&#xD;
             the time of rollover from the parent study as assessed by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serum pregnancy test within 7 days prior to start of study treatment in women&#xD;
             of childbearing potential&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women of childbearing potential: agreement to remain abstinent or use&#xD;
             contraceptive methods, and agreement to refrain from donating eggs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For men: agreement to remain abstinent or use contraceptive measures, and agreement to&#xD;
             refrain from donating sperm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meet any of the study treatment discontinuation criteria specified in the parent study&#xD;
             at the time of enrollment in the extension study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Study treatment is commercially marketed in the patient's country for the&#xD;
             patient-specific disease and is accessible to the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Time between the last dose of treatment received in parent study and first dose in&#xD;
             extension study is longer than the interruption period (±7 days) allowed in the parent&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with any anti-cancer treatment (other than treatment permitted in the parent&#xD;
             study) during the time between last treatment in the parent study and the first dose&#xD;
             of study treatment in the extension study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent discontinuation of atezolizumab for any reason during the parent study or&#xD;
             during the time between last treatment in the parent study and the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment in the extension study (if applicable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any unresolved or irreversible toxicities during the parent study that required&#xD;
             permanent discontinuation of study treatment, in accordance to the parent study or&#xD;
             local prescribing information&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing serious adverse events that have not resolved to baseline level or Grade ≤1&#xD;
             from the parent study or during the time between the last treatment in the parent&#xD;
             study and the first dose of study treatment in the extension study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious uncontrolled concomitant disease that would contraindicate the use of&#xD;
             study treatment at the time of the extension study or that would place the patient at&#xD;
             high risk for treatment-related complications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent participation in any therapeutic clinical trial (other than the parent&#xD;
             study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating, or intending to become pregnant during the extension study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hoffmann-La Roche</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Reference Study ID Number: YO42713 https://forpatients.roche.com/</last_name>
    <phone>888-662-6728 (U.S. Only)</phone>
    <email>global-roche-genentech-trials@gene.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beijing Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beijing</city>
        <zip>100142</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atezolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Qualified researchers may request access to individual patient level data through the clinical study data request platform (www.vivli.org). Further details on Roche's criteria for eligible studies are available here (https://vivli.org/ourmember/roche/). For further details on Roche's Global Policy on the Sharing of Clinical Information and how to request access to related clinical study documents, see here (https://www.roche.com/research_and_development/who_we_are_how_we_work/clinical_trials/our_commitment_to_data_sharing.htm).</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

