<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05114642</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019/669</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05114642</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Orthopedic Face Mask Use on Head Posture and Pharyngeal Airway</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Effect of Face Mask Treatment on Head Posture, Pharyngeal Airway, Skeletal and Dental Structures in Patients With Maxillary Retrognathia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Taner OZTURK, DDS, MS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>TC Erciyes University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study was to evaluate the changes in head posture, position of the hyoid&#xD;
      bone, pharyngeal airway and cervical posture after the use of Petit type face mask in&#xD;
      patients with skeletal class III malocclusion (ANB angle &lt; 0) with ongoing growth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No other study was found in the literature in which head posture, cervical posture, and hyoid&#xD;
      bone position were evaluated after the use of a face mask and compared with a control group&#xD;
      consisting of patients of the same age group and the same malocclusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All radiographic assessments, including cephalometric, pharyngeal airway and craniocervical&#xD;
      measurements were performed by the same researcher and she was blind to all the treatment&#xD;
      details, orthodontic records, and information of the subjects to prevent bias. Lateral&#xD;
      cephalometric radiographs were taken digitally with an X-ray unit (OP300; Instrumentarium&#xD;
      Dental, Tuusula, Finland) according to the manufacturer and same technician. Subjects were&#xD;
      positioned at the natural head position, teeth in centric occlusion, and lightly closed lips&#xD;
      for lateral cephalometric radiographs. Skeletal development of individuals was evaluated&#xD;
      using cervical vertebra maturation method (Ref: Bacetti T., An Improved Version of the&#xD;
      Cervical Vertebral Maturation (CVM) Method for the Assessment of Mandibular Growth. Angle&#xD;
      Orthod.). The skeletal development of individuals was evaluated using the cervical vertebra&#xD;
      maturation method and it was determined that all patients were in the prepubertal stage&#xD;
      (CS1-CS3). (Ref: Cevidanes L., Comparison of two protocols for maxillary protraction: bone&#xD;
      anchors versus face mask with rapid maxillary expansion. Angle Orthod.)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 30, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Head posture on lateral cephalometric radiographs taken before and after the application of the rapid maxillary expansion device with hooks to the upper dental arch and the Petit type face mask treatment applied after the skeletal class III patients due to maxillary retrognathia, whose growth development continues, for treatment to the Orthodontics Department of the Faculty of Dentistry, cervical posture, pharyngeal airway, and hyoid bone positions are determined.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Craniocervical posture change</measure>
    <time_frame>Before treatment (T0) and after treatment (up to about 10-12 month; T1) for the study group. First measurement (T0) for the control group and after similar follow-up time (up to about 10-12 month; T1) as for the treatment group.</time_frame>
    <description>Investigation of the change in head posture after treatment of class III malocclusion due to maxillary deficiency with a face mask using craniocervical angles (NSL/CVT, NSL/OPT, CVT/HOR, OPT/HOR, NL/VER, NSL/VER).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharyngeal airway change</measure>
    <time_frame>Before treatment (T0) and after treatment (up to about 10-12 month; T1) for the study group. First measurement (T0) for the control group and after similar follow-up time (up to about 10-12 month; T1) as for the treatment group.</time_frame>
    <description>Investigation of the change in pharyngeal airway dimensions after treatment of class III malocclusion due to maxillary deficiency with a face mask using pharyngeal airway sagittal dimension measurements (PNS-UPW, Cv2-MPW, Cv3-LPW, HRL/U-PNS, U-PNS, PASmin).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hyoid bone position change</measure>
    <time_frame>Before treatment (T0) and after treatment (up to about 10-12 month; T1) for the study group. First measurement (T0) for the control group and after similar follow-up time (up to about 10-12 month; T1) as for the treatment group.</time_frame>
    <description>Investigation of the change in hyoid bone position after treatment of class III malocclusion due to maxillary deficiency with a face mask using hyoid bone location measurements (H-Cv2, H-Cv3, H-Mandibular line, H-Me).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of craniocervical posture, pharyngeal airway and hyoid bone change</measure>
    <time_frame>Before treatment (T0) and after treatment (up to about 10-12 month; T1) for the study group. First measurement (T0) for the control group and after similar follow-up time (up to about 10-12 month; T1) as for the treatment group.</time_frame>
    <description>Investigation of the relationship between changes in craniocervical posture, pharyngeal airway dimensions and hyoid bone position.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Class III Malocclusion</condition>
  <condition>Hyoid Bone</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Skeletal Class III Malocclusion Treatment with Face Mask Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In patients with skeletal class III malocclusion (ANB angle &lt; 0,0) due to maxillary deficiency, rapid maxillary expansion appliances prepared on dental plaster models made of acrylic material covering all the upper dental posterior tooth surfaces were applied before the upper jaw was orthopedically brought forward with a face mask. This process was stopped when the expansion was made so that the palatal tubercles of the maxillary permanent first molars align with the buccal tubercles of the mandibular permanent first molars. Immediately afterwards, the petit-type face mask was applied to the hooks of the maxillary expansion device with the help of elastic bands and used continuously for at least 18 hours a day. After obtaining a positive overjet, the face mask appliance was used at night to ensure retention, and then the treatment was terminated.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>A control group was formed from patients in the same age group who had skeletal class III malocclusion due to maxillary growth deficiency but were not treated. In this way, the changes that occurred in the normal process in the head, craniocervical postures, pharyngeal airway and hyoid bones of the patients whose growth and development continued could be distinguished.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Skeletal Class III Malocclusion Treatment with Face Mask Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Expanding the maxilla, which is narrower than the mandible in the transverse dimension, using a rapid maxillary expansion device and protraction of the maxilla, which is located behind in the sagittal dimension, forward using the face-mask appliance.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Skeletal Class III Malocclusion Treatment with Face Mask Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Maxillary expansion</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the study group it is as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with skeletal Class III association (ANB &lt; 0°)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Maxillary insufficiency patients&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with ongoing growth development&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients who have used a 'Petit type face mask' for anterior positioning of the&#xD;
                  maxilla&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the control group it is as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with skeletal Class III association (ANB &lt; 0°)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Maxillary insufficiency patients&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with ongoing growth development&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients who have not had any orthodontic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with a congenital anomaly or a craniofacial deformity&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have undergone orthodontic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with tooth extraction or tooth loss&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with a history of trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who have completed growth development (patients with Ru on wrist film)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gokhan Coban, DDS, MDS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Erciyes University, Faculty of Dentistry, Department of Orthodontics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erciyes University Faculty of Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kayseri</city>
        <zip>38039</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Solow B, Sandham A. Cranio-cervical posture: a factor in the development and function of the dentofacial structures. Eur J Orthod. 2002 Oct;24(5):447-56.</citation>
    <PMID>12407940</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gul Amuk N, Kurt G, Baysal A, Turker G. Changes in pharyngeal airway dimensions following incremental and maximum bite advancement during Herbst-rapid palatal expander appliance therapy in late adolescent and young adult patients: a randomized non-controlled prospective clinical study. Eur J Orthod. 2019 May 24;41(3):322-330. doi: 10.1093/ejo/cjz011.</citation>
    <PMID>30892615</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kilinç AS, Arslan SG, Kama JD, Ozer T, Dari O. Effects on the sagittal pharyngeal dimensions of protraction and rapid palatal expansion in Class III malocclusion subjects. Eur J Orthod. 2008 Feb;30(1):61-6. Epub 2007 Sep 28.</citation>
    <PMID>17906307</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>TC Erciyes University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Taner OZTURK, DDS, MS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Class III Malocclusion</keyword>
  <keyword>Craniocervical Posture</keyword>
  <keyword>Hyoid Bone Position</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharyngeal Airway</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prognathism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malocclusion</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malocclusion, Angle Class III</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

