<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05110313</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>420620</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-056</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05110313</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Tildrakizumab on Epigenetic Age</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Tildrakizumab (ILUMYA) Use on Epigenetic Age Acceleration and Psoriasis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Carlos Wambier</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sun Pharmaceutical Industries Limited</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lifespan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ocean State Research Institute, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rhode Island Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Design: Single-center open-label clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: Evaluate if tildrakizumab reverses peripheral blood leukocyte DNA methylation&#xD;
      (epigenetic aging) observed in chronic psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of subjects: 30. Intervention group: 20 (10 men, 10 women) with moderate-to-severe&#xD;
      psoriasis. Control group: 10 (5 men, 5 women) with other skin diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population: &gt;35-year-old subjects will be recruited from Brown Dermatology Clinics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biological samples: Blood samples will be collected for all subjects at screening, and weeks&#xD;
      16, 28 and 52. Urine pregnancy tests will be performed for females of childbearing potential&#xD;
      at weeks 4, 16, and 28. Serum pregnancy test and QuantiFERON test for tuberculosis will be&#xD;
      performed at screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety parameters: Adverse events and screening, week 16, week 28 blood samples laboratory&#xD;
      results. Females of childbearing potential: serum pregnancy test at screening visit, urine&#xD;
      pregnancy test at weeks 4, 16, and 28. DMSB board will review data and laboratory flags&#xD;
      quarterly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study center: Rhode Island Hospital, Providence, RI, USA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trial Duration: One year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Introduction&#xD;
&#xD;
           Psoriasis is a common, chronic, inflammatory disorder that affects millions of&#xD;
           individuals worldwide.1,2 Although psoriasis etiology is still largely unknown and its&#xD;
           precision management remains to be improved, advances in understanding the pathogenic&#xD;
           cytokine network of psoriasis have led to the development of biologic therapy, such as&#xD;
           FDA-approved on-label indication for moderate-to-severe psoriasis of tildrakizumab-asmn&#xD;
           (ILUMYA, Sun Pharma Global, Princeton, NJ), an injectable monoclonal antibody that&#xD;
           inhibit interleukin (IL)-23, a pro-inflammatory cytokine. Epidemiologic studies have&#xD;
           promoted the recognition of psoriasis as a systemic disorder.3 We reported the&#xD;
           associations between psoriasis and incident risk of diabetes, cardiovascular disease,&#xD;
           Crohn's disease, and gout in prospective studies.4-7 However, the mechanism underlying&#xD;
           the systemic manifestations has been a knowledge gap for research on psoriasis.8&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Epigenetic aging (DNA methylation)&#xD;
&#xD;
           The complex interplays of genetic and environmental factors in psoriasis may occur&#xD;
           through the epigenetic mechanisms. DNA methylation of cytosine followed by guanine&#xD;
           residues (CpG dinucleotides), the epigenetic process that participates in the&#xD;
           transcriptional regulation and gene expression, has been linked to psoriasis.9 As the&#xD;
           precise pathogenesis underlying the development of psoriasis remains largely undefined,&#xD;
           further exploration of the role of epigenetics would offer a biologically plausible&#xD;
           perspective to clarify psoriasis etiology. Epigenetic epidemiology would serve as a tool&#xD;
           to elucidate the susceptibility and to identify novel biomarkers for psoriasis.10 The&#xD;
           epigenetic clock is a novel biomarker of aging, developed based on DNA methylation.11-13&#xD;
           The epigenetic clock may capture aspects of &quot;biological age&quot; and older epigenetic age of&#xD;
           blood has been associated with all-cause mortality,14,15 obesity,16 and many&#xD;
           diseases.17-20 Although whether epigenetic age is associated with psoriasis is not yet&#xD;
           known, we recently found that average epigenetic age in psoriasis patients was 5 years&#xD;
           higher than their corresponding chronological age (data not published), suggesting&#xD;
           possible epigenetic age acceleration in psoriasis. Therefore, epigenetic age&#xD;
           acceleration may serve as a novel biomarker for psoriasis and its systemic&#xD;
           manifestations. It may also potentially be used as an intermediate biomarker assessing&#xD;
           the systemic effects of ILUMYA.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Blood-based measures of epigenetics have the advantage of interrogating the systemic&#xD;
           health status or treatment responses and assessing biomarkers across a large variety of&#xD;
           disease domains.10,21&#xD;
&#xD;
           Rationale for the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Although epigenetic changes are tissue-specific, the connections between epigenetic&#xD;
           epidemiology and psoriasis in blood-based epigenetic studies would decipher novel&#xD;
           systemic inflammation and immune states of psoriasis and elucidate the effect of ILUMYA&#xD;
           use on affecting the epigenetic age acceleration. Comprehensive assessment of epigenetic&#xD;
           age acceleration in blood leukocytes between psoriasis and controls, and the change in&#xD;
           epigenetic age acceleration after ILUMYA initiation may lead to the identification of&#xD;
           methylation markers for predicting the systemic risk of psoriasis and the effect of&#xD;
           ILUMYA on psoriasis. If confirmed to be an intermediate marker for the effect of&#xD;
           psoriasis therapy with ILUMYA, epigenetic age may be used to better profile the&#xD;
           beneficial role of immunomodulation, promoting the management of psoriasis and its&#xD;
           systemic comorbidities.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Psoriasis is an inflammatory disease of the skin and joints and has been recognized as a&#xD;
           systemic disorder. In this proposed study, we hypothesize that epigenetic age&#xD;
           acceleration may be associated with risk of psoriasis, and ILUMYA may be able to affect&#xD;
           the epigenetic age acceleration associated with psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our goal is to determine the association between epigenetic age acceleration and risk of&#xD;
      psoriasis, and also to evaluate if ILUMYA can reverse peripheral blood leukocyte DNA&#xD;
      methylation (epigenetic aging) associated with chronic psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1: To examine the association between epigenetic age acceleration and psoriasis:&#xD;
      by comparing the baseline samples of peripheral blood leukocyte genome-wide DNA methylation&#xD;
      assay collected at screening for psoriasis patients and controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 2: To evaluate dynamic changes in epigenetic age of the on-label use of ILUMYA&#xD;
      (week 28 vs screening visit). And upon discontinuation (week 28 vs week 52). Assess if&#xD;
      epigenetic age could be a marker for the effect of ILUMYA on psoriasis through psoriasis&#xD;
      severity scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 3: we will evaluate the possible correlation/association with psoriasis severity&#xD;
      scores and the presence of systemic co-morbidities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      References&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Lowes MA, Bowcock AM, Krueger JG. Pathogenesis and therapy of psoriasis. Nature.&#xD;
           2007;445(7130):866-873.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Kurd SK, Gelfand JM. The prevalence of previously diagnosed and undiagnosed psoriasis in&#xD;
           US adults: results from NHANES 2003-2004. Journal of the American Academy of&#xD;
           Dermatology. 2009;60(2):218-224.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Li WQ, Cho E, Weinstock MA, Mashfiq H, Qureshi AA. Epidemiological Assessments of Skin&#xD;
           Outcomes in the Nurses' Health Studies. American journal of public health.&#xD;
           2016;106(9):1677- 1683.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Li W, Han J, Hu FB, Curhan GC, Qureshi AA. Psoriasis and risk of type 2 diabetes among&#xD;
           women and men in the United States: a population-based cohort study. The Journal of&#xD;
           investigative dermatology. 2012;132(2):291-298.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Li WQ, Han JL, Manson JE, et al. Psoriasis and risk of nonfatal cardiovascular disease&#xD;
           in U.S. women: a cohort study. The British journal of dermatology.2012;166(4):811-818.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Li WQ, Han JL, Chan AT, Qureshi AA. Psoriasis, psoriatic arthritis and increased risk of&#xD;
           incident Crohn's disease in US women. Annals of the rheumatic diseases.&#xD;
           2013;72(7):1200-1205.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Merola JF, Wu S, Han J, Choi HK, Qureshi AA. Psoriasis, psoriatic arthritis and risk of&#xD;
           gout in US men and women. Annals of the rheumatic diseases. 2015;74(8):1495- 1500.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Ryan C, Korman NJ, Gelfand JM, et al. Research gaps in psoriasis: opportunities for&#xD;
           future studies. Journal of the American Academy of Dermatology. 2014;70(1):146-167.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Gudjonsson JE, Krueger G. A role for epigenetics in psoriasis: methylated Cytosine-&#xD;
           Guanine sites differentiate lesional from nonlesional skin and from normal skin. The&#xD;
           Journal of investigative dermatology. 2012;132(3 Pt 1):506-508.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Nelson HH, Kelsey KT. Epigenetic epidemiology as a tool to understand the role of&#xD;
           immunity in chronic disease. Epigenomics. 2016;8(8):1007-1009.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Horvath S. DNA methylation age of human tissues and cell types. Genome biology.&#xD;
           2013;14(10): R115.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Bocklandt S, Lin W, Sehl ME, et al. Epigenetic predictor of age. PloS one. 2011;6(6):&#xD;
           e14821.&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Hannum G, Guinney J, Zhao L, et al. Genome-wide methylation profiles reveal quantitative&#xD;
           views of human aging rates. Mol Cell. 2013;49(2):359-367.&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. Marioni RE, Shah S, McRae AF, et al. DNA methylation age of blood predicts all- cause&#xD;
           mortality in later life. Genome biology. 2015; 16:25.&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Christiansen L, Lenart A, Tan Q, et al. DNA methylation age is associated with mortality&#xD;
           in a longitudinal Danish twin study. Aging cell. 2016;15(1):149-154.&#xD;
&#xD;
       16. Horvath S, Erhart W, Brosch M, et al. Obesity accelerates epigenetic aging of human&#xD;
           liver.&#xD;
&#xD;
       17. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America.&#xD;
           2014;111(43):15538-15543.&#xD;
&#xD;
       18. Horvath S, Ritz BR. Increased epigenetic age and granulocyte counts in the blood of&#xD;
           Parkinson's disease patients. Aging. 2015;7(12):1130-1142.&#xD;
&#xD;
       19. Horvath S, Levine AJ. HIV-1 Infection Accelerates Age According to the Epigenetic Clock.&#xD;
&#xD;
       20. Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2015;212(10):1563-1573.&#xD;
&#xD;
       21. Levine ME, Hosgood HD, Chen B, Absher D, Assimes T, Horvath S. DNA methylation age of&#xD;
           blood predicts future onset of lung cancer in the women's health initiative. Aging-Us.&#xD;
           2015;7(9):690-700.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>We will enroll 30 subjects aged 35 years or older.&#xD;
Arm 1 (psoriasis treatment): 20 subjects with moderate-to-severe psoriasis (including 10 men and 10 women).&#xD;
Arm 2 (non-psoriasis, non-treatment): 10 age and sex matched controls without psoriasis (including 5 men and 5 women).&#xD;
The blood leukocytes will be collected to evaluate DNA methylation at baseline (week 0) for both arms. The psoriasis treatment arm will undergo blood leukocytes collection during treatment (at week 28) and post-treatment (week 52).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Epigenetic aging in psoriatic patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>To examine the association between epigenetic age acceleration and psoriasis: by comparing the baseline samples of peripheral blood leukocyte genome-wide DNA methylation assay sample collected at the screening visit for psoriasis vs non-psoriasis patients.&#xD;
The epigenetic aging test is based on the Methylation EPIC BeadChip (Illumina), covering over 850,000 methylation sites. Specific patterns and quantifications will be compared between groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamics of tildrakizumab on epigenetic aging of psoriatic patients.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and treatment weeks 28 and 52.</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate dynamic effects and changes in epigenetic age of the on-label use of ILUMYA (week 28 vs screening visit). And upon discontinuation (week 28 vs week 52). Assess if epigenetic age could be a marker for the effect of ILUMYA on psoriasis through psoriasis severity scores.&#xD;
Specific patterns and quantifications will be compared between timeframes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of individual characteristics on epigenetic aging</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the possible correlation/association with psoriasis severity scores (BSA, PASI and CAPP) and the presence of systemic co-morbidities on epigenetic aging.&#xD;
Multivariate analysis will be conducted with variables that include, but are not limited to age, body mass index, previous diagnoses, and medical interventions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effects of individual characteristics on tildrakizumab response</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and treatment weeks 28 and 52.</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the possible correlation/association with changes in psoriasis severity scores (BSA, PASI and CAPP) and the presence of systemic co-morbidities on epigenetic aging. Multivariate analysis will be conducted with variables that include, but are not limited to baseline epigenetic aging assay results, age, body mass index, previous diagnoses, and medical interventions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Psoriasis</condition>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PSORIASIS TREATMENT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1 syringe containing 1 mL of 100 mg/mL tildrakizumab-asmn. 100mg delivered by subcutaneous injection at weeks 0, 4, 16 and 28. Total of 20 subjects (10 male, 10 female).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NON-PSORIASIS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention. Total of 10 subjects (5 male, 5 female).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TILDRAKIZUMAB</intervention_name>
    <description>ILUMYA (tildrakizumab-asmn) is a humanized IgG1/k monoclonal antibody that selectively binds to the p19 subunit of IL-23 and inhibits its interaction with the IL-23 receptor. IL-23 is a naturally occurring cytokine that is involved in inflammatory and immune responses.&#xD;
ILUMYA injection for subcutaneous use is a sterile, clear to slightly opalescent, colorless to slightly yellow solution supplied in 1mL single-dose prefilled syringe which contains 100 mg of tildrakizumab-asmn formulated in: L-histidine (0.495 mg), L-histidine hydrochloride monohydrate (1.42 mg), polysorbate 80 (0.5 mg), sucrose (70.0 mg), and Water for Injection, USP with a pH of 5.7-6.3. ILUMYA is supplied in a single-dose prefilled syringe with a glass barrel and 29-gauge fixed, 1/2-inch needle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PSORIASIS TREATMENT</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ILUMYA™</other_name>
    <other_name>tildrakizumab-asmn</other_name>
    <other_name>ATC CODE: L04AC17 (WHO)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 35 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psoriasis subjects: moderate-to-severe psoriasis: PASI (Psoriasis Area and Severity&#xD;
             Index ≥12) and a minimum Body Surface Area (BSA) involvement of 10%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Control Subjects: other skin diseases without psoriasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients aged less than 35 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with previous skin cancer or other cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women of childbearing potential without effective contraceptive method, or lactating&#xD;
             women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prisoners.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Psoriasis patients who have had a severe allergic reaction to ILUMYA or any of its&#xD;
             ingredients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Psoriasis patients who have chronic or recurring infections. Positive QuantiFERON upon&#xD;
             screening will be exclusionary for this trial (latent tuberculosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may interfere with patient's&#xD;
             ability to participate in the study, such as severe cognitive impairment or other&#xD;
             comorbidities that would, in the opinion of the investigator, predictably limit&#xD;
             compliance with the study plan.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos G Wambier, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Warren Alpert Medical School of Brown University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melissa-Lauren Hooks, MS</last_name>
    <phone>401-606-4697</phone>
    <email>Melissa-Lauren.Hooks@Lifespan.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lynn Morris</last_name>
    <phone>401-444-7853</phone>
    <email>Lmorris3@Lifespan.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinical Trials Center for Skin Diseases: Rhode Island Hospital, 593 Eddy Street, Dermatology Research, Jane Brown Building, 1st floor, Room 115</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02903</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://brownderm.org/clinical-trials/</url>
    <description>Brown Dermatology Clinical Trials Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rhode Island Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carlos Wambier</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Dermatology, Clinician Educator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Epigenetic aging</keyword>
  <keyword>DNA methylation</keyword>
  <keyword>interleukin (IL)-23</keyword>
  <keyword>Neutrophilic inflammation</keyword>
  <keyword>Psoriasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Aging</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Psoriasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Antibodies, Monoclonal</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

