<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05111990</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1-10-72-296-18</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05111990</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Human Milk and Its Effect on Infant's Metabolism and Infant Gut Microbiome</brief_title>
  <acronym>MAINHEALTH</acronym>
  <official_title>The Influence of Maternal Health on Human Breast Milk Composition With Potential Downstream Effects on Infant Metabolism and Gut Colonization</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Aarhus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Copenhagen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Arla Foods</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Aarhus University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Aarhus</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This protocol explains the MAINHEALTH cohort. The study examine the influence of maternal&#xD;
      health parameters on human breast milk composition and integrates milk phenotype with infant&#xD;
      metabolism and infant gut microbial content and metabolism.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The birth of a living human being is the result of an approximately nine-month pregnancy in&#xD;
      which the developing foetus has taken exactly the building blocks necessary to grow and&#xD;
      develop from its mother. However, growth and development continues in multiple dimensions at&#xD;
      an increasing pace after birth. The nutrition in the first 1,000 days from conception to the&#xD;
      child's 2nd birthday plays a pivotal role in shaping the future health of the child. Yet,&#xD;
      little is known of how breast milk components vary due to maternal factors or of the&#xD;
      biological mechanisms behind the beneficial actions of many breast milk nutrients. The&#xD;
      investigators propose to overcome these obstacles by combining specialties to give a more&#xD;
      complete account of what breast milk is (major and minor milk constituents and microbiota),&#xD;
      how it affects the infants directly or indirectly through breast milk-gut microbiome&#xD;
      interactions and by which mechanisms. In this study longitudinal samples from 200&#xD;
      mother-infant dyads during the first year of life across three groups of pregestational&#xD;
      maternal BMI; normal weight (BMI 18.5-24.99), overweight (BMI 25-30), and obese (BMI &gt;30) are&#xD;
      collected. The samples give a comprehensive record of what the infant has ingested (milk&#xD;
      samples) and how the infant and infant gut microbiome responds to this (infant urine and&#xD;
      feces). Maternal diet in pregnancy and at milk sample deliveries are recorded through a 24h&#xD;
      online food recall and diary system. Maternal health attributes will, besides BMI, be&#xD;
      analysed through clinical blood biochemistry parameters. Follow-up samples and infant dietary&#xD;
      intake as the infant grows allow investigating how early life diet shaped infant growth and&#xD;
      gut colonization more long term. The investigators have formed an experienced team of&#xD;
      scientists within metabolomics, microbiology and medicine, holding leading positions within&#xD;
      their respective fields in Denmark. The novelty in the study is the interdisciplinarity,&#xD;
      unique study design and the emphasis to integrate a number of dynamic measurements thereby&#xD;
      offering the ability to identify the factors in breast milk affecting infant metabolism and&#xD;
      gut colonization. Knowing this enable the optimization of infant formula.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research questions asked in this project are three-fold.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  First, the investigators want to determine the variability of breast milk nutrients by&#xD;
           application of multi-omics (metabolomics, proteomics and glycomics). The production of&#xD;
           human breast milk has a high maternal metabolic cost. Thus, hypothesis is that maternal&#xD;
           health attributes (metabolic dysfunction or obesity) influence which breast milk&#xD;
           nutrients are made available to the infant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Second, the investigators want to establish the microbiome of breast milk. Maternal&#xD;
           obesity can lead to an apparent gut microbial ecology and increases the risk of obesity&#xD;
           for the child. Thus, the hypothesis is that maternal obesity confers distinct&#xD;
           microorganisms to the infant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Third, the investigators want to identify biological mechanisms for how breast milk&#xD;
           nutrients are metabolised in the infants. Infants exclusively breast-feeding offer total&#xD;
           compliance. Thus, the hypothesis is that by deconstructing breast milk components and&#xD;
           markers of infant metabolism through comprehensive analysis of infant urine and feces,&#xD;
           bioactivity of breast milk nutrients can be elucidated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolite profile of human milk</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Human milk metabolites by Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spectroscopy. Data will be analysed as absolute concentrations of milk metabolites; how milk metabolite profiles are related to mother's blood chemistry, milk microbial profiles, milk oligosaccharides, infant urine metabolome, and infant fecal microbiomes will be explored using multivariate analyses.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolite profile of human milk by Liquid Chromatography-Mass Spectrometry (LC-MS) analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Human milk metabolites by LC-MS-based metabolomics. Data will be analysed as absolute concentrations of milk metabolites; how milk metabolite profiles are related to milk microbial profiles, milk oligosaccharides, infant urine metabolome, and infant fecal microbiomes will be explored using multivariate analyses.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Milk proteome profile</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Human milk proteome by LC-MS-based, bottom-up proteomics. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of milk proteins.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Milk protein post-translational modification (PTM) profile</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Post-translational modifications of human milk proteins is analysed by LC-MS-based and 2D- gel-based proteomics. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of milk protein PTMs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Milk glycome profile</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Human milk glycome by LC-MS-based glycomics. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of milk glycans.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial structure of human milk</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Human milk microbiome by nanopore sequencing. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of bacteria from phylum to genus levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial structure of infant feces</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 5 years of age</time_frame>
    <description>Infant fecal microbiome by nanopore sequencing. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of bacteria from phylum to genus levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial structure of infant oral cavity</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Oral cavity microbiome by nanopore sequencing. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of bacteria from phylum to genus levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial structure of mother's skin microbiome</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days postpartum</time_frame>
    <description>Skin microbiome by nanopore sequencing. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of bacteria from phylum to genus levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolite profile of infant fecal material</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 5 years of age</time_frame>
    <description>Infant fecal metabolome by NMR-based metabolomics. Data will be analysed as absolute concentrations of fecal metabolites</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Infant metabolism investigated by infant urine metabolomics</measure>
    <time_frame>Birth to 3 months of age</time_frame>
    <description>Infant urine metabolome by NMR-based metabolomics. Data will be analysed as absolute concentrations of urine metabolites</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial structure of maternal vagina and rectum to investigate vertical transmission of bacteria to infant during birth</measure>
    <time_frame>During birth</time_frame>
    <description>Vertical transmission of microbiome from mother to infant. Vaginal and rectal microbiome by nanopore sequencing. Data will be analysed as relative abundances of bacteria from phylum to genus levels.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mother's 24-h dietary recall (myfood24)</measure>
    <time_frame>During pregnancy (Gestational age 30), 30, 60, and 90 days postpartum. In each case two times within a week (one weekday and one weekend day).</time_frame>
    <description>Aggregated nutrient intake data (e.g. proteins, vitamins, fibers, omega-3-fatty acids)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Milk Collection</condition>
  <condition>Human Milk/Breastfeeding</condition>
  <condition>Human Milk Microbiome</condition>
  <condition>Infant Gut Microbiome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal pre-gestational BMI 18.5&lt;25</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal pre-gestational BMI 25&lt;30</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Maternal pre-gestational BMI &gt;30</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood sample (mother, Gestational age (GA) week 20-24) Vaginal swap (Copan Eswab; mother at&#xD;
      birth) Rectum swap (Copan Eswab; mother at birth) Breast milk (3, 30, 60, 90 days postpartum)&#xD;
      Urine (infant; 30, 60, 90 days postpartum) Feces (infant; 30, 60, 90 days and 1, 2, 3, 4, and&#xD;
      5 years postpartum) Saliva (Copan Eswab; infant 30 days postpartum) Breast skin (Copan Eswab;&#xD;
      mother 30 days postpartum)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Residence in Aarhus area is necessary and Aarhus University Hospital has to be the place of&#xD;
        giving birth. This is due to samples being collected by midwifes during labor and when&#xD;
        study personnel collect samples in study participants' homes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria related to mother:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residing in Aarhus area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Above 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI above 18.5 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intention to breastfeed the first four to six months following birth&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to communicate in Danish&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria related to mother:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suffering from the following chronic diseases that demands medical treatment: diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus, celiac disease, inflammatory bowel disease (Chrohn's disease or ulcerosa&#xD;
             colitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking medicaments for irritable bowel syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking medicine for metabolic disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Taking medicine for psychological disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have had gastric bypass surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned caesarean section&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received antibiotics after week 12 in their pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Utilizing significant amount of infant formula following birth&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria related to infant:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants born after gestational age 37 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants with a birth weight between 2500 g and 5000 g&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria related to infant:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Inborn errors of metabolism&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ulrik K Sundekiled, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Aarhus</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ulrik K Sundekilde, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+45 22479963</phone>
    <email>uksundekilde@food.au.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aarhus University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aarhus</city>
        <zip>8200</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ulrik K Sundekilde, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>22479963</phone>
      <email>uksundekilde@food.au.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>milk metabolites, multi-omics, gut microbiome</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

