<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05111756</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Braining - personell</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05111756</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Braining - Physical Exercise in Psychiatry - Evaluation of Feasibility, Implementation and Health Among Staff</brief_title>
  <official_title>Braining Study - Implementation of Physical Activity for Patients and Staff in Specialist Psychiatry, Feasibility on Pilot Unit and Effect Evaluation in Randomized Controlled Multi-center Study.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Region Stockholm</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Region Stockholm</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Physical exercise (PE) shows beneficial effects on somatic and psychiatric symptoms.&#xD;
      &quot;Braining&quot; is a clinical invention where psychiatric staff exercise together with patients to&#xD;
      help patients start and execute PE regularly. In the present study feasibility of the&#xD;
      intervention will be evaluated, how Braining is perceived and implemented, and effects on&#xD;
      health and physical activity among staff. It is hypothesized that staff health and physical&#xD;
      activity will increase after implementing Braining at the unit. Braining will be implemented&#xD;
      at four psychiatric units in Region Stockholm, Sweden. During 6 months staff will be trained&#xD;
      and receive implementation support. To measure feasibility the staff will answer self-rating&#xD;
      questionnaires and be invited to a focus group interview post the implementation period.&#xD;
      Implementation will be evaluated by ratings of compliance, the self-rating questionnaire&#xD;
      Normalization Process Theory Measure (S-NoMAD), and focus group interviews. Health will be&#xD;
      measured by self ratings of stress, sleep, general health, and engagement pre implementation&#xD;
      and every month during the 6 month implementation phase. Ratings will be repeated at follow&#xD;
      up 12 month after implementation started. Physical activity will be rated during the 6 months&#xD;
      implementation phase using an oura ring, tracker of activity and at follow up 12 month after&#xD;
      implementation started. All staff at the units will be invited to participate in the&#xD;
      evaluations, approximately 20 individuals per unit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      &quot;Braining&quot; is a clinical invention that helps patients in psychiatry to start and execute&#xD;
      physical exercise (PE) regularly in psychiatric care. The core components are basic high&#xD;
      performance group training session and motivational work led by the psychiatric staff.&#xD;
      Braining is used as add-on treatment to regular psychiatric care and is included in the&#xD;
      patient care plan. Braining is unique in that it:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Includes trained psychiatric clinical staff exercising together with patients from both&#xD;
           out- and inpatient ward units in daily, high endurance group training sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. is included in regular healthcare fee, (free of charge)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. includes a motivational and educational visit (as a group seminar or as an individual&#xD;
           visit) at the start and end of a twelve week training period&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. includes regular measurements (self-assessment questionnaires, blood samples, physical&#xD;
           and mental health examination and education before and after the twelve week training&#xD;
           period)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. offers short individual motivating visits before every training session, including&#xD;
           assessment of day shape and fitness to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the present study focus is on the feasibility of the intervention, how Braining is&#xD;
      perceived and implemented, and effects on health and physical activity among staff. The&#xD;
      research questions are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  How do staff experience Braining regarding acceptability, applicability and suitability?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Is there a correlation between the staff's work with Braining and occupational health,&#xD;
           measured as performed PE, perceived stress, and general health?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Is there a correlation between the staff's work with Braining and occupational health,&#xD;
           measured as exhaustion, sleep, sick leave, and job engagement?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  How compliant are staff to the Braining method in the sense of number completed training&#xD;
           sessions, quality of completed sessions, compliance with the core components of the&#xD;
           method?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To what extent is Braining integrated into ordinary work at the unit in short (6 months)&#xD;
           and long term (1 and 2 years)?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Braining is to be implemented at 4 psychiatric care units the upcoming years starting nov&#xD;
      2021. Approximately 20 personnel on each unit will be included. Planned design is a&#xD;
      longitudinal pre-post study with four measurements during ongoing intervention (weeks 1, 4, 8&#xD;
      and 12) and two follow-ups (6 months and 12 months post inclusion). Improved design with&#xD;
      three baseline observation (data points) and possible interrupted time series design, (ITSD).&#xD;
      Relationships between the staff's work with Braining and their own occupational health are&#xD;
      examined self-estimates, see list. Physical activity level is measured with OURA ring for 3&#xD;
      weeks measurement before training and measured throughout the 6 months and at follow-up after&#xD;
      12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experience of the implementation process is evaluated with S-NoMAD, which is administered at&#xD;
      two occasions during the intervention, after completion and at follow-up after 2 years. Staff&#xD;
      experience of working with Braining is examined with self-assessments and in focus group&#xD;
      interviews after the end of the intervention. Staff compliance with Braining is evaluated&#xD;
      based on a checklist where data is collected through weekly follow-ups of the work on the&#xD;
      unit as well as observation of completed training sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis Qualitative analysis: Recorded material from focus group interviews is&#xD;
      transcribed and analyzed based on the thematic analysis method according to Braun &amp; Clarke et&#xD;
      al 2006). The method aims to understand the individual's perspective in relation to a&#xD;
      particular phenomenon and is often used as an inductive hypothesis-generating approach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Continuous data will be analyzed using mixed effects models or t-test, nominal data analyzed&#xD;
      mainly with chi2 test. In mixed effects models of differences between groups the interaction&#xD;
      effect of group and time will be the central estimate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes spent on Physical movement (high, moderate, low)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from inclusion to follow up 4 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Physical exercise conducted by staff, measured by oura ring</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes spent on Physical movement (high, moderate, low)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from inclusion to follow up 6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Physical exercise conducted by staff, measured by actigraph</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes spent on Physical movement (high, moderate, low)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from inclusion to follow up 6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Physical exercise conducted by staff, measured by self ratings of International Physical Activity Questionnaires (IPAQ)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>General health</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from inclusion to follow up 6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>General health measured by self ratings of General health questionnaire (GHQ), scores 0-12, higher scores indicates more mental distress</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from inclusion to follow up 6 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived stress measured by self ratings of Perceived stress scale (PSS-10), , scores 0-40, higher scores indicates more mental distress</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived feasibility of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility measured by self ratings of Feasibility of Intervention Measure (FIM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived feasibility of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility measured by self ratings of Feasibility of Intervention Measure (FIM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability measured by self ratings of Acceptability of Intervention Measure (AIM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability measured by self ratings of Acceptability of Intervention Measure (AIM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Appropriateness</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Intervention Appropriateness measured by self ratings of Intervention Appropriateness Measure (IAM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention Appropriateness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Intervention Appropriateness measured by self ratings of Intervention Appropriateness Measure (IAM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Summary of compliance 6 months after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Compliance to intervention measured by weekly observations and reports of performed training activities</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Normalization of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Normalization of intervention measured by The Swedish version of the Normalization Process Theory Measure (S-NoMAD)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Normalization of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Normalization of intervention measured by The Swedish version of the Normalization Process Theory Measure (S-NoMAD)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Normalization of intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Normalization of intervention measured by The Swedish version of the Normalization Process Theory Measure (S-NoMAD)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Qualitative interviews</measure>
    <time_frame>After the implementation phase i.e., 6 months after implementation start</time_frame>
    <description>Qualitative interviews concerning acceptability, feasibility, appropriateness, compliance and normalization of the intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Burnout</measure>
    <time_frame>Three baseline observations (approx. bi-weekly) prior to implementation, monthly throughout implementation phase 6 months, at follow up 12 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Burnout measured by self ratings of Burnout Shirom-Melamed Burnout Questionnaire (SMBQ-6), scores 6-42, higher scores indicates more burnout symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sleep difficulties</measure>
    <time_frame>Three baseline observations (approx. bi-weekly) prior to implementation, monthly throughout implementation phase 6 months, at follow up 12 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Sleep difficulties measured by self ratings of Insomnia Severity Index (ISI), , scores 0-28, higher scores indicates more sleep difficulties</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Work and illness</measure>
    <time_frame>At inclusion before implementation start, monthly throughout implementation phase 6 months, at follow up 12 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Work and illness measured by section C of Treatment Inventory of Costs in Patients with psychiatric disorders (TIC-P)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Engagement at work</measure>
    <time_frame>Three baseline observations (approx. bi-weekly) prior to implementation, monthly throughout implementation phase 6 months, at follow up 12 months after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Engagement at work measured by Utrecht work engagement scale (UWES-9S), scores 0-54, higher scores indicates more work engagement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Physical Inactivity</condition>
  <condition>Occupational Stress</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Unit A</arm_group_label>
    <description>Staff at first phase units, receiving Braining, physical exercise</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Unit B</arm_group_label>
    <description>Staff at second phase units, receiving Braining, physical exercise</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Staff of a psychiatric care unit&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Works at one of the relevant units regardless of occupational category, including&#xD;
             administrative services.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Permanent employment or fixed-term employment for at least one more year after the&#xD;
             start of studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe mental disorder such as ongoing mania, psychosis, and conditions when high risk&#xD;
             of suicide or high risk of violence available according to the assessment of&#xD;
             psychiatric staff at the unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical conditions such as heart or lung disease, infection, abstinence where heart&#xD;
             rate-increasing physical activity is considered contraindicated due to Medical&#xD;
             reasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical disability that makes it impossible to move independently to the gym and&#xD;
             performing the indicated exercise in the training sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental disability which means that you can not participate in group training.&#xD;
             Difficulty speaking or understanding the Swedish language.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing heavy substance use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Full-time sick leave&gt; 1 month during the training period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lina Martinsson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Region Stockholm and Karolinska institiutet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lina Martinsson, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46707684604</phone>
    <email>lina.martinsson@ki.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sigrid Salomonsson, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0708442283</phone>
    <email>Sigrid.salomonsson@ki.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Region Stockholm, Liljeholmsberget</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rebecka Broman, Nurse</last_name>
      <email>rebecka.broman@regionstockholm.se</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lina Martinsson, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sigrid Salomonsson, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>physical exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>psychiatric staff</keyword>
  <keyword>Occupational Stress</keyword>
  <keyword>implementation</keyword>
  <keyword>feasibility</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Occupational Stress</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

