<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05111236</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NIRM-Physio/01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05111236</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Potential Benefits of Home Based Exercise Programs in the Management of Spastic Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
  <acronym>HEP&amp;CP</acronym>
  <official_title>Potential Benefits of Home Based Exercise Programs With and Without Traditional Massage in the Management of Spastic Cerebral Palsy: A Randomized Controlled Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Rehabilitation Medicine, Islamabad, Pakistan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Rehabilitation Medicine, Islamabad, Pakistan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study will be conducted to see the potential benefits of home based exercise program&#xD;
      comprising routine physical therapy and traditional massage in the management of spastic&#xD;
      cerebral palsy (CP). It will be a randomized controlled trial having two groups, RPT group&#xD;
      and Massage group. Both groups will be provided with routine physical therapy treatment&#xD;
      comprising stretching of spastic muscles, strengthening of weak muscles, positioning and&#xD;
      posturing strategies. Massage group will also receive traditional massage in addition to&#xD;
      routine physical therapy. Parents/Caregivers will be trained to perform routine physical&#xD;
      therapy and traditional massage at home. Data will collected using a structured&#xD;
      questionnaire, Modified Ashworth Scale (MAS), Gross Motor Function Measure (GMFM),Gross Motor&#xD;
      Function Classification System (GMFCS) and CP Child's Caregiver Priorities &amp; Child Health&#xD;
      Index of Life with Disabilities at baseline, after 6th and 12th weeks of intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      CP is among the most common type of physical disabilities presenting itself in children&#xD;
      across the globe. Although its incidence range has been reported from 2 to 2.5 cases per 1000&#xD;
      live births globally, however it may be many folds in poor counties due to lack of reporting&#xD;
      and absence of CP registries at national level . Many interventions are in use to manage the&#xD;
      disabling and lifelong consequences of this condition. However majority of these&#xD;
      interventions remain beyond the reach of poor population especially in under developed&#xD;
      countries with poor socio-economic status like Pakistan. This creates a need for search to&#xD;
      such interventions which should be locally available, accessible, low cost, affordable, and&#xD;
      doable by the poor population so that disabling consequences of this condition may be&#xD;
      minimized. RPT and traditional massage performed by parents at home after proper training&#xD;
      fall in the category of such low cost interventions. Hence there is dire need to investigate&#xD;
      the potential benefits of such interventions. That is why this RCT has been planned.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>It is a RCT with two groups, RPT and Massage. Both groups will receive routine physical therapy (with addition of traditional massage in Massage group only) five days a week for a period of 12 weeks.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Outcome assessor will be kept blind about group allocation and identification of the participants before assessments at baseline, after 06 weeks and 12 weeks of intervention</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Ashworth scale (MAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Twelve weeks</time_frame>
    <description>0 = No increase in muscle tone&#xD;
1 = Slight increase in muscle tone, manifested by a catch and release or by minimal resistance at the end of the range of motion when the affected part(s) is moved in flexion or extension&#xD;
1+ = Slight increase in muscle tone, manifested by a catch, followed by minimal resistance throughout the remainder (less than half) of the Range Of Motion (ROM)&#xD;
2 = More marked increase in muscle tone through most of the ROM, but affected part(s) easily moved&#xD;
3 = Considerable increase in muscle tone, passive movement difficult.&#xD;
4 = Affected part(s) rigid in flexion or extension</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gross motor Function Measure (GMFM-88)</measure>
    <time_frame>Twelve weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It is used to check the gross motor ability having total of 88 items to be checked in 05 different domain Lying and Rolling (total score 51), Sitting (Total score 60), Crawling and Kneeling( total 42), standing (total 39), walking running jumping (total 72)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gross Motor Function Classification System (GMFCS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Twelve weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It has five levels I to V showing the mobility level. Level I to III represent ambulatory status while IV and V represent Non- ambulatory status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CPCHILD ( Caregiver Priorities &amp; child health index of life with Disabilities</measure>
    <time_frame>Twelve weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It is used to check the quality of life of children with cerebral palsy. It has 09 sections to be completed representing different states related to quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">86</enrollment>
  <condition>Cerebral Palsy, Spastic, Diplegic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RPT Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Routine physical therapy comprising stretching of spastic muscles, Strengthening of weak muscles, positioning ( how to make sitting and standing postures at home) and posturing strategies. This whole regimen will be practiced fives times a week for a period of twelve weeks.&#xD;
Other Names:&#xD;
• Routine Physical Therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Massage Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Traditional massage of thirty minutes duration ( five minutes of massage will be provided to all four limbs, front and back of trunk area) prior to routine physical therapy. Routine physical therapy comprising stretching of spastic muscles, Strengthening of weak muscles, positioning ( how to make sitting and standing postures at home) and posturing strategies.&#xD;
Other Names:&#xD;
• Routine physical therapy and Traditional massage</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Routine physical therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Rehabilitation strategies in management of children with spastic CP</description>
    <arm_group_label>Massage Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RPT Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Traditional massage</intervention_name>
    <description>Rehabilitation strategies in management of children with spastic CP</description>
    <arm_group_label>Massage Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child should have established diagnosis of spastic cerebral palsy (diplegic types&#xD;
             only).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children having moderate to severe contractures.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Children having moderate to severe mental retardation and with multiple&#xD;
                  disabilities.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Children with Attention Deficit Hyperactive Disorder (ADHD), uncontrolled&#xD;
                  seizures and behavioral disorders&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Qamar Mahmood</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>HOD, Physiotherapy Department</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Qamar Mahmood</last_name>
    <phone>Mahmood</phone>
    <email>qamarpt@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Rehabilitation Medicine (NIRM)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Islamabad</city>
        <state>Federal Capital</state>
        <zip>44000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Qamar Mahmood, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+923335151063</phone>
      <email>qamarpt@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kirby RS, Wingate MS, Van Naarden Braun K, Doernberg NS, Arneson CL, Benedict RE, Mulvihill B, Durkin MS, Fitzgerald RT, Maenner MJ, Patz JA, Yeargin-Allsopp M. Prevalence and functioning of children with cerebral palsy in four areas of the United States in 2006: a report from the Autism and Developmental Disabilities Monitoring Network. Res Dev Disabil. 2011 Mar-Apr;32(2):462-9. doi: 10.1016/j.ridd.2010.12.042. Epub 2011 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>21273041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reddihough DS, Collins KJ. The epidemiology and causes of cerebral palsy. Aust J Physiother. 2003;49(1):7-12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12600249</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bhasin TK, Brocksen S, Avchen RN, Van Naarden Braun K. Prevalence of four developmental disabilities among children aged 8 years--Metropolitan Atlanta Developmental Disabilities Surveillance Program, 1996 and 2000. MMWR Surveill Summ. 2006 Jan 27;55(1):1-9. Erratum in: MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2006 Feb 3;55(4):105-6.</citation>
    <PMID>16437058</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reddihough DS, Jiang B, Lanigan A, Reid SM, Walstab JE, Davis E. Social outcomes of young adults with cerebral palsy. J Intellect Dev Disabil. 2013 Sep;38(3):215-22. doi: 10.3109/13668250.2013.788690. Epub 2013 May 14.</citation>
    <PMID>23672634</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hurvitz EA, Leonard C, Ayyangar R, Nelson VS. Complementary and alternative medicine use in families of children with cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2003 Jun;45(6):364-70.</citation>
    <PMID>12785436</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Novak I, McIntyre S, Morgan C, Campbell L, Dark L, Morton N, Stumbles E, Wilson SA, Goldsmith S. A systematic review of interventions for children with cerebral palsy: state of the evidence. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2013 Oct;55(10):885-910. doi: 10.1111/dmcn.12246. Epub 2013 Aug 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23962350</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mahmood Q, Habibullah S, Babur MN. Potential effects of traditional massage on spasticity and gross motor function in children with spastic cerebral palsy: A randomized controlled trial. Pak J Med Sci. 2019 Sep-Oct;35(5):1210-1215. doi: 10.12669/pjms.35.5.478.</citation>
    <PMID>31488980</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Novak I, Berry J. Home program intervention effectiveness evidence. Phys Occup Ther Pediatr. 2014 Nov;34(4):384-9. doi: 10.3109/01942638.2014.964020. Epub 2014 Oct 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25317927</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cerebral palsy, massage, spasticity, motor function</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscle Spasticity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

