<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04767178</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Ozgul1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04767178</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pain Management During Screening for Retinopathy of Prematurity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Oral Ibuprofen Versus Oral Paracetamol in Pain Management During Screening for Retinopathy of Prematurity: A Prospective Observational Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Medeniyet University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Medeniyet University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Abstract Background: Screening examinations for retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) is critical&#xD;
      to reduce ROP-related vision loss, however, the procedure is painful and uncomfortable, and&#xD;
      topical anesthetics do not completely suppress the painful responses. The number of safe and&#xD;
      effective pharmacological options to reduce pain during eye examinations for ROP screening in&#xD;
      preterm infants is limited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: This study compared the efficacy of oral ibuprofen and oral paracetamol in&#xD;
      reducing pain during screening for ROP in preterm infants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: This prospective observational study was conducted at a tertiary-care neonatal&#xD;
      intensive care units. Forty-four preterm infants with gestational age ≤ 32 weeks undergoing&#xD;
      ROP screening were included. Each enrolled infant received either oral ibuprofen 10 mg/kg (n&#xD;
      = 22) or oral paracetamol 10 mg/kg (n = 22) one hour before eye examination. The primary&#xD;
      outcome measure was pain assessed by the Neonatal Pain, Agitation, and Sedation (N-PASS)&#xD;
      scale. Secondary outcome measures were tachycardia, bradycardia, desaturations, and crying&#xD;
      time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) is a physiopathological condition that develops upon&#xD;
      abnormal proliferation of the retinal veins in neonates, and its pathogenesis is unknown.1&#xD;
      With the advancements in neonate care, the survival rate of premature babies with extremely&#xD;
      low gestational ages and birth weights has increased significantly; however, this has also&#xD;
      resulted in an increasing incidence of ROP, which may lead to vision defects and/or&#xD;
      blindness. Early diagnosis, and timely and effective treatment may prevent vision loss and&#xD;
      thus improve the developmental process and the quality of life of these infants. Therefore,&#xD;
      recurring screening with retinal examination is essential to identify neonates who need ROP&#xD;
      treatment.2, 3 The American Academy of Pediatrics and American Academy of Ophthalmology&#xD;
      recommend ROP screening for preterm infants with a birth weight of ≤1500 g or a gestational&#xD;
      age of ≤30 weeks, and selected infants with a birth weight between 1500 and 2000 g or a&#xD;
      gestational age of &gt;30 weeks who have received cardiopulmonary supportive therapy, or who are&#xD;
      considered by the attending clinician to be at risk for the development of ROP.4 The&#xD;
      ophthalmological examinations for screening ROP involve repeated use of mydriatic eye drops,&#xD;
      physical constriction, forced opening of the eyelids, insertion of the blepharostat, scleral&#xD;
      indentation, and dense light, all of which cause pain and stress to the infant.5, 6 The&#xD;
      extreme and long-term unreduced pain resulting from the interventions applied in the neonatal&#xD;
      intensive care units (NICU) may generally cause life-threatening effects in organs and&#xD;
      systems. Inadequate management of pain in preterm neonates can cause physiological changes&#xD;
      and may also obscure the behavior of the infant, interactions between the family and the&#xD;
      infant, and the adaptation of the infant to the social world, causing neurological and&#xD;
      behavioral disorders and negatively affecting growth.7, 8, 9, 10 Thus, determination of&#xD;
      optimal strategies for stress reduction and pain management related to these medical&#xD;
      procedures is important in order to minimize the discomfort experienced by these neonates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to reduce the pain and stress related to ROP examination, non-pharmacological&#xD;
      methods, including the use of pacifiers, skin-to-skin touch, swaddling, kangaroo care,&#xD;
      positioning, musical therapy, breast milk and breast feeding, single or recurring doses of&#xD;
      oral sucrose, and personalized developmental care applications, have been used.5, 11, 12, 13,&#xD;
      14 However, a recent meta-analysis of randomized controlled studies evaluated a variety of&#xD;
      non-pharmacological pain-reducing interventions in addition to topical ophthalmic anesthetics&#xD;
      for ROP examination. Although multisensory pain treatments (e.g., oral dextrose/sucrose&#xD;
      solution, breast milk, swinging, singing, non-feeding suction, swaddling) may reduce the pain&#xD;
      to varying degrees, no specific treatment has been reported to show significant pain-relief&#xD;
      ability. The Premature Infant Pain Profile (PIPP) score in most of the studies was &gt;12.11&#xD;
      Pharmacological methods are used for pain relief as well as non-pharmacological in neonates.&#xD;
      The pharmacological agents include local anesthetics, non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs&#xD;
      (NSAIDs), and opioid medications.15 Although topical anesthetics are routinely used in ROP&#xD;
      examination in the NICU, they do not offer complete relief from pain.12 Moreover, opioid&#xD;
      analgesics should be used carefully, due to their adverse effects such as respiratory&#xD;
      depression, apnea, bradycardia, hypotension, intestinal hypoperistalsis, and bladder&#xD;
      dysfunction. 16 NSAIDs are commonly used in newborns and children as antipyretic agents to&#xD;
      control fever and as analgesic, anti-inflammatory, and vasoactive agents to manage pain and&#xD;
      modulate inflammation.17 Paracetamol shows analgesic and antipyretic effects by inhibiting&#xD;
      the cyclooxygenase (COX)-2 enzyme.17 It can be used safely in neonates during mild to&#xD;
      moderately painful procedures and in the postoperative period. Malnory et al. showed that the&#xD;
      preoperative use of paracetamol during circumcision of late preterm and term infants reduced&#xD;
      pain within the first 24 h.18 Ceelie et al. reported that the intravenous use of paracetamol&#xD;
      in neonates and infants after major surgeries reduced the need for morphine in the first 48 h&#xD;
      following surgery.19 Ibuprofen, another NSAID, inhibits COX-1 and COX-2 enzymes to show&#xD;
      analgesic, antipyretic, and anti-inflammatory effects.17 However, the role of ibuprofen in&#xD;
      reducing pain in neonates has not been studied in detail. Recently, these two medications are&#xD;
      commonly used in NICUs for ductus closure.20 To our knowledge, no previous study has compared&#xD;
      the pain-reducing effect of ibuprofen and paracetamol in preterm infants during ROP&#xD;
      examinations. Thus, this study aimed to compare the pain-reducing effects of single-dose&#xD;
      ibuprofen and paracetamol in preterm infants during ROP examination by using the Neonatal&#xD;
      Pain, Agitation, and Sedation (N-PASS) scale.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 15, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Neonatal Pain, Agitation, and Sedation scale</measure>
    <time_frame>8 month</time_frame>
    <description>The mean of the Neonatal Pain, Agitation, and Sedation score (A score &gt;+3 indicates pain)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Retinopathy of Prematurity</condition>
  <condition>Pain Management</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ibuprofen group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Infants that received oral ibuprofen were categorized into the ibuprofen group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Paracetamol group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Infants that received oral paracetamol were categorized into the paracetamol group</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ibuprofen (Sanofi, Istanbul, Turkey)</intervention_name>
    <description>Each enrolled infant received oral ibuprofen at a dose of 10 mg/kg 60 min before the onset of the eye examination.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ibuprofen group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Dolven</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paracetamol (GlaxoSmithKline, Istanbul, Turkey)</intervention_name>
    <description>Each enrolled infant received oral paracetamol at a dose of 10 mg/kg 60 min before the onset of the eye examination.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Paracetamol group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Parol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The present study enrolled preterm infants with a gestational age of ≤32 weeks or birth&#xD;
        weight ≤ 1500 g who were screened for ROP.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm infants of ≤32 weeks of gestational&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm infants ≤ 1500 gram of birth weight&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major congenital abnormalities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants who were mechanically ventilated and/or sedated, hemodynamically unstable&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants &gt; 32 weeks of gestational&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The infants whose parents denied consent were also not included.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>22 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>33 Weeks</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ozgul Bulut</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medeniyet University Göztepe Training and Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medeniyet University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34674</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Medeniyet University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ozgul Bulut</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Analgesia</keyword>
  <keyword>ibuprofen</keyword>
  <keyword>N-PASS</keyword>
  <keyword>pain management</keyword>
  <keyword>paracetamol</keyword>
  <keyword>preterm infant</keyword>
  <keyword>retinopathy of prematurity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinopathy of Prematurity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ibuprofen</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

