<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04764123</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04764123</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Typical and Atypical AVNRT High-resolution Mapping</brief_title>
  <acronym>AVNRTmap</acronym>
  <official_title>To Investigate Whether Remnants of the &quot;Ring Tissues&quot; Constitute the Substrate of the Circuit of Atrioventricular Nodal Reentrant Tachycardia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cardiovascular Research Society, Greece</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cardiovascular Research Society, Greece</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is aimed at :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identifying the exact location of the circuit of typical and atypical AVNRT by applying&#xD;
           high-resolution electroanatomic mapping.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Investigating the possibility that the recently described &quot;ring tissues&quot; participate in&#xD;
           the AVNRT circuit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background The exact circuit of atrioventricular nodal reentrant tachycardia still remains&#xD;
      unknown despite advances in high-density mapping, tissue histochemistry, and connexin&#xD;
      genotyping. Theoretical calculations have derived a range of 0.8 to 5.2 cm for the length of&#xD;
      the slow pathway, whereas that of the fast pathway should be within the range of 2.4 to 11.2&#xD;
      cm. Recent histology data also indicate that the distance of the right inferior extension of&#xD;
      the atrioventricular node within the tricuspid vestibule, as judged histologically, and as&#xD;
      measured from the site of penetration of the conduction axis in 31 hearts, is 8.2±2.4 mm,&#xD;
      with a range from 5.2 to 13.6 mm. These results are compatible with theoretical calculations&#xD;
      of the slow pathway previously performed by the investigators. On 3-dimensional reconstructed&#xD;
      fluoroscopic images, the average distance between the compact AV node and the ablating&#xD;
      electrode in cases of successful AVNRT ablation, however, is 17.2±1.6 to 17.8±0.9 mm. This&#xD;
      clearly suggests that successful ablation interrupts the AVNRT circuit at a point beyond the&#xD;
      identifiable right posterior extension, and at a consistent area on the the septal isthmus&#xD;
      between the CS ostium and the TV. This site is beyond the histologically identifiable&#xD;
      inferior extensions of the node.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is additional evidence in animal studies that the right inferior extension continues&#xD;
      within the vestibule of the tricuspid valve as &quot;ring tissue&quot;, ie a remnant of the primary&#xD;
      ring, while the left atrial vestibule is derived from the initial atrioventricular canal of&#xD;
      the developing heart, which is itself known to be slow conducting but cannot be distinguished&#xD;
      histologically from the left atrial myocardium. In the human heart, the primary ring extends&#xD;
      through the atrioventricular node, and includes the bundle of His, which is rapidly&#xD;
      conducting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis The investigators hypothesized that, in humans, the extent of ring tissues varies&#xD;
      in such a way that some subjects are susceptible to atrioventricular nodal re-entry, whereas&#xD;
      others are not. Thus, the entirety of the tricuspid vestibule, or even part of the mitral&#xD;
      vestibule, are parts of the re-entry circuit, at least in some atypical forms with prolonged&#xD;
      His-atrial intervals. The circumference of the right atrioventricular orifice has been&#xD;
      measured at between 9 and 11 centimeters in patients aged less than 65 years, whereas that of&#xD;
      the mitral orifice is from 7 to 9 centimeters. The possibility of the vestibules being&#xD;
      involved in the circuit, therefore, cannot theoretically be excluded. Recently, high-density&#xD;
      mapping of the re-entry circuit has provided valuable insights into the electrophysiologic&#xD;
      patterns of this arrhythmia, identifying the circuit in the vicinity of the nodal area. All&#xD;
      these mapping studies, however, were conducted in patients with typical AVNRT. In this&#xD;
      setting, the remnants of the ring tissues might be short enough as not to allow proper&#xD;
      discrimination of the circuit limbs. The investigators propose to apply high-resolution&#xD;
      electroanatomic mapping in patients with both typical atypical AVNRT in which the circuit may&#xD;
      contain longer circuit components. Mapping should be focused on both the septal area and the&#xD;
      tricuspid, and, if feasible, the mitral ring.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims of the Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study, therefore, is aimed at :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identifying the exact location of the circuit of typical and atypical AVNRT by applying&#xD;
           high-resolution electroanatomic mapping.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Investigating the possibility that the recently described &quot;ring tissues&quot; participate in&#xD;
           the AVNRT circuit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods Clinical Studies Patients Patients with typical and atypical AVNRT will be recruited&#xD;
      following informed consent. The investigators anticipate to study 30 patients with typical,&#xD;
      and 10 patients with atypical AVNRT within the next two years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definitions AVNRT is diagnosed by fulfillment of established criteria during detailed atrial&#xD;
      and ventricular pacing maneuvers. Typical (slow-fast) AVNRT is defined by an&#xD;
      atrial-His/His-atrial ratio (AH/HA) &gt;1, and HA interval ≤70 ms. Atypical AVNRT is defined by&#xD;
      delayed retrograde atrial activation with HA&gt;70 ms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mapping Electroanatomic mapping will be performed with CARTO, Rhythmia or Ensite programs at&#xD;
      the operator's discretion. High-resolution mapping of the atrial vestibules is inherently&#xD;
      difficult in this setting, nonetheless, because of the problems in separating a large&#xD;
      ventricular electrogram from the atrial tracing. During atrioventricular nodal reentry, all&#xD;
      these areas should show a fused signal consisting of nodal activation. Any mapping system&#xD;
      will struggle to annotate the fused signal appropriately in the window and during&#xD;
      tachycardia. It may also preferentially annotate the His bundle electrogram because of its&#xD;
      high frequency (dv/dt). The implication of this error is that a site annotated as&#xD;
      representing the earliest atrial activity may be representing activity in the His bundle.&#xD;
      Conversely, a site marked as late may, in fact, be early, being obscured by far field&#xD;
      ventricular activity. These limitations may also apply to animal models using micro-electrode&#xD;
      mapping. To overcome this problem, pacing maneuvers with ventricular extrastimuli are used to&#xD;
      differentiate atrial from ventricular electrogram components where activation appeared to be&#xD;
      superimposed owing to simultaneous local activation. In addition, the investigators will&#xD;
      exclude points that result in discrepant activation relative to the surrounding isochronal&#xD;
      information due to the movement of the CS reference catheter. Activation points from ectopic&#xD;
      beats will be excluded manually. The voltage map will be automatically acquired according to&#xD;
      the same criteria. After automated mapping, an offline retrospective analysis will be&#xD;
      performed by 2 independent observers, in order to manually over-read the sites of earliest&#xD;
      atrial activation, at an override activation strength of 100 mV in cases in which (1) the&#xD;
      earliest activation on automated mapping appeared diffuse or (2) automated annotation tagged&#xD;
      the local ventricular component at the annulus. The His-bundle signal is generally&#xD;
      automatically annotated by the system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Entrainment Entrainment of AVNRT is feasible at sites close to the nodal extensions. Attempts&#xD;
      will be made to entrain the tachycardia from various points on the TV annulus in order to&#xD;
      investigate potential participation of the right-sided ring tissue into circuit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Catheter ablation Being on the operation discretion, before conventional catheter ablation of&#xD;
      the slow pathway, at least two 30 sec lesions will be delivered on the TV annulus near the&#xD;
      isthmus, if this feasible. Interruption of the tachycardia or evoked junctional beats will be&#xD;
      sought. Conventional catheter ablation of the slow pathway will be performed as previously&#xD;
      described.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Histology Studies Databases from human hearts specimens will be examined and&#xD;
      tissue-characterized in an attempt to identify the presence and extent of &quot;ring tissues&quot; in&#xD;
      the human myocardium.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Participation of ring tissues in the AVNRT Circuit</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Tachycardia entrainment by pacing at the anatomical ring tissue site or tachycardia termination with successful ablation at the ring tissue site</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fast and slow pathway activation time in the circuit of AVNRT.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>TIme in ms required for fast and slow pathway activation during tachycardia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Tachycardia, Atrioventricular Nodal Reentry</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AVNRT Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients admitted for electrophysiological study and ablation due to AVNRT tachycardia.&#xD;
During the study and before the ablation high density electroanatomical mapping will be performed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AVNRT mapping</intervention_name>
    <description>AV annuli mapping during AVNRT</description>
    <arm_group_label>AVNRT Cohort</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Electroanatomic mapping</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with typical or atypical AVNRT admitted for electrophysiological study and&#xD;
        ablation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with atypical or typical AVNRT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;16 or &gt;75 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe comorbidities with estimated life expectancy &lt; 6 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Demosthenes G Katritsis, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+306944845505</phone>
    <email>dkatrits@dgkatritsis.gr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cardiovascular Research Society, Greece</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr D Katritsis</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Atrioventricular</keyword>
  <keyword>Nodal Reentry</keyword>
  <keyword>Tachycardia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tachycardia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tachycardia, Atrioventricular Nodal Reentry</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

