<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04762524</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201909716</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04762524</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Impact of CRRT Modality on Filter Life</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Impact of CRRT Modality on Filter Life</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Iowa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Iowa</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators plan to start patients who need CRRT on either CVVH or CVVHD by block&#xD;
      randomization, and then to measure filter life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Continuous renal replacement therapy (CRRT) is a dialysis modality used in critically ill&#xD;
      intensive care unit (ICU) patients because it is associated with less hemodynamic instability&#xD;
      than traditional hemodialysis. CRRT can be conducted using one of two different modalities,&#xD;
      which are continuous venovenous hemofiltration (CVVH) and continuous venovenous hemodialysis&#xD;
      (CVVHD). CVVH used conductive clearance, whereas CVVHD uses diffusive clearance (CVVHD).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In CVVH, plasma water is removed across the filter using transmembrane pressure which forces&#xD;
      fluid into the effluent space. Solutes are removed via &quot;solvent drag&quot;, which is the process&#xD;
      by which solutes follow fluid flow. The rate of fluid removal is high (usually around 2-3&#xD;
      L/hr), and so hemodynamic collapse would quickly occur in the fluid were not replaced. The&#xD;
      patient is therefore given &quot;replacement fluid&quot; which can be given pre-filter or post-filter,&#xD;
      and usually nearly matches the fluid removal rate. For instance, if 2 L are removed per hour,&#xD;
      2 L are given back in the form of replacement fluid, if volume neutrality is desired. If&#xD;
      fluid removal is desired, 1.9 L (e.g) may be given back, resulting in the net loss of 0.1 L&#xD;
      of fluid per hour. The composition of the replacement fluid determines the serum&#xD;
      concentration. As an example, if 2 L of fluid with a potassium concentration of 6.0 mmol/L (a&#xD;
      high amount, 4.0 is normal) is removed and replaced with 2 L of replacement fluid with a&#xD;
      potassium concentration of 2 mmol/L, then 8 mmol of potassium will be &quot;removed&quot; per hour, and&#xD;
      the potassium concentration of the serum will fall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In CVVHD, dialysate flows in the effluent space, creating a gradient which leads to movement&#xD;
      of solutes either into or out of the blood, depending on the gradient direction. For&#xD;
      instance, if serum has a potassium concentration of 6 mmol/L, and the dialysate has a&#xD;
      concentration of 2 mmol/L, potassium will move from the blood into the dialysate, until the&#xD;
      dialysate concentration is also equal to 6 mmol/L. At that point, net potassium movement will&#xD;
      be 0, as the concentration will be equal. As with CVVH, with a dialysate flow rate of 2 L/hr&#xD;
      will result in the removal of 8 mmol of potassium per hour. While these technical details&#xD;
      concern only the specialist, the important take away is that both of these modalities achieve&#xD;
      equivalent clearance, via different mechanisms. Notably, there are no differences in clinical&#xD;
      outcomes with use of one or the other modality, and these modalities are currently thought to&#xD;
      have complete equipoise. The decision is generally based on provider comfort and preference.&#xD;
      There is no clinical scenario where one modality would be preferable to the other, based on&#xD;
      current evidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A major issue when using CRRT is filter clotting, which occurs on average every 30 hours.&#xD;
      Clotting renders the circuit unusable, and requires that the machine be reset, which is a&#xD;
      process that takes 1-2 hours on average, and potentially longer depending on the availability&#xD;
      of the dialysis nurses who change the circuits. This results in less delivery of dialysis&#xD;
      than what is prescribed, and clotting is often also associated with the loss of the blood&#xD;
      that is clotted in the circuit. This could be up to 150 ccs, which is a potentially&#xD;
      significant amount in critically ill patients. As noted within the figures, post-filter CVVH&#xD;
      is associated with hemoconcentration, and is thought to be associated with more clotting than&#xD;
      CVVHD, where no hemoconcentration occurs. The situation is more complicated in pre-filter&#xD;
      CVVH, however. As in Figure 3, the fluid is initially diluted, and then the fluid is removed&#xD;
      over the course of flow through the filter. Some Nephrologists believe that this initial&#xD;
      dilution of the blood results in decreased risk of clotting. However, other nephrologists&#xD;
      believe that due to differential flow rates in the blood and replacement fluid that&#xD;
      hemoconcentration still occurs within the filter, albeit to a much lesser degree than in&#xD;
      post-filter CVVH (this argument is difficult to explain conceptually to a lay audience, but&#xD;
      an attempt is made within Figure 3). It is therefore unclear currently whether pre-filter&#xD;
      CVVH and CVVHD have equal or unequal rates of clotting. Because centers tend to use&#xD;
      exclusively one modality or the other (or a combination, which is beyond the scope of this&#xD;
      summary), retrospective analyses are often not possible due to lack of a comparison group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Figure 3. In pre-filter CVVH, replacement fluid is administered prior to the blood passing&#xD;
      through the filter. Nephrologists argue about the effect this has on the rates of&#xD;
      hemoconcentration. Some would argue that after the initial dilution, the blood only returns&#xD;
      to its initial concentration by the end of the filter, and thus over the course of the&#xD;
      filter, there is actually hemodilution that decreases likelihood of clotting. Other&#xD;
      nephrologists argue like so: With a blood flow rate of 12 L/hr (standard), and a fluid flow&#xD;
      rate of 2 L/hr, then 14 L/hr enter the fluid, and 2 L/hr are removed, which is 14% (2/14) of&#xD;
      the fluid that entered. If the fluid flow rate is increased to 4 L/hr, then 16 L /hr enter&#xD;
      the filter, and 4L/hr are removed, which is 25% (4/16). This would therefore theoretically&#xD;
      result in higher degrees of clotting. The question of pre-filter CVVH and its impact on&#xD;
      clotting relative to CVVHD is therefore unanswered, and is the reason for the proposed&#xD;
      study.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
      In short, the investigators plan to start patients who need CRRT on either CVVH or CVVHD by&#xD;
      block randomization, and then to measure how often the filters on the machine need to be&#xD;
      replaced.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to exclude minors, prisoners, and patients undergoing a certain&#xD;
      procedure called &quot;extracorporeal membrane oxygenation&quot; (ECMO). ECMO is designed to pump blood&#xD;
      and provide oxygen to the patient when the heart and lungs are not working correctly (ECMO&#xD;
      attempts to do the work of the heart and lungs in instances where the patient's organs have&#xD;
      failed). CRRT can be added to an ECMO circuit if renal failure is also present, but this is a&#xD;
      specialized instance with unique risk factors for clotting, and is not representative of the&#xD;
      general CRRT population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 11, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Filter Life</measure>
    <time_frame>Until CRRT discontinuation, on average 4-5 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hours on average until filter clots</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Through hospital discharge, on average 2-4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>in-hospital mortality</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">192</enrollment>
  <condition>AKI</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Initiation on CVVH</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this arm were initiated on CVVH, rather than CVVHD</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Initiation on CVVHD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this arm were initiated on CVVHD, rather than CVVHDH</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CVVH vs CVVHD</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients are initiated on CRRT in either the CVVH or CVVHD modality</description>
    <arm_group_label>Initiation on CVVH</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Initiation on CVVHD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Adult patients initiated on CRRT at University of Iowa Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minors&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECMO use at the time of CRRT initiation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>89 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Iowa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Iowa City</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52242</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Iowa</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Benjamin Griffin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

