<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04769622</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NST001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04769622</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Influence of Environmental Factors on the Efficacy of Non-surgical Periodontal Treatment. A Pre-post Quasi-experimental Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Influence of Environmental Factors on the Efficacy of Non-surgical Periodontal Treatment. A Pre-post Quasi-experimental Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Siena</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Siena</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Periodontitis is a biofilm-mediated chronic inflammatory disease which causes the destruction&#xD;
      of the supporting tissues of the tooth. Risk factors for periodontitis include familiarity&#xD;
      for periodontal diseases, diabetes, cardiovascular diseases, metabolic syndrome, obesity and&#xD;
      stress. Some studies demonstrated how these risk factors negatively influence the patients'&#xD;
      response to non-surgical periodontal treatment. The success of non-surgical periodontal&#xD;
      therapy is defined through the treat-to-target concept (i.e. a maximum of 4 sites with&#xD;
      Probing Pocket Depth &gt;5mm and presence of Bleeding on Probing); therefore, periodontal&#xD;
      treatment is successful whenever this threshold is reached. Moreover, given the available&#xD;
      data regarding the association between more severe forms of periodontitis and a lower&#xD;
      frequency of physical activity, a worse sleep quality and more perceived stress, it is&#xD;
      reasonable to hypothesize that these factors could influence the patients' response to&#xD;
      non-surgical periodontal treatment. With regards to diet, despite many studies appraised the&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory effect of the mediterranean diet, no study has ever related adherence to&#xD;
      Mediterranean Diet to oral health status. The novelty that the present study would introduce&#xD;
      is the evaluation of how environmental factors (i.e. diet, physical exercise, perceived&#xD;
      stress) influence patients' response to non-surgical periodontal therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 25, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treat-to-target after treatment (yes/no)</measure>
    <time_frame>outcome measured at reevaluation (3 months after the completion of non-surgical periodontal treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Binary outcome defining the success of non-surgical periodontal treatment. The treat-to-target is reached whenever patients at reevaluation have a maximum of 4 sites with Probing Pocket Depth (PPD) &gt;5mm and presence of Bleeding on Probing (BoP)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of adherence to Mediterranean diet on the success of non-surgical periodontal treatment (treat-to-target)</measure>
    <time_frame>outcome measured at reevaluation (3 months after the completion of non-surgical periodontal treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>results obtained from the questionnaire about adherence to Mediterranean Diet (Gnagnarella et al. 2018) will be placed in a logistic regression model, whose aim will be to investigate the influence of adherence to Mediterranean diet (predictors) on the success of non surgical periodontal treatment (treat to target; dependent variable). Adherence to Mediterranean diet is evaluated on a scale between 0 and 9; the higher the score, the higher the adherence to Mediterranean Diet.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of Sleep Quality on the success of non-surgical periodontal treatment (treat-to-target)</measure>
    <time_frame>outcome measured at reevaluation (3 months after the completion of non-surgical periodontal treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>results obtained from the questionnaire about Sleep Quality (Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index) will be placed in a logistic regression model, whose aim will be to investigate the influence of sleep quality (predictor) on the success of non surgical periodontal treatment (treat to target; dependent variable). Sleep quality is evaluated on a scale between 0 and 21; the higher the score, the poorer the Sleep Quality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of Physical Activity on the success of non-surgical periodontal treatment (treat-to-target)</measure>
    <time_frame>outcome measured at reevaluation (3 months after the completion of non-surgical periodontal treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>results obtained from the questionnaire about Physical Activity (International Physical Activity Questionnaire) will be placed in a logistic regression model, whose aim will be to investigate the influence of amount of Physical activity (predictor) on the success of non surgical periodontal treatment (treat to target; dependent variable). Physical activity is evaluated on a scale between 0 and 2 (0= low physical activity; 1= moderate physical activity; 2= intense physical activity).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence of Perceived Stress on the success of non-surgical periodontal treatment (treat-to-target)</measure>
    <time_frame>outcome measured at reevaluation (3 months after the completion of non-surgical periodontal treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>results obtained from the questionnaire about Perceived stress (Italian Perceived Stress Scale) will be placed in a logistic regression model, whose aim will be to investigate the influence of perceived stress (predictor) on the success of non surgical periodontal treatment (treat to target; dependent variable). Perceived Stress is evaluated on a scale between 0 and 40; the higher the score, the higher the stress perceived.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">125</enrollment>
  <condition>Non Surgical Periodontal Treatment</condition>
  <condition>Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Periodontal Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>patients affected by untreated Periodontitis</arm_group_label>
    <description>patients coming to the Unit of Periodontics at the University of Siena will be screened for the inclusion in the study. All patients eligible for the inclusion in the study will undergo non-surgical periodontal treatment and will be administered a questionnaire about lifestyles (adherence to mediterranean diet, sleep quality, physical activity, perceived stress). Patients will be then reevaluated at 3 months after the completion on non-surgical periodontal therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Non-surgical periodontal treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>all included patients will be subjected to non-surgical periodontal therapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>patients affected by untreated Periodontitis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients will be asked to complete a set of questionnaires regarding:&#xD;
adherence to Mediterranean Diet;&#xD;
sleep quality;&#xD;
physical activity;&#xD;
perceived stress.</description>
    <arm_group_label>patients affected by untreated Periodontitis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with untreated periodontitis coming to the Unit of Periodontics at the&#xD;
        University of Siena and meeting the inclusion and exclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age between 18 and 70 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of untreated periodontitis (Papapanou at al. 2018);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ability and willingness to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy or lactation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who underwent non-surgical periodontal therapy in the last 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients taking immunosuppressive drugs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability or unwillingness to give informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nicola Discepoli, DDS, MsC, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0577585772</phone>
    <email>nicola.discepoli2@unisi.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AOUS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Siena</city>
        <zip>53100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicola Discepoli</last_name>
      <email>ndiscepoli@me.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Siena</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nicola Discepoli</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>periodontitis</keyword>
  <keyword>non surgical periodontal treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

