<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04763616</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-10-038</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04763616</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Isatuximab and Cemiplimab in Relapsed or Refractory Natural Killer/T-cell Lymphoid Malignancy</brief_title>
  <acronym>ICING</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Isatuximab and Cemiplimab in Relapsed or Refractory Natural Killer/T-cell Lymphoid Malignancy : Nick Name - ICING Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Won Seog Kim</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sanofi</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Samsung Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is to analyze the efficacy of PD1 inhibitor and anti-CD38 antibody in relapsed or&#xD;
      refractory NK/T-cell lymphoid malignancy. The investigational products of this study are&#xD;
      cemiplimab (PD1 inhibitor) and isatuximab (anti-CD38 antibody).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The rationale for the use of cemiplimab in patients with NK/T-cell lymphoid malignancy is the&#xD;
      aforementioned PD-L1 expression in tumor cells of ENKTL and ANKL. In addition, the proven&#xD;
      efficacy of pembrolizumab in relapsed or refractory ENKTL support the use of PD1 inhibitor as&#xD;
      a salvage therapy for this disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The addition of isatuximab to cemiplimab might induce synergistic activity because&#xD;
      CD38-mediated immunosuppression as a mechanism of tumor cell escape from PD-1/PD-L1 blockade.&#xD;
      Furthermore, targeting CD38 by isatuximab can preferentially block immunosuppressive&#xD;
      regulatory T-cells and thereby restore immune effector function against multiple myeloma.&#xD;
      These functions of CD38 blocking antibody might help to improve the efficacy of immune&#xD;
      checkpoint inhibitor such as PD1 inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the presence of antibody-mediated cytotoxicity and direct anti-tumor effect of&#xD;
      isatuximab against CD38-positive tumor cells, the combination of isatuximab with cemiplimab&#xD;
      might show the synergistic activity resulting more improved treatment outcome than PD1&#xD;
      inhibitor alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, The investigators designed a phase II study of cemiplimab and isatuximab for patients&#xD;
      with relapsed or refractory ENKTL and ANKL. In this study, The investigators analyze the&#xD;
      efficacy of this novel combination and their adverse effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This clinical trial is a study that uses two antibodies called 'Isatuximab' and 'Cemiplemab'&#xD;
      as a rescue anticancer therapy for patients with relapsed or refractory'NK/T cell lymphoma'.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cemiplimab is an antibody against the PD1 protein of cytotoxic T cells. By inhibiting the&#xD;
      binding of the PDL1 protein expressed on the surface of tumor cells, cancer cells use the&#xD;
      PDL1 protein expressed on the surface of their cells to the tumor immune function It works to&#xD;
      prevent getting involved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When the interaction between PD1 and PDL1 protein is suppressed in this way, T cells in&#xD;
      human's body attack and kill cancer cells, and cancer cells are killed through this process.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, immuno-cancer drugs that inhibit the interaction of PD1 and PDL1 proteins have&#xD;
      already been developed other than Cemiplimab, and have proven excellent therapeutic effects&#xD;
      in lung cancer and Hodgkin's lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the investigators have started this clinical trial because Cemiplimab, one of the&#xD;
      immuno-cancer drugs, is expected to be effective in the 'NK/T cell lymphoma' that you have&#xD;
      been diagnosed with. However, the effect of Cemiplimab in the disease has not yet been&#xD;
      proven, and a research report has recently been published that other anticancer drugs that&#xD;
      inhibit the PD1 protein may be effective in'extralymphatic NK/T cell lymphoma'.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, this is not conclusive because it is a study involving a small number of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, if this clinical trial proves that cemiplimab is effective in 'NK/T cell lymphoma',&#xD;
      it could contribute to the development of new treatments for this disease. In addition, all&#xD;
      of the previous studies have studied the therapeutic effect using only a single antibody that&#xD;
      inhibits the PD1 protein, but in this study, an antibody against the CD38 antigen called&#xD;
      isatuximab is used together. The CD38 antigen is expressed in several hematocrit cells, and&#xD;
      in multiple myeloma, antibodies to CD38 are already used as standard treatments for relapsed&#xD;
      or refractory diseases. However, the high frequency of expression of CD38 antigen on the&#xD;
      surface of tumor cells of NK/T cell lymphoma is expected as a therapeutic target, but its&#xD;
      therapeutic effect has not yet been proven. Istuximab used in this study is an antibody&#xD;
      targeting CD38, and can be expected to kill tumor cells expressing CD38, so when administered&#xD;
      in combination with cemiplimab, its therapeutic effect can be increased. In this study,&#xD;
      patients diagnosed and treated as'NK/T cell lymphoma' but did not reach cure and the disease&#xD;
      worsened, or patients who experienced a cure but later recurred. The investigators want to&#xD;
      evaluate the effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Through this, the goal is to improve the prognosis by discovering a new treatment that is&#xD;
      ultimately effective for the treatment of relapsed or refractory 'NK/T cell lymphoma.'&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after completion of the clinical trial drug administration of the last subject</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of subjects with complete response (CR)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Adverse Events [Safety and Tolerability]).</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after completion of the clinical trial drug administration of the last subject</time_frame>
    <description>Investigation of Adverse evensts occurred in subject</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after completion of the clinical trial drug administration of the last subject</time_frame>
    <description>Time between the date of treatment start and the date of death due to any cause or date of disease progression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after completion of the clinical trial drug administration of the last subject</time_frame>
    <description>Time between the date of treatment start and the date of death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease control rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after completion of the clinical trial drug administration of the last subject</time_frame>
    <description>complete response, partial response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Natural Killer/T-cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Relapsed Natural Killer/T-cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Natural Killer/T-cell Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Isatuximab and Cemiplimab combined therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug : Isatuximab&#xD;
1 cycle : 10mg/kg IV every week. It is administered on Day 2, Day 9, Day 16, Day 23.&#xD;
2~6 cycle : 10mg/kg every 2 weeks . It is administered on Day 2, Day 16.&#xD;
7th cycle and beyond : 10mg/kg IV every 3 weeks. It is administered on Day 2.&#xD;
Drug : Cemiplimab&#xD;
1st - 6th cycle : 250mg IV every 2 weeks. It is administered on Day 1, Day 15.&#xD;
7th cycle and beyond : 350mg every 3 weeks. It is administered on Day 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isatuximab</intervention_name>
    <description>The treatment cycle will be repeated up to 2 years. If a patient shows disease progression or unacceptable toxicity, the study treatment will be discontinued and followed up for efficacy and safety after the discontinuation of study treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Isatuximab and Cemiplimab combined therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cemiplimab</intervention_name>
    <description>The treatment cycle will be repeated up to 2 years. If a patient shows disease progression or unacceptable toxicity, the study treatment will be discontinued and followed up for efficacy and safety after the discontinuation of study treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Isatuximab and Cemiplimab combined therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients should be histologically diagnosed with extranodal NK/T-cell lymphoma or&#xD;
             aggressive NK-cell leukemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient should be previously treated with at least one type of chemotherapy regimen&#xD;
             including autologous stem cell transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient should have relapsed or refractory disease before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient written informed consent obtained prior to any screening procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient should be a male or female ≥ 19 years (Maximum 85 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient should have at least one measurable lesion on the CT or PET/CT scan. In case&#xD;
             of PET/CT, diagnostic quality CT part of PET/CT is needed to define measurability. Cf.&#xD;
             If a patient only has non-measurable lesion on the CT or PET/CT scan (e.g. bone marrow&#xD;
             involvement, malignant effusion, and hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis), its&#xD;
             association with disease progression or relapse should be determined by an&#xD;
             investigator. Based on investigators' decision, patients with non-measurable lesion&#xD;
             could be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient should have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status ≤&#xD;
             2 which is not declining during the last 2 weeks before the signature of the main&#xD;
             study Informed Consent Form (S-ICF).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient should have adequate bone marrow function as defined by the following&#xD;
             laboratory values: Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥ 1.0 x 109/L; Platelets ≥ 50 x&#xD;
             109/L; Hemoglobin ≥ 8.0 g/dL Cf. If the cause of cytopenia is related with bone marrow&#xD;
             involvement of tumor cells, a patient could be enrolled after blood transfusion or&#xD;
             G-CSF support by investigator's decision.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Female patient should fulfill the following criteria 1) Pregnancy test: Negative serum&#xD;
             or urine pregnancy test at screening for women of childbearing potential; 2)&#xD;
             Contraception: Highly effective contraception for both male and female subjects&#xD;
             throughout the study and for at least 6 months after last administration of study drug&#xD;
             if the risk of conception exists.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient should have adequate organ function as defined by the following laboratory&#xD;
             values: Serum Creatinine ≤ 2.0 × ULN; Serum Bilirubin ≤ 2.0 × ULN; AST and ALT ≤ 3 ×&#xD;
             ULN. Cf. If the values of liver function tests more than the above-mentioned criteria&#xD;
             are related with disease relapse or progression to liver, a patient could be enrolled&#xD;
             by investigator's decision in case of ≤ 5.0 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients should have archived tumor tissue or fresh tissue sample obtained from&#xD;
             re-biopsy at relapse available for targeted sequencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. In case of written consent to participation in clinical study: Must sign the subject&#xD;
             consent form that states the blood sampling done according to the study protocol and&#xD;
             that the subject has comprehended the purpose and the necessary procedures of clinical&#xD;
             study with intention to participate in the clinical study (or signed by the subject's&#xD;
             representative).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient has history of or known carcinomatous meningitis, or evidence of symptomatic&#xD;
             leptomeningeal disease or secondary CNS involvement on CT or MRI scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient has a concurrent malignancy or has had a malignancy in the last 3 years prior&#xD;
             to start of study treatment (with the exception of adequately treated basal or&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma or cervical carcinoma in situ)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient has had major surgery within 21 days prior to starting study drug or has not&#xD;
             recovered from major side effects of the surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient with current use of immunosuppressive medication, EXCEPT for the following: -&#xD;
             Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injection (e.g.,&#xD;
             intra-articular injection) - Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses ≤ 10 mg/day&#xD;
             of prednisone or equivalent - Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions&#xD;
             (e.g., CT scan premedication). The use of 10 mg or more of prednisolone may be&#xD;
             acceptable for adrenal insufficiency according to the investigator's judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient has clinically significant (i.e., active) cardiovascular disease: cerebral&#xD;
             vascular accident/stroke (&lt; 6 months prior to enrollment), myocardial infarction (&lt; 6&#xD;
             months prior to enrollment), unstable angina, congestive heart failure (≥ New York&#xD;
             Heart Association Classification Class II), or serious cardiac arrhythmia requiring&#xD;
             medication including any of the following: - Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction (LVEF)&#xD;
             &lt; 50% as determined by echocardiogram - QTc &gt; 480 msec on screening ECG (using the&#xD;
             QTcF formula) - Unstable angina pectoris - Ventricular arrhythmias except for benign&#xD;
             premature ventricular contractions - Supraventricular and nodal arrhythmias not&#xD;
             controlled with medication - Conduction abnormality requiring a pacemaker - Valvular&#xD;
             disease with documented compromise in cardiac function&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient has known history of testing positive for HIV or known acquired&#xD;
             immunodeficiency syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient has known prior severe hypersensitivity to investigational product or any&#xD;
             component in its formulations, including known severe hypersensitivity reactions to&#xD;
             monoclonal antibodies (NCI CTCAE v.5.0 Grade ≥ 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient has other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical condition that would,&#xD;
             in the investigator's judgment contraindicate her participation in the clinical study&#xD;
             (e.g. uncontrolled diabetes, chronic pancreatitis, active chronic hepatitis etc.).&#xD;
             Other severe acute or chronic medical conditions include colitis, inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             disease, pneumonitis, pulmonary fibrosis or psychiatric conditions including recent&#xD;
             (within the past year) or active suicidal ideation or behavior; or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormalities that may increase the risk associated with study participation or study&#xD;
             treatment administration or may interfere with the interpretation of study results&#xD;
             and, in the judgment of the investigator. Cf. &quot;Persisting toxicity related to prior&#xD;
             therapy (NCI CTCAE v.5.0 Grade &gt; 1); however, alopecia, sensory neuropathy Grade ≤ 2,&#xD;
             or other Grade ≤ 2 not constituting a safety risk based on investigator's judgment are&#xD;
             acceptable.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient has active infection requiring systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient has prior organ transplantation including allogenic stem-cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient has active autoimmune disease that might deteriorate when receiving an&#xD;
             immuno-stimulatory agent. However, patients with diabetes type I, vitiligo, psoriasis,&#xD;
             or hypo- or hyperthyroid diseases not requiring immunosuppressive treatment are&#xD;
             eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patient is not able to understand or to comply with study instructions and&#xD;
             requirements or has a history of non-compliance to medical regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient is a pregnant or nursing (lactating) woman, where pregnancy is defined as the&#xD;
             state of a female after conception and until the termination of gestation, confirmed&#xD;
             by a positive serum hCG laboratory test (&gt; 5 mIU/mL).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Vaccination within 4 weeks of the first dose of isatuximab and cemiplimab, and while&#xD;
             on trials is prohibited except for administration of inactivated vaccines.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patient has hepatitis B virus (HBV) associated liver disease as follows - Liver&#xD;
             cirrhosis and chronic hepatitis with HBV reactivation - Hepatitis B virus (HBV) or&#xD;
             hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection at screening (positive HBV surface antigen or HCV&#xD;
             RNA if anti-HCV antibody screening test positive).&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Prior treatment with an agent (approved or investigational) that blocks either&#xD;
             PD1/PDL1 or CD38 (participants who joined a study with an anti-CD38 or anti-PD1/PDL1&#xD;
             but have written confirmation they were on control arm are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Wash out period of less than 2 weeks from previous antitumor chemotherapy, tyrosine&#xD;
             kinase inhibitor immunotherapy, or any palliative radiotherapy; less than 4 weeks from&#xD;
             previous antitumor biological therapy (e.g., rituximab and brentuximab vedotin).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Participant has received wide field radiotherapy ≤4 weeks prior to starting study&#xD;
             treatment, or limited field radiation for palliation ≤2 weeks prior to starting study&#xD;
             treatment, or has not recovered from the side effects of such therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Last dose of prior investigational agent within 28 days from initiation of study&#xD;
             intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Predicted life expectancy is less than 3 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wonseog Kim, MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Samsung Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wonseog Kim, MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>82-2-3410-6548</phone>
    <email>wonseog.kim@samsung.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Seokjin Kim, MD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>82-2-3410-1766</phone>
    <email>kstwoh@skku.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Samsung Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <state>Kangnamgu</state>
        <zip>06351</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wonseog Kim, MD.Phd</last_name>
      <phone>+82-2-3410-6548</phone>
      <email>wonseog.kim@samsung.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Seokjin Kim, MD.Phd</last_name>
      <phone>+82-2-3410-1766</phone>
      <email>kstwoh@skku.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Samsung Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Won Seog Kim</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cemiplimab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

