<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04766138</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CALMI-CLIN-2019-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04766138</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial to Evaluate Fecobionics in Healthy Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>NORMAL</acronym>
  <official_title>Neurophysiological Mechanism in Sacral Neuromodulation in Patients Suffering From Fecal Incontinence</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The California Medical Innovations Institute, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The California Medical Innovations Institute, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Fecobionics combines several existing tests to provide novel insight into anorectal function.&#xD;
      The purpose for the development was to overcome the technological controversies and&#xD;
      disagreement between various tests and unphysiological test conditions. The aim was to&#xD;
      imitate defecation as much as possible to the natural process. Fecobionics was developed to&#xD;
      simulate stool and to provide the driving pressure and resulting deformations of stool along&#xD;
      with a measure of an objective anorectal angle during defecation in a single examination.&#xD;
      Fecobionics makes it possible to describe objectively, without disturbing the defecation&#xD;
      process, the opening characteristics and pressure signatures during initial entry into the&#xD;
      relaxing anal canal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal is to provide mechanistic understanding of defecation in health and&#xD;
      defecatory disorders. It exceeds previous attempts to make artificial stool for evaluation of&#xD;
      defecation and integrates other technologies as well. It was designed to have a consistency&#xD;
      and deformability of Type 4 (range type 3-5) on the Bristol stool form scale. The range from&#xD;
      types 3-5 is found in 70% of healthy subjects. A major novelty is that Fecobionics measures&#xD;
      pressures in axial direction; i.e., in the flow direction. It is anticipated that Fecobionics&#xD;
      will shed light on the neurophysiology of defecation in health and disease, including&#xD;
      understanding the effect of biofeedback and neuromodulatory effect of SNS. It will be of&#xD;
      great value to provide endpoints in normal subjects that in future studies can be objective&#xD;
      measures for monitoring treatment efficacy. The present protocol is on normal subjects only.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Fecal continence is maintained by several mechanisms including anatomical factors, anorectal&#xD;
      sensation, rectal compliance, stool consistency, anal muscle strength, mobility, and&#xD;
      psychological factors. The homeostatic balance is easily disturbed by functional or&#xD;
      structural anorectal disturbances that may coexist. Common anorectal disorders are fecal&#xD;
      incontinence, functional anorectal pain, and functional defecation disorders. These&#xD;
      conditions greatly affect life quality for the patients. Current technologies for anorectal&#xD;
      functional assessment studies have limitations and often overlap is found between patient&#xD;
      groups with lack of correlation between measurements and symptoms. Defecation physiology has&#xD;
      been studied for many years but the mechanics and mechanosensation of defecation are still&#xD;
      not well understood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fecobionics combines several existing tests to provide novel insight into anorectal function.&#xD;
      The purpose for the development of Fecobionics was to overcome the technological&#xD;
      controversies and disagreement between various tests and unphysiological test conditions. The&#xD;
      aim was to imitate defecation as close as possible to the natural process. Fecobionics was&#xD;
      developed to simulate stool and to provide the driving pressure and resulting deformations of&#xD;
      stool along with a measure of an objective anorectal angle during defecation in a single&#xD;
      examination. Fecobionics makes it possible to describe objectively, without disturbing the&#xD;
      defecation process, the opening characteristics and pressure signatures during initial entry&#xD;
      into the relaxing anal canal as well as other parameters&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal is to provide mechanistic understanding of defecation in health and&#xD;
      defecatory disorders. Fecobionics exceeds previous attempts to make artificial stool for&#xD;
      evaluation of defecation and integrates other technologies as well. It was designed to have a&#xD;
      consistency and deformability of Type 4 (range type 3-5) on the Bristol stool form scale. The&#xD;
      range from types 3-5 is found in 70% of healthy subjects. A major novelty is that Fecobionics&#xD;
      measures pressures in axial direction; i.e., in the flow direction. It is anticipated that&#xD;
      Fecobionics will shed light on the neurophysiology of defecation in health and disease,&#xD;
      including understanding the effect of biofeedback and neuromodulatory effect of SNS. It will&#xD;
      be of great value to provide endpoints in normal subjects that in future studies can be&#xD;
      objective measures for monitoring treatment efficacy. The present protocol is on normal&#xD;
      subjects only, i.e. studying mechanisms of defecation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 21, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 21, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration-based device expulsion parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Expulsion Duration - The time it takes to defecate Fecobionics</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pressure-based device expulsion parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Pressure difference between front and rear of Fecobionics device - A measure of anal sphincter relaxation and key to the determination of defecation phases. Pressure profiles</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mechanical-based expulsion parameters Endpoints</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Mechanical Tension of Fecobionics Device (Pressure multiplied with radius).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Device orientation and bending-based expulsion parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>orientation of the device (degrees) and bending angle (degrees, a proxy of the anorectal angle during defecation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Shape-based expulsion parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>bag shape during defecation. Topographic characteristics of Fecobionics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Normal Subjects</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fecobionics studies</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single-arm study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fecobionics</intervention_name>
    <description>Fecobionics is a new device to be inserted through the anal canal into rectum for studying defecation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fecobionics studies</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject must provide written informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age 18 years and of age of legal consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Normal defecation pattern;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Within normal range for fecal incontinence severity index (FISI) and Wexner&#xD;
             Constipation Scoring System (CSS) scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female, who is pregnant or lactating;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Prior abdominal surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of fecal incontinence, constipation or anorectal pain.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hans Gregersen, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>California Medical Innovations Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>California Medical Innovations Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92121</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The California Medical Innovations Institute, Inc.</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hans Gregersen, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>anorectal</keyword>
  <keyword>Fecobionics</keyword>
  <keyword>defecation</keyword>
  <keyword>bionics</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

