<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04761835</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00279285</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04761835</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>STEP-IT-UP - Peanut Allergy Study for Infants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Subthreshold Peanut in Infants - Understanding Plasticity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multicenter randomized (1:1) trial of strict avoidance versus sub-threshold dietary&#xD;
      introduction of peanut in peanut allergic infants 4-14 months of age who react at a minimum&#xD;
      cumulative dose of at least 430 mg of peanut protein at initial oral food challenge (OFC) for&#xD;
      12 months, followed by cross-over to sub-threshold dietary introduction of peanut in those&#xD;
      randomized initially to avoidance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Withdrawn in IRB&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open label, randomized trial (1:1) to either dietary peanut intake or strict avoidance prior to a double blind placebo controlled food challenge 52 weeks later.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral food challenge threshold to peanut at week 52</measure>
    <time_frame>52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>compare the oral food challenge threshold (in milligrams) to peanut during a double-blind placebo-controlled food challenge (DBPCFC) after 12 months between subjects randomized to dietary peanut introduction and those randomized to avoidance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1. Oral food challenge threshold to peanut at week 52 for those initially randomized to dietary peanut compared to the oral food challenge threshold at week 104 for those initially randomized to strict avoidance</measure>
    <time_frame>104 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the oral food challenge threshold (in milligrams) to peanut during a double-blind placebo-controlled food challenge (DBPCFC) after 12 months of dietary peanut between subjects randomized to dietary peanut introduction first and those randomized to avoidance for 52 weeks and subsequent dietary peanut after week 52.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral food challenge threshold at 1 month avoidance after 12 months in each treatment group</measure>
    <time_frame>56 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of OFC threshold (in milligrams) at 1 month of avoidance (sustained unresponsiveness) after 12 months of dietary peanut between those initially randomized to peanut and those randomized to delayed introduction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral food challenge threshold at 2 months avoidance after 12 months in each treatment group</measure>
    <time_frame>60 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of OFC threshold (in milligrams) at 2 months of avoidance (sustained unresponsiveness) after 12 months of dietary peanut between those initially randomized to peanut and those randomized to delayed introduction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety with dietary introduction of peanut or avoidance</measure>
    <time_frame>52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants who have severe (grade 3) anaphylaxis secondary to any DBPCFC or ingestion of the measured dose of peanut.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of discontinuation of dietary peanut</measure>
    <time_frame>104 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants randomized to dietary peanut who discontinue peanut.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of eczema as assessed by the Scoring Atopic Dermatitis (SCORAD) score</measure>
    <time_frame>104 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Eczema severity as assessed by the SCORAD. The SCORAD has a component for patient measured outcomes and also provider assessment of eczema involvement. It has an overall score range of 0-100, where higher scores signify more severe eczema.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peanut skin prick test wheal size</measure>
    <time_frame>104 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Average wheal size (millimeters) of peanut skin prick test for participants in each group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Peanut Allergy</condition>
  <condition>Food Allergy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dietary Peanut</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will be asked to continue peanut in their diet for 1 year at a dose determined from the double blind placebo controlled food challenge at baseline. After the 1 year period, participants will be given another double blind placebo controlled food challenge which will be used to determine their current peanut threshold. The current peanut threshold will be used to determine which participants will go into clinical care and which will get sustained unresponsiveness food challenges to peanut.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Strict avoidance</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will be asked to strictly avoid any peanut in their diet for 1 year. After the 1 year period, participants will be given another double blind placebo controlled food challenge which will be used to determine whether they will transition to daily dietary peanut or continue with clinical care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peanut powder or peanut butter</intervention_name>
    <description>Commercially available peanut powder or peanut butter.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dietary Peanut</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children age 4-14 months suspected to be peanut allergic&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant medical problems&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>14 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Corinne Keet</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>infant food allergy</keyword>
  <keyword>treatment study</keyword>
  <keyword>peanut allergy treatment</keyword>
  <keyword>increase threshold of peanut intake for peanut allergic children</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Food Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peanut Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No individual participant level data will be shared. Only aggregate data from the study will be shared.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

