<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04765891</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ExSc PRT vs TM</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04765891</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Positional Release Therapy and Therapeutic Massage Reduce Muscle Trigger and Tender Points</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRT vs TM</acronym>
  <official_title>Positional Release Therapy and Therapeutic Massage Reduce Muscle Trigger and Tender Points</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brigham Young University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham Young University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if positional release therapy (PRT) or therapeutic&#xD;
      massage (TM) are more effective at decreasing muscle pain and tightness in the upper&#xD;
      trapezius muscle.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction Myofascial pain is a common disorder affecting individuals across the general&#xD;
      population and in specific populations, such as athletes, resulting in compromised function,&#xD;
      performance, and productivity. It has been associated with many pain conditions including&#xD;
      tension-type headache, spine disorder, and neck and shoulder pain. Myofascial pain&#xD;
      characteristically results from hyperirritable nodules of muscle (trigger points or tender&#xD;
      points) associated with pain in affected regions of the body. These areas within the muscle&#xD;
      are subjected to continued contraction of muscle fibers due to &quot;too much&quot; calcium resulting&#xD;
      in compromised oxygenation of the muscle tissue. These hyperirritable nodules often occur in&#xD;
      fatigued muscles that are subjected to imbalanced postural positions, such as the forward&#xD;
      head and rounded shoulders postures. It can also occur from repetitive movements commonly&#xD;
      seen in athletics, and individuals performing manual work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positional release therapy (PRT) and therapeutic massage (TM) are methods used to treat&#xD;
      trigger or tender points. Separate studies on each method have shown efficacy in reducing&#xD;
      pain muscle tightness and improving joint mobility. PRT is a manual therapeutic technique&#xD;
      that first locates tender points within a muscle. Once identified, the practitioner places&#xD;
      the muscle in a passively shortened position, while applying slight pressure. TM involves the&#xD;
      manipulation of soft tissue using techniques such as effleurage and petrissage, to restore&#xD;
      blood flow and oxygenation of the muscle tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Various methods have previously been used to find and assess severity of tender or trigger&#xD;
      points. Among those commonly used are the pressure pain algometer with pressure pain&#xD;
      threshold (PPT), range of motion electromyography and visual analog scales (VAS). Some&#xD;
      studies have also utilized B-mode (two-dimensional) ultrasound imaging (US) to locate,&#xD;
      define, trace, and quantify myofascial trigger points after palpation providing a useful&#xD;
      means of quantification. Shear wave elastography ultrasound (SWE) has been used to calculate&#xD;
      the elastic modulus (tissue stiffness) of muscle reliably, but has not been used quantify&#xD;
      changes within trigger points following treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives The purpose of our study was to quantify the effectiveness of PRT or TM at&#xD;
      reducing pain, trigger point tenderness, and muscle stiffness in the upper trapezius muscle&#xD;
      by using a combination of the visual analog scale, PPT, B-mode US and SWE to assess changes&#xD;
      within triggers points.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants We recruited 60 healthy Participants, 24 males and 36 females, (age=27.1±8.8&#xD;
      years, wt=75.2±17.9 kg, ht= 172.8±9.7 cm) to participate in the study. Many of the&#xD;
      participants participated on a University dance team. Participants admitted into the study&#xD;
      were required to have upper trapezius pain, during palpation, of at least 10 mm on the 100mm&#xD;
      visual analog scale and muscle tightness with an accompanying trigger point in their upper&#xD;
      trapezius. Participants who had suffered an acute injury to their upper trapezius in the last&#xD;
      6 days, were undergoing current treatment for their upper trapezius, or were unable to lie on&#xD;
      their stomach for an extended amount of time were removed from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study was approved by the university's Institutional Review Board before participant&#xD;
      recruitment. All participants provided written informed consent before individual data&#xD;
      collection began.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Instruments We used a GE LOGIC S8 ultrasound machine with the 9L soundhead to measure muscle&#xD;
      thickness and stiffness. Muscle thickness was measured using B-mode ultrasound and SWE&#xD;
      measured stiffness of the tissue.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to quantify subjective perception of pain we used PPT algometer with a .5 cm2&#xD;
      applicator tip along with the 100 mm visual analog scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures During the first visit participants underwent screening for presence of inclusion&#xD;
      and exclusion criteria as well as palpation for trigger points, following guidelines by&#xD;
      Simons, Travell and Speicher. Each side was examined and pain produced during palpation was&#xD;
      measured with previously published methods using the VAS. The side that was to be treated was&#xD;
      determined by the higher VAS score. Trigger point location, found through palpation, was&#xD;
      marked so that all measurements were taken in the same location. All baseline measurements&#xD;
      were taken according to the methods listed below. The participants were then randomly&#xD;
      assigned into one of two treatment groups, one being positional release therapy, the other&#xD;
      therapeutic massage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The same order of measurement was used for all participants since we felt that pressure from&#xD;
      the PPT algometer could act as a treatment and influence the visual analog scale or&#xD;
      elastography measures. Measurements were taken at rest with the participant in prone&#xD;
      position, with their arms at their sides for all measurement series, before and after&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pain Pressure Threshold Pain pressure threshold was determined by a digital pressure&#xD;
      algometer on the same point identified during screening. The area was measured once by&#xD;
      pressing perpendicularly into the trigger point until the subject declared it to be painful.&#xD;
      The peak force measured was then recorded in kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ultrasound and Elastography The ultrasound machine with a 9L sound head was used to measure&#xD;
      two different variables of muscle tension; 1) muscle thickness (B-mode) and tissue stiffness&#xD;
      via SWE over the same spot found and marked during screening. Using B-mode on the ultrasound&#xD;
      machine, two images aligned with the muscle fibers obtain were taken to obtain muscle&#xD;
      thickness. Internal software was used to measure muscle thickness and the 2 images were&#xD;
      averaged and recorded in cm. The elastography measure used a 3 cm2 box positioned over the&#xD;
      area containing the trigger point. Nine sample circles of .5cm dimeter were set within the&#xD;
      box side by side in rows in order to cover as much of the box as possible (shown in figure&#xD;
      1). (source?) Each circle registered a strain modulus reading in kPa. The average of the 9&#xD;
      sample circles was used to represent the stiffness of the muscle in the data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment groups Therapeutic Massage Participants in the TM treatment group received a timed&#xD;
      massage for 5 minutes by the same experienced research. A combination of effleurage and&#xD;
      petrissage techniques were used in an organized pattern. Treatment started with effleurage&#xD;
      (1-1.5 minutes) and proceeded to petrissage (2.5 to 3 minutes) again followed by effleurage&#xD;
      (1 minute) over the marked area of the trigger point, but also in some surrounding areas. The&#xD;
      pressure applied by the researcher progressed throughout the massage into the petrissage&#xD;
      phase as tolerated by the participant and pressure was then reduced during the final&#xD;
      effleurage phase. After the treatment was completed, the same dependent variable measurements&#xD;
      were taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Positional Release Therapy Participants in the PRT group received three successive treatments&#xD;
      or releases in the marked area. The researcher located the marked trigger point and while&#xD;
      maintaining contact, a light pressure with the clinician's fingertip was applied creating&#xD;
      slight dimpling of the skin and blanching of the clinician's fingernail bed. Following&#xD;
      palpation, the researcher moved the participant's shoulder into passive abduction and&#xD;
      scapular upward rotation and retraction until a position of comfort was achieved with no pain&#xD;
      reported by the participant, as directed by Speicher, &quot;Clinical Guide to Positional Release&#xD;
      Therapy&quot;. The participant was instructed to remain completely relaxed during the 90 second&#xD;
      treatment. After the recommended 90 seconds had passed the limb was returned to the starting&#xD;
      position. This was repeated immediately 2 more times in tender points immediately adjacent to&#xD;
      the first one, as recommended by Speicher. Following treatment, the same dependent variable&#xD;
      measurements were taken.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Posttreatment measurements Each participant returned 48 hours post treatment, where dependent&#xD;
      measurements were taken. Participants were also given an activity survey to record the number&#xD;
      of hours they exercised between the last session and the current session to note any&#xD;
      abnormalities or increase in normal exercise. The mark made from the first session, over the&#xD;
      examined trigger point, was still visible at the second visit for all participants and was&#xD;
      used to determine the location for performing dependent measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis A mixed-models analysis of variance was performed for each of the&#xD;
      dependent variables (VAS, US, elastography, and PPT). The covariates considered in the&#xD;
      analysis were the participants' sex, side of treatment, height, weight, and age. A step-wise&#xD;
      regression was used to determine significant covariates for each of the dependent variables.&#xD;
      Following the step-wise regression the primary variables of interest, treatment and time of&#xD;
      measurement were added along with their interaction for each of the dependent variables. Post&#xD;
      hoc t-tests were used to evaluate differences in the measurements. All analyses were&#xD;
      performed using SAS, version 9.4 and alpha was set at p&lt;0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 5, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 9, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 9, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain perception</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Rating of perceived pain as measured by the visual analog scale (VAS) on a scale of 0 to 100. With 100 being the highest pain score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Pressure Threshold (PPT)</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Pressure was measured by an algometer on a continuous scale. A higher score would indicate an individual tolerating more pressure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tissue Stiffness</measure>
    <time_frame>72 Hours</time_frame>
    <description>Tissue stiffness was measured using Shear Wave Elastography on a scale of 0 150, with larger numbers indicating a higher tissue stiffness.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle Thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>B-Mode Ultrasound was used to measure the resting thickness of the trapezius. muscle</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Trigger Point Pain, Myofascial</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Positional Release Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants were randomly assigned the positional release therapy treatment group. The participants underwent the treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Therapeutic Massage</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants were randomly assigned the therapeutic massage treatment group. The participants underwent the treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Positional release therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Positional release therapy was administered in the upper trapezius muscle. The muscle was placed in a shortened position with light pressure and held for 90 seconds per treatment location.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Positional Release Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Strain Counter Strain</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Therapeutic Massage</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants underwent a petrissage type massage for 5 minutes at the site of the trigger point in the upper trapezius.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Therapeutic Massage</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  dancers at the university&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects experiencing upper trapezius pain and muscle tightness, with associated&#xD;
             tender or trigger points&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need to be able to lie on stomach for at least 30 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not be currently receiving treatment from the Dance Athletic Training Room on their&#xD;
             trapezius.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to lie on stomach for 30 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently be receiving treatment on their upper trapezius muscle.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aaron W Johnson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Associate Professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham Young University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Provo</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84606</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aboodarda SJ, Spence AJ, Button DC. Pain pressure threshold of a muscle tender spot increases following local and non-local rolling massage. BMC Musculoskelet Disord. 2015 Sep 28;16:265. doi: 10.1186/s12891-015-0729-5.</citation>
    <PMID>26416265</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Borg-Stein J, Simons DG. Focused review: myofascial pain. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 2002 Mar;83(3 Suppl 1):S40-7, S48-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11973695</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Buttagat V, Eungpinichpong W, Chatchawan U, Arayawichanon P. Therapeutic effects of traditional Thai massage on pain, muscle tension and anxiety in patients with scapulocostal syndrome: a randomized single-blinded pilot study. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2012 Jan;16(1):57-63. doi: 10.1016/j.jbmt.2011.04.005. Epub 2011 Jun 22.</citation>
    <PMID>22196428</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cojocaru MC, Cojocaru IM, Voiculescu VM, Cojan-Carlea NA, Dumitru VL, Berteanu M. Trigger points--ultrasound and thermal findings. J Med Life. 2015 Jul-Sep;8(3):315-8.</citation>
    <PMID>26351532</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>D'Ambrogio KJ, Roth GB 1997 Positional Release Therapy. Mosby.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dommerholt J, Bron C, Franssen J 2006 Myofascial trigger points: an evidence-informed review. Journal of Manual &amp; Manipulative Therapy 14, 203-221.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Draper D 2015 The Deep Muscle Stimulator's Effects on Tissue Stiffness in Trigger-Point Therapy. Athletic Therapy Today 10, 52-53.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ghanbari A, Rahimijaberi A, Mohamadi M, Abbasi L, Sarvestani FK. The effect of trigger point management by positional release therapy on tension type headache. NeuroRehabilitation. 2012;30(4):333-9. doi: 10.3233/NRE-2012-0764.</citation>
    <PMID>22672949</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jafri MS. Mechanisms of Myofascial Pain. Int Sch Res Notices. 2014;2014. pii: 523924.</citation>
    <PMID>25574501</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>JG T, SH R 1983 Myofascial pain and dysfunction: the trigger point manual. Williams &amp; Wilkins, Baltimore MD.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kelencz CA, Tarini VA, Amorim CF. Trapezius upper portion trigger points treatment purpose in positional release therapy with electromyographic analysis. N Am J Med Sci. 2011 Oct;3(10):451-5. doi: 10.4297/najms.2011.3451.</citation>
    <PMID>22363082</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Knight KL, Draper DO 2013 Therapeutic Modalities: The Art and Science. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, Baltimore, MD.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kumbhare DA, Elzibak AH, Noseworthy MD. Assessment of Myofascial Trigger Points Using Ultrasound. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2016 Jan;95(1):72-80. doi: 10.1097/PHM.0000000000000376. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26334421</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mohammadi Kojidi M, Okhovatian F, Rahimi A, Baghban AA, Azimi H. The influence of Positional Release Therapy on the myofascial trigger points of the upper trapezius muscle in computer users. J Bodyw Mov Ther. 2016 Oct;20(4):767-773. doi: 10.1016/j.jbmt.2016.04.006. Epub 2016 Apr 7.</citation>
    <PMID>27814857</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Müller CE, Aranha MF, Gavião MB. Two-dimensional ultrasound and ultrasound elastography imaging of trigger points in women with myofascial pain syndrome treated by acupuncture and electroacupuncture: a double-blinded randomized controlled pilot study. Ultrason Imaging. 2015 Apr;37(2):152-67. doi: 10.1177/0161734614546571. Epub 2014 Aug 12.</citation>
    <PMID>25116293</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nagrale AV, Glynn P, Joshi A, Ramteke G. The efficacy of an integrated neuromuscular inhibition technique on upper trapezius trigger points in subjects with non-specific neck pain: a randomized controlled trial. J Man Manip Ther. 2010 Mar;18(1):37-43. doi: 10.1179/106698110X12595770849605.</citation>
    <PMID>21655422</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Myofascial trigger points, a possible explanation. Pain. 1981 Feb;10(1):106-109. doi: 10.1016/0304-3959(81)90053-1.</citation>
    <PMID>7232007</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sweety CC, Vinod KB, Kumar NS, Ayyappan V 2014 Effect of Positional Release Technique in Subjects with Subacute Trapezitis. Int J Physiother 1, 91-99.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tessier DG 2005 Sports massage: An overview. International Journal of Athletic Therapy and Training 10, 67-69.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wong CK. Strain counterstrain: current concepts and clinical evidence. Man Ther. 2012 Feb;17(1):2-8. doi: 10.1016/j.math.2011.10.001. Epub 2011 Oct 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22030379</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>If data is requested through e-mail by another investigator or institution, and approved by the institutional review board then data will be shared.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will become available upon e-mail request. This will be for at least 3 years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>E-mail to principal investigator from validated researchers.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 4, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/91/NCT04765891/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 7, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/91/NCT04765891/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

