<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04766099</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202101089</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04766099</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Video Education for Labor and Delivery</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of a Video Education Tool for the Second Stage of Labor</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Washington University School of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Washington University School of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The second stage of labor or the pushing stage can be challenging and intimidating for&#xD;
      patients delivering for the fist time. Among women with neuraxial anesthesia pushing may not&#xD;
      be instinctive and therefore various coaching methods are used to maximize maternal expulsive&#xD;
      efforts and minimize pushing time. Time intensive strategies including transperineally&#xD;
      ultrasound and bio-feedback have been employed to assist with pushing but they are difficult&#xD;
      to implement widely. While some women may attend birthing classes or have previously been&#xD;
      coached on pushing prior to the onset of labor, many women are unable to access classes prior&#xD;
      to labor or do not retain what they learned in a class weeks prior to labor. Previous studies&#xD;
      have evaluated the effect of coached pushing on the length of second stage and have indicated&#xD;
      that coaching can decrease the second stage up to 13 minutes. In most clinical scenarios,&#xD;
      coaching or guidance from the nurse or provider happens once the patient attains complete&#xD;
      dilation. There are limitations to this approach as waiting to coach after a potentially long&#xD;
      and arduous labor is suboptimal. Therefore, we propose a randomized controlled trial&#xD;
      investigating the use of an educational video during the first stage of labor on length of&#xD;
      the second stage.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Childbirth education is critical to maternal outcomes. Receiving formal education on the&#xD;
      birthing process sets the stage for optimal mother/baby bonding, postpartum mood, and future&#xD;
      interactions with healthcare professionals. The American Congress of Obstetrics and&#xD;
      Gynecology recommends patients attend birthing classes prior to labor and delivery, however&#xD;
      previous studies found that attendance is dropping with only 56% of first-time mothers&#xD;
      attending childbirth education classes in 2005 compared to 70% in 2001.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multiple barriers to accessing prenatal childbirth education have been identified.&#xD;
      Traditionally, childbirth education classes are structured as in person lectures with&#xD;
      multiple sessions over a period of weeks and are taken prior to the onset of labor. Most&#xD;
      childbirth education classes have accompanying costs ranging from $20-$50 for hospital&#xD;
      classes and hundreds of dollars for private classes. Significant barriers impact patients&#xD;
      ability to attend these classes including difficulty obtaining childcare, financial&#xD;
      constraints, getting time off from work, and obtaining transportation. The Coronavirus&#xD;
      pandemic has further worsened barriers to accessing childbirth education as most in-person&#xD;
      group classes have been cancelled due to lack of funding or need for social distancing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most childbirth education focuses on preparation for labor and pain management in the first&#xD;
      stage of labor neglecting the second stage. This is the stage of labor that requires the most&#xD;
      maternal involvement and effort. Among women with epidural anesthesia pushing may not be&#xD;
      instinctive and hence, coaching and preparation are integral to success.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current standard of care for teaching a patient how to push is nurse-led coaching&#xD;
      performed at the bedside immediately before the patient starts pushing. At this point, most&#xD;
      patients are tired, anxious, and have not had enough time to process the new knowledge&#xD;
      learned about how to push. A long or abnormal second stage is associated with adverse&#xD;
      outcomes such as cesarean delivery, infection, and hemorrhage. Nulliparous patients are&#xD;
      especially vulnerable to these adverse outcomes in the second stage so long as they do not&#xD;
      feel empowered, knowledgeable, or involved in their own birth experiences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous literature shows that coached pushing can decrease second stage duration up to 13&#xD;
      minutes. This is important as a prolonged second stage of labor is associated with maternal&#xD;
      and neonatal morbidity including higher rates of cesarean delivery, chorioamnionitis,&#xD;
      perineal trauma, NICU admission, neonatal sepsis, and APGAR score &lt; 4 at 5 minutes. In most&#xD;
      clinical scenarios, the standard of care is coaching or guidance from the nurse or provider&#xD;
      once the patient reaches complete dilation. There are limitations to this approach as waiting&#xD;
      to coach after a potentially long and arduous labor course is suboptimal. While physicians&#xD;
      and nurses are qualified to coach, they may not be universally available to all patients and&#xD;
      the quality of coaching may be impacted by volume and acuity on Labor &amp; Delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In theory, the advent of video-based education can easily be transferred to the hospital to&#xD;
      address this issue and allows for education during labor once an epidural is placed, the&#xD;
      patient is comfortable, and well before pushing starts. The average duration of labor and&#xD;
      delivery in a first-time mother ranges from 14 to 20 hours. This presents an opportune window&#xD;
      of time for video-based childbirth education to narrow gaps in childbirth education&#xD;
      disparities and increase maternal involvement without the barriers present in the outpatient&#xD;
      setting. The efficacy of this novel way of providing childbirth education has not been&#xD;
      tested.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To address this quality gap, we propose a randomized trial comparing an intrapartum video&#xD;
      education tool to standard provider-based coaching&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of the Second Stage of Labor</measure>
    <time_frame>delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Time from complete dilation to delivery of the fetus</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Labor Satisfaction Scores</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day ( Assessed via survey prior to discharge from the hospital)</time_frame>
    <description>Labor satisfaction as measured by the Mackey Childbirth Satisfaction Rating Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">152</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy Related</condition>
  <condition>Educational Problems</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard bedside coaching by labor and delivery staff</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Educational Video</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will watch the provided coaching video in addition to standard bedside coaching by labor and delivery staff</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Childbirth Educational Video</intervention_name>
    <description>Educational video describing techniques for pushing</description>
    <arm_group_label>Educational Video</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nulliparous women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 year of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Single fetus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Term: has completed 36 weeks of pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  fetal anomalies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior cesarean delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindication to valsalva&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  blind patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  admission in the second stage of labor&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rebecca R Rimsza, MD</last_name>
    <phone>314-747-2362</phone>
    <email>rimsza@wustl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cassy Hardy</last_name>
    <phone>314-362-7539</phone>
    <email>cassandra.hardy@wustl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goodman P, Mackey MC, Tavakoli AS. Factors related to childbirth satisfaction. J Adv Nurs. 2004 Apr;46(2):212-9.</citation>
    <PMID>15056335</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Committee on Obstetric Practice. Committee Opinion No. 687: Approaches to Limit Intervention During Labor and Birth. Obstet Gynecol. 2017 Feb;129(2):e20-e28. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000001905. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28121831</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Declercq ER, Sakala C, Corry MP, Applebaum S, Herrlich A. Major Survey Findings of Listening to Mothers(SM) III: Pregnancy and Birth: Report of the Third National U.S. Survey of Women's Childbearing Experiences. J Perinat Educ. 2014 Winter;23(1):9-16. doi: 10.1891/1058-1243.23.1.9.</citation>
    <PMID>24453463</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lu MC, Prentice J, Yu SM, Inkelas M, Lange LO, Halfon N. Childbirth education classes: sociodemographic disparities in attendance and the association of attendance with breastfeeding initiation. Matern Child Health J. 2003 Jun;7(2):87-93.</citation>
    <PMID>12870624</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Simpson KR, Newman G, Chirino OR. Patients' perspectives on the role of prepared childbirth education in decision making regarding elective labor induction. J Perinat Educ. 2010 Summer;19(3):21-32. doi: 10.1624/105812410X514396.</citation>
    <PMID>21629391</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grobman WA, Rice MM, Reddy UM, Tita ATN, Silver RM, Mallett G, Hill K, Thom EA, El-Sayed YY, Perez-Delboy A, Rouse DJ, Saade GR, Boggess KA, Chauhan SP, Iams JD, Chien EK, Casey BM, Gibbs RS, Srinivas SK, Swamy GK, Simhan HN, Macones GA; Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Maternal-Fetal Medicine Units Network. Labor Induction versus Expectant Management in Low-Risk Nulliparous Women. N Engl J Med. 2018 Aug 9;379(6):513-523. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1800566.</citation>
    <PMID>30089070</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fenwick J, Toohill J, Gamble J, Creedy DK, Buist A, Turkstra E, Sneddon A, Scuffham PA, Ryding EL. Effects of a midwife psycho-education intervention to reduce childbirth fear on women's birth outcomes and postpartum psychological wellbeing. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2015 Oct 30;15:284. doi: 10.1186/s12884-015-0721-y.</citation>
    <PMID>26518597</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Çankaya S, Şimşek B. Effects of Antenatal Education on Fear of Birth, Depression, Anxiety, Childbirth Self-Efficacy, and Mode of Delivery in Primiparous Pregnant Women: A Prospective Randomized Controlled Study. Clin Nurs Res. 2021 Jul;30(6):818-829. doi: 10.1177/1054773820916984. Epub 2020 Apr 13.</citation>
    <PMID>32281410</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sperlich M, Gabriel C, St Vil NM. Preference, knowledge and utilization of midwives, childbirth education classes and doulas among U.S. black and white women: implications for pregnancy and childbirth outcomes. Soc Work Health Care. 2019 Nov-Dec;58(10):988-1001. doi: 10.1080/00981389.2019.1686679. Epub 2019 Nov 4.</citation>
    <PMID>31682786</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Washington University School of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rebecca Rimsza</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Fellow</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

