<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04765384</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CR108962</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-005330-14</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>VAC31518COV2004</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04765384</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Ad26.COV2.S in Healthy Pregnant Participants (COVID-19)</brief_title>
  <acronym>HORIZON 1</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Phase 2 Study to Evaluate the Safety, Reactogenicity, and Immunogenicity of Ad26.COV2.S in Healthy Pregnant Participants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Vaccines &amp; Prevention B.V.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Vaccines &amp; Prevention B.V.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to assess the safety and reactogenicity of Ad26.COV2.S&#xD;
      administered intramuscularly (IM) as a 1-dose schedule at the standard dose level, or 2-dose&#xD;
      schedule at a lower dose level, at a ratio of approximately 325:75 adult participants&#xD;
      (regardless of serostatus), during the second and/or third trimester of pregnancy and&#xD;
      (potentially) post-partum; to assess the humoral immune response in peripheral blood of adult&#xD;
      participants to Ad26.COV2.S administered IM as a 1-dose, or 2-dose schedule, during the&#xD;
      second and/or third trimester of pregnancy, 28 days after the first vaccination and 14 days&#xD;
      after the second vaccination.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There is an increased risk of severe coronavirus disease-2019 (COVID-19) during pregnancy, as&#xD;
      well as an increased risk of adverse birth outcomes. Therefore, the aim of this study is to&#xD;
      assess the safety, reactogenicity and immunogenicity of Ad26.COV2.S in adult participants in&#xD;
      the second and/or third trimester of pregnancy. Ad26.COV2.S (also known as Ad26COVS1) is a&#xD;
      monovalent vaccine composed of a recombinant, replication incompetent adenovirus type 26&#xD;
      (Ad26) vector, constructed to encode the severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus-2&#xD;
      (SARS-CoV-2) spike (S) protein. For adult participants, the total study duration from&#xD;
      screening until the last follow-up visit will be approximately 16 months (depending on the&#xD;
      gestational age at enrollment and if the second dose of vaccine will need to be administered&#xD;
      post-partum [PP]). The study will consist of a screening phase (28 days), vaccination phase&#xD;
      (1-month or 3-month) and a follow up phase (up to 12 months PP). For neonates/infants (born&#xD;
      to adult participants who received vaccination) the total study duration from birth until the&#xD;
      last follow-up visit will be approximately 12 months. Safety assessments will include&#xD;
      immunogenicity assessments, physical examination, vital signs, clinical safety laboratory&#xD;
      assessments, medical, obstetric and delivery history, neonate safety assessment, adverse&#xD;
      events (AEs), serious adverse events (SAEs), and adverse events of special interest (AESI).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 18, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 16, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>Yes</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Solicited Local Adverse Events (AEs) for 7 Days After Each vaccination or Until Resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after each vaccination or until resolution (Up to Day 64)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study. Solicited local AEs are pre-defined local (at the injection site) AEs for which participants are specifically asked and which are noted by participants in their reactogenicity diary for 7 days post each vaccination or until resolution. Solicited local AEs are: injection site pain/tenderness, erythema, swelling at the vaccination site.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Solicited Systemic AEs for 7 Days After Each Vaccination or Until Resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after each vaccination or until resolution (Up to Day 64)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study. Participants will be instructed on how to note signs and symptoms in the diary on a daily basis for 7 days post-vaccination (Day of vaccination and the subsequent 7 days) or until resolution for solicited systemic AEs. Solicited systemic events include fatigue, headache, nausea and myalgia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Unsolicited AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after each vaccination (Up to Day 85)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study. Unsolicited AEs are all AEs for which the participant is not specifically questioned in the participant's reactogenicity diary.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>SAE is any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose results in any of the following outcomes: death; initial or prolonged inpatient hospitalization; life-threatening experience (immediate risk of dying); persistent or significant disability/incapacity; congenital anomaly/birth defect; suspected transmission of any infectious agent via a medicinal product or medically important.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with AESIs will be reported. Thrombosis with thrombocytopenia syndrome is considered to be an AESI.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Medically-attended Adverse Events (MAAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after last vaccination (Up to Day 240)</time_frame>
    <description>MAAEs are defined as AEs with medically-attended visits including hospital, emergency room, urgent care clinic, or other visits to or from medical personnel for any reason. Routine study visits will not be considered medically-attended visits. New onset of chronic diseases will be collected as part of the MAAEs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with AEs leading to Discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is any untoward medical occurrence in a participant participating in a clinical study that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the pharmaceutical/biological agent under study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serological Response to Vaccination as Measured by Enzyme-linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA) 28 Days After the First Vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after the first vaccination (Day 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Serological response to vaccination as measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (S-ELISA, ELISA Units/milliliter [EU/mL]), 28 days after first vaccination will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serological Response to Vaccination as Measured by ELISA 14 Days After the Second Vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days after the Second vaccination (Day 71)</time_frame>
    <description>Serological response to vaccination as measured by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (S-ELISA, ELISA Units/milliliter [EU/mL]), 14 days after the second vaccination will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Antibody Geometric Mean Concentration (GMC) 28 Days After the First Vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after the first vaccination (Day 29)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with antibody GMC (S-ELISA, EU/mL), 28 days after the first vaccination will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Antibody GMC 14 Days After the Second Vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days after the second vaccination (Day 71)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with antibody GMC (S-ELISA, EU/mL), 14 days after the second vaccination will be reported.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adult Participants with Pregnancy Outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of adult participants with pregnancy outcomes (including, live term birth, live preterm birth, stillbirth, and abortion) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adult Participants with Pregnancy Related AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of adult participants with pregnancy-related AEs including: gestational diabetes, gestational hypertension, premature rupture of membranes, premature labor, premature uterine contractions, poor or restricted fetal growth, pre-eclampsia, eclampsia, vaginal or intrauterine hemorrhage (non-exhaustive) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serological Response to Vaccination as Measured by ELISA at all Blood Collection Timepoints in Adult Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>Serological response to vaccination as measured by ELISA (S-ELISA, EU/mL), at all blood collection timepoints in adult participants will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adult Participants with Antibody GMC (S-ELISA)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 16 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of adult participants with antibody GMC (S-ELISA, EU/mL) will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serological Response to Vaccination as Measured by Virus Neutralization Assay (VNA) Titers 28 Days After the First Vaccination and 14 Days After the Second Vaccination in Adult Participants</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after the First vaccination (Day 29), 14 days after the second vaccination (Day 71)</time_frame>
    <description>Serological response to vaccination as measured by VNA titers, 28 days after the first vaccination and 14 days after the second vaccination in adult participants will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adult Participants with Antibody Geometric Mean Titer (GMTs) (VNA) 28 Days After the First Vaccination and 14 Days After the Second Vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after the first vaccination (Day 29), 14 days after the second vaccination (Day 71)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of adult participants with antibody GMTs (VNA), 28 days after the first vaccination and 14 days after the second vaccination will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serological Response to Vaccination as Measured by ELISA</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 2 months, 6 months, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Serological response to vaccination as measured by ELISA (S-ELISA, EU/mL) will be reported for neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) at birth (in cord blood) and up to 2 months, 6 months, and 12 months of age.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with Antibody GMCs</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 2 months, 6 months, 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) with antibody GMCs (S-ELISA, EU/mL) will be reported at birth and up to 2 months, 6 months, and 12 months of age.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serological Response to Vaccination as Measured by VNA Titers at Birth</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Serological response to vaccination as measured by VNA titers will be reported for neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) at birth (in cord blood).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with Antibody GMT (VNA)</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) with antibody GMT will be reported at birth (in cord blood).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with SAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) with SAEs including multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C) from birth up to 12 months of age will be reported. Patients with MIS-C usually present with persistent fever, fatigue and a variety of signs and symptoms including multiorgan (example, cardiac, gastrointestinal, renal, hematologic, dermatologic, neurologic) involvement, elevated inflammatory markers and, in severe cases, hypotension and shock.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with AESIs</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants with AESIs will be reported. Thrombosis with thrombocytopenia syndrome is considered to be an AESI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with MAAEs</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) with MAAEs from birth up to 6 months of age will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with AEs leading to Study Discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants (born to adult participants who received vaccination) with AEs leading to discontinuation from birth up to 12 months of age will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Neonates and Infants with any Complications, Anomalies and Deaths</measure>
    <time_frame>From birth up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of neonates and infants with any complication, anomalies and death will be reported. This will also includes normal neonate, term neonate with complications, preterm neonate with complications, neonatal infection, respiratory distress, congenital anomalies, neonatal death, low birth weight, and small for gestational age measured from birth up to 12 months of age (non exhaustive).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ad26.COV2.S (One or Two Dose)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive 1 dose of Ad26.COV2.S at standard dose level as intramuscular (IM) injection on Day 1 to assess safety and reactogenicity profile in sentinels group at Day 4 and if acceptable, in safety cohort at Day 8. If the safety and reactogenicity profile is considered acceptable per Independent Data Monitoring Committee (IDMC), the remaining participants will be randomized to receive a single standard dose of Ad26.COV2.S or two doses of Ad26.COV2.S at a lower dose level on Day 1 and 57.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ad26.COV2.S (Two Dose)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive 2 doses of Ad26.COV2.S at a lower dose level on Day 1 and 57. If the safety and reactogenicity profile after 1 dose at standard dose level is not considered acceptable per IDMC, all remaining participants (except sentinels and safety cohort) will receive 2 doses of Ad26.COV2.S at a lower dose level on Day 1 and 57.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ad26.COV2.S</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive IM injection of Ad26.COV2.S.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ad26.COV2.S (One or Two Dose)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Ad26.COV2.S (Two Dose)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>JNJ-78436735, Ad26COVS1</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If on medication for a condition, the medication dose must have been stable for at&#xD;
             least 12 weeks preceding vaccination and expected to remain stable for the duration of&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant will be included on the basis of physical examination, medical history,&#xD;
             and vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant will be at second or third trimester of pregnancy, that is, Week 16 to&#xD;
             Week 38 of gestation (inclusive), at the time of vaccination, based on ultrasound at&#xD;
             the time of screening (unless performed elsewhere within 28-days prior to vaccination)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agrees to not donate bone marrow, blood, and blood products from the first&#xD;
             study vaccine administration until 3 months after receiving the last dose of study&#xD;
             vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be willing to provide verifiable identification, has means to be&#xD;
             contacted and to contact the investigator during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with medical or obstetric histories that put them at higher risk for&#xD;
             maternal or fetal complications (example, preeclampsia, premature birth during&#xD;
             previous pregnancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with abnormal pregnancy screening test (example, ultrasound fetal&#xD;
             abnormalities, maternal blood screen)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of malignancy within 5 years before screening (exceptions&#xD;
             are squamous and basal cell carcinomas of the skin and carcinoma in situ of the&#xD;
             cervix, or malignancy, which is considered cured with minimal risk of recurrence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known or suspected allergy or history of anaphylaxis or other&#xD;
             serious adverse reactions to vaccines or their excipients (including specifically the&#xD;
             excipients of the study vaccine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of any serious, chronic, or progressive neurological&#xD;
             disorders or seizures including Guillain-Barre syndrome, with the exception of febrile&#xD;
             seizures during childhood&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a positive diagnostic test result (polymerase chain reaction [PCR]&#xD;
             based viral ribonucleic acid [RNA] detection) severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
             coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) infection at screening or Day 1 (if more than 4 days in&#xD;
             between)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of thrombosis with thrombocytopenia syndrome (TTS),&#xD;
             including cerebral venous sinus thrombosis (CVST), or heparin-induced thrombocytopenia&#xD;
             (HIT)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of capillary leak syndrome (CLS)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Janssen Vaccines &amp; Prevention B.V. Clinical Trial</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Janssen Vaccines &amp; Prevention B.V.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Study Contact</last_name>
    <phone>844-434-4210</phone>
    <email>JNJ.CT@sylogent.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Central Research Associates, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SEC Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dothan</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>36303</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Southern California</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90089</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford Health Care - Positive Care Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stanford</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94306-5640</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Holy Cross Hospital - Michael and Dianne Bienes Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fort Lauderdale</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Spectrum Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medpharmics, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gulfport</city>
        <state>Mississippi</state>
        <zip>39503</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Meridian Clinical Research, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Island</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68803</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Meridian Clinical Research, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68701</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Excel Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wr-Crcn, Llc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89123</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medpharmics, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albuquerque</city>
        <state>New Mexico</state>
        <zip>87102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10019</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Monroe Biomedical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monroe</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28112</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wake Forest Baptist Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winston-Salem</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cincinnati Children's Hospital Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Synexus Clinical Research US, Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43212</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center (UPMC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tekton Research Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor College of Medicine and Texas Childrens Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centex Studies, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77058</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maximos OB/GYN</name>
      <address>
        <city>League City</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77573</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Clinicas da Universidade Federal De Minas Geraisnas Gerais</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belo Horizonte</city>
        <zip>30130-100</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>HMCP - Hospital e Maternidade Celso Pierro - PUC-Campinas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Campinas</city>
        <zip>13060-904</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Do Cancer Do Hospital Pompeia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Caxias do Sul</city>
        <zip>95010-005</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital São José</name>
      <address>
        <city>Criciúma</city>
        <zip>88801-250</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitário da UNIMAR</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marília</city>
        <zip>17525-160</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro de Estudos e Pesquisas em Moléstias Infecciosas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Natal</city>
        <zip>59025-050</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de Clínicas de Porto Alegre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto Alegre</city>
        <zip>90035-903</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Geral de Nova Iguacu - HGNI DST/AIDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rio De Janeiro</city>
        <zip>26030-380</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fundacao Faculdade Regional De Medicina De Sao Jose Do Rio Preto</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sao Jose do Rio Preto</city>
        <zip>15090-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Sao Paulo Brazil NICHD CRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sao Paulo</city>
        <zip>14049-900</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CMPC - Consultoria Médica e Pesquisa Clínica</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sorocaba</city>
        <zip>18040-425</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CEMEC - Centro Multidisciplinar de Estudos Clínicos</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Bernardo do Campo</city>
        <zip>09715-090</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universidade Municipal de Sao Caetano do Sul</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Caetano do Sul</city>
        <zip>09521-160</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Das Clinicas Da Faculdade De Medicina Da Universidade De Sao Paulo</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <zip>05403-000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ndlovu Elandsdoorn Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dennilton</city>
        <zip>0485</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shandukani Research Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Johannesburg</city>
        <zip>2001</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanza Clinical Research Centre : Mamelodi</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mamelodi East</city>
        <zip>0122</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Setshaba Research Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Soshanguve</city>
        <zip>152</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Withdrawn</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Perinatal HIV Research Unit, Chris Hani Baragwanath Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Soweto</city>
        <zip>1864</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vaccines and Infectious Diseases Analytics Research Unit (VIDA), Formely RMPRU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Soweto</city>
        <zip>1864</zip>
        <country>South Africa</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
    <country>South Africa</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Finland</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://pam.sylogent.com/cr/CR108962</url>
    <description>To learn how to participate in this trial please click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The data sharing policy of the Janssen Pharmaceutical Companies of Johnson &amp; Johnson is available at www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency. As noted on this site, requests for access to the study data can be submitted through Yale Open Data Access (YODA) Project site at yoda.yale.edu</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.janssen.com/clinical-trials/transparency</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

