<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04767997</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>L-019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04767997</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Probiotics on Sleep Among Adults Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Probiotics on Sleep Quality Among Mildly Stressed Adults: A Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Double-blind, Parallel Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lallemand Health Solutions</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lallemand Health Solutions</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to determine the impact of a probiotic formulation on subjective&#xD;
      sleep patterns. It is hypothesized that participants given the probiotics will improve their&#xD;
      sleep patterns compared to participants receiving placebo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants with symptoms of insomnia and work-related stress will be recruited to&#xD;
      participate in a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind interventional study for&#xD;
      approximately 15 since the signature of the informed consent. Participants will first be seen&#xD;
      at the Screening visit when they will be administered several questionnaires to determine&#xD;
      eligibility (assessing symptoms of insomnia, work-related stress, psychological distress and&#xD;
      other sleep disorders). Participants will receive a 2-week sleep journal and an actigraphy to&#xD;
      record their sleep patterns. At visit 2 returning participants will be randomized to receive&#xD;
      probiotics or placebo for the following 12 weeks. During this visit, participants will be&#xD;
      administered questionnaires assessing sleep quality, work-related productivity, quality of&#xD;
      life, and mood. Participants will also be asked to bring to site a stool sample and saliva&#xD;
      samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked to return at 6 weeks for visit 3. During this visit participants&#xD;
      will be administered questionnaires (insomnia, sleep quality, work-related stress and&#xD;
      productivity, quality of life, mood and psychological distress).&#xD;
&#xD;
      They will also bring two saliva samples. Two weeks prior to visit 4, participants will be&#xD;
      asked to complete another sleep journal and be dispensed another actigraphy which shall be&#xD;
      returned at visit 4. Lastly, participants will return on for visit 4 at week 12 in which the&#xD;
      same questionnaires as visit 3 will be administered. Participants will also be asked to bring&#xD;
      to site another stool sample and two saliva samples.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of insomnia</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of sleep quality assessed by the Insomnia Severity Index among probiotic versus placebo</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptoms of insomnia (progressive treatment)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of sleep quality assessed by the Insomnia Severity Index among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective assessment of sleep: Sleep Latency</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of sleep latency recorded by actigraphy of probiotic versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective assessment of sleep: Sleep Efficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of sleep efficiency recorded by actigraphy of probiotic versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective assessment of sleep: Wake after sleep onset (WASO)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of WASO recorded by actigraphy of probiotic versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective sleep patterns</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of sleep quality, assessed via Visual Analogue Scale (0 to 12; higher scores indicate worse sleep patterns), among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective sleep patterns (progressive treatment)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of sleep quality, assessed via Visual Analogue Scale (0 to 12; higher scores indicate worse sleep patterns), among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Work-related stress</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of overall score obtained at the Effort-Reward Imbalance (ERI; scores below 0.8 denote higher reward) among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Work Productivity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of overall score obtained at the Work Productivity and Activity Impairment (WPAI; 0% to 100%, with higher scores indicating higher impairment and lower productivity) questionnaire among probiotics versus placebo groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change on Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of overall score obtained at the questionnaires WHOQOL-Bref (0 to 100; higher scores denote higher quality of life) and Kessler 10 (K10; 5 - no psychological distress to 50 - high psychological distress) among probiotics versus placebo groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of overall score obtained at the HADS questionnaire (0 - no mood disorder to 21 - responder likely suffers depression and/or anxiety) among probiotics versus placebo groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of sleep-related hormones</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the cortisol and melatonin quantified from saliva samples among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of intervention (number of Serious and Adverse events)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the number of adverse events and serious adverse events reported by participants randomized to receive probiotics compared to those receiving placebo.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Sleep Disturbance</condition>
  <condition>Sleep Patterns</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will be randomized to receive probiotic formulation for the following 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group will be randomized to receive placebo for the following 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Probiotic formulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be asked to take one capsule daily, containing 3 billion CFU of the probiotics.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be asked to take a placebo capsule daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Men and women aged between 18 and 65 years-old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Scores 8 ≥ in the ISI&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Having a score higher to 0.8 in the ERI questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Body mass index (BMI) below or equal to 30.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Otherwise healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Working (paid or unpaid) at the same position for at least the past 3 months and plans&#xD;
             to have the same position for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Willing to discontinue consumption of probiotics supplements and probiotic fortified&#xD;
             products throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Presence of unrelated sleep disorders (Obstructive Sleep Apnea and REM Sleep Behavior&#xD;
             Disorder) as per questionnaires (STOP BANG and the RBD single question, respectively).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Diagnosis of mental disorders (diagnosed by a health professional in the last year,&#xD;
             including insomnia) or showing high psychosocial stress assessed by K10 (score equal&#xD;
             or above 17).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diabetes (type I and II), blood/bleeding disorders, liver and/or kidney disorders,&#xD;
             unstable cardiovascular diseases, neurological diseases (such as, but not limited to&#xD;
             Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's disease, epilepsy), gastrointestinal diseases (such&#xD;
             as, but not limited to gastric ulcers, Crohn's disease, ulcerative colitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Irregular bedtime schedule (schedule resulting in usual bedtime earlier than 8 PM or&#xD;
             later than 2 AM or arising time earlier than 4 AM or later than 10 AM).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Currently suffering from periodontitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy, planning to be pregnant or currently breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Use of medication to improve sleep, such as Zopiclone, Doxepine, Trazodone, Melatonin,&#xD;
             any H1-antagonist, antipsychotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Milk and soy allergy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Lactose intolerance.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Charles Morin, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre de recherche CERVO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Manon Lamy</last_name>
    <phone>418-656-2131</phone>
    <phone_ext>412467</phone_ext>
    <email>manon.lamy@psy.ulaval.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Brunella Gonzalez Cautela</last_name>
    <phone>514-283-1387</phone>
    <email>bgonzalez@lallemand.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre d'étude des troubles du sommeil, Centre de recherche CERVO/BRAIN</name>
      <address>
        <city>Quebec</city>
        <zip>G1J 2G2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Manon Lamy</last_name>
      <phone>418-558-5470</phone>
      <email>manon.lamy@psy.ulaval.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyssomnias</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Parasomnias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>After publications of the results, de-identified data will be shared with qualified researchers and scientists upon reasonable request to the sponsor including a detailed proposal of the intended use of the data, as per the Lallemand Health Solutions Inc. Policy on Clinical Trial Transparency and Data Sharing (available upon request).</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

