<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01723033</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BHMC-5200</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01723033</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Differences in Cognitive Performance and Brain Activity Between Patients With PTSD and OCD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Differences in Cognitive Performance and Brain Activity Between Patients With PTSD and OCD</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beersheva Mental Health Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beersheva Mental Health Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Comparison of the neurophysiological response of OCD and PTSD patients (both considered&#xD;
      anxiety syndromes) in error processing. The patients will perform three computerized tasks&#xD;
      while a net of electrodes (for EEG measurement) will be placed on their head. This data will&#xD;
      then be compared to a previously collected healthy control sample.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Scientific background Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD) Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD)&#xD;
      is a chronic mental disturbance classified as an anxiety disorder, which causes a severe&#xD;
      social and occupational damage. It is characterized with repetitive and intrusive thoughts,&#xD;
      and with the urge to perform reoccurring rituals. Illness' course is usually chronic and is&#xD;
      characterized with fluctuation in symptoms severity. Only a minority of patients gain full&#xD;
      relief, even following the appropriate treatment. There are two main useful treatments, a&#xD;
      behavioral therapy and a medicinal treatment using SSRI's. Even though medicinal treatments&#xD;
      are improving, large amount of patients are irresponsive to a variety of medicinal treatment&#xD;
      and about a third is classified as Refractory to Treatment. Of those who will gain relief,&#xD;
      relapse rate is high (Catapano et al., 2006).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Brain imaging studies demonstrate that the neurophysiological basis of OCD appears to be&#xD;
      abnormal functioning of frontal subcortical circuits and that illness' symptoms are related&#xD;
      to an increase in cortical activity of different areas: anterior cingulate gyrus (Saxena &amp;&#xD;
      Rauch, 2000) orbitofrontal cortex, caudate nucleus, and thalamus. ERP studies provide a&#xD;
      number of indicators of cerebral abnormalities in OCD, during critical aspects of cognitive&#xD;
      processing (Clark et al., 2009). The sharp negative deflection associated with errors is&#xD;
      referred to as error-related negativity (ERN; Gehring, Coles, Meyer, &amp; Donchin, 1995).&#xD;
      Gehring et al. (2000) found that OCD patients had an increased ERN amplitude which was&#xD;
      significantly associated with symptom severity. Johannes et al. (2001) using a visual&#xD;
      discrimination task also reported larger ERN amplitudes in OCD patients, whilst Hajcak and&#xD;
      Simons (2002) found increased ERN-like deflections to both incorrect and correct trials in&#xD;
      University under- graduates with high levels of obsessive compulsive characteristics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      From cognitive behavioral perspective, obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) has been&#xD;
      associated with impairments in stop-signal inhibition, a measure of motor response&#xD;
      suppression (Morein-Zamir, Fineberg, Robbins, &amp; Sahakian, 2010). Another study has related&#xD;
      OCD to an attention bias shifting towards the right hemifield in a well-established visual&#xD;
      attention task (Maril, Hermesh, Gross-Isseroff, &amp; Tomer, 2007). Furthermore this shift of&#xD;
      attention had been reported to be positively correlated with OCD symptoms as measured by the&#xD;
      Y-BOCS (e.g. less Y-BOCS score correlated with less shifting of attention).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) Posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) is associated with&#xD;
      increased rates of health complaints (Beckham et al., 1998) medical morbidity (Beckham et&#xD;
      al., 2003) health service utilization (Calhoun, et al., 2002), and mortality (Boscarino,&#xD;
      2006). The prevalence of PTSD in the general population is estimated to be between 7% and 12%&#xD;
      (Breslau, 2009).&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the anatomical level reports vary with certain areas emerging as possibly implicated in&#xD;
      PTSD predisposition and pathology. The hippocampus, important in learning and memory, has&#xD;
      been shown to be reduced in volume in PTSD patients ( reviewed by Nutt &amp; Malizia, 2004). Two&#xD;
      additional regions implicated in PTSD are the amygdale- involved in emotional behavior, and&#xD;
      the medial frontal cortex - important in regulation of the HPA axis ( reviewed by Nutt &amp;&#xD;
      Malizia, 2004).The major shortcoming of these anatomical studies is their retrospective&#xD;
      nature, precluding the possibility of extracting causality. Thus the question of temporal&#xD;
      sequence remains to be resolved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data reviewed by Etkin et al. (2011) suggest a controlled conscious top-down regulation, like&#xD;
      emotional conflict regulation, uses ventral ACC and mPFC areas to inhibit negative emotional&#xD;
      processing in the amygdala, thus dampening task interference. The ventral ACC and mPFC might&#xD;
      thus perform a generic negative emotion inhibitory function that can be recruited by other&#xD;
      regions (e.g. dorsal ACC and mPFC and lateral PFC) when there is a need to suppress limbic&#xD;
      reactivity. One might speculate that a dysfunction in this circuit might contribute to a PTSD&#xD;
      dysfunction in regulating negative emotional conflict. Unable to regulate and suppress&#xD;
      emotional arousal related to trauma relevant information, the PTSD affected individual might&#xD;
      choose to avoid it all together. The limbic reactivity might contribute to hyper vigilant&#xD;
      responses, and affect memory processes leading to intrusion, as well. In short, dysfunction&#xD;
      in the ventral medial PFC structures and their connections might contribute to all symptom&#xD;
      clusters.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Summary Taken together the described neurophysiological and neuropsychological findings, it&#xD;
      is compelling to further investigate antinational and response inhibition mechanisms in OCD&#xD;
      patients compared to PTSD patients by tapping on performance in cognitive paradigms sensitive&#xD;
      to the activity in medial prefrontal brain structures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study goal This study's main goal is to compare OCD and PTSD which are both considered an&#xD;
      anxiety syndrome by means of the patient's performance and neurophysiologic response while&#xD;
      engaged in an error detection task.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design For the primary goal of the study, we will use a cross section design by comparing&#xD;
      PTSD sample to the OCD sample. Cognitive and electrophysiological data from the clinical&#xD;
      population will be compared to a previously collected healthy student's data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol After an explanation of the required procedure, all subjects will be kindly asked to&#xD;
      sign an informed consent version that can be found on the ethics committee application form.&#xD;
      Depicted in Figure 1, psychiatric and neurocognitive assessments will be taken at the&#xD;
      clinical neurophysiology department at the Beer-Sheva Mental Health Institute and cognitive&#xD;
      tasks while recording electrophysiology data will take place at the Cognitive Neurophysiology&#xD;
      Lab at Ben Gurion University of the Negev.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Figure 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to evaluate the error processing in a domain general perspective, the&#xD;
      electrophysiological research will include three computerized tasks. In all three procedures&#xD;
      the subjects will be asked to perform a task, while a net of electrodes for EEG acquisition&#xD;
      will be placed on their head. During all tasks a number of within task breaks are inserted in&#xD;
      order to reduce the discomfort of the subjects as much as possible. The total procedure,&#xD;
      including all tasks, breaks within and in between tasks, will require approximately 2 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Task description:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The Attention network test (Fan, McCandliss, Sommer, Raz, &amp; Posner, 2002) has been&#xD;
           previously implemented in studying of clinical disorders (Posner &amp; Rothbart, 2007). In&#xD;
           this task subject will be presented with five horizontal arrow stimuli and will be asked&#xD;
           to identify the direction of the centrally presented arrow by pressing a button with the&#xD;
           index finger. The procedure will require approximately 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. In the Stroop with misspelled words task (Mesika &amp; Berger, in preparation) subjects will&#xD;
           be asked to name the color of the word presented, while avoiding its meaning. On some&#xD;
           trials, spelling errors will be inserted in the presented words, while in others no&#xD;
           spelling errors will be present. This procedure will require approximately 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The Arithmetic verification task is a modified version of the task which Tzur and&#xD;
           colleagues have used previously (Tzur, Berger, Luria, &amp; Posner, 2010; Tzur &amp; Berger,&#xD;
           2007). The subjects participating in the task will be presented with either correct&#xD;
           (e.g. 3X6=18) or incorrect (e.g. 3X6=21) arithmetical equations, and will be asked to&#xD;
           decide each trial whether the equation presented is correct or incorrect. This procedure&#xD;
           will require approximately 45 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three weeks after the initial examination, all subjects will be invited to participate in a&#xD;
      follow-up session at the Cognitive Neurophysiology Lab at Ben Gurion University of the Negev&#xD;
      regardless of the treatment they were participating in during this period. At this point all&#xD;
      subjects will be kindly asked to sign a new informed consent so that there will be no&#xD;
      obligatory relationship been participating at the first phase and at follow-up of the&#xD;
      experiment. Also, the subject's treatment between the sessions will be determined by the&#xD;
      patients attending physician without the intervention of the research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be evaluated using several widely used rating scales adminstered by a trained&#xD;
      psychiatrist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neurocognitive assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Raven's Progressive Matrices (Raven, 2000) - a measure of fluid intelligence; a factor&#xD;
           which may be relevant to PTSD development. This will also allow better control for&#xD;
           differences between patients normal population.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. MindStreams®: neurocognitive assessment battery. Regularly used for diagnostic purposes&#xD;
           in the center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All cognitive assignments are computerized and will take place at the Clinical&#xD;
      Neurophysiology department at the Beer-Sheva Mental Health center. The patient will either&#xD;
      read the instructions on the computer monitor or a trained experimenter will read the task&#xD;
      instruction for him.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electrophysiology data acquisition&#xD;
&#xD;
      EEG recordings will take place at both the initiation and at the end of the research&#xD;
      protocol. We will use the EGI Geodesic Sensor net (128 electrodes) and system for data&#xD;
      acquisition (Electrical Geodesics, Oregon, USA). All equipment and materials that will be&#xD;
      used are FDA approved for clinical and research use and are been routinely applied on&#xD;
      patients, children and infants therefore can be considered safe. During all procedures the&#xD;
      use of the equipment will be according to the manufacturer's instructions only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before applying the net, subject's head will be measured in order to determine the&#xD;
      appropriate net size for EEG recording. Afterwards, using a soft and wide edged china marker,&#xD;
      a small mark will be drawn on the scalp to indicate the midpoint of the head. While measuring&#xD;
      the head, the electrode net will be dipped in electrolyte solution, composed of purified&#xD;
      water, salt and baby shampoo. The solution then will be warmed up to body temperature to&#xD;
      minimize the discomfort which could be caused by wetting the subject's head. During net&#xD;
      application procedure no scraping of the scalp is required. Preparation process should take&#xD;
      no more than 20 minutes and will cause no distress to the subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics&#xD;
&#xD;
      Behavioral data will be collected as reaction time (in milliseconds) and accuracy (in&#xD;
      proportion) for each condition for each task, and will be analyzed using analysis of variance&#xD;
      (ANOVA) method for between subject analyses. Within subject analyses will be performed using&#xD;
      the repeated measures ANOVA on the same variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EEG data will be analyzed using the event related potentials (ERP) method, extracting the&#xD;
      amplitude (in microvolt) and latency (in milliseconds) of electrophysiological components. In&#xD;
      the statistical analysis ANOVA and repeated measures ANOVA will be implemented accordingly.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>December 2012</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Yale Brown Obsessive Compulsive Scale (Y-BOCS)</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Montgomery Asberg Depression Rating Scale (MADRAS)</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Clinician rating scale for assessing current and lifetime PTSD (CAPS)</measure>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>PTSD</condition>
  <condition>OCD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EEG acquisition</arm_group_label>
    <description>15 PTSD patients and 15 OCD patients who will, while wearing a net of electrodes for EEG acquisition on their heads, perform three error detection tasks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Previously collected healthy student's data</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients will be recruited from the outpatient clinic of the Beersheva Mental Health&#xD;
        Center. 15 OCT and 15 PTSD patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of PTSD or OCD by DSM-IV criteria;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For OCD subjects a Y-BOCS score larger than 16 composted form both obsession and&#xD;
             compulsion patient's responses;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For PTSD population a CAPS score larger than 40.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Either no medicated patients or a combination of anti-anxiety, anti-depressant and&#xD;
             tranquilizers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with minimum depression symptoms (MDRAS &lt; 18)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A medical history of other major psychiatric disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known ailment of the central nervous system.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of loss of consciousness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of head injury or abnormal head trauma upon routine imaging.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No anti-psychotic or anti-epileptic and tricyclic drugs&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Doron Todder, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beersheva Mental Health Center and Ben Gurion University of the Negev</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Doron Tudor, MD</last_name>
    <phone>972-8-6401401</phone>
    <email>doron.todder@pbsh.health.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>November 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 5, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 7, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 8, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Beersheva Mental Health Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Doron Todder</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PTSD</keyword>
  <keyword>OCD</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

