<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00060736</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>030175</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>03-M-0175</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00060736</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of Estrogen Withdrawal on Mood Symptoms in Women</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of Acute Withdrawal of Estradiol on Mood Symptoms in Women With Perimenopausal Depression</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study evaluates the effects on mood when stopping estrogen replacement therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to investigate the effects of estrogen levels on perimenopausal&#xD;
      depression. This study will examine short-term withdrawal of estrogen in women whose mood had&#xD;
      improved with estrogen therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Perimenopause-related mood disorders cause significant distress in a large number of women.&#xD;
      Evidence suggests that estradiol may have beneficial effects in women with perimenopausal&#xD;
      depression. However, the effect of declining estradiol secretion during perimenopause has not&#xD;
      been fully examined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peri- and post-menopausal women who experience a remission of perimenopause-related&#xD;
      depression symptoms while on estrogen therapy and a control group of healthy volunteers on&#xD;
      hormone replacement therapy (HRT) will be switched from their current form of HRT to&#xD;
      estradiol for a 3-week period; volunteers will also complete symptom ratings to confirm the&#xD;
      absence of mood symptoms. Participants will then be randomly assigned to either continue&#xD;
      estradiol or take a placebo (an inactive pill) for an additional 3 weeks. Mood ratings will&#xD;
      be used to determine response to estradiol withdrawal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Perimenopause-related mood disorders cause significant distress to a large number of women.&#xD;
      Recent studies have reported the therapeutic benefits of estradiol in women with these mood&#xD;
      disorders; however, a relevant pathophysiologic role of declining estradiol secretion during&#xD;
      the perimenopause has not been demonstrated. In this protocol we wish to investigate the&#xD;
      effects of acute withdrawal of estradiol on mood under placebo controlled conditions. Thus,&#xD;
      mood and behavior symptoms may be precipitated by the experimental conditions of this&#xD;
      protocol. This protocol will address the following hypothesis: women with a past history of&#xD;
      perimenopause-related depression but not women without such a history will experience a&#xD;
      recurrence of mood and behavioral symptoms during acute estradiol withdrawal but not during&#xD;
      continued estradiol administration. The nature of the relationship between the declining&#xD;
      secretion of estradiol and mood in perimenopausal depressed women will be examined as&#xD;
      follows: Peri- and postmenopausal women reporting the onset of depression during the&#xD;
      perimenopause and who report remission of depressive symptoms on estrogen therapy (ET) will&#xD;
      be withdrawn from ET under blinded and placebo-controlled conditions. We will recruit as a&#xD;
      comparison group asymptomatic women on hormone replacement and without a history of&#xD;
      perimenopause-related depression. During a three week baseline phase, all women will be&#xD;
      switched from their current form of hormone replacement therapy to estradiol and will&#xD;
      complete symptom ratings to confirm the absence of mood symptoms prior to entry into the&#xD;
      study. After the screening, all women will be randomized to receive either estradiol or&#xD;
      placebo for an additional three weeks. Comparison of mood ratings during these contrasting&#xD;
      treatment conditions will allow us to examine the specific role of estrogen withdrawal in&#xD;
      depression that is responsive to ET.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 5, 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 27, 2016</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Perimenopausal Depression</condition>
  <condition>Post Menopausal</condition>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All subjects for this protocol will be either self-referred in response to newspaper&#xD;
        advertisements or referred by their personal physician. The women participating in this&#xD;
        protocol will have previously completed the screening protocol # 88-M-0131 and, therefore,&#xD;
        will have had the presence or absence of perimenopausal or menopausal reproductive status&#xD;
        evaluated and documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Women with a past perimenopause-related depression (within 12 years) and whose&#xD;
             depression responded to ET will be recruited to participate in this randomized,&#xD;
             parallel-design, double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Women with histories of&#xD;
             either perimenopausal depression that was not responsive to ET or hormone replacement&#xD;
             therapy-induced dysphoria due to either the estrogen or the progesterone components of&#xD;
             their hormone replacement will be excluded. The diagnosis of perimenopause-related&#xD;
             depression will be based on a history of a past depressive episode (major or minor&#xD;
             depression confirmed by Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV (SCID) or Schedule of&#xD;
             Affective Disorders and Schizophrenia-Lifetime Version (SADS-L), respectively) at&#xD;
             midlife in association with menstrual cycle irregularity and the history of remission&#xD;
             (also confirmed by SCID or SADS-L) of this depression after ET. Additionally, all&#xD;
             women will report that they were placed on HRT for the treatment of perimenopausal&#xD;
             symptoms, including depression.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Age 45 to 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. In good medical health&#xD;
&#xD;
        &lt;TAB&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Women without past perimenopausal depression -&#xD;
&#xD;
        To control for the effects of the hormonal manipulations in this protocol, we will also&#xD;
        recruit a group of asymptomatic controls who are either currently on ET or were prescribed&#xD;
        ET previously and with no previous history of perimenopause-related depression or&#xD;
        HRT-induced dysphoria. Women who participate in this study as the asymptomatic comparison&#xD;
        group will meet the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Women who received hormone therapy (HT) with no previous history of&#xD;
             perimenopause-related depression or HT-induced dysphoria&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No current mood or behavioral problems&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age 45 to 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. In good medical health&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. past history of severe major depression with suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. current treatment with antidepressant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. history of ischemic cardiac disease, pulmonary embolism, or thrombophlebitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. renal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. hepatic dysfunction&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. women with a history of carcinoma of the breast&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. women with a history of uterine cancer, ill-defined pelvic lesions, particularly&#xD;
             undiagnosed ovarian enlargement, undiagnosed vaginal bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. cerebrovascular disease (stroke)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. recurrent migraine headaches&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter J Schmidt, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rossouw JE, Anderson GL, Prentice RL, LaCroix AZ, Kooperberg C, Stefanick ML, Jackson RD, Beresford SA, Howard BV, Johnson KC, Kotchen JM, Ockene J; Writing Group for the Women's Health Initiative Investigators. Risks and benefits of estrogen plus progestin in healthy postmenopausal women: principal results From the Women's Health Initiative randomized controlled trial. JAMA. 2002 Jul 17;288(3):321-33.</citation>
    <PMID>12117397</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Serin IS, Ozçelik B, Başbuğ M, Aygen E, Kula M, Erez R. Long-term effects of continuous oral and transdermal estrogen replacement therapy on sex hormone binding globulin and free testosterone levels. Eur J Obstet Gynecol Reprod Biol. 2001 Dec 1;99(2):222-5.</citation>
    <PMID>11788176</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schmidt PJ, Nieman L, Danaceau MA, Tobin MB, Roca CA, Murphy JH, Rubinow DR. Estrogen replacement in perimenopause-related depression: a preliminary report. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2000 Aug;183(2):414-20.</citation>
    <PMID>10942479</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 27, 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 9, 2003</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 9, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 12, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 13, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 13, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 16, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hormone Replacement</keyword>
  <keyword>Gonadal Steroids</keyword>
  <keyword>Estrogen</keyword>
  <keyword>Major Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Minor Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Perimenopause</keyword>
  <keyword>Estradiol</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Perimenopausal Depression</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

