<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00067392</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NIDCR-14185</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01DE014185</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00067392</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Implants Placed Immediately or Delayed Into Extraction Sites</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prospective Evaluation of Immediate Temporized Implants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center in New Orleans</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research (NIDCR)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Implant Innovations</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Louisiana State University Health Sciences Center in New Orleans</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine the difference in success when placing implants&#xD;
      immediately into an extraction site compared to delaying the implant placement until the&#xD;
      extraction site has healed. In addition, the level of bone around the implants will be&#xD;
      compared to determine if one method leads to better results over time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This revised application is a clinical trial designed to evaluate crestal bone level changes&#xD;
      when implants are placed into extraction sites and immediately provisionalized. Extraction of&#xD;
      maxillary incisor teeth is a common procedure as documented in our school clinics.&#xD;
      Traditional treatment when a tooth is extracted includes a period of healing followed by&#xD;
      placement of an implant. Our preliminary data indicates that the delayed approach results in&#xD;
      labial bone loss with resultant horizontal deficiency in over 50% of cases, requiring hard&#xD;
      and soft tissue grafting to achieve a functional result. Additional preliminary data&#xD;
      indicates that grafting the extraction site and/or immediate implant placement and&#xD;
      provisionalization results in a functional restoration, without the need for additional&#xD;
      adjunctive grafting procedures. It is unclear how the crestal bone levels change during&#xD;
      healing of the extraction site prior to implant placement, in contrast to immediate implant&#xD;
      placement, with immediate provisionalization with a crown. We hypothesize that there will be&#xD;
      differences in the crestal bone levels (primary endpoint), and differences in soft tissue&#xD;
      levels and indices (secondary endpoints) between implants immediately temporized, placed&#xD;
      either delayed or immediately after tooth extraction, with more bone loss in the immediate&#xD;
      placement group (experimental) compared to the delayed placement group (control). The&#xD;
      long-term goal is to determine if the crestal bone remodeling after tooth extraction or the&#xD;
      apical position of the implant determines the final level of the crestal bone. Two groups of&#xD;
      45 patients will be evaluated. All subjects will have a single rooted maxillary tooth&#xD;
      extracted. One group will have the socket grafted with mineralized bone and allowed four&#xD;
      months prior to implant placement. The crestal bone in this group will have remodeled during&#xD;
      the four months of healing prior to implant placement. The second group will have the implant&#xD;
      placed immediately after tooth extraction, thus the crestal bone will remodel in the presence&#xD;
      of the implant and the immediately placed temporary restoration, as a one-stage procedure.&#xD;
      For both groups, the implants will be immediately temporized with a crown after implant&#xD;
      placement. Standardized hard and soft tissue data will be collected pre-extraction as&#xD;
      baseline, and then prospectively for at least two years in this trial, to compare the methods&#xD;
      and contrast the effectiveness of the proposed immediate restoration therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>November 2003</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Crestal bone levels adjacent to the implants</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Position of the papillary complex and facial gingival margin, and indicator of the inflammatory state of the perimplant tissues.</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Caries</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dental Implant</intervention_name>
    <description>Dental Implant 4 month time frame</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients will be willing to be present for examination two times a year for at&#xD;
             least three years, as well as maintenance cleanings twice a year 3 months prior to the&#xD;
             data collection visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients will be free of uncontrolled diabetes (any type), existing malignancy,&#xD;
             and will not be receiving any therapy that suppresses their immune system, such as&#xD;
             radiation, chemotherapy, or chronic steroid usage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Need for extraction of a single rooted maxillary central or lateral incisor, canine,&#xD;
             or premolar, with no signs of acute infection (purulent exudate, erythema, pain, and&#xD;
             swelling).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will have bone present on all surfaces of the tooth within 3 mm of the&#xD;
             gingival margin of the planned restoration, in order to provide sufficient bone to&#xD;
             circumferentially cover the implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients will have adequate space for satisfactory restoration of the edentulous&#xD;
             space.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Each patient's dentition will be free of active periodontal disease or exhibit&#xD;
             controllable periodontal disease such that their teeth will clinically be non-mobile&#xD;
             and have probing depths less than 3 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All prospective sites will have at least 2mm of attached or keratinized gingiva.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The crestal bone width should be enough to accommodate either a 3.75 diameter implant&#xD;
             for the central incisor, canine, and premolar sites, or a 3.25 mm diameter implant for&#xD;
             the lateral incisor tooth sites. Bone height should be at least 14 mm for&#xD;
             accommodation of the implant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with labial dehiscence defects greater than 3 mm from the proposed gingival&#xD;
             margin of the planned restoration will be excluded from this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who cannot come for follow up due to conflicts of schedules will not be&#xD;
             accepted into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with advanced cardiovascular, pulmonary, renal, liver disease that place them&#xD;
             in an ASA III or IV rating will be excluded. Post-menopausal women with known&#xD;
             osteoporosis as determined by their medical internist, will be excluded. Patients with&#xD;
             known alcohol abuse will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael S Block, DMD, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>LSU School of Dentistry</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>LSU School of Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Orleans</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70119</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2008</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 15, 2003</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 19, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 20, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 8, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 8, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 9, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Michael S Block</name_title>
    <organization>LSU School of Dentistry</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Partial edentulism</keyword>
  <keyword>Bone atrophy</keyword>
  <keyword>Bone healing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

