<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00067821</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>030278</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>03-C-0278</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00067821</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT00070512</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of PET and Proton MRS Imaging to Evaluate Pediatric Brain Tumor Activity</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Comparative Study of Pediatric CNS Tumor Activity as Assessed by [18]F-FDG PET Imaging and Proton Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopic Imaging ([1]H-MRSI)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study in children and young adults will compare two types of imaging, positron emission&#xD;
      tomography ([(18)F]-DG PET) and proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy ((1)H-MRSI), to&#xD;
      determine activity of a brain tumor or abnormal tissue in the brain following treatment for a&#xD;
      brain tumor. Children with brain tumors are generally followed with magnetic resonance&#xD;
      imaging (MRI) scans to evaluate response to treatment. However, because MRI only provides&#xD;
      information on the structure of the brain, it may difficult to tell if an abnormal finding is&#xD;
      due to tumor, swelling, scar tissue, or dead tissue. (1)H-MRSI and [(18)F]-DG PET, on the&#xD;
      other hand, provide information on the metabolic activity of brain lesions. These two methods&#xD;
      will be compared and evaluated for their ability to provide important additional information&#xD;
      on childhood brain tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients between 1 and 21 years of age with a brain tumor or brain tissue abnormality&#xD;
      following treatment for a brain tumor may be eligible for this study. Candidates will be&#xD;
      screened with a medical history and physical examination, pregnancy test in women who are&#xD;
      able to become pregnant, and a blood test for glucose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will undergo the following procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (1)H-MRSI - This test is similar to MRI and is done in the same scanning machine. In MRI,&#xD;
      scans of the brain are obtained by applying a strong magnetic field and then collecting the&#xD;
      signals released from water after the magnetic field is changed. Pictures of the brain are&#xD;
      then obtained by computer analysis of these signals. In (1)H-MRSI, the computer blocks the&#xD;
      signal from water to get information on brain chemicals that can indicate whether an&#xD;
      abnormality is tumor or dead tissue. Both MRI and MRI and (1)H-MRSI are done in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For these tests, the child lies on a stretcher that moves into the scanner - a narrow metal&#xD;
      cylinder with a strong magnetic field. The child's head is placed in a headrest to prevent&#xD;
      movement during the scan. He or she will hear loud thumping noises caused by the electrical&#xD;
      switching of the magnetic field. A contrast agent is given through an intravenous (IV)&#xD;
      catheter (plastic tube placed in an arm vein) or through a central line if one is in place.&#xD;
      The contrast material brightens the images to provide a clearer picture of abnormalities.&#xD;
      Children who have difficulty holding still or being in a scanning machine are given&#xD;
      medications by an anesthesiologist to make them sleep through the procedure. Children who are&#xD;
      awake during the procedure can communicate with the MRI technician at all times and ask to be&#xD;
      removed from the scanner at any time. The MRI and (1)H-MRSI take 1-1/2 to 2 hours to&#xD;
      complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      [(18)F]-DG PET - For this test, [(18)F]-DG (a radioactive form of glucose) is injected into&#xD;
      the patient's arm vein through a catheter, followed by the PET scan, similar to a very open&#xD;
      MRI scan without the noise. The PET scan tells how active the patient's tumor is by tracking&#xD;
      the radioactive glucose. All cells use glucose, but cells with increased metabolism, such as&#xD;
      cancer cells, use more glucose than normal cells. After the glucose injection, the patient&#xD;
      lies quietly in a darkened room for 30 minutes, after which he or she is asked to urinate to&#xD;
      help reduce the dose of radiation to the bladder. Then, the scan begins. When the scan is&#xD;
      finished (after about 1 hour), the child is asked to urinate again and then every 3 to 4&#xD;
      hours for the rest of the day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients remain in the study for 2 years unless they withdraw, become pregnant, or require&#xD;
      sedation but can no longer use an anesthetic. MRI and 1H-MRSI scans may be repeated every few&#xD;
      months during the study period, if necessary. Only one PET scan is done each year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Children with brain tumors are generally followed for response or progression by imaging&#xD;
           studies, such as CT or MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  While these imaging studies help delineate the anatomical location and extent of a tumor&#xD;
           within the CNS, they give no information regarding the biologic or metabolic activity of&#xD;
           the lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Proton Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopic Imaging ((1)H-MRSI) is a non-invasive&#xD;
           method of detecting and measuring cellular metabolites in vivo, providing biochemical&#xD;
           information in conjunction with the spatial information obtained by MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Positron Emission Tomography (PET) is a technique that also provides data on metabolic&#xD;
           activity of brain lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A comparison of these two methods in determining a lesion s metabolic activity has not&#xD;
           been reported in children with brain tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -To compare (1)H-MRSI and [(18)F-]-FDG PET scanning percentage (%) of agreement between&#xD;
      supratentorial and infratentorial tumors, and between brainstem and cerebellum intratentorial&#xD;
      tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age: greater than or equal to 1 year and less than to 21 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients must have a brain tumor that is measurable or evaluable on standard MRI or CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients referred for this study will have both (1)H-MRSI and (18)F-FDG PET imaging&#xD;
           performed within 2 weeks of each other at the NCI&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients will remain on study for 5 years or until one of the off-study criteria have&#xD;
           been met (whichever occurs first)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 11, 2014</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison</measure>
    <time_frame>One scan each/year X 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>compare results from Proton Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopic Imaging (1HMRSI) and [18F]-FDG Positron Emission Tomography (PET) in brain tumors</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison</measure>
    <time_frame>One scan each/year X 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>correlate results of compare results from Proton Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopic Imaging (1H-MRSI) and [18F]- FDG Positron EmissionTomography (PET) with MRI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate change</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate changes over time in brain tumors</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">79</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Must have a brain tumor, or residual abnormality that is measurable or evaluable on standard MRI or CT</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients must have a brain tumor (including, but not limited to high grade gliomas,&#xD;
        low-grade gliomas, primitive neuroectodermal tumors, ependymomas) or residual abnormality&#xD;
        (e.g. post-operatively or postradiation) that is measurable or evaluable on standard MRI or&#xD;
        CT&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Age: greater than or equal to 1 years and less than or equal to 21 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Radiographic diagnosis: Patients must have a brain tumor (including, but not&#xD;
                  limited to high grade gliomas, low-grade gliomas, primitive neuroectodermal&#xD;
                  tumors, ependymomas) or residual abnormality (e.g. post-operatively or&#xD;
                  post-radiation) that is measurable or evaluable on standard MRI or CT.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. All patients or their legal guardians (if the patient is less than 18 years of&#xD;
                  age) must sign a document of informed consent indicating their awareness of the&#xD;
                  investigational nature and the risks of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Prior treatment: Patients will be eligible regardless of prior treatment.&#xD;
                  Therefore, patients who are newly diagnosed, post-operative, post-radiation or&#xD;
                  post-chemotherapy are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients under age 18 years who weigh greater than 70 kg are excluded because they&#xD;
             would exceed the standard allowable dosimetry for pediatric patients (i.e. Effective&#xD;
             Dose greater than 0.5 REM/year). In addition, patients who weigh greater than 136 kg&#xD;
             are excluded, as this is the maximum weight allowable on PET scanner tables.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any patient who is unable (either because of physical or psychological factors) to&#xD;
             undergo imaging studies without sedation but is not considered an anesthesia&#xD;
             candidate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any patient with a metallic MRI incompatible implant, including cardiac pacemakers,&#xD;
             neural pacemakers, aneurysmal clips, shrapnel, cochlear implants or ferrous surgical&#xD;
             clips.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any patient with a history of a severe reaction (CTC v.4 Grade greater than or equal&#xD;
             to 2) to Gadolinium or other contrast agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any patient with Diabetes mellitus or steroid-induced hyperglycemia (fasting glucose&#xD;
             greater than 150) because this may interfere with the interpretation of the&#xD;
             [(18)F]-FDG PET scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any patient with permanent braces, permanent retainers or nonferrous implant that, in&#xD;
             the judgment of the Principal Investigator, would interfere with obtaining&#xD;
             spectroscopy in the area of the tumor.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John W Glod, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2003-C-0278.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 13, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2003</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2003</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 28, 2003</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brain Tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Children</keyword>
  <keyword>Metabolic</keyword>
  <keyword>Spectroscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>PET</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

