<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01934634</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12104</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>CLCL161AUS03T</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01934634</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase I Trial of LCL161 and Gemcitabine Plus Nab-Paclitaxel in Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Trial of the Proapoptotic Agonist, LCL161, and Gemcitabine Plus Nab-Paclitaxel in Patients With Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>US Oncology Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Delta Clinical Research, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>US Oncology Research</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to identify the maximum tolerated dose and dose-limiting side&#xD;
      effects of LCL161 in combination with gemcitabine and nab-paclitaxel and to provide safety&#xD;
      data in patients with measurable metastatic pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Improved therapeutic options for advanced pancreatic adenocarcinoma treatment need to&#xD;
      continue to be investigated. Since 1997, gemcitabine has been the agent of choice for&#xD;
      first-line therapy in advanced pancreatic cancer, with a median survival of 5.7 months, and a&#xD;
      20% 1-year survival (Eli Lilly 1996). Combination therapies using gemcitabine as a backbone&#xD;
      have been investigated, but none are superior to gemcitabine monotherapy, except for a modest&#xD;
      increase in overall survival (OS) with erlotinib and gemcitabine (Moore et al 2007). In a&#xD;
      study of FOLFIRINOX compared with gemcitabine as first-line therapy in 342 metastatic&#xD;
      pancreatic cancer patients, median OS was 11.1 months in the FOLFIRINOX group and 6.8 months&#xD;
      in the gemcitabine group; however, the FOLFIRINOX group experienced more adverse events&#xD;
      particularly febrile neutropenia (Conroy et al 2011).&#xD;
&#xD;
      LCL161 is a biostable, cell-permeable, small molecular weight Smac-mimetic compound. It is an&#xD;
      orally bioavailable pan-IAP inhibitor that demonstrates anti-tumor efficacy as a single agent&#xD;
      in a small subset of cell lines, and in many more cell lines and xenograft models when given&#xD;
      in combination with paclitaxel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nanoparticle albumin-bound paclitaxel (nab-paclitaxel) is a formulation that is readily&#xD;
      soluble in saline, eliminating the need for lipid-based solvents (ie, Cremophor EL) and&#xD;
      corticosteroid and antihistamine premedications for hypersensitivity reactions required for&#xD;
      traditional unbound paclitaxel. nab-paclitaxel has also been shown to actively bind to&#xD;
      secreted protein acidic and rich in cysteine (SPARC) in the tumor stroma, which is highly&#xD;
      expressed in pancreatic cancer and actively binds to the albumin in nab-paclitaxel and&#xD;
      further concentrates the drug into the tumor. SPARC expression in the stroma of tumor cells&#xD;
      has been associated with poor survival. In a Phase I/II trial (Von Hoff et al 2011) involving&#xD;
      67 patients with metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma, the regimen of nab-paclitaxel plus&#xD;
      gemcitabine had tolerable adverse effects with substantial antitumor activity, warranting&#xD;
      Phase III evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Phase III study (MPACT) was a large, international study that determined that survival&#xD;
      with nab-paclitaxel plus gemcitabine is superior to gemcitabine alone. nab-paclitaxel plus&#xD;
      gemcitabine is a new standard for treatment of patients with metastatic pancreatic cancer&#xD;
      (Von Hoff et al 2013). However, although this study shows promise for substantially improving&#xD;
      OS in patients with pancreatic adenocarcinoma, insensitivity to these agents is likely to&#xD;
      occur due to resistance to apoptosis, which has been observed in laboratory studies to occur&#xD;
      for most of the cytotoxic agents used to treat pancreatic cancer in the past (Westphal and&#xD;
      Kaltoff 2003). Exploitation of the apoptosis pathway may ultimately provide more effective,&#xD;
      less toxic anticancer therapy that selectively circumvents treatment-resistant pathways.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on the above, there is a high likelihood that LCL161 in combination with nab-paclitaxel&#xD;
      and gemcitabine will be determined to be safe and well tolerated, and will show substantial&#xD;
      antitumor activity, warranting Phase II evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 24 patients will be enrolled in Part A - Phase I Safety study. If the combination&#xD;
      therapy is determined to be safe and well tolerated and shows substantial antitumor activity,&#xD;
      a safety expansion cohort of 12 additional patients will be enrolled in Part B - Efficacy&#xD;
      study to further confirm the tolerability and efficacy of LCL161 with an endpoint of complete&#xD;
      response (CR).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>March 2014</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose of LCL161</measure>
    <time_frame>1.6 years</time_frame>
    <description>The maximum dose of LCL161 (tablets: 600, 1200, or 1800 mg once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days) that is tolerated by the patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients with Dose-Limiting Toxicities</measure>
    <time_frame>1.6 years</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of patients that have side effects that require dosage of LCL161 to be stopped or reduced.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1.6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with Complete Response or Partial Response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161 +Gemcitabine +nab-Paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>LCL161 (tablets): 600, 1200, or 1800 mg once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days Gemcitabine IV: 1,000 mg/m2 once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days nab-paclitaxel IV: 100 or 125 mg/m2 once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LCL161</intervention_name>
    <description>LCL161 (tablets): 300, 600, 1200, or 1800 mg once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161 +Gemcitabine +nab-Paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gemcitabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Gemcitabine IV: 1,000 mg/m2 once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161 +Gemcitabine +nab-Paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Gemzar</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>nab-Paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>nab-paclitaxel IV: 125 mg/m2 once a week (Day 1, 8, 15) for 3 weeks, every 28 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>LCL161 +Gemcitabine +nab-Paclitaxel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Abraxane</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients must provide written informed consent prior to any screening procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A signed Patient Authorization Form (HIPPA) has been obtained prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan and laboratory tests&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient is able to swallow and retain oral medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Histologically or cytologically documented measureable metastatic (Stage IV)&#xD;
             pancreatic cancer with disease by computed tomography scan as defined by RECIST&#xD;
             Version 1.1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ECOG performance status 0-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Required baseline laboratory status:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin (Hgb) ≥ 90 g/L (9 g/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x 109/L (100,000/mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥ 1.5 x 109/L (1500/mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x ULN (upper limit of normal)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN, except for patients with tumor involvement&#xD;
                  of the liver who must have AST and ALT ≤ 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN or 24-hour creatinine clearance ≥ 40 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient did not receive previous treatment for Stage IV pancreatic cancer. Note:&#xD;
             However, prior adjuvant treatment with fluorouracil or gemcitabine administered as a&#xD;
             radiation sensitizer during and up to 4 weeks after radiation therapy is allowed. If&#xD;
             patient received adjuvant therapy, tumor recurrence must have occurred ≥ 6 months&#xD;
             after the last treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient has any concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions that could&#xD;
             increase the patient's risk for toxicity while on the study or that could confound&#xD;
             discrimination between disease- and study treatment-related toxicities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient has impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac diseases,&#xD;
             including any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History or presence of ventricular tachyarrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of unstable atrial fibrillation (ventricular response &gt; 100 bpm);&#xD;
                  Patients with stable atrial fibrillation are eligible, provided they do not meet&#xD;
                  any of the other cardiac exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient is currently receiving chronic (&gt; 14 days) treatment with corticosteroids at a&#xD;
             dose ≥ 10 mg of prednisone (or its glucocorticoid equivalent) per day, or any other&#xD;
             chronic immunosuppressive treatment that cannot be discontinued prior to starting&#xD;
             study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient is currently receiving treatment with agents that are metabolized solely&#xD;
             through CYP3A4/5 and have a narrow therapeutic index or are strong CYP2C8 inhibitors;&#xD;
             or are receiving treatment with agents that carry a risk for QT prolongation and are&#xD;
             CYP3A substrates. Caution should be used in patients taking other CYP2C8- or&#xD;
             CYP3A4/5-interacting agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient has impairment of Gastrointestinal (GI) function or GI disease that may&#xD;
             significantly alter the absorption of LCL161.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient is a pregnant or breast feeding (lactating) woman, where pregnancy is defined&#xD;
             as the state of a female after conception and until the termination of gestation,&#xD;
             confirmed by a positive β-HCG laboratory test (&gt; 5 mIU/mL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient is a woman of child-bearing potential, defined as all women physiologically&#xD;
             capable of becoming pregnant and refusing to use highly effective methods of&#xD;
             contraception during dosing and for 90 days after study treatment. Highly effective&#xD;
             contraception methods include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total abstinence or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Male partner or female sterilization or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Combination of any 2 of the following (a+b or a+c, or b+c):&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Use of oral, injected, or implanted hormonal methods of contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Placement of an intrauterine device (IUD) or intrauterine system (IUS)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Barrier methods of contraception: condom for male partner or occlusive cap&#xD;
                       (diaphragm or cervical/vault caps) with spermicidal form/gel/film/cream/&#xD;
                       vaginal suppository.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Note: Postmenopausal women are allowed to participate in this study. Women are&#xD;
             considered postmenopausal and not of child bearing potential if they have had 12&#xD;
             months of natural (spontaneous) amenorrhea with an appropriate clinical profile (eg,&#xD;
             age appropriate, history of vasomotor symptoms) or have had surgical bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy (with or without hysterectomy) or tubal ligation at least 6 weeks&#xD;
             earlier. In the case of oophorectomy alone, a woman is considered to be not of child&#xD;
             bearing potential only when her reproductive status has been confirmed by follow-up&#xD;
             hormone level assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient is abstaining from using a condom. Sexually active males must use a condom&#xD;
             during intercourse while taking the drug and for 3 months after stopping study drug&#xD;
             and should not father a child in this period. A condom is required to be used also by&#xD;
             vasectomized men in order to prevent delivery of the drug via seminal fluid.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient has a history of lymphoma with or without treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient has a history of interstitial pneumonitis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yvonne M. Coyle, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>US Oncology Research, McKesson Specialty Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos H. Becerra, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>US Oncology Research, McKesson Specialty Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>2 Sites</name>
      <address>
        <city>incl Tyler, TX and Dallas, TX</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 29, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 29, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 4, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 10, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Stage IV Pancreatic Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Stage IV metastatic pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

