<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01930539</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>395-13-FB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01930539</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Vitamin D Deficiency in Intestinal Rehabilitation Clinic Patients With a Portable Ultraviolet B Lamp</brief_title>
  <official_title>Treatment of Vitamin D Deficiency in Intestinal Rehabilitation Clinic Patients With a Portable Ultraviolet B Lamp</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Nebraska</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Nebraska</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, controlled, unblinded pilot study for patients with vitamin D&#xD;
      deficiency in Intestinal Rehabilitation clinic. These patients are not able to absorb oral&#xD;
      vitamin D efficiently and thus have a high prevalence of vitamin D deficiency, leading to low&#xD;
      bone density.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will use FDA approved portable Ultraviolet B lamp for the intervention&#xD;
      group, 70 patients will be recruited from October 2013 to end of January 2014 and study&#xD;
      period is 12 weeks for each patient. Study completion will be end of April 2014.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study hypothesis: Ultraviolet B light with a portable UV device will increase Total 25&#xD;
      hydroxy vitamin D level in Intestinal Rehabilitation Clinic patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Vitamin D plays an integral role in bone metabolism and is one of the principal hormonal&#xD;
      regulators of calcium and phosphorus absorption in the body. In 2011, the Endocrine Society&#xD;
      defined Vitamin D deficiency as a 25 hydroxy vitamin D below 20 ng/ml and vitamin D&#xD;
      insufficiency as a 25 hydroxy vitamin D of 21 ng/ml to 29 ng/ml.Without vitamin D, only 10 to&#xD;
      15% of dietary calcium and about 60% of phosphorus is absorbed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intestinal Rehabilitation clinic at University of Nebraska Medical Center includes patients&#xD;
      with short bowel syndrome, multiple abdominal fistulae, and altered GI motility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypovitaminosis D is associated with increased parathyroid hormone secretion,increased bone&#xD;
      turnover, osteoporosis, histological osteomalacia and increased risk of hip and other&#xD;
      fractures, and, in its most severe expression,clinical osteomalacia. These patients have been&#xD;
      given high doses of both oral vitamin D2 and vitamin D3 supplementation without an&#xD;
      improvement in vitamin D status due to poor intestinal absorption . Standardized treatment of&#xD;
      vitamin D deficiency in most healthy individuals is achieved by giving vitamin D2 50,000 IU&#xD;
      once a week for few weeks and then daily supplementation with lower doses. In the&#xD;
      investigators Intestinal rehabilitation clinic, these patients are vitamin D insufficient or&#xD;
      deficient while on large replacement doses of vitamin D2/D3 with some taking 200,000 IU&#xD;
      daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It has been reported that irradiation with Ultraviolet B can be used safely and effectively&#xD;
      to treat vitamin D deficiency among vitamin D deficient patients. Exposure of the body in a&#xD;
      bathing suit to 1 Minimum Erythemal Dose (MED) of sunlight is equivalent to ingesting about&#xD;
      10,000 IU to 25,000 IU of vitamin D. Thus, exposure of 6% to 10% of the body surface to 1 MED&#xD;
      is equivalent to ingesting about 600 to 2500 IU of vitamin D. Although ultraviolet&#xD;
      irradiation can be achieved from exposure to sunlight, it is generally available only&#xD;
      seasonally and difficult for persons who are too ill to spend much time outdoors.&#xD;
      Ultraviolet-Fluorescent lamp (KBD, Inc, Crescent Springs, Kentucky,USA) was designed to use&#xD;
      ultraviolet B emitting fluorescent bulbs that have lower heat emission and allows a larger&#xD;
      area of skin exposure. The Lamp is equipped with a timer for improved safety. This device is&#xD;
      FDA (Food and Drug Administration) approved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline labs include 25 hydroxy D, intact parathyroid hormone and complete metabolic&#xD;
      profile. Patients will receive a 3 minute skin exposure to Ultraviolet B light and if they do&#xD;
      not develop a sun burn, they will be randomized to Control or Ultraviolet B light group.&#xD;
      Patients will continue their current dose of Vitamin D2/D3 for 12 weeks in both&#xD;
      groups.Ultraviolet B light will be administered in 3 different areas on the same day for 5&#xD;
      minutes each, once a week at a distance of 14 inches wearing an UV eye shield. Areas of skin&#xD;
      exposure will be based on rule of nine for body surface area which includes back, abdomen,&#xD;
      thighs, and arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will get blood draws every 4 weeks to monitor response to Ultraviolet B light. If&#xD;
      Ultraviolet B light is able to increase total 25 hydroxy vitamin D level, it can potentially&#xD;
      be used at home by these patients after receiving basic training and instructions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Serum levels of 25 hydroxy vitamin D level from baseline to 12 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Our hypothesis is that Ultraviolet B light with a portable Ultraviolet device will increase Total 25 hydroxy vitamin D level in Intestinal Rehabilitation Clinic patients.&#xD;
We will measure serum level of 25 hydroxy D at baseline and every 4 weeks until 12th week to monitor the response of Ultraviolet B exposure administered by the portable Ultraviolet B lamp.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Serum Intact Parathyroid hormone level from baseline to 12 weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Hypovitaminosis D is associated with increased Parathyroid hormone secretion (inversely related to 25 hydroxy D),increased bone turnover, osteoporosis, histological osteomalacia and increased risk of hip and other fractures, and, in its most severe expression,clinical osteomalacia.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Vitamin D Deficiency</condition>
  <condition>Short Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ultraviolet B lamp</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention arm: Patients in the Ultraviolet B lamp group will continue vitamin D2/D3 daily and will receive 3 treatment sessions of Ultraviolet B light once a week for 12 weeks. Patients will receive Ultraviolet B light from Ultraviolet B lamp at a distance of 14 inches for duration of 5 minutes each area while wearing an Ultraviolet eye shield. Areas of skin exposure will include 3 different areas amounting to 27% of body surface area. 9% body surface area will include front of abdomen, lower back, each arm, each leg is 18%, each thigh. Ultraviolet B light sessions will be supervised and conducted by study personnel or Center for Clinical and Translational Research staff. A food questionnaire will be reviewed at each visit to assess dietary intake of calcium. Skin exam will be conducted at the beginning and end of the session.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in control group will continue with their current dose of Vitamin D2/D3 for 12 weeks.Patients will remain on the same steady dose for the duration of the study.These patients will not receive Ultraviolet B light sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ultraviolet B lamp</intervention_name>
    <description>Ultraviolet-Fluorescent lamp (KBD, Inc, Crescent Springs, Kentucky, USA) was designed to use Ultraviolet B emitting fluorescent bulbs that have lower heat emission and allows a larger area of skin exposure. The Lamp is equipped with a timer for improved safety. This device is FDA (Food and Drug Administration) approved.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ultraviolet B lamp</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sperti sunlamp &quot;Del Sol&quot;; Sperti, Crescent Springs, Kentucky</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  25-hydroxy vitamin D level between 15ng/ml to 30mg/ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 19 years and above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on a stable dose of vitamin D2/D3 for last 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypercalcemia (Serum Calcium (calculated) more than 1 mg/dl above the upper limit of&#xD;
             normal i.e 11.3 mg/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic Hypocalcemia (described as tetany )&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Sarcoidosis or Granulomatous diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on Calcitriol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver failure defined as bilirubin more than 3, International Normalized Ratio of more&#xD;
             than 3, Hepatic Transaminases 3 times of upper limit of normal, Decompensated&#xD;
             cirrhosis with signs or icterus, varices, portal hypertension, encephalopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of transplant or undergoing transplant evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned or Elective surgery in 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Personal or Family history of skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of photosensitivity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active skin disease in the areas planned for Ultraviolet B exposure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medications that limit sunlight exposure (such as tetracyclines or fluoroquinolones)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients already undergoing tanning sessions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are planning pregnancy or are breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with fair skin type I (Always burns easily, never tans)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lynn Mack, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Nebraska Medical Center, Omaha</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nebraska Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omaha</city>
        <state>Nebraska</state>
        <zip>68198</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.sperti.com</url>
    <description>Portable Ultraviolet B lamp</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holick MF, Binkley NC, Bischoff-Ferrari HA, Gordon CM, Hanley DA, Heaney RP, Murad MH, Weaver CM; Endocrine Society. Evaluation, treatment, and prevention of vitamin D deficiency: an Endocrine Society clinical practice guideline. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Jul;96(7):1911-30. doi: 10.1210/jc.2011-0385. Epub 2011 Jun 6. Erratum in: J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2011 Dec;96(12):3908.</citation>
    <PMID>21646368</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Holick MF. Vitamin D deficiency. N Engl J Med. 2007 Jul 19;357(3):266-81. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17634462</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosen CJ. Clinical practice. Vitamin D insufficiency. N Engl J Med. 2011 Jan 20;364(3):248-54. doi: 10.1056/NEJMcp1009570. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21247315</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DiBaise JK, Young RJ, Vanderhoof JA. Intestinal rehabilitation and the short bowel syndrome: part 1. Am J Gastroenterol. 2004 Jul;99(7):1386-95. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15233682</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DiBaise JK, Young RJ, Vanderhoof JA. Intestinal rehabilitation and the short bowel syndrome: part 2. Am J Gastroenterol. 2004 Sep;99(9):1823-32. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15330926</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Armas LA, Dowell S, Akhter M, Duthuluru S, Huerter C, Hollis BW, Lund R, Heaney RP. Ultraviolet-B radiation increases serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D levels: the effect of UVB dose and skin color. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2007 Oct;57(4):588-93. Epub 2007 Jul 16.</citation>
    <PMID>17637484</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dabai NS, Pramyothin P, Holick MF. The effect of ultraviolet radiation from a novel portable fluorescent lamp on serum 25-hydroxyvitamin D3 levels in healthy adults with Fitzpatrick skin types II and III. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2012 Dec;28(6):307-11. doi: 10.1111/phpp.12000.</citation>
    <PMID>23126292</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chandra P, Wolfenden LL, Ziegler TR, Tian J, Luo M, Stecenko AA, Chen TC, Holick MF, Tangpricha V. Treatment of vitamin D deficiency with UV light in patients with malabsorption syndromes: a case series. Photodermatol Photoimmunol Photomed. 2007 Oct;23(5):179-85.</citation>
    <PMID>17803596</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Khazai NB, Judd SE, Jeng L, Wolfenden LL, Stecenko A, Ziegler TR, Tangpricha V. Treatment and prevention of vitamin D insufficiency in cystic fibrosis patients: comparative efficacy of ergocalciferol, cholecalciferol, and UV light. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2009 Jun;94(6):2037-43. doi: 10.1210/jc.2008-2012. Epub 2009 Mar 31.</citation>
    <PMID>19336509</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 29, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 25, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 25, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Nebraska</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lynn Mack, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Short Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamin D Deficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

