<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00580710</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0108012609</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2R01DK020495-37</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00580710</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigation Into the Effects Upon Brain Response to Change in Circulating Glucose Levels in Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
  <official_title>Investigation Into the Effects Upon Brain Response to Change in Circulating Glucose Levels in Diabetes Mellitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to investigate the effects of diabetes mellitus and its treatment upon&#xD;
      the body's responses to low blood glucose (blood sugar) levels. Diabetes is a medical&#xD;
      condition in which blood glucose can rise very high. Treatment of diabetes mellitus involves&#xD;
      giving insulin (a hormone), which can occasionally cause blood glucose to fall too low. The&#xD;
      body responds to low glucose levels by producing a number of hormones, which act against the&#xD;
      insulin to help correct the low blood glucose. These hormones also provide symptoms which&#xD;
      warn that the glucose is falling too far. These protective warnings by the body may be&#xD;
      different in people with diabetes. We want to test whether this also means that diabetes&#xD;
      changes the sensitivity of brain function to a lowering of blood glucose levels. In order to&#xD;
      answer this question, we need to compare the response of people with diabetes with the&#xD;
      response of people who do not have diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The plan of the study is to lower the subject's blood glucose using insulin, while measuring&#xD;
      what changes occur in brain function using what is called functional magnetic resonance&#xD;
      imaging (fMRI).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Previous studies have shown that a person with type 1 diabetes is less likely to suffer the&#xD;
      long term microvascular complications of diabetes (eye, kidney and nerve damage) if they&#xD;
      strive to achieve as near normal a blood glucose as possible. Unfortunately the tighter the&#xD;
      blood glucose control is, the more likely the subject is to suffer episodes of hypoglycemia.&#xD;
      Hypoglycemia is often the aspect of diabetes management most feared by people with diabetes&#xD;
      and may cause more anxiety than the threat of advanced complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For many people with diabetes the problem of hypoglycemia is compounded by the development of&#xD;
      the syndrome of hypoglycemia unawareness. One aspect of hypoglycemia unawareness is&#xD;
      impairment of the hormones normally released as blood glucose falls. Hypoglycemia triggers a&#xD;
      release of such insulin antagonists as epinephrine, norepinephrine, glucagon, growth hormone&#xD;
      and cortisol. These hormones act synergistically with the autonomic nervous system to raise&#xD;
      blood glucose, counteracting insulin and restoring normoglycemia. These homeostatic&#xD;
      mechanisms are also responsible for some of the early symptoms of low blood glucose,&#xD;
      providing a warning to insulin-treated diabetics as glucose falls. A number of studies&#xD;
      including research from this unit have established that strict metabolic control is&#xD;
      associated with impairment of the normal counterregulatory response to hypoglycemia and a&#xD;
      loss of hypoglycemia awareness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The brain is central to the recognition of hypoglycemia and the coordination of the&#xD;
      counterregulatory response. Neural tissue depends mainly on glucose for its energy supply. As&#xD;
      circulating glucose falls beneath the level needed to maintain glucose transport across the&#xD;
      blood-brain barrier, a variety of defense mechanisms are activated, including symptoms of&#xD;
      cognitive dysfunction. However, the precise nature and causes of the adverse CNS effects of&#xD;
      hypoglycemia are not well understood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) provides a tool to measure the effects of&#xD;
      hypoglycemia on the patterns and magnitudes of neuronal activation in the human brain, in&#xD;
      both normal and diabetic subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2001</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain response to blood glucose levels</measure>
    <time_frame>4 to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Brain response is operationally defined as: fMRI BOLD signal to detect differences in brain activation in response to changes in glucose levels taken between 4 to 8 weeks after subject enrollment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>7</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">164</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 1 Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Hypoglycemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>conventionally treated</arm_group_label>
    <description>conventionally treated, relatively poorly controlled patients with type 1 diabetes</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>intensively treated</arm_group_label>
    <description>intensively treated, well controlled patients with type 1 diabetes</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lean healthy</arm_group_label>
    <description>age- and sex- matched non-diabetic, normal weight (BMI &gt; or = 18.5 but &lt; or = 25 kg/m2) control subjects</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>obese subjects</arm_group_label>
    <description>obese individuals defined as BMI &gt; or = 30kg/m2</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>type 2 diabetics</arm_group_label>
    <description>Type 2 diabetics on diet only or diet and Metformin</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>type 1 diabetes unaware</arm_group_label>
    <description>Type 1 diabetics unaware of hypoglycemic symptoms</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>type 1 diabetes aware</arm_group_label>
    <description>Type 1 diabetics aware of hypoglycemic symptoms</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The recruited subjects will reflect the gender and ethnic distribution of the Yale and New&#xD;
        Haven community. The recruited subjects with type 1 diabetes will reflect the demographics&#xD;
        of the clinic population in New Haven. Subject selection is independent of race and sex.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  on a weight maintaining diet&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ability to read and speak English fluently&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For All Type 1 Diabetics all of the above inclusion criteria AND C-peptide negative&#xD;
             AND no evidence of neuropathy or proliferative retinopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only for Type 1 Diabetics in the intensively treated group: HbA1c &lt; 7.5% AND&#xD;
             documented hypoglycemia at least once per week over at least 4 weeks of frequent daily&#xD;
             self monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only for Type 1 Diabetics in the conventionally treated group:HbA1c ≥ 8.5%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-40 years in the groups 1,2, and 3. Age 18-50 in groups arm 2 obese and control.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt;30 in the groups 1,2, and 3; BMI &gt;18.4 but &lt; or = 25 in the arm control group;&#xD;
             and BMI &gt; or = 30kg/m2 in the obese group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of neurologic or cardiovascular disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert Sherwin, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06520</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 19, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 19, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 27, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>type 1 diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>hypoglycemia</keyword>
  <keyword>magnetic resonance imaging</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoglycemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

