<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00586443</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00001082</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00586443</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BEP Study Phase I (Bevacizumab, Everolimus, Panitumumab)</brief_title>
  <acronym>BEP</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study of Bevacizumab, Everolimus, and Panitumumab for Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Herbert Hurwitz, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Amgen</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Targeting molecular pathways of tumor growth has become a major focus of anti-cancer&#xD;
      treatments. This study aims to investigate the toxicity, pharmacokinetics, and preliminary&#xD;
      efficacy of the triplet combination of bevacizumab, RAD001, and panitumumab in patients with&#xD;
      refractory solid tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This open-labeled, non-randomized phase I trial of bevacizumab, everolimus and panitumumab is&#xD;
      designed to assess the safety, tolerability and efficacy of this combination in adult&#xD;
      patients with advanced solid tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      EGFr inhibition has been shown to have down-regulatory effects on VEGF expression and&#xD;
      angiogenesis. The combination of anti-VEGF and anti-EGFr targeting is clinically rational,&#xD;
      and preliminarily has shown at least additive, if not synergistic effects [12, 13]. Further,&#xD;
      preclinical data has shown that constitutive activation of the AKT pathway is a mechanism of&#xD;
      resistance to EGFr inhibitors [14]. Therefore, inhibition of both EGFr and AKT pathways by&#xD;
      panitumumab and RAD001 may create a synergistic antitumor effect. There is also rationale&#xD;
      that RAD001 and anti-VEGF therapies may be synergistic. Preliminary results from a Phase I&#xD;
      dose escalation study of bevacizumab in combination with RAD001 has reported a recommended&#xD;
      Phase II dose of this combination, and has described a minor response in a colorectal cancer&#xD;
      patient previously refractory to bevacizumab-based therapy, and over 10 months of stable&#xD;
      disease in another colorectal cancer patient previous refractory to bevacizumab-based therapy&#xD;
      [15].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bevicizumab (Avatstin) is a humanized monoclonal antibody to VEGF. VEGF is known to play a&#xD;
      pivotal role in tumor angiogenesis and is a significant mitogenic stimulus for arterial,&#xD;
      venous and lymphatic endothelial cells. The addition of bevacizumab to chemotherapy has been&#xD;
      shown to increase overall response rate, duration of response and survival for patients with&#xD;
      metastatic colon cancer (4) and is beneficial in first line non-small cell lung cancer and&#xD;
      metastatic breast cancer [1, 2], and second line metastatic colorectal cancer (7). VEGF&#xD;
      signals through phosphoatidylinositol 3-kinase (PI3K) and Akt as well as through the&#xD;
      extracellular regulated kinase (ERK 1/2), a mitogen activated protein kinase (MAPK). VEGF's&#xD;
      multiple biologic actions may be mediated by different pathways. Erikkson demonstrated that&#xD;
      VEGF induced hyperpermeability was highly dependent on activation of the AKT pathway, while&#xD;
      the angiogenic effect was largely unaffected by blocking this pathway and likely depended on&#xD;
      ERK activation [3].&#xD;
&#xD;
      RAD001 (Everolimus), an oral derivative of rapamycin, selectively inhibits mTOR (mammalian&#xD;
      target of rapamycin), an intracellular protein kinase implicated in the control of cellular&#xD;
      proliferation of activated T-lymphocytes or neoplastic cells. mTOR is considered to be a&#xD;
      downstream component of the PI3K/AKT/TSC pathway, a signalling module known to be heavily&#xD;
      deregulated in many human cancers[4, 5]. In this context, there is an increasing body of&#xD;
      evidence suggesting that AKT regulates mTOR activity[5-7], and that the activation status of&#xD;
      the PI3K/AKT pathway may be indicative of responsiveness to rapamycins such as RAD001.&#xD;
      Specifically, loss of PTEN or constitutive/hyper-activation of AKT has been suggested to&#xD;
      sensitize tumors to the effects of inhibition of mTOR[6-8]. Indeed, RAD001 preferentially&#xD;
      inhibits the proliferation of tumor cells displaying high AKT activity and totally reverses&#xD;
      AKT-driven prostate intraepithelial neoplasia in a mouse transgenic model[7]. Rapamycins also&#xD;
      inhibit downstream signaling pathways of VEGF. The rapamycin-regulated PI3K and p70s6&#xD;
      pathways are known to be involved in mediating VEGF's effects on endothelial cells [9]. In&#xD;
      animal models, rapamycins modestly decrease tumor VEGF expression, and significantly blunt&#xD;
      typical angiogenic responses to VEGF. Everolimus has been shown to inhibit tumor growth and&#xD;
      reduce number of blood vessels in a murine melanoma model, indicating that RAD001 has direct&#xD;
      antiangiogenic effects [10].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Panitumumab (Vectibix) is a fully humanized monoclonal antibody directed against epidermal&#xD;
      growth factor receptor (EGFr), which is a 170-kD transmembrane glycoprotein with a&#xD;
      cytoplasmic protein kinase domain essential for tumor growth and division. The receptor binds&#xD;
      multiple ligands including epidermal growth factor and transforming growth factor-alpha&#xD;
      (TGF-alpha). The tyrosine kinase intracellular domain of the receptor is activated via&#xD;
      binding of a ligand to EGFr, which in turn initiates a cascade of intracellular signals.&#xD;
      These downstream signaling pathways again include the phosphorylation of mitogen-activated&#xD;
      protein kinase (MAPK) through the ras/raf pathway. Inhibition of these signaling pathways can&#xD;
      result in cell growth arrest and apoptosis, respectively[11].&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Sandler, A.B., et al. Randomized phase II/III trial of paclitaxel (P) plus carboplatin&#xD;
           (C) with or without bevacizumab (NSC #704865) in patients with advanced non-squamous&#xD;
           non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC): An Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Trial-&#xD;
           E4599. in Proc Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2005.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Miller, K.D., et al. E2100: A randomized phase III trial of paclitaxel versus paclitaxel&#xD;
           plus bevacizumab as first line threapy for locally recurrent or metastatic breast&#xD;
           cancer. in American Society for Clinical Oncology. 2005. Orlando, FL.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Eriksson, A., et al., Small GTP-binding protein Rac is an essential mediator of vascular&#xD;
           endothelial growth factor-induced endothelial fenestrations and vascular permeability.&#xD;
           Circulation, 2003. 107(11): p. 1532-8.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Vivanco, I. and C.L. Sawyers, The phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase-akt pathway in human&#xD;
           cancer. Nature Cancer, 2002. 2: p. 489-501.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Krymskaya, V.P., Tumor suppressors hamartin and tuberin: intracellular signaling. Cell&#xD;
           Signal, 2003. 15: p. 729-739.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Bjornsti, M.-A. and P.J. Houghton, The TOR pathway: A target for cancer chemotherapy.&#xD;
           Nat Rev Cancer, 2004. 4: p. 335-348.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Majumder, P.K., et al., mTOR inhibition reverses Akt-dependent prostate intraepithelial&#xD;
           neoplasia through regulation of apoptotic and HIF-1-dependent pathways. Nat Med, 2004.&#xD;
           10: p. 594-601.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Noh, W.C., et al., Determinants of rapamycin in breast cancer cells. Clin Cancer Res,&#xD;
           2004. 10: p. 1013-1023.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Yu, Y. and J.D. Sato, MAP kinases, phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase, and p70 S6 kinase&#xD;
           mediate the mitogenic response of human endothelial cells to vascular endothelial growth&#xD;
           factor. J Cell Physiol, 1999. 178(2): p. 235-46.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Lane, H., et al. Antiangiogenic activity of RAD001, an orally active anticancer agent.&#xD;
           in Proc AACR. 2002.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Ciardiello, F. and G. Tortora, A novel approach in the treatment of cancer: Targeting&#xD;
           the epidermal growth factor receptor. Clin Cancer Res, 2001. 7: p. 2958-2970.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Spigel, D.R., et al. Bevacizumab and erlotinib in the treatment of patients with&#xD;
           metastatic renal cell cancer (RCC): Update of a phase II multicenter trial. in Proc Am&#xD;
           Soc Clin Oncol. 2005.&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Saltz, L.B., et al. Randomized phase II trial of cetuximab/bevacizumab/irinotecan (CBI)&#xD;
           versus cetuximab/bevacizumab (CB) in irinotecan-refractory colorectal cancer. in Proc Am&#xD;
           Soc Clin Oncol. 2005.&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. She, Q.B., et al., Resistance to gefitinib in PTEN-null HER-overexpressing tumor cells&#xD;
           can be overcome through restoration of PTEN function or pharmacologic modulation of&#xD;
           constitutive phosphatidylinositol 3'-kinase/Akt pathway signaling. Clin Cancer Res,&#xD;
           2003. 9(12): p. 4340-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Zafar, Y., et al. Preliminary results of a phase I study of bevacizumab (BV) in&#xD;
           combination with everolimus (E) in patients with advanced solid tumors. in Proc Am Soc&#xD;
           Clin Oncol. 2006.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the MTD/recommended phase II regimen and evaluate safety of panitumumab added to RAD001 plus bevacizumab in adult patients with advanced solid tumors.</measure>
    <time_frame>Every cycle (28-days)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To preliminarily describe any clinical activity (PR, CR or duration of SD) associated with this regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>Every cycle (28-days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">56</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>I</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is a Phase I safety study. There is only one arm.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>bevacizumab, everolimus, panitumumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Cohort # subjects Bevacizumab Everolimus Panitumumab&#xD;
3 3-6 5 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks 5 mg PO QoD 3.6 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks&#xD;
2 3-6 5 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks 5 mg PO QoD 4.8 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks&#xD;
1 3-6 10 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks 5 mg PO QD 4.8 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks&#xD;
3-6 10 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks 10 mg PO QD 4.8 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks&#xD;
3-6 10 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks 10 mg PO QD 6 mg/kg IV Q2 weeks 3a 10 RPTD* RPTD* RPTD* 3b 10 RPTD** RPTD** RPTD**&#xD;
Panitumumab and RAD001 started on Day 1, bevacizumab started on Day 15. **Bevacizumab and RAD001 started on Day 1, panitumumab started on Day 15.</description>
    <arm_group_label>I</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>avastin</other_name>
    <other_name>RAD001</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically confirmed malignancy that is metastatic or&#xD;
             unresectable and for which standard curative or palliative measures do not exist or&#xD;
             are no longer effective. Disease must be measurable or evaluable by RECIST criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have had radiation therapy, hormonal therapy, biologic therapy or&#xD;
             chemotherapy for cancer within the 28 days prior to study day 1. Patients must not&#xD;
             have had major surgery within the 28 days prior to study day 1 or minor surgical&#xD;
             procedures within the 7 days prior to study day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance status &gt; 70%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have normal organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
             **Absolute neutrophil count greater or equal to 1,500/μl; Platelets greater or equal&#xD;
             to 100,000/μl; Total bilirubin, less or equal to 1.5 X upper limit of normal&#xD;
             (ULN)AST(SGOT)/ALT(SGPT)less or equal to 2.5 X ULN less or equal to 5 X ULN if known&#xD;
             hepatic metastases; Creatinine clearance greater or equal to 50 mL/min/m2 for patients&#xD;
             with creatinine levels (by Cockroft-Gault equation or 24 hour urine; Hemoglobin &gt; 9&#xD;
             g/dL; Magnesium &gt; 1.2 mg/dL; Calcium (corrected for albumin)&gt; 8.7 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effect of the investigational drugs on the developing human fetus is not known,&#xD;
             but these drugs are likely to be embryo- and feto- toxic. Women of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal or barrier method&#xD;
             of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of study&#xD;
             participation. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while she or&#xD;
             her partner are participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician&#xD;
             and study PI immediately. Oral, implantable, or injectable contraceptives may be&#xD;
             affected by cytochrome P450 interactions, and are therefore not considered effective&#xD;
             for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had radiation therapy, hormonal therapy, biologic therapy, or&#xD;
             chemotherapy for cancer within the 28 days prior to day 1 of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received any other investigational agents within the 28 days prior&#xD;
             to day 1 of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known CNS metastases or centrally-located non-small cell lung cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inadequately controlled hypertension (defined as systolic blood pressure &gt;150 and/or&#xD;
             diastolic blood pressure &gt; 100 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant vascular disease (e.g., aortic aneurysm, aortic dissection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptomatic peripheral vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy. Patients on full dose anticoagulation&#xD;
             are excluded from this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or significant traumatic injury within 28 days&#xD;
             prior to study enrollment (56 days for hepatectomy, thoracotomy, neurosurgery) or&#xD;
             anticipation of need for major surgical procedure during the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Core biopsy or other minor surgical procedure, excluding placement of a vascular&#xD;
             access device, within 7 days prior to study enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, or intra-abdominal abscess&#xD;
             within 6 months prior to study enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious, non-healing wound, ulcer, or bone fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proteinuria at screening as demonstrated by Urine protein:creatinine (UPC) ratio&#xD;
             greater than 1.0&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any prior history of hypertensive crisis or hypertensive encephalopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New York Heart Association (NYHA) Grade II or greater congestive heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of myocardial infarction or unstable angina within 6 months prior to study&#xD;
             enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of stroke or transient ischemic attack within 6 months prior to study&#xD;
             enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of intolerance or hypersensitivity to prior treatment with bevacizumab,&#xD;
             RAD001, or panitumumab. Prior treatment with these agents is otherwise permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic treatment with systemic steroids or another immunosuppressive agent, though&#xD;
             steroids may be used on an as-needed basis - ie - for treatment of nausea. Treatment&#xD;
             with megace is permitted for treatment of anorexia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other concurrent severe and/or uncontrolled medical disease which could compromise&#xD;
             safety of treatment (i.e., severely impaired lung function, uncontrolled diabetes,&#xD;
             uncontrolled hypertension, severe infection, severe malnutrition, ventricular&#xD;
             arrhythmias, active ischemic heart disease, chronic liver or renal disease, active&#xD;
             upper GI tract ulceration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A known history of HIV seropositivity, hepatitis C virus, acute or chronic active&#xD;
             hepatitis B infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impairment of gastrointestinal function or gastrointestinal disease that may&#xD;
             significantly alter drug absorption (e.g., inflammatory bowel disease, uncontrolled&#xD;
             nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, malabsorption syndrome or significant small bowel&#xD;
             resection)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an active, bleeding diathesis or on oral anti-vitamin K medication&#xD;
             (except low dose coumarin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unwilling to or unable to comply with the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical need for the continued administration of any of the following drugs which&#xD;
             affect CYP3A. (see Appendix A ifor a list of common medications).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit safety or&#xD;
             compliance with study requirements or may interfere with the interpretation of the&#xD;
             results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of interstitial lung disease e.g. pneumonitis or pulmonary fibrosis or any&#xD;
             evidence of interstitial lung disease on baseline chest CT scan&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Herbert I Hurwitz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 21, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 4, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Duke University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Herbert Hurwitz, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>solid tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>avastin</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase I</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase 1</keyword>
  <keyword>combination therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>bevacizumab</keyword>
  <keyword>RAD001</keyword>
  <keyword>everolimus</keyword>
  <keyword>pantitumumab</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Panitumumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

