<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03495115</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17-552</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03495115</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparing Restriction Spectrum Imaging (RSI) to Conventional and Abbreviated Breast MRI for Breast Cancer Screening</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparing Restriction Spectrum Imaging (RSI) to Conventional and Abbreviated Breast MRI for Breast Cancer Screening</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Radiological Society of North America</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is looking at a breast cancer screening technique, restriction spectrum imaging&#xD;
      (RSI), as a possible alternative to the breast Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) used by most&#xD;
      healthcare professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The technique involved in this study is:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Restriction Spectrum Imaging (RSI)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this research study is to measure RSI's ability to diagnose breast&#xD;
      cancer in comparison to standard breast MRIs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      RSI is a technique that has been shown to address the limitations of certain types of MRI&#xD;
      exams used to make images of the prostate and brain. RSI is not a FDA-approved technique for&#xD;
      screening, but is a type of advanced diffusion technique and diffusion weighted imaging is&#xD;
      used as a part of the standard breast MRI. RSI has been shown to improve tumor detection in&#xD;
      prostate and brain. For example, a recent pilot study in prostate showed that adding RSI&#xD;
      improved the ability to find a certain stage of prostate cancer in comparison to an MRI&#xD;
      without the use of the RSI technique. By comparing RSI's ability to diagnose breast cancer,&#xD;
      future clinical testing can determine whether RSI is a more efficient way to screen for&#xD;
      breast cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 18, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnostic accuracy of breast restriction spectrum imaging (RSI) in comparison to conventional breast MRI</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>We will test the non-inferiority of RSI compared to DCE-MRI using ROC curves created for the BI-RADS score, based on the reader study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnostic accuracy of RSI compared to that of abbreviated MRI (Ab-MRI) in breast cancer screening</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>We will test the non-inferiority of RSI compared to Ab-MRI using ROC curves created for the BI-RADS score, based on the reader study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">910</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SCREENING MRI</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard MRI procedure will be used.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SCREENING MG BI-RADS 4/5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>RSI is a DWI sequence with a built in distortion-correction technique that can be applied to any diffusion technique using echo planar imaging acquisition.&#xD;
RSI will be performed using pulsed-field gradient, spin-echo, echo planar imaging with &quot;multi-shell&quot; diffusion data .&#xD;
The b0 images will be collected in both the forward and reverse phase encoding directions to allow for post-processing correction of spatial distortion from magnetic field.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MRI</intervention_name>
    <description>A MRI uses a strong magnet to produce detailed pictures of the inside of your body.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCREENING MRI</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RSI</intervention_name>
    <description>RSI is a technique that aims to improve the pictures produced during a MRI exam.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCREENING MG BI-RADS 4/5</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Group 1 will consist of women who present for screening breast MRI:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age &gt;= 18&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Asymptomatic for breast disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presenting for routine breast cancer screening with MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Group 2 will consist of women who presented for a screening mammogram (2D or 3D&#xD;
             tomosynthesis) AND who have had a biopsy recommended after diagnostic workup:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age &gt;= 18&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Asymptomatic for breast disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presenting for routine breast cancer screening with mammogram (2D or 3D&#xD;
                  tomosynthesis) and/or ultrasound&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Biopsy recommended after subsequent diagnostic workup (BI-RADS 4 or 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Radiologist Reader Participant&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have clinical experience in interpreting breast MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have interpreted at least 10 breast MRI exams with RSI interpretation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Known or suspected renal insufficiency, rendering the participant unable to safely receive&#xD;
        intravenous contrast based on institutional clinical protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Renal insufficiency for the purposes of exclusion includes any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failed Chokye questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of end stage renal disease with EGFR&lt;30 mL/min/1.73m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Point of care (POC) measure of creatinine clearance (eGFR) prior to obtaining the MRI&#xD;
             &lt;35. We will perform this POC test as needed per institutional policy for routine MRI&#xD;
             if: (a) no creatinine result is available in the OMR within 30 days of the MRI exam,&#xD;
             (b) the patient is &gt; 60 years old, or (c) the patient is on hydroxyurea.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of adverse or allergic-like reaction to gadolinium MRI intravenous&#xD;
                  contrast, rendering the participant unable to safely receive intravenous contrast&#xD;
                  based on institutional clinical protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of MRI unsafe devices or objects which would make having an MRI unsafe,&#xD;
                  as per institutional clinical protocol. MRI unsafe devices or objects for the&#xD;
                  purposes of exclusion include but are not limited to certain intracranial&#xD;
                  aneurysm clips, cardiac pacemaker, and implantable defibrillator devices,&#xD;
                  metallic heart valve, or coronary artery stents, breast tissue expanders, bio or&#xD;
                  neurostimulators, pellets and bullets, ocular implants and devices, otologic and&#xD;
                  cochlear implants. Other devices or metallic objects may be deemed unsafe for MRI&#xD;
                  at the radiologist's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unable to tolerate exam (i.e., secondary to untreatable claustrophobia,&#xD;
                  positioning constraints/unable to lie prone).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Body weight exceeds that allowable by the MRI table.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breast biopsy or surgical intervention planned before the test RSI-MRI in this&#xD;
                  study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breast implants (silicone or saline).&#xD;
&#xD;
                  8. Nursing or thinks she may be or is pregnant, as gadolinium contrast-enhanced&#xD;
                  MRI is unsafe. We will perform a pregnancy test as needed per institutional&#xD;
                  policy for routine breast MRI. Per institutional clinical protocol, all females&#xD;
                  of childbearing potential who are uncertain if they are pregnant or think they&#xD;
                  are pregnant must have a blood test or urine study within 2 weeks prior to the&#xD;
                  MRI exam to rule out pregnancy. A female of childbearing potential is any woman,&#xD;
                  regardless of sexual orientation or prior tubal ligation, who:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has not had a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has not been naturally post-menopausal for at least 2 years (i.e., has had menses&#xD;
                  at any time in the preceding 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Radiologist Reader Participant&#xD;
&#xD;
        -None.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vandana Dialani, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 4, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 4, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 11, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vandana Dialani</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

