<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03492606</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LipidMediators</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03492606</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lipid Mediators in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>LipidMediators</acronym>
  <official_title>Specialized Pro-resolving Lipid Mediators in the Resolution of Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Neuromed IRCCS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Neuromed IRCCS</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multiple sclerosis (MS) is a chronic inflammatory neurodegenerative disease associated with&#xD;
      uncontrolled inflammation and autoimmunity and for which there is still an unmet need for new&#xD;
      diagnostic and therapeutic options, especially for the progressive forms. Recent studies&#xD;
      suggest that chronic inflammation can be a consequence of failure to resolve inflammation,&#xD;
      the resolution of which is mediated by a newly discovered genus of highly potent&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory lipids derived metabolically from omega-3 essential fatty acids and termed&#xD;
      specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators (SPMs).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Herein, we propose to identify SPMs as leads for the control of MS pathology and progression&#xD;
      and to propose them as novel disease-modifying treatments by assessing their ex vivo/in vitro&#xD;
      and in vivo role in modulating the balance of effector and regulatory cells and/or the&#xD;
      mechanisms leading to chronicity as wells as in promoting activation of anti-inflammatory and&#xD;
      neuroprotective pathways.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Uncontrolled or unresolved inflammation is associated with several widely occurring diseases&#xD;
      such as multiple sclerosis (MS), which is the most common chronic inflammatory demyelinating&#xD;
      disease of the central nervous system and a major cause of disability, triggered by an&#xD;
      autoimmune response to myelin that eventually leads to progressive neurodegeneration.Although&#xD;
      knowledge on its underlying immunopathogenesis has considerably improved and is mostly&#xD;
      believed to be mediated by autoreactive T cells that cause oligodendrocyte death and axonal&#xD;
      damage, resulting in demyelination, synaptic alteration, and neuronal loss, there is still an&#xD;
      unmet need for new diagnostic and therapeutic options, especially for the progressive forms&#xD;
      of MS for which no drugs are still available. In recent years, previously unrecognized&#xD;
      metabolites, termed specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators (SPMs), temporally and&#xD;
      spatially synthesized from omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids, were identified and have&#xD;
      emerged as biomarkers and potent mediators that control the magnitude and extent of&#xD;
      inflammatory events by activating local resolution programs. Despite emerging data suggest&#xD;
      that SPMs might control chronic inflammation, research on these mediators on MS is still&#xD;
      absent. Thus, a detailed investigation is needed to identify SPMs as modulators of&#xD;
      inflammation and disease progression in MS, which might lead to the development of new&#xD;
      disease-modifying treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis and Significance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our hypothesis is that the underlying mechanism of chronic inflammation in MS could be the&#xD;
      failure of activating pro-resolving mechanisms, involving the newly discovered omega-3&#xD;
      essential fatty acids-derived mediators of resolution of inflammation: resolvins, maresins,&#xD;
      and protectins. Endogenous mechanisms that curtail excessive inflammation and promptits&#xD;
      timely resolution are of considerable interest; our findings that these SPMs (recently&#xD;
      identified also in human lymphoidorgans, where most naïve-to-effector T cell differentiation&#xD;
      occurs) exert a non-cytotoxic regulatory role on cells central inautoimmunity, acting on the&#xD;
      balance between pathogenic Th1/Th17 and tolerogenic Treg cells - typically altered in MS&#xD;
      -represents a promising beginning for a new avenue of research for MS. The elucidation of&#xD;
      these mechanisms operating invivo to keep acute inflammation within physiologic boundaries as&#xD;
      well as to stimulate resolution and prevent chronicinflammation is particularly significant&#xD;
      and offers a novel opportunity to manage MS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preliminary Data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thanks to an ongoing collaboration with Prof. Serhan from Harvard Medical School (the father&#xD;
      and inventor of SPMs) we have demonstrated for the first time that specific SPMs modulate&#xD;
      adaptive immune responses in human peripheral blood T cells. These SPMs strongly reduce&#xD;
      cytokine production from activated T cells, prevent naïve CD4 T-cell differentiation into Th1&#xD;
      and Th17 and enhance the de novo generation and function of Foxp3+ regulatory T (Tregs)&#xD;
      cells. These results are supported in vivo in a mouse model deficient elongase 2 (Elovl2-/-),&#xD;
      the key enzyme for DHA synthesis (the precursor of resolvins and maresins). These findings&#xD;
      suggest that SPMs might act on the balance between pathogenic Th1/Th17 and tolerogenic Treg&#xD;
      cells and provide a new evidence for SPM-based therapeutic approaches to modulate T-cell&#xD;
      mediated chronic inflammatory and autoimmune diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Characterization of the resolution code of inflammation in MS patientsInvestigation of SPMs&#xD;
      potential in modulating ex vivo/in vitro T cells in MS patientsExploitation of the&#xD;
      therapeutic potential of SPMs in animal models of MS&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 30, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SPMs in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>2021</time_frame>
    <description>levels of the different members of the family of SPMs in plasma</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>T cells</measure>
    <time_frame>2021</time_frame>
    <description>analysis of T cells functions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>EAE</measure>
    <time_frame>2021</time_frame>
    <description>we will treat acute EAE mice (n=8 per each experimental group) at the peak of the disease (day 16-19) with those SPMs that will result to be the most efficacious in modulating pathogenic T-cell responses</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>multiple sclerosis patients</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Samples</intervention_name>
    <description>lumbar puncture, blood and CSF samples, SNPs analysis</description>
    <arm_group_label>multiple sclerosis patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      blood samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        20 recurrent-remitting patients (RR-MS) and 10 primary-progressive patients (P-MS),&#xD;
        according to the MacDonald or Poser method, without any type of treatment and 15 healthy&#xD;
        donors of the same age and with no previous history of neurological diseases. Blood samples&#xD;
        will be recruited at the IRCCS INM Neuromed, under the supervision of dr. Fabio Buttari who&#xD;
        will make the diagnosis. The diagnosis of MS will be performed according to the criteria of&#xD;
        MacDonald or Poser. On this occasion, the patient will be offered participation in the&#xD;
        study, giving informed consent and explaining in non-technical language, what the research&#xD;
        consists of, which parameters will be evaluated and for what purpose. Once consent is&#xD;
        obtained from the patients, venous samples will be taken (15 mL).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion in the study is foreseen for sex subjects, ideally in a ratio of 1: 2.5 in favor&#xD;
        of the female (according to the incidence of the disease), aged between 18 and 60 years,&#xD;
        affected by the recurrent form - Multiple sclerosis emitter with EDSS between 1 and 3.&#xD;
        Blood sampling will be performed at least one month after the last cortisone treatment.&#xD;
        Taking into account that 20% of the enrolled patients could have a variability in the cell&#xD;
        count of the monocytes to be purified, the number of the sample up to 24 is better than&#xD;
        20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who have at least one of the following characteristics will not be included in the&#xD;
        study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. subjects with CNS or autoimmune diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. subjects affected by RR-MS in immunomodulatory treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. subjects with RR-MS with monocytosis, infections or fever&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>April 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 3, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 3, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 10, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 10, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 10, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 12, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

