<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03496207</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A011-09</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2017-004738-27</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03496207</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Sotatercept for the Treatment of Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (PAH)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PULSAR</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Randomized Study to Compare the Efficacy and Safety of Sotatercept (ACE-011) Versus Placebo When Added to Standard of Care for the Treatment of Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension (PAH)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Acceleron Pharma Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Acceleron Pharma Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study A011-09 is designed to assesses the efficacy and safety of sotatercept (ACE-011)&#xD;
      relative to placebo in adults with pulmonary arterial hypertension (PAH). Eligible&#xD;
      participants will receive study treatment for 6 months in the Placebo-Controlled Treatment&#xD;
      Period, and then will be eligible to enroll into an 18- month Extension Period during which&#xD;
      all participants will receive sotatercept. All treated patients will be also undergo&#xD;
      follow-up period after last study drug treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2, double blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, parallel-group study of&#xD;
      sotatercept plus SOC versus placebo plus SOC in participants with PAH of WHO Group 1,&#xD;
      functional class II-III.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomly assigned in a 3:3:4 ratio to receive placebo every 21 days,&#xD;
      sotatercept 0.3 mg/kg subcutaneously (SC) every 21 days, or sotatercept 0.7 mg/kg SC every 21&#xD;
      days, for a period of 24 weeks in the Placebo-Controlled Treatment Period of the study while&#xD;
      on standard of care therapy. Evaluations will include changes in pulmonary vascular&#xD;
      resistance (PVR), six-minute-walk distance (6MWD), quality of life questionnaires,&#xD;
      echocardiographic parameters, and safety. Participants who have not discontinued early from&#xD;
      the Placebo-Controlled Treatment Period and have had their post-Treatment Period PVR&#xD;
      assessment will be able to continue into the 18-month Extension Period in which&#xD;
      sotatercept-treated participants will receive their latest dose level of sotatercept SC every&#xD;
      21 days and placebo-treated participants willbe re-randomized 1:1 to receive sotatercept 0.3&#xD;
      mg/kg SC every 21 days or sotatercept 0.7 mg/kg SC every 21 days while on standard of care&#xD;
      therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 27, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 16, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Pulmonary Vascular Resistance (PVR) as measured by right heart catheterization</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Change from baseline in PVR at Cycle 25 (or next cycles up to Cycle 33) for the Delayed-Start efficacy analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion up to 24 months.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Change from baseline in PVR at Cycle 25 (or next cycles up to Cycle 33) for the Placebo-Crossed efficacy analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion up to 24 months.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Safety and tolerability assessments based on AEs, clinical laboratory values, and vital signs</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion up to 24 months.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in 6-Minute Walk Distance (6MWD)</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in amino-terminal brain natriuretic propeptide (NT-proBNP)</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in tricuspid annular plane systolic excursion (TAPSE) by echocardiography (ECHO)</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Cambridge Pulmonary Hypertension Outcome Review (CAMPHOR) patient-reported outcome (PRO) score</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
    <description>The CAMPHOR questionnaire contains 65 items in total, 25 relating to symptoms, 15 relating to activities, and 25 relating to Quality of Life (QoL). It is negatively weighted; a higher score indicates worse QoL and greater functional limitation. Symptom and QoL items are both scored out of 25: &quot;yes/true&quot; scores 1 and &quot;no/not true&quot; scores 0. Activity items have three possible responses (score 0-2), giving a score out of 30.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in 36-Item Short Form Health Survey (SF-36) patient-reported outcome (PRO) score</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
    <description>The SF-36 questionnaire is a 36-item, patient-reported survey of patient health. The questionnaire consists of eight scaled scores, which are the weighted sums of the questions in their section. Each scale is directly transformed into a 0-100 scale on the assumption that each question carries equal weight. The lower the score the more disability. The higher the score the less disability i.e., a score of zero is equivalent to maximum disability and a score of 100 is equivalent to no disability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical worsening (e.g., hospitalizations, change in WHO functional class, and as defined in Section 8.5.4) from C1D1 to C9D1A</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in WHO functional class at 24 weeks (C9D1A) vs. screening</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability assessments based on adverse events (AEs).</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of vital signs - weight</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of vital signs - blood pressure (systolic/diastolic)</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of vital signs - respiratory rate</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of vital signs - EKG (QTcF interval)</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of PK parameter(s) Maximum Plasma Concentration [Cmax]</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Change from baseline in 6MWD at Cycle 25 (or next cycles up to Cycle 33) for the Delayed-Start efficacy analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Change from baseline in 6MWD at Cycle 25 (or next cycles up to Cycle 33) for the Placebo-Crossed efficacy analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Change from baseline in WHO FC at Cycle 25 (or next cycles up to Cycle 33) for the Delayed-Start efficacy analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extension Period - Change from baseline in WHO FC at Cycle 25 (or next cycles up to Cycle 33) for the Placebo-Crossed efficacy analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>From initiation of treatment (Study Day 1) to end of placebo-controlled treatment period (Study Day 168)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">106</enrollment>
  <condition>Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo SC every 21 days plus SOC for 24 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sotatercept 0.3 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sotatercept, 0.3 mg/kg SC every 21 days plus SOC for 24 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sotatercept 0.7 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sotatercept, 0.7 mg/kg SC every 21 days plus SOC for 24 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sotatercept</intervention_name>
    <description>Sotatercept (ACE-011) is a recombinant fusion protein consisting of the extracellular domain of the human activin receptor type IIA linked to the Fc piece of human IgG1</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sotatercept 0.3 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sotatercept 0.7 mg/kg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ACE-011</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Documented diagnostic right heart catheterization (RHC) at any time prior to Screening&#xD;
             confirming diagnosis of WHO diagnostic pulmonary hypertension Group I: PAH in any of&#xD;
             the following subtypes:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Idiopathic ii. Heritable PAH iii. Drug- or toxin-induced PAH iv. PAH associated&#xD;
             with connective tissue disease v. PAH associated with simple, congenital&#xD;
             systemic-to-pulmonary shunts at least 1 year following shunt repair&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Symptomatic pulmonary hypertension classified as WHO functional class II or III&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Screening RHC documenting a minimum PVR of ≥ 400 dyn·sec/cm5 (5 Wood units)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pulmonary function tests (PFTs) within 6 months prior to Screening as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Total lung capacity (TLC) &gt; 70% predicted; or if between 60 to70% predicted, or&#xD;
                  not possible to be determined, confirmatory high-resolution computed tomography&#xD;
                  (CT) indicating no more than mild interstitial lung disease (ILD), per&#xD;
                  investigator interpretation, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Forced expiratory volume (first second) (FEV1)/ forced vital capacity (FVC) &gt; 70%&#xD;
                  predicted&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ventilation-perfusion (VQ) scan (or, if unavailable a negative CT pulmonary angiogram&#xD;
             [CTPA] result, or pulmonary angiography result), any time prior to Screening Visit or&#xD;
             conducted during the Screening Period, with normal or low probability result),&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No contraindication per investigator for RHC during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. 6MWD ≥ 150 and ≤ 550 meters repeated twice at Screening and both values within 15% of&#xD;
             each other, calculated from the highest value&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. PAH therapy at stable (per investigator) dose levels of SOC therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Stopped receiving any pulmonary hypertension chronic general supportive therapy (e.g,&#xD;
             diuretics, oxygen, anticoagulants, digoxin) within 60 days prior to study visit C1D1&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received intravenous inotropes (e.g., dobutamine, dopamine, norepinephrine,&#xD;
             vasopressin) within 30 days prior to study visit C1D1&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of atrial septostomy within 180 days prior to Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of more than mild obstructive sleep apnea that is untreated&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known history of portal hypertension or chronic liver disease, including hepatitis B&#xD;
             and/or hepatitis C (with evidence of recent infection and/or active virus&#xD;
             replication), defined as mild to severe hepatic impairment (Child-Pugh Class A-C)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of human immunodeficiency virus infection-associated PAH&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Prior exposure to sotatercept (ACE-011) or luspatercept (ACE-536)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Initiation of an exercise program for cardiopulmonary rehabilitation within 90 days&#xD;
             prior to C1D1 or planned initiation during the study (participants who are stable in&#xD;
             the maintenance phase of a program and who will continue for the duration of the study&#xD;
             are eligible).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Uncontrolled systemic hypertension as evidenced by sitting systolic blood pressure&#xD;
             (BP) &gt; 160 mm Hg or sitting diastolic blood pressure &gt; 100 mm Hg during Screening&#xD;
             Visit after a period of rest&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Systolic BP &lt; 90 mmHg during Screening or at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of known pericardial constriction&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Electrocardiogram (ECG) with Fridericia's corrected QT interval (QTcF) &gt; 480 msec&#xD;
             during Screening Period or C1D1&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Personal or family history of long QTc syndrome or sudden cardiac death&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Cerebrovascular accident within 3 months of C1D1&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of restrictive or congestive cardiomyopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt; 45% on historical echocardiogram (ECHO)&#xD;
             within 6 months prior to Screening Period (or done as a part of the Screening Period)&#xD;
             or pulmonary capillary wedge pressure (PCWP) &gt; 15 mmHg as determined in the Screening&#xD;
             Period RHC.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any current or prior history of symptomatic coronary disease (prior myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, percutaneous coronary intervention, coronary artery bypass graft surgery,&#xD;
             or cardiac anginal chest pain)&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Acutely decompensated heart failure within 30 days prior to study visit C1D1, as per&#xD;
             investigator assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Significant (≥ 2+ regurgitation) mitral regurgitation (MR) or aortic regurgitation&#xD;
             (AR) valvular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Any of the following clinical laboratory values during the Screening Period prior to&#xD;
             C1D1:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Baseline Hgb &gt; 16.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Serum alanine aminotransferase or aspartate aminotransferase levels &gt; 3X upper&#xD;
                  limit of normal (ULN) or total bilirubin &gt; 1.5X ULN within 28 days of C1D1&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Estimated glomerular filtration rate &lt; 30 ml/min/1.73m2 (4-variable Modification&#xD;
                  of Diet in Renal Disease equation) within 28 days of C1D1 or required renal&#xD;
                  replacement therapy within 90 days&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. WBC count &lt; 4000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Platelets &lt; 100,000/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. History of opportunistic infection (e.g., invasive candidiasis or pneumocystis&#xD;
             pneumonia) within 6 months prior to Screening; serious local infection (e.g.,&#xD;
             cellulitis, abscess) or systemic infection (e.g., septicemia) within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reaction or hypersensitivity to recombinant&#xD;
             proteins or excipients in the investigational product&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Major surgery within 8 weeks prior to C1D1. Participants must have completely&#xD;
             recovered from any previous surgery prior to C1D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Prior heart or heart-lung transplants or life expectancy of &lt; 12 month&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Pregnant or breastfeeding females&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. If on corticosteroids, and at any time in the last 30 days prior to the Screening&#xD;
             Period: have been receiving doses of &gt; 20 mg/day of prednisone (or equivalent) or on a&#xD;
             new or changing dose of ≤ 20 mg/day; only participants receiving stable doses of ≤ 20&#xD;
             mg prednisone (or equivalent) in last 30 days prior to the Screening Period permitted&#xD;
             in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. History of active malignancy, with the exception of fully excised or treated basal&#xD;
             cell carcinoma, cervical carcinoma in-situ, or ≤ 2 squamous cell carcinomas of the&#xD;
             skin&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. History of clinically significant (as determined by the investigator) non-PAH related&#xD;
             cardiac, endocrine, hematologic, hepatic, (auto)immune, metabolic, urologic,&#xD;
             pulmonary, neurologic, neuromuscular, dermatologic, psychiatric, renal, and/or another&#xD;
             disease that may limit participation in the study. Autoimmune diseases are excluded&#xD;
             with the exception of those related to PAH etiologies included in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. Participation in another clinical trial involving intervention with another&#xD;
             investigational drug, approved therapy for investigational use, or investigational&#xD;
             device within 4 weeks prior to C1D1, or if the half-life of the previous product is&#xD;
             known, within 5 times the half-life prior to C1D1, whichever is longer&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. Weight &gt; 140 kg at Screening&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pulmonary Associates, PA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85006</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arizona Pulmonary Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85012</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Banner-University Medical Center Phoenix</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85381</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Arizona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85724</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Francisco Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94143</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Colorado Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UF Health Shands Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66160</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lindner Clinical Trial Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cincinnati</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>45129</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of South Carolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29425</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Houston Methodist Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Vincent's Hospital Sydney</name>
      <address>
        <city>Darlinghurst</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2010</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Westmead Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Westmead</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2145</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>John Hunter Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Lambton</city>
        <state>New South Whales</state>
        <zip>2305</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prince Charles Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chermside</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <zip>4032</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Madre Teresa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belo Horizonte</city>
        <state>Minas Gerais</state>
        <zip>30430</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Irmandade Da Santa Casa de Misericordia de Porto Alegre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Porto Alegre</city>
        <state>Riogrande Do Sul</state>
        <zip>90035</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Dia do Pulmão</name>
      <address>
        <city>Blumenau</city>
        <state>Santa Catarina</state>
        <zip>89010</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto do Coracao - HCFMUSP</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cerqueira César</city>
        <zip>05403-900</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Sao Lucas da PUCRS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jardim Botânico</city>
        <zip>05403-900</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital São Paulo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sao Paulo</city>
        <zip>04037</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Arnaud de Villeneuve</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <state>Hérault</state>
        <zip>34295</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Michallon</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Tronche</city>
        <zip>38700</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Bicêtre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Le Kremlin-Bicêtre</city>
        <zip>94275</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Saint Etienne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint-Étienne</city>
        <zip>42055</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medizinische Hochschule Hannover</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hannover</city>
        <state>Niedersachsen</state>
        <zip>30625</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitatsklinikum Halle (Saale)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Halle</city>
        <state>Sachsen-Anhalt</state>
        <zip>06120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitatsklinikum Leipzig</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leipzig</city>
        <state>Sachsen</state>
        <zip>04103</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Carl Gustav Carus an der TU Dresden</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dresden</city>
        <zip>01307</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Barzilai Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ashkelon</city>
        <zip>78278</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lady Davis Carmel Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haifa</city>
        <zip>34362</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Meir Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kefar Sava</city>
        <zip>4428100</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rabin Medical Center - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Petach-Tikva</city>
        <zip>49100</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chaim Sheba Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <zip>52621</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Marques de Valdecilla</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santander</city>
        <state>Cantabria</state>
        <zip>39008</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Puerta de Hierro-Majadahonda</name>
      <address>
        <city>Majadahonda</city>
        <state>Madrid</state>
        <zip>28222</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Vall d'Hebron - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinic de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08036</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <zip>28041</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Golden Jubilee National Hospital - PPDS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Clydebank</city>
        <zip>G81 4DY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Free London NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>NW32QG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>W2 1NY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Brazil</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Israel</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 12, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PAH</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Arterial Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Familial Primary Pulmonary Hypertension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

