<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03124056</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12/225</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03124056</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical and Biomarker Study of the Efficacy of Extracorporeal Photopheresis in Graft-versus-host Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>BIOECP_GVHD</acronym>
  <official_title>Clinical and Biological Study of the Efficacy of the Use of Closed Extracorporeal Photopheresis in Acute or Chronic Graft Versus Host Disease After Allogeneic Hematopoietic Transplantation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación para la Investigación del Hospital Clínico de Valencia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación para la Investigación del Hospital Clínico de Valencia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aims of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To evaluate the clinical efficacy of the use of extracorporeal photopheresis in the&#xD;
           treatment of Graft-versus-host disease under standard clinical indications as&#xD;
           pre-defined by the participants Centers (members of the Spanish Group for Hematopoietic&#xD;
           Transplantation).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To explore and identify biomarkers of clinical response to extracorporeal photopheresis&#xD;
           treatment of acute or chronic Graft-versus-host disease after Allogeneic hematopoietic&#xD;
           stem cell transplantation&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Title: Exploratory study of biomarkers associated with clinical response to extracorporeal&#xD;
      photopheresis in the treatment of acute and chronic graft-versus-host disease post allogeneic&#xD;
      hematopoietic stem cell transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To evaluate the clinical efficacy of the use of extracorporeal photopheresis in the&#xD;
           treatment of acute or chronic Graft-versus-host disease under standard clinical&#xD;
           indications as pre-defined by the participants Centers (Spanish Group for Hematopoietic&#xD;
           Transplantation).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To explore and identify biomarkers of clinical response to extracorporeal photopheresis&#xD;
           by means of a comprehensive analysis of different immune populations including T, B and&#xD;
           Natural Killer cells, prior to and within the episodes of clinical graft-versus-host&#xD;
           disease and the kinetic profile of plasma cytokines (Interferon-gamma, B cell activating&#xD;
           factor, Tumor Necrosis Factor-alfa and Interleukin-6) in relation with Graft-versus-host&#xD;
           disease .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      50 patients with acute or chronic graft-versus-host disease after Allogeneic hematopoietic&#xD;
      stem cell transplantation whatever be the cell source (blood, bone marrow or cord blood),&#xD;
      diagnosed and treated in one of the participant centers with closed extracorporeal&#xD;
      photopheresis in the indications detailed bellow, will be analyzed in order to identify&#xD;
      potential biomarkers of Graft versus host disease-response. Analyses of T, B and Natural&#xD;
      Killer populations will be performed by Intracellular Cytokine Staining and Flow Cytometry.&#xD;
      Cytokine measurement in plasma will be performed by Enzyme-Linked ImmunoSorbent Assay.&#xD;
      Participants Centers:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital Clinico. Valencia. Spain&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital Clinico. Salamanca. Spain&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital Ramon y Cajal. Madrid. Spain.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital Murcia. Spain&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hospital de Navarra, Pamplona. Spain&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each Centre will obtain approval of the study by the Local Ethical Committee and patients&#xD;
      will sing inform consent. No risks are expected of the participation of the patients in this&#xD;
      exploratory analytical study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frequency of treatment The frequency of treatment will depend on the type of&#xD;
      Graft-versus-host disease (acute or chronic) and will be modified depending on the clinical&#xD;
      response. All samples will be obtain at the same time that other standard blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acute graft versus host disease: treatment will be initiated using 3 sessions/week, 1st week.&#xD;
      Usually response will be determined in 3-4 weeks. If clear progression after 2 weeks of&#xD;
      treatment or no response after 6-8 weeks treatment will be withhold and additional treatment&#xD;
      will depend on the investigator decision. If response, the frequency of treatment will be&#xD;
      reduced according to the following schedule:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  2 treatments every week from week 2 to week 12&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  1 treatment every 2 weeks from week 13, until total suppression of corticosteroid&#xD;
           treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Response evaluation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Complete remission: resolution of all signs of Graft-versus-host disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Partial remission: improvement in at least 1 grade.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Absence of response&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic Graft-versus-host disease : treatment will be initiated using 3 sessions during week&#xD;
      1, 2 sessions every 2 weeks during weeks 2 to 12. If no progression, first evaluation will be&#xD;
      done at 3 months (week 12). If no response, extracorporeal photopheresis will be withhold,&#xD;
      except for sclerodermiform graft versus host disease in which evaluation will be done at 6&#xD;
      months. If response on week 12: 2 sessions every month for 3 additional months, after&#xD;
      suppression of corticosteroid treatment. Use of NIH Consensus Group criteria of response&#xD;
      (2006)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biomarkers study: Samples: 2 x 10 ml whole blood in ethylenediaminetetraacetate. will be&#xD;
      obtain in each time point analysis: pre-extracorporeal photopheresis and on days +7, +14,&#xD;
      +21, +30 post-extracorporeal photopheresis in acute GVHD and pre-extracorporeal photopheresis&#xD;
      and on days +15, +30, +45, +60, +75, +90 post-extracorporeal photopheresis in chronic Graft&#xD;
      versus host disease. Samples will be processed in each participant Center in order to obtain&#xD;
      mononuclear cells following the attached protocol and stored freezed until transportation to&#xD;
      the Centralized processing Laboratory at the Hospital Clinico, Valencia, Spain and sending&#xD;
      the clinical information included in the attached Excel Database.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Analyses of T, B and Natural Killer populations including Treg cells and dendritic cells&#xD;
           Will be performed by Intracellular Cytokine Staining and Flow Cytometry (BD and&#xD;
           Bioscience).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Cell-populations and time-point to be monitored: pre-extracorporeal photopheresis and on&#xD;
           days +7, +14, +21, +30 post-extracorporeal photopheresis in acute Graft versus host&#xD;
           disease and pre-extracorporeal photopheresis and on days +15, +30, +45, +60, +75, +90&#xD;
           post-extracorporeal photopheresis in chronic Graft versus host disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Cytokine measurement in plasma (Interferon-gamma, Tumor Necrosis Factor-alfa,&#xD;
           Interleukin-10, B cell activating factor and Interleukin-6)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 10, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Graft versus host disease Response</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of clinical partial and complete response of acute and chronic Graft versus host disease to the intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine rate of moderate and severe toxicity associated to extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of Participants With Treatment-Related Adverse Events as Assessed by CTCAE v4.0, Change From Baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To identify biomarkers associated with clinical response to extracorporeal photopheresis</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Association between levels of peripheral blood lymphocyte populations or serum cytokines and Clinical response</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Graft-versus-host Disease</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Extracorporeal photopheresis</intervention_name>
    <description>Extracorporeal photopheresis using non-open system</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with acute or chronic graft-versus-host disease resistant or dependent to&#xD;
        corticosteroids after Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation whatever be the&#xD;
        cell source (blood, bone marrow or cord blood), diagnosed and treated in one of the&#xD;
        participant centers&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with acute or chronic graft-versus-host disease resistant or dependent to&#xD;
        corticosteroids after Allogeneic Hematopoietic transplantation whatever be the cell source&#xD;
        (blood, bone marrow or cord blood), diagnosed and treated in one of the participant centers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Definitions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Acute Graft versus host disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Refractory to corticosteroids: progression after 3-4 days of standard first line&#xD;
             treatment with calcineurin inhibitor and glucocorticoids or no response after 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Corticosteroids dependent: flare o evidence of progression of Graft versus host&#xD;
             disease in the same or new affected organ after reduction of full dose (2 mg/Kg/día),&#xD;
             that has been maintained for at least 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Acute Graft versus host disease grade ≥ II, with response to 1st line treatment with&#xD;
             cyclosporine A and prednisone in patients who present intolerable adverse effects that&#xD;
             preclude to maintain this treatment as evaluated by the responsable physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient with viral reactivation during acute Graft versus host disease that need&#xD;
             reduction of immunosuppression as evaluated by the responsable physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Chronic Graft versus host disease: Muco-cutaneous or hepatic moderate or severe chronic&#xD;
        Graft versus host disease (as defined by NIH Consensus Group criteria (Biol Blood Marrow&#xD;
        Transplantation 2005;11:945), refractory to steroids (1 mg/Kg/day of methylprednisolone&#xD;
        during 15-30 days) or steroid-dependent (requiring more than 10 mg/day of&#xD;
        methylprednisolone to control manifestations).&#xD;
&#xD;
        First line&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Associated to corticosteroids if exists contraindication for calcineurin inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Associated to calcineurin inhibitors and corticosteroids in case of pulmonary chronic&#xD;
             Graft versus host disease diagnosis (optional) Second line&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive cutaneous moderate or severe chronic Graft versus host disease after acute&#xD;
             Graft versus host disease that is being treated with calcineurin inhibitors and&#xD;
             corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate or severe cutaneous (both lichenoid or sclerodermiform) o mucosal chronic&#xD;
             Graft versus host disease refractory to corticosteroids:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No Partial remission after 1 month of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No Complete remission after 3 months of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Disease progression after 2-3 weeks of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncontrolled Infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance score &lt;3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of adequate vascular access&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos Solano, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Clinico of Valencia, Spain</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>April 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 3, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 18, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 18, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 18, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Extracorporeal photopheresis</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarker of response</keyword>
  <keyword>Steroid resistant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

