<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03127670</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BSMMU-012-CT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03127670</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Solanum Melongena Extract in the Treatment of Arsenical Skin Lesion</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Solanum Melongena Extract in the Treatment of Arsenical Skin Lesion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University, Dhaka, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University, Dhaka, Bangladesh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Solanum melongena is a common vegetable contains phytochemicals which prevent, reduce or&#xD;
      delay the oxidation of DNA and alter the cellular signal transduction pathways controlling&#xD;
      cell proliferation and apoptosis of human cancer. The skin of Solanum melongena peel contains&#xD;
      nasunin an anthocyanins and chlorogenic acid which have anti-inflammatory, antioxidant,&#xD;
      antimutagenic and antiangiogenic properties. Extract of Solanum melongena is used in actinic&#xD;
      keratosis and Squamous cell carcinoma of the skin. This study will determine any change in&#xD;
      arsenical skin lesion after administrating Solanum melongena extract cream.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Bangladesh is grappling with the world greatest ever environmental health disaster in&#xD;
      history. About three decades, more than thirty millions people subsistence with this problem&#xD;
      without any potential treatment. So, now arsenic crisis as a major issue and becomes a demand&#xD;
      of era to find out the way to solve this problem. Chronic ingestion of arsenic contaminated&#xD;
      water is a silent killer of the human because even it may cause death by carcinoma. Arsenic&#xD;
      has an affinity to keratin-rich tissue like skin, hair, nail due to the presence of&#xD;
      sulphydryl group, as a consequence, they manifest of clinical symptoms like hyperpigmentation&#xD;
      or melanosis, diffuse dark brown spot of skin or characteristic rain drop appearance over the&#xD;
      trunks, limbs; keratosis. Even due to prolong exposure to arsenic e.g. invasive skin lesion&#xD;
      as Bown's disease and squamous cell carcinoma appear. Arsenic as neglected disease arsenic&#xD;
      patients has no established treatment except preventive and supportive treatment of melanosis&#xD;
      by drinking arsenic free water and salicylic acid as keratolytic substance. But the malignant&#xD;
      condition of arsenic skin lesion treatment is not yet documented. Solanum melongena belongs&#xD;
      to Leptostemonum Clade (the &quot;spine&quot; solanums) species-rice in solanaceae. It also called&#xD;
      brinjal or eggplant. Solanum melongena is a common vegetable contains phytochemicals which&#xD;
      prevent, reduce or delay the oxidation of DNA and alter the cellular signal transduction&#xD;
      pathways controlling cell proliferation and apoptosis of human cancer. Polyphenols of Solanum&#xD;
      melongena exhibit an anticancer effect both in vitro and in vivo experiments. Polyphenol&#xD;
      reduces scavenge free radicals, induce apoptosis, inhibit cell proliferation and angiogenesis&#xD;
      and exhibit phytoestrogen activity. On other hand, they suppress the NF-κB and the activating&#xD;
      protein (AP-1), inhibit the mitogen-activated proteins (MAPKs), the protein kinase and growth&#xD;
      factor receptor-mediated pathways which are involved in cell cycle arrest and possess&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory properties. Solanum melongena has solasodine glycoalkaloids which are&#xD;
      cytotoxic and bind with endogenous endocytic lectin of cancer cell membrane and induce&#xD;
      apoptosis and cell death both in vivo and in vitro. The skin of Solanum melongena peel&#xD;
      contains nasunin an anthocyanins and chlorogenic acid which have anti-inflammatory,&#xD;
      antioxidant, antimutagenic and antiangiogenic properties. It has a cytotoxic effect on brine&#xD;
      shrimp. Therefore, this study will be conducted to determine is there any change in the&#xD;
      patient with arsenical skin lesions before and after application of topical Solanum melongena&#xD;
      extract cream. Twenty-five patients with arsenical skin lesions will be recruited on the&#xD;
      basis of inclusion and exclusion criteria after IRB approval. The patients will be applied&#xD;
      Solanum melongena extract cream twice daily for 12 weeks without any interruption. Water and&#xD;
      nails samples will be collected for confirming the diagnosis. Blood samples will be collected&#xD;
      before and after treatment to evaluate the liver and renal function tests. So, this study&#xD;
      will determine any change in arsenical skin lesion after administrating Solanum melongena&#xD;
      extract cream.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 14, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Solanum melongena peel extract</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in palmer arsenical keratosis</measure>
    <time_frame>Clinical outcome [Time Frame:[0 week (baseline),12 weeks (end)] [Safety Issue: No]] [Safety Issue: No]]</time_frame>
    <description>Size of keratotic lesion will be decreased</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the liver function test</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in lesion size [ Time Frame: [0 week (baseline), 12 weeks (end)] [Safety Issue: No]] [Safety Issue: No]]</time_frame>
    <description>Abnormal liver function tests will be returned toward normal</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Arsenical Keratosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Solanum melongena peel extract 0.05%</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>25 Patients Solanum melongena peel extract 0.05% Twice daily applied topically for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Solanum melongena peel extract 0.05%</intervention_name>
    <description>Administered topically twice daily for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Solanum melongena peel extract 0.05%</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Solanum melongena peel extract cream</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 18-60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sex: Both male and female&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arsenicosis: Severe arsenical skin lesions with Bowen's disease or Squamous cell&#xD;
             carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drinking arsenic contaminated water (&gt; 50 µg/L) for more than 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient voluntarily agreed to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who understood the instruction of applying medicine and apply it as he or she&#xD;
             will be instructed&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: Less than 18 and above 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expectant, Pregnant and lactating mother&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major health problems Tuberculosis, Hepatic diseases, Renal diseases, Systamic lupus&#xD;
             erythrometosis,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rheumatoid arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with other skin diseases like ectopic dermatitis, psoriasis, eczema, drug&#xD;
             allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Food allergy of Solanum melongena&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who received treatment within last three months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with Bowen disease and Squamous cell carcinoma due to other cause&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient did not voluntarily agree to participants&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mir Misbahuddin, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>BSMMU</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bhanga</name>
      <address>
        <city>Faridpur</city>
        <zip>7830</zip>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 12, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 20, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 25, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bangabandhu Sheikh Mujib Medical University, Dhaka, Bangladesh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Mir Misbahuddin</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Keratosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

