<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04371042</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2576</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04371042</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PROtocol of Metabolic and Cryptogenic livEr Disease regisTry for intEgration of Omic Studies</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROMETEO</acronym>
  <official_title>PROtocol of Metabolic and Cryptogenic livEr Disease regisTry for intEgration of Omic Studies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione Policlinico Universitario Agostino Gemelli IRCCS</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main aim of the study is to set up an observational cohort with NAFLD (Non-alcoholic&#xD;
      fatty liver disease) at different stage of disease (from simple steatosis to cirrhosis and/or&#xD;
      HCC-Hepatocellular carcinoma) and for comparative purpose a cohort of subjects with diabetes&#xD;
      and/or obesity and/or other risk factors (i.e. psoriasis, IBD (inflammatory bowel disease),&#xD;
      dyslipidemia) without NAFLD in order to have a clinical phenotypical characterization and the&#xD;
      collection of biological specimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will collect clinical data, biological samples and imaging results in order to perform&#xD;
      future cross-sectional studies and/or longitudinal studies for elucidating pathways of the&#xD;
      disease and develop and validate biomarkers for diagnosis, prognosis and monitoring liver&#xD;
      disease and comorbidities in order to contribute to precision medicine in this field.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD) is characterized by the excessive accumulation of&#xD;
      triglycerides in the liver and is often associated, in the absence of significant alcohol&#xD;
      consumption, to insulin resistance and to the metabolic syndrome of which it shares the most&#xD;
      frequent clinical manifestations (hypertension, dyslipidemia, visceral adiposity, glucose&#xD;
      intolerance). Because of the pandemic spread of obesity and diabetes and by virtue of the&#xD;
      best control of viral hepatitis, in western countries NAFLD is the most common cause of liver&#xD;
      injury with prevalence that is around 20-30% of the general population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      NAFLD encompasses a broad spectrum of liver conditions associated with fat accumulation that&#xD;
      ranges from benign fatty liver (FL), non-progressive liver fat accumulation to severe liver&#xD;
      injury, cirrhosis, and liver failure. The histological signature ballooning degeneration&#xD;
      (with or without Mallory bodies) and/or inflammation and/or fibrosis is typical of&#xD;
      nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH), that may progress to: i) cirrhosis and contribute to one&#xD;
      category of cryptogenic cirrhosis (CC), in which steatosis may be present or absent; ii)&#xD;
      hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC). Furthermore, the correct indication of subjects with&#xD;
      significant fibrosis in the highest risk populations could also contribute to reducing the&#xD;
      increasing prevalence of cirrhosis secondary to NAFLD as an indication to liver&#xD;
      transplantation. Moreover, the expected impact of NAFLD and its complication on public health&#xD;
      is quite impressive worldwide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hepatic steatosis is emerging as an early and common determinant of many of these diseases&#xD;
      and co-morbidities, as reported also by our research group. Fatty liver, in fact, may cause&#xD;
      lipid accumulation, inflammation, and oxidative stress at the hepatic level leading to NAFLD,&#xD;
      and facilitating the occurrence of additional clinical co-morbidities by the activation of&#xD;
      common molecular and cellular mechanisms. In fact, NAFLD is correlated to several metabolic&#xD;
      diseases, such as Metabolic Syndrome (MetS), Cardiovascular Diseases (CVD), Chronic Kidney&#xD;
      Disease (CKD), Hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), Obstructive sleep apnoea (OSA), Polycystic&#xD;
      ovary syndrome (PCOS) and Chronic Plaque Psoriasis NAFLD is considered the liver&#xD;
      manifestation of metabolic syndrome and beyond effects on the liver (risk of cirrhosis and&#xD;
      HCC), can also increase the risk of morbidity due to CVD, CKD, psoriasis, PCOS, OSA, and&#xD;
      mortality related to T2DM, coronary heart disease, even in absence of well-known risk factors&#xD;
      (i.e. smoking, hypertension, T2DM, dyslipidaemia). In this regard, interventions such as&#xD;
      lifestyle modification (proper nutrition and exercise), along with pharmacological agents are&#xD;
      vital to reduce co-morbidities. Interestingly, the role of the liver seems to be central in&#xD;
      the onset and progression of its co-morbidities. However, there are still insufficient&#xD;
      information regarding the disease pathways and mechanisms common to these disorders&#xD;
      co-occurring with NAFLD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within this scenario the appropriate management of NAFLD may have a beneficial effect also on&#xD;
      the co-morbidities. At today, the investigation of the common pathogenic mechanisms of the&#xD;
      abovementioned inter-related diseases has been approached rather ineffectively, leaving major&#xD;
      holes and undermining the development of appropriate management programs for NAFLD/NASH and&#xD;
      its related co-morbidities. In order to fill the gap and increase the quality of data for a&#xD;
      multi-omic approach we decided to set up a certified local repository. Therefore, the&#xD;
      understanding of the pathogenesis of NAFLD and its relevance in the development of related&#xD;
      co-morbidities is crucial to guide the development of future treatments and to inform&#xD;
      European Union health and economic policies. The clinical impact of NAFLD is considerable and&#xD;
      represents a real driver of the major clinical outcomes that impact on the health of the&#xD;
      individual, consequently creating a real burden of disease, especially in those populations&#xD;
      considered at higher risk of fibrosis such as diabetics or obese. The global burden of&#xD;
      NAFLD/NASH and CC require a multi-omic approach in order to prevent and to provide health&#xD;
      plans for avoid implications for the population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the high epidemiology impact, there are still significant areas of unmet clinical&#xD;
      need in NAFLD: i) the lack of knowledge on molecular mechanism leading to progression of&#xD;
      liver disease; ii) a poor understanding of disease sub-phenotypes; iii) the lack of&#xD;
      biomarkers of disease progression that allow risk stratification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current availability of the -omics technologies generating libraries of genome-wide data,&#xD;
      metabolomes, proteomes and microbiome will allow a precision medicine approach in order to&#xD;
      improve the knowledge of disease and to generate a personalized approach to improve the&#xD;
      clinical practice and optimize the public health plans for prevention programs and NAFLD&#xD;
      management.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2035</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2035</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Registry creation</measure>
    <time_frame>35 years</time_frame>
    <description>Set up an observational cohort with NAFLD at different stage of disease (from simple steatosis to cirrhosis and/or HCC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>NAFLD - Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Cirrhosis</condition>
  <condition>Liver Cancer</condition>
  <condition>NASH - Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis</condition>
  <condition>HCC - Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Fatty Liver</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Clinical data will be collected in the electronic form at baseline and thereafter on an&#xD;
      annual basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the prospective project, biological sample (DNA, RNA, sera or whole blood; urine, feces,&#xD;
      bile and liver tissues) are collected, only on a voluntary basis, at the time of recruitment&#xD;
      and follow-up and stored at the biobank facility XBIOGEM at Fondazione Policlinico Univ. A.&#xD;
      Gemelli IRCCS in Rome&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients under the care at Fondazione Policlinico Gemelli IRCCS Hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical phenotype of NAFLD (simple steatosis, NASH, metabolic cirrhosis, NAFLD-HCC)&#xD;
             based on any of:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver biopsy providing histological evidence of NAFLD or,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biochemical and/or radiological findings consistent with NAFLD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Average alcohol consumption ≤21/14 units/week (males/females) in preceding 6 months&#xD;
             and no history of sustained excessive consumption of alcohol in past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clearance of HCV infection with new DAAs drugs with a SVR (sustained virological&#xD;
             response) period &gt; 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of risk factors for NAFLD (i.e. diabetes, metabolic syndrome, obesity,&#xD;
             psoriasis) and absence of fatty liver at US&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal or inability (lack of capacity) to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Average alcohol ingestion &gt;21/14 units/week (males/females) in preceding 6 months or&#xD;
             history of sustained excessive consumption of alcohol in past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or presence of Type 1 diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not meeting inclusion criteria or judged by the investigator to be unsuitable&#xD;
             for inclusion in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>LUCA MIELE, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+390631051</phone>
    <email>luca.miele@policlinicogemelli.it; luca.miele@unicatt.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Catholic University of Rome, Fondazione Policlinico Gemelli IRCCS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <state>Rome/lazio/italy</state>
        <zip>00168</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Luca Miele, MD PhD</last_name>
      <email>luca.miele@policlinicogemelli.it; luca.miele@unicatt.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 1, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>NAFLD</keyword>
  <keyword>NASH</keyword>
  <keyword>NON-ALCHOLIC</keyword>
  <keyword>LIVER</keyword>
  <keyword>CIRRHOSIS</keyword>
  <keyword>HEPATOCELLULAR CARCINOMA</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

