<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01832714</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NKI-W81XWH-12-C-0205</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01832714</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of Oculomotor, Vestibular and Reaction Time Response Following a Concussive Event</brief_title>
  <acronym>NKI-RIF1</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment of Oculomotor, Vestibular and Reaction Time Response Following a Concussive Event</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Neurolign</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Neurolign</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to evaluate the use of a collection of tests that measure the eye&#xD;
      response, balance, oculomotor and reaction time tests to aid in the diagnosis of mTBI. The&#xD;
      tests use highly precise measurement tools to assess various neurologic functions. (For&#xD;
      example, high-speed cameras to record eye movement, high-end motors to precisely spin and&#xD;
      move the subject, comprehensive analysis to stitch together the stimulus and the response.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A battery of oculomotor, vestibular and reaction time tests will generate variables that&#xD;
           when properly weighted and run through a given multi-variant analysis, will separate the&#xD;
           subjects into one of two groups, mTBI or not-mTBI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A battery of neurologic assessment tests including reaction time, vestibular and&#xD;
           oculomotor tests taxing a range of neurologic functions and executed using one or more&#xD;
           of the I-Portal® family of devices, will generate responses that, when used by a trained&#xD;
           physician, can aid in the diagnosis of an mTBI.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study uses a prospective, between-subjects design comparing an Investigational (mTBI)&#xD;
      Group to a Control Group. The Investigational Group includes SM who had been diagnosed with&#xD;
      an mTBI. The Control Group consists of SM who do not have clinical symptoms consistent with&#xD;
      mTBI. There will be 90 participants in each group, for a target total of 180 study&#xD;
      participants&#xD;
&#xD;
      Existing mTBI evaluation tools will be used to qualify the type and severity of a patient's&#xD;
      mTBI symptoms. After the volunteer has been assessed by a physician, the following&#xD;
      questionnaires and screening tools will be administered:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Demographic, included control and patient demographics, education, military service, see&#xD;
           Appendix A;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  History of health problems and treatments included medication and mTBI history and&#xD;
           stress level before testing, including page 1 of MACE, see Appendix B; History of health&#xD;
           problems and treatments included medication and mTBI history and stress level before&#xD;
           testing, including page 1 of MACE, used for seconds and third tests only, see Appendix&#xD;
           B1;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Glasgow Coma Scale, use only in 24 hrs after accident, see Appendix C;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Functional Gait Assessment(FGA) - This is an assessment where the individual is asked to&#xD;
           perform ten gait tasks. Each gait task is scored by a trained observer on a 0-3 scale&#xD;
           (with 0 being could not perform and 3 being performed well). The individual will end up&#xD;
           with a total FGA of between 0-30. The test is very sensitive for demonstrating balance&#xD;
           dysfunction and improvement.(see Appendix D)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Trail Making Test (TMT) - This test is a cognitive test in which subjects use a pencil&#xD;
           to draw a line between an ordered series of letters or letters/numbers on a paper.&#xD;
           Subjects are instructed to follow the appropriate order without lifting the pencil from&#xD;
           the paper. Time to completion is a sensitive measure of cognitive performance. (see&#xD;
           Appendix E)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dizziness Handicap Inventory,(DHI)-This validated questionnaire is commonly used by&#xD;
           clinicians to qualify and quantify symptoms associated with dizziness, light-headedness,&#xD;
           vertigo, migraine associated dizziness, and to assist with identifying complaints of&#xD;
           dizziness related to anxiety, depression, post-traumatic-stress disorder, etc. This tool&#xD;
           will capture subjective symptoms associated with mTBI prior to completing the objective&#xD;
           measures (see Appendix F)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Device will be comprehensive oculomotor/ neuro-otologic testing system. System components:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Motorized Chair that can move in up to 3 axis&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Full field Optokinetic stimulus&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pursuit Tracker™ - laser target generator&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Isolation enclosure&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient monitoring and communication technology&#xD;
&#xD;
      FDA classification: The NOTC is covered under an FDA 510K, and certified to standards&#xD;
      60601-1, 60601-1-1, 60601-1-2, and 60601-1-4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Modifications to approved device:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Included by manufacturer:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A new function to existing buttons for reaction time test&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Audio stimulus for audio reaction time test&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. 2 stationary LED's installed inside enclosure ceiling for crHIT test&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigational software which incorporates newly defined oculomotor and reaction time tests&#xD;
      designed to investigate mTBI will be installed on the device.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Variability of latency in reflexive saccades (ms)</measure>
    <time_frame>within 7 days of a concussion event</time_frame>
    <description>Examine the latency of subjects with mTBI with respect to mean latency and standard deviation of control subjects.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Variability of latency in reaction time test (ms)</measure>
    <time_frame>within 7 days of a concussion event</time_frame>
    <description>Examine the latency of subjects with mTBI with respect to mean latency and standard deviation of control subjects.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Variability of error in subjective visual vertical test (degrees)</measure>
    <time_frame>within 7 days of a concussion event</time_frame>
    <description>Examine the mean error of subjects with mTBI with respect to mean error and standard deviation of control subjects.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Concussion, Mild</condition>
  <condition>Concussion, Intermediate</condition>
  <condition>Concussion, Severe</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>mTBI</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects who undergo an mTBI event</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects who do not undergo an mTBI</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The Investigational Group includes Service Members (SM) and civilians who had been&#xD;
        diagnosed with an mTBI. The Control Group consists of SM and civilians who do not have&#xD;
        clinical symptoms consistent with mTBI. There will be at least 90 participants in each&#xD;
        group, for a target total of at least 180 study participants.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria for all subjects (Control and mTBI) - Males or females from 19 - 45years&#xD;
        of age and of all races.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Inclusion criteria for mTBI Subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Diagnosed with traumatic brain injury utilizing 2007 DoD Standard diagnosis of&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1) Exposed to an event,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2) Suffered alteration or loss of consciousness secondary to the event, and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  3) Had a sequelae from the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for all subjects (Control and mTBI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brain injury resulting from a penetrating wound to the head, neck, face or brain (to&#xD;
             include gunshot wounds)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of severe aphasia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons whom have had an mTBI within the prior month and are symptomatic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons with a previous history of multiple mTBIs and are symptomatic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of neuropsychiatric disorders antedating the head injury (e.g.&#xD;
             hypochondriasis, major depression, schizophrenia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior disorders of hearing and balance including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Meniere's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic migraine&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Multiple sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vestibular neuritis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vestibular schwannoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sudden sensorineural hearing loss&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cerebrovascular disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic disorders: e.g. chronic renal failure, cirrhosis of the liver, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medications which depress the sensorium precluding patient compliance with the testing&#xD;
             (considered on a case-by-case basis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous contraindicating surgeries at the discretion of the study physicians or&#xD;
             audiologists&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Exclusion criteria for Control Subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concussion within the last year (12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Repeated blast exposure&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex Kiderman, PhD ME</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Neuro Kinetics, Inc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Naval Medical Center San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92134</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Madigan Army Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tacoma</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98431</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 10, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 16, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 16, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 16, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Concussion</keyword>
  <keyword>mTBI</keyword>
  <keyword>military</keyword>
  <keyword>MACE</keyword>
  <keyword>NKI</keyword>
  <keyword>NOTC</keyword>
  <keyword>VNG</keyword>
  <keyword>VOG</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuro Kinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>oculomotor</keyword>
  <keyword>vestibular</keyword>
  <keyword>reaction time</keyword>
  <keyword>I-Portal</keyword>
  <keyword>eye tracking</keyword>
  <keyword>Dizziness Handicap Inventory</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Concussion</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

