<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04130282</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VAC077</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04130282</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>VAC077: Safety and Immunogenicity of the Pfs25-IMX313/Matrix-M Vaccine</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ia Study to Assess Safety and Immunogenicity of the Plasmodium Falciparum Malaria Vaccine Candidate Pfs25-IMX313 in Matrix-M1 Adjuvant in Healthy Adults Living in the UK</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Oxford</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open label, single-site, first-in-human, Phase Ia study to assess safety and&#xD;
      immunogenicity of the Plasmodium falciparum malaria vaccine candidate Pfs25-IMX313 in&#xD;
      Matrix-M1 adjuvant in healthy adults living in the UK&#xD;
&#xD;
      Volunteers will receive 3 doses of vaccine over 2 months and will be followed up for&#xD;
      approximately 8 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This Phase 1a clinical trial is designed primarily to assess the safety and tolerability of&#xD;
      the Pfs25-IMX313/Matrix-M transmission blocking vaccine in healthy adult volunteers. An&#xD;
      important secondary objective is to to assess the immune response to the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8 volunteers will receive 3 doses of 10µg Pfs25-IMX313 in 50 µg Matrix-M1 on days 0, 28 and&#xD;
      56. Blood samples will be taken for safety testing and to collect information about the&#xD;
      immune response. Any symptoms that occur after vaccination will also be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy volunteers aged 18-45 will be recruited in England at the Centre for Clinical&#xD;
      Vaccinology and Tropical Medicine, Churchill Hospital, Oxford.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Delays caused by Covid-19&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 27, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 22, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 22, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of safety and reactogenicity through collection of data on the frequency, duration and severity of solicited and unsolicited adverse events.</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>The following parameters will be assessed:&#xD;
Frequency, duration and severity of solicited local reactogenicity signs and symptoms for 7 days following each vaccination&#xD;
Frequency, duration and severity of solicited systemic reactogenicity signs and symptoms for 7 days following the vaccination&#xD;
Frequency, duration and severity of unsolicited adverse events for 28 days following the vaccination&#xD;
Change from baseline for safety haematological and biochemical laboratory measures, which will presented according to local grading scales, for 28 days following vaccination&#xD;
Frequency, duration and severity of serious adverse events during the whole study duration</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Humoral and cellular immunogenicity of the Pfs25-IMX313/Matrix-M1 vaccine, when administered to healthy adult volunteers</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Pfs25-specific immunogenicity will be assessed by immunological assays, with comparison before and after vaccination. The main outcome measures will be humoral and B cell responses to the Pfs25 protein - total IgG, isotypes and avidity; T cell responses to Pfs25 by ex vivo ELISpot and flow cytometry assays.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ex-vivo efficacy of the Pfs25-IMX313/Matrix-M1 vaccine, when administered to healthy adult volunteers</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>Ex vivo functional blocking activity of purified IgG against the P. falciparum NF54 strain will be assessed by standard membrane feeding assay.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Malaria,Falciparum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>8 volunteers receiving 3 doses of 10µg Pfs25-IMX313 in 50 µg Matrix-M1 on days 0, 28 and 56</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pfs25-IMX313/Matrix-M1</intervention_name>
    <description>3 doses of 10µg Pfs25-IMX313 in 50 µg Matrix-M1 on days 0, 28 and 56</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The volunteer must satisfy all the following criteria to be eligible for the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy adult aged 18 to 45 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing (in the Investigator's opinion) to comply with all study&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to allow the Investigators to discuss the volunteer's medical history with&#xD;
             their General Practitioner.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women only: Must practice continuous effective contraception for the duration of the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement to refrain from blood donation for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent to participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The volunteer may not enter the study if any of the following apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinical malaria (any species).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Travel to a clearly malaria endemic locality during the study period or within the&#xD;
             preceding six months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of immunoglobulins or blood products (e.g., blood transfusion) at any time in the&#xD;
             past.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any vaccine in the 30 days preceding enrolment, or planned receipt of any&#xD;
             other vaccine within 30 days following each vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of an investigational product in the 30 days preceding enrolment, or planned&#xD;
             receipt during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent involvement in another clinical trial or planned involvement during the&#xD;
             study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior receipt of an investigational vaccine likely to impact on interpretation of the&#xD;
             trial data, as assessed by the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient state, including HIV&#xD;
             infection; asplenia; recurrent, severe infections and chronic (more than 14 days)&#xD;
             immunosuppressant medication within the past 6 months (inhaled and topical steroids&#xD;
             are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of&#xD;
             the vaccine (e.g. egg products)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of anaphylaxis in reaction to vaccinations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, lactation or intention to become pregnant during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cancer (except basal cell carcinoma of the skin and cervical carcinoma in&#xD;
             situ).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of serious psychiatric condition that may affect participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other serious chronic illness requiring hospital specialist supervision.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected or known current alcohol abuse as defined by an alcohol intake of greater&#xD;
             than 25 standard UK units every week.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected or known injecting drug abuse in the 5 years preceding enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) detected in serum.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Seropositive for hepatitis C virus (antibodies to HCV) at screening or (unless has&#xD;
             taken part in a prior hepatitis C vaccine study with confirmed negative HCV antibodies&#xD;
             prior to participation in that study, and negative HCV RNA PCR at screening for this&#xD;
             study).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteers unable to be closely followed for social, geographic or psychological&#xD;
             reasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant abnormal finding on biochemistry or haematology blood&#xD;
             tests, urinalysis or clinical examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other significant disease, disorder, or finding which may significantly increase&#xD;
             the risk to the volunteer because of participation in the study, affect the ability of&#xD;
             the volunteer to participate in the study or impair interpretation of the study data.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability of the study team to contact the volunteer's GP to confirm medical history&#xD;
             and safety to participate.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Angela Minassian, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CCVTM, University of Oxford, Churchill Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <zip>OX3 7LE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 8, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 17, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pfs25</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Malaria</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malaria, Falciparum</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

