<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04132869</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1 ASTWH190077-01-00</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1 ASTWH190077-01-00</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04132869</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>YES! We Can PLAY: A Physical Activity and Nutrition After-School Program for Middle School Students</brief_title>
  <official_title>YES! We Can PLAY: A Physical Activity and Nutrition After School Program for 6th Graders</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Birmingham City School System</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      YES! We can PLAY: A Physical Activity and Nutrition After-School Program for Middle School&#xD;
      Students, is a collaborative partnership between the University of Alabama at Birmingham and&#xD;
      the Birmingham City Schools District to decrease health disparities in obesity and&#xD;
      obesity-related diseases by increasing physical activity levels and healthy eating behavior&#xD;
      among Birmingham youth. Through the after-school program in which children choose from a menu&#xD;
      of sports programming, the proposed intervention will increase physical literacy of the&#xD;
      students through education related to both physical activity and nutrition as well as&#xD;
      social-emotional learning which will increase students' ability to integrate the information&#xD;
      and activities of the program into their lives moving forward.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Physical Activity Guidelines for Americans recommend that youth engage in 60 minutes of&#xD;
      MVPA per day, but most U.S. youth do not meet this goal. Already inadequate levels of&#xD;
      physical activity drop still further as children transition from elementary school to middle&#xD;
      school; during this transition sports participation and overall physical activity decrease.&#xD;
      According to data from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Youth Risk Behavior&#xD;
      Survey data from 2009, the most recent year for which Alabama data is available for&#xD;
      middle-school students, only 30% or fewer of the responding youth reported adherence to&#xD;
      Physical Activity Guidelines for Americans. Additional data indicates these poor health&#xD;
      behaviors in middle school carry forward into high school. Ninth graders in Alabama report&#xD;
      low levels of vegetable and fruit consumption, with roughly 10% of the students indicating&#xD;
      that they had eaten no fruit or vegetables at all in the 7 days prior to the survey. In a&#xD;
      study conducted in Birmingham, researchers found that school-based resources were the most&#xD;
      important determinants of physical activity among youth ages 12-14. This information is&#xD;
      particularly meaningful when placed in context with the high prevalence of sedentary behavior&#xD;
      among Birmingham youth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because physical activity and sports participation decrease in the transition to middle&#xD;
      school, interventions that provide opportunities for physical activity and sports&#xD;
      participation for middle school students have the potential to impact the short-term and&#xD;
      long-term health of youth. In Alabama middle schools, only 7th and 8th graders are eligible&#xD;
      to play on Alabama High School Athletic Association (AHSAA) sports teams, leaving 6th graders&#xD;
      who do not have access to club or recreational sports due to finances, transportation or&#xD;
      other issues related to poverty, with few options for participating in organized sports. For&#xD;
      students who live in neighborhoods that experience high rates of crime, informal physical&#xD;
      activity options are rare as well. Lack of opportunities for both organized and informal&#xD;
      physical activity may lead 6th graders to drop sports participation altogether, which could&#xD;
      impact lifetime physical activity habits and lead to lower health status. Because of&#xD;
      COVID-19, 7th and 8th grade sports are currently on hold, so they have few options for sports&#xD;
      and physical activity participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The school setting is a prime location for improving eating habits and increasing physical&#xD;
      activity since schools have direct contact with the children for about eight hours a day, and&#xD;
      out of school time programs have been shown to be a desirable environment for such&#xD;
      intervention and can be effective in promoting higher fruit and vegetable intake, as well as&#xD;
      increased physical activity. Currently the Birmingham City Schools District for 3rd through&#xD;
      5th graders. Let's Move began over 15 years ago and has evolved since. There are&#xD;
      approximately 1300 students that participate in some of the Let's Move program components,&#xD;
      which include 2 days per week of after-school sports programming. The program emphasizes&#xD;
      basic skills instruction while encouraging a positive, fitness-oriented, after-school program&#xD;
      supporting healthy lifestyles. Let's Move serves as important foundation for the organization&#xD;
      and implementation of the proposed program as it expands the content and elevates the target&#xD;
      audience to middle school students. Due to COVID restrictions, the YES! program will operate&#xD;
      virtually. in out of school time. During the school year it will take place after school at&#xD;
      least 3 days per week. Once public health guidelines allow for in person programming,&#xD;
      participants may choose to take part in the program face-to-face at his/her school (during&#xD;
      the school year) or at the YMCA of Birmingham's Youth Center (during the summer). The virtual&#xD;
      option will continue to be available during the summer as well to Birmingham City Schools&#xD;
      students.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 13, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This research study uses a cluster randomized design who attend the intervention schools. For the control group, we will invite students from comparison schools that do not participate in the intervention.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes of MVPA per day - accelerometer</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Number of minutes of MVPA per day - recorded by accelerometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes of MVPA per day - accelerometer</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of minutes of MVPA per day - recorded by accelerometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes of MVPA per day - accelerometer</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of minutes of MVPA per day - recorded by accelerometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minutes of MVPA per day - accelerometer</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of minutes of MVPA per day - recorded by accelerometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">336</enrollment>
  <condition>Child Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In Spring of 2020, all 6th graders in Wave 1 intervention schools (6 schools), which include 561 total 6th graders, will be invited to participate the intervention. Those in the experimental group will complete all measures according to the timeline. Those not in the experimental group will also complete the intervention, but will not participate in measurements. In Fall 2020 all 6th graders who attend the Wave 2 intervention schools (schools that were the control schools in Spring), will be invited to participate the intervention. Those in the experimental group will complete all measures on schedule. *Note these activities were delay due to schools shutting down in March 2020 because of COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Wave 1 comparison schools (2 Schools) have a total of 267 6th graders. Students will be invited to join the comparison group. and will have measurements taken at baseline and 6 months. Wave 2 comparison schools (3 Schools) have a total of 363 6th graders adn will be invited to join the comparison group and will have measurements taken at baseline and 6 months. These students will continue with their normal activities as usual.*Note these activities were delay due to schools shutting down in March 2020 because of COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sports Readiness Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Sixth graders will participate in a 6 month after-school program in which each daily session will last 90 minutes, 60 minutes of which will be moderate to vigorous physical activity. Two sports tracks will be offered during each 8-week season, and children will choose which they prefer. Coaches will be trained through a one day capacity building session and will receive online training throughout the program. Coaches will integrate sports readiness/physical activity programming, nutrition and healthy eating, and social emotional learning into the program with a focus on habit formation. A text-based platform will be utilized to encourage habits learned in the active portion of the program during June and July as well as on weekends during the intervention. Parents will be sent fliers weekly summarizing concepts addressed, and will be invited to cooking classes to watch students compete.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In 6th-8th grade in targeted middle schools&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 11-15 at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be able to attend an after school program daily&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>11 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>15 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lori B Bateman, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lori B Bateman, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>205-934-2924</phone>
    <email>loribateman@uabmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Olivia Affuso, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>205-975-7662</phone>
    <email>oaffuso@uab.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35205</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lori B Bateman, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>205-934-2924</phone>
      <email>loribateman@uabmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Olivia Affuso, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>205-975-7662</phone>
      <email>oaffuso@uab.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35209</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 14, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 16, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lori Bateman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Instructor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>social emotional learning</keyword>
  <keyword>healthy eating</keyword>
  <keyword>sports readiness</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pediatric Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

