<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02469194</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UPCC 09915</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02469194</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mechanisms and Predictors of Unusual Radiation or Chemotherapy Toxicity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mechanisms and Predictors of Unusual Radiation or Chemotherapy Toxicity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Abramson Cancer Center of the University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Abramson Cancer Center of the University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In general, the toxicity of radiation therapy and chemotherapy exhibits a strong&#xD;
      dose-response relationship. However, patients receiving similar doses still exhibit a range&#xD;
      of toxicity responses due to a variety of factors, including comorbid conditions, disease&#xD;
      (cancer) specific factors, and inter-individual genetic variation. A very small percentage of&#xD;
      patients experience side effects that are either extremely severe or extremely mild compared&#xD;
      to the majority of patients for the dose of radiation or chemotherapy given. Currently, the&#xD;
      reasons for this are not entirely clear, but likely relate to patient specific factors such&#xD;
      as immune response, cell/tissue repair capacity and other factors that fundamentally rely on&#xD;
      rare genetic variations at loci involved in these responses. For example, patients with&#xD;
      homozygous deletions in DNA damage response genes such as ATM are uniquely sensitive to DNA&#xD;
      damaging agents. Many patients with severe, homozygous mutations in such genes have other&#xD;
      sequela that lead to medical recognition of the syndrome prior to therapy. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that patients with unusually severe toxicity from therapy that do not exhibit&#xD;
      classical signs of homozygous mutation syndromes are heterozygous for nonfunctional or&#xD;
      hypofunctional alleles at these loci, such that the defect is only uncovered under the&#xD;
      relatively acute, severe stress on that pathway by radiation or chemotherapy. Conversely,&#xD;
      patients with very mild reactions could exhibit rare variants/combinations of variants that&#xD;
      make them uniquely resistant to chemotherapy or radiotherapy toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study is to better understand these mechanisms with the eventual goal of&#xD;
      developing predictive markers that will allow us to help individually tailor cancer therapy&#xD;
      is in future patients. Will accomplish these goals by studying a variety of factors from a&#xD;
      single vial of blood. These will include circulating proteins and hormones, circulating cells&#xD;
      and the levels and sequences of white blood cell DNA or RNA using a variety of techniques&#xD;
      including but not limited to determination of cytokine/hormone levels, proteomic analysis,&#xD;
      immunocytochemical assays, whole exome sequencing and qPCR.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Severe or Mild Toxicity From Radiotherapy and/or Chemotherapy</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood Draw</intervention_name>
    <description>5-10 cc of whole blood will be obtained using standard, sterile venipuncture techniques</description>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      5-10 cc of whole blood will be obtained using standard, sterile venipuncture techniques&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects will be recruited from the inpatient and outpatient clinical practices in the&#xD;
        University of Pennsylvania Health System. There will be no attempt to advertise enrollment&#xD;
        on this protocol to physicians outside of the treating departments (i.e. Radiation&#xD;
        Oncology, Surgery, Medical Oncology).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects will be age 18 or greater Subjects will have undergone chemotherapy and/or&#xD;
             radiotherapy and experienced unusually mild or severe toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects for who, after initial review of medical records by study team personnel are&#xD;
             not judged by the PI and/or sub-investigators to have sufficiently unusual toxicity&#xD;
             from therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Keith Cengel, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Abramson Cancer Center of the University of Pennsylvania</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Abramson Cancer Center of the University of Pennsylvania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 10, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 11, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 10, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 10, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 11, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

