<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04647851</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1442844Pilot</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04647851</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Remote Exercise Study for Individuals With Down Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of a Remote Exercise Intervention on Aerobic Endurance, Strength, Gait and Balance in Individuals With Down Syndrome - Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Nevada, Las Vegas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Nevada, Las Vegas</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This pilot study aims to test whether remote delivery of the exercise intervention provides a&#xD;
      sufficient training stimulus. This pilot study will be remote and online-only, and will have&#xD;
      no in-person interaction, data collection or intervention. 20 Participants will participate&#xD;
      in a 12-wk, 3hrs/wk remote exercise intervention and in a pre- and a posttest remote testing&#xD;
      session. We will use Zoom for all testing and exercise sessions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Design: Repeated measures design: 20 participants will participate in the remote exercise&#xD;
      intervention study with a pre-test and a post-test to investigate training effects on aerobic&#xD;
      endurance, strength, balance and gait.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: The program we will be using is specifically developed for individuals with&#xD;
      Down syndrome based on the Mann Method PT Principles. The MMPT Principles TM focus on a&#xD;
      progressive program of therapeutic activity (cardiovascular activity), therapeutic exercise&#xD;
      (foundational strengthening and hip strengthening activities), and neuromuscular&#xD;
      rehabilitation (visual/vestibular and balance activities) to address the unique needs of&#xD;
      individuals with Down syndrome. This program has been developed and successfully implemented&#xD;
      in Down syndrome activity centers across the country. This program will be offered through&#xD;
      Zoom. Intensity will be submaximal for both data collection and during the exercise sessions,&#xD;
      and recorded with Polar heart rate monitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements: We will use only field tests instead of the original lab-based testing for&#xD;
      aerobic endurance, strength, balance and gait, and all tests will be conducted remotely.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline measurements: height, weight, circumferences Aerobic endurance: 2 Minute Step Test:&#xD;
      participant marches in place as fast as possible with a set height for how high to lift the&#xD;
      knees, for two minutes. Outcome is heart rate and number of steps in two minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Strength: 30 Second Chair Stand and 5 Times Chair Stand: participants starts seated, then&#xD;
      stands up and sits down as fast as possible, first counting the number of times within 30&#xD;
      seconds, then timing the number of seconds for 5 times.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Balance: Timed Up and Go: This is a timed test where the participant stands up from a chair,&#xD;
      walk 10ft, turn around, walk back and sit down again, as fast as possible. Modified CTSIB&#xD;
      (Clinical Test on Sensory Information on Balance) and FICSIT-4 (Frailty and Injuries:&#xD;
      Cooperative Studies of Intervention Techniques): Standing balance in different conditions and&#xD;
      positions. Functional Reach Test: Reaching from a standing position as far as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Gait: Comfortable and Fast Walking Speed, Observational Gait Analysis based on anterior,&#xD;
      posterior and lateral video recordings of the participant's walking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, participants (and/or parents/caregivers for the group with Down syndrome) will&#xD;
      complete a health history questionnaire and physical activity questionnaire, a questionnaire&#xD;
      about risk of falling (Short Falls Efficacy Scale-1) and about attitudes towards exercise&#xD;
      (Health Matters Evaluation Toolkit).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 18, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Pre- and post test design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Aerobic endurance</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>We measure aerobic endurance with the 2-min Step Test, outcome measure is number of times the right leg is lifted.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Leg strength</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>30 Second Chair Stand, measured in number of times to stand up.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Leg strength</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>5 times Chair Stand, measured in number of seconds it takes to stand up and sit down 5 times.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Timed Up and Go, measured in seconds to complete task.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Modified CTSIB (Clinical Test on Sensory Information on Balance), measured in seconds</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>FICSIT-4 (Frailty and Injuries: Cooperative Studies of Intervention Techniques, measured in seconds</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Functional reach, measured in centimeter</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gait</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Walking speed, measured in meter/second</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gait</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Observational Gait Analysis, measured in total score for deviations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Down Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Remote exercise intervention Down syndrome</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention: The program we will be using is specifically developed for individuals with Down syndrome based on the Mann Method PT Principles. The MMPT Principles TM focus on a progressive program of therapeutic activity (cardiovascular activity), therapeutic exercise (foundational strengthening and hip strengthening activities), and neuromuscular rehabilitation (visual/vestibular and balance activities) to address the unique needs of individuals with Down syndrome. This program has been developed and successfully implemented in Down syndrome activity centers across the country. This program will be offered through Zoom. Intensity will be submaximal for both data collection and during the exercise sessions, and recorded with Polar heart rate monitors.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remote exercise intervention Down syndrome</intervention_name>
    <description>See arm description</description>
    <arm_group_label>Remote exercise intervention Down syndrome</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between 18 and 35 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  generally healthy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  sedentary (defined as being involved in less than 30 minutes of moderately-intense&#xD;
             physical activity per day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  additionally for the participants with Down syndrome:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  diagnosis of Down syndrome trisomy 21 and&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  normal thyroid function or stable thyroid function (and medications) for at least&#xD;
                  6 mo.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  congenital heart disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  atherosclerotic or other vascular disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  asthma or other pulmonary disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hypertension (defined BP &gt;140/90 mmHg);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  blood pressure below 90/60 mmHg;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of pre-syncope or syncope;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diabetes (defined as Hba1c of &gt;7.5% or use of glucose lowering medication);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe obesity (defined as BMI &gt;40);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  medications affecting heart rate, blood pressure or arterial function;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anti-inflammatory medication including NSAIDS;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  current smoking and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thessa Hilgenkamp, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Nevada, Las Vegas</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Nevada, Las Vegas</name>
      <address>
        <city>Las Vegas</city>
        <state>Nevada</state>
        <zip>89154</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://unlvptlabs.com/research-projects/</url>
    <description>Study information on UNLVPT CARE-Lab website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 28, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Nevada, Las Vegas</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thessa Hilgenkamp</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Down Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual patient data will be made available to other researchers upon request.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

