<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04642105</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S64726</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04642105</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch Study in Epilepsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Multimodal Profiling of People With Epilepsy to Determine Which Signals Are Clinically Useful for Long-term Home Monitoring</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Byteflies</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators plan to determine whether it is possible to use a small, unobtrusive&#xD;
      wearable device (the Sensor Dot with Plug 'n Patch system) to follow-up epilepsy in the home&#xD;
      environment through measurement of different biosignals (EEG, ECG, EMG, motion, skin&#xD;
      temperature, respiration and oxygen saturation) for prolonged periods in patients with&#xD;
      epilepsy. If this is possible, the investigators will study the chronobiology of epilepsy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the investigators will make use of a small, discrete and unobtrusive wearable,&#xD;
      the Sensor-Dot (https://www.byteflies.com/) and newly developed electrode patches (Plug 'n&#xD;
      Patch system). The aim is multimodal profiling of people with epilepsy to determine which&#xD;
      signals are clinically useful for long-term home monitoring. Biosignals that will be&#xD;
      registered include EEG, EMG, and ECG, respiration, oxygen saturation, skin temperature and&#xD;
      motion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first part of the study is hospital-based and will last 5 days. The investigators will&#xD;
      compare the biosignals of the Sensor Dot and the Plug 'n Patch system with those measured&#xD;
      with hospital equipment. Participants are 15 patients with refractory focal epilepsy who will&#xD;
      be admitted to the hospital for long-term videoEEG registration of epileptic seizures as part&#xD;
      of a presurgical evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second part of the study is home-based and will last for a maximum of 1 year. Sixty&#xD;
      participants will be selected with refractory idiopathic generalized epilepsy (n=15),&#xD;
      refractory focal epilepsy (n=30) and frequent nocturnal tonic-clonic seizures (n=15). The aim&#xD;
      is to determine and improve usability of the Sensor Dot and Plug 'n Patch system upon&#xD;
      long-term use in the home environment. The investigators will determine the number of&#xD;
      patients with side effects and adverse events of the Sensor Dot and Plug 'n Patch system,&#xD;
      e.g. contact allergic eczema. The investigators will determine the total time that&#xD;
      participants wear the Sensor Dot and Plug 'n Patch system, and the reason why participants do&#xD;
      not wear it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators further aim to determine whether epileptic seizures occur in cycles, and&#xD;
      will study interactions between epilepsy and sleep. The investigators will also study whether&#xD;
      body temperature occurs in recurring cycles and is related with the occurrence of epileptic&#xD;
      seizures. The investigators will study changes in EEG, respiration, heart rate, skin&#xD;
      temperature and oxygen saturation during tonic-clonic seizures. The investigators will&#xD;
      determine whether it is possible that the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system can be used as&#xD;
      a seizure forecaster.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Hospital-based study: 15 patients will be selected in this study which will last 5 days.&#xD;
Home-based study: 60 patients will be selected in this study which will last a maximum of 1 year.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Epileptic seizures</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the hospital-based study, the investigators will compare the number epileptic seizures measured with the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system in comparison with the hospital-based equipment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the hospital-based study, the investigators will compare the heartrate of participants measured with the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system in comparison with hospital-based equipment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the hospital-based study, the investigators will compare oxygen saturation of participants measured with a finger pulse oximetry versus the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Respiration</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the hospital-based study, the investigators will compare the respiration rate of participants measured with a chest belt during videoEEG registration versus the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Skin temperature</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days</time_frame>
    <description>In the hospital-based study, the investigators will compare the skin temperature of participants using axillary measurement with a negative temperature coefficient thermistor versus the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system, which is based on infrared thermometry.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with adverse events and side effects</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>In the home-based study, the investigators will determine the number of patients with side effects and adverse events of the Sensor Dot and Plug 'n Patch system, e.g. contact allergic eczema</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total time that participants wear the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>In the home-based study, the investigators will determine the total time that participants wear the Sensor Dot and Plug 'n Patch system, and the reason why participants do not wear it</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cycles in epileptic seizure</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To study whether epileptic seizures occur in recurring cycles or patterns</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cycles in interictal epileptic discharges</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To study whether interictal epileptic discharges occur in recurring cycles or patterns</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cycles in sleep patterns</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To study whether sleep occurs in recurring cycles or patterns</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cycles in body temperature</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To study whether body temperature occurs in recurring cycles or patterns</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seizure forecasting</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To study whether cycles in epileptic seizures, interictal epileptic discharges, sleep and skin temperature allow to define a pro-ictal state during which the occurrence of epileptic seizures is more likely, i.e. seizure forecasting</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physiological changes during tonic-clonic seizures</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To study changes in EEG, respiration, heart rate, skin temperature and oxygen saturation during tonic-clonic seizures</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Catamenial epilepsy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if changes in IEDs, skin temperature, sleep cycles can define seizure recurrence in women with catamenial epilepsy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hospital-based study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The investigators will select 15 patients with refractory focal epilepsy who are admitted to the videoEEG room for longterm videoEEG recording as part of a presurgical evaluation. The Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch recordings will be compared with the gold-standard videoEEG recordings.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Home-based study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The investigators will select 30 patients with refractory focal epilepsy, 15 patients with refractory idiopathic generalized epilepsy and 15 patients with frequent tonic-clonic seizures, i.e. a group at increased risk for sudden unexpected death in epilepsy (SUDEP).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system</intervention_name>
    <description>We will use a small, unobtrusive wearable (Sensor-Dot) to measure different biosignals (EEG, ECG, EMG, motion, skin temperature, respiration and oxygen saturation) for up to one year using newly developed skin adhesives and patches (Plug 'n Patch system)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Home-based study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Hospital-based study</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are 18 years of age or older, who signed an informed consent form, and&#xD;
             teenagers over 16 years of age who assent, with their parents signing an informed&#xD;
             consent form, and:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Epilepsy syndrome: idiopathic generalized epilepsy (n=15), patients at increased risk&#xD;
             for SUDEP, i.e. have more than 1 nocturnal tonic clonic seizures (TCS) per month&#xD;
             (n=15), refractory focal epilepsy with a presurgical evaluation at UZ Leuven (n=30)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum one seizure per month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is able and motivated to handle the Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system&#xD;
             independently, to fill out the Helpilepsy app on a daily basis and to wear the&#xD;
             Sensor-Dot and Plug 'n Patch system for a full year 24/24-7/7; fallback option for&#xD;
             patients for whom wearing the device during the day is too obtrusive: measurement only&#xD;
             during the evening and nighttime.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide written informed consent or assent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to electrodes and patches.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Implanted device, such as a pacemaker, cardioverter defibrillator (ICD), and/or neural&#xD;
             stimulation device.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wim Van Paesschen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UZ Leuven</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wim Van Paesschen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+3216344332</phone>
    <email>wim.vanpaesschen@uzleuven.be</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <state>Vlaams-Brabant</state>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jaiver Macea, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+3216348273</phone>
      <email>jaiver.macea@kuleuven.be</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Wim Van Paesschen, MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+3216344332</phone>
      <email>Wim.vanpaesschen@uzleuven.be</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Paesschen WV. The future of seizure detection. Lancet Neurol. 2018 Mar;17(3):200-202. doi: 10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30034-6.</citation>
    <PMID>29452676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Verdru J, Van Paesschen W. Wearable seizure detection devices in refractory epilepsy. Acta Neurol Belg. 2020 Dec;120(6):1271-1281. doi: 10.1007/s13760-020-01417-z. Epub 2020 Jul 6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32632710</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mikkelsen KB, Ebajemito JK, Bonmati-Carrion MA, Santhi N, Revell VL, Atzori G, Della Monica C, Debener S, Dijk DJ, Sterr A, de Vos M. Machine-learning-derived sleep-wake staging from around-the-ear electroencephalogram outperforms manual scoring and actigraphy. J Sleep Res. 2019 Apr;28(2):e12786. doi: 10.1111/jsr.12786. Epub 2018 Nov 13.</citation>
    <PMID>30421469</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gu Y, Cleeren E, Dan J, Claes K, Van Paesschen W, Van Huffel S, Hunyadi B. Comparison between Scalp EEG and Behind-the-Ear EEG for Development of a Wearable Seizure Detection System for Patients with Focal Epilepsy. Sensors (Basel). 2017 Dec 23;18(1). pii: E29. doi: 10.3390/s18010029.</citation>
    <PMID>29295522</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Cooman T, Vandecasteele K, Varon C, Hunyadi B, Cleeren E, Van Paesschen W, Van Huffel S. Personalizing Heart Rate-Based Seizure Detection Using Supervised SVM Transfer Learning. Front Neurol. 2020 Feb 26;11:145. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2020.00145. eCollection 2020.</citation>
    <PMID>32161573</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vandecasteele K, De Cooman T, Dan J, Cleeren E, Van Huffel S, Hunyadi B, Van Paesschen W. Visual seizure annotation and automated seizure detection using behind-the-ear electroencephalographic channels. Epilepsia. 2020 Apr;61(4):766-775. doi: 10.1111/epi.16470. Epub 2020 Mar 11.</citation>
    <PMID>32160324</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We plan to share the individual biosignals (EEG, EMG, ECG, movement, skin temperature, respiration), de-identified demographics and epilepsy-related data two years after the finish of the study upon request to researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data wil be shared after the end of the study. We do not foresee an end-date.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data will be made available upon request to researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal. Proposals should be directed to Wim.vanpaesschen@uzleuven.be</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

