<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04645602</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-493</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04645602</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lenvatinib and Pembrolizumab Combination Therapy In HPV-associated Recurrent Respiratory Papilloma Patients With Laryngeal, Tracheal, and/or Pulmonary Involvement</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Lenvatinib in Combination With Pembrolizumab in HPV-associated Recurrent Respiratory Papilloma Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eisai Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study is studying Lenvatinib in combination with Pembrolizumab in people with&#xD;
      human papillomavirus (HPV)-associated recurrent respiratory papillomatosis (RRP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The names of the study drugs involved in this study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pembrolizumab&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lenvatinib&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a non-randomized phase II trial in adult male and female subjects diagnosed with&#xD;
      human papillomavirus (HPV)-associated Recurrent Respiratory Papilloma to test the safety and&#xD;
      efficacy of the drug combination Lenvatinib and Pembrolizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has not approved Pembrolizumab or Lenvatinib for&#xD;
      HPV-associated Recurrent Respiratory Papilloma but they have been approved for other uses.&#xD;
      Lenvatinib works by blocking certain proteins that are associated with tumor growth.&#xD;
      Lenvatinib also blocks the growth of blood vessels feeding tumors to cause tumor cell death.&#xD;
      Pembrolizumab helps the body's immune system destroy cancer cells. This study is&#xD;
      investigating whether the combination of Lenvatinib and Pembrolizumab may eliminate&#xD;
      HPV-associated RRPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research study procedures include screening for eligibility, study treatment and&#xD;
      evaluations and follow up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will receive study treatment for up to 2 years and will be followed for 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is expected that about 21 people will take part in this research study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Merck is supporting this research study by providing Pembrolizumab and supporting the&#xD;
      research study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eisai is supporting this research study by providing Lenvatinib.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Based on clinical assessment and/or RECIST 1.1 criteria for those patients with RECIST evaluable disease.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events will be classified and graded according to the CTCAE v.5.0. Frequencies of adverse events will be summarized overall.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood Biomarkers Changes</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to a post-baseline timepoint up to 2 years and/or end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline to a post-baseline timepoint will also be compared between patients whose disease responded (CR,PR) and those whose disease did not respond using the Wilcoxon rank-sum test .</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tissue Biomarkers Changes</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to a post-baseline timepoint up to 2 years and/or end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Changes from baseline to a post-baseline timepoint will also be compared between patients whose disease responded (CR,PR) and those whose disease did not respond using the Wilcoxon rank-sum test .</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to a post-baseline timepoint up to 2 years and/or end of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life (QOL) will be assessed via self-report questionnaires</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">21</enrollment>
  <condition>Human Papilloma Virus</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Respiratory Papillomatosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib + Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will take:&#xD;
Lenvatinib - At a pre-determined dose, 1x daily during each 3 week study cycle up to 35 cycles/2 years&#xD;
Pembrolizumab - At a pre-determined dose, 1x on Day 1 of each 3 week study cycle up to 35 cycles/2 years&#xD;
Participants will be given a drug diary and asked to document information in the drug diary about the study treatment.&#xD;
Participants will be asked to check their blood pressure 3x every week and document in a supplied diary.&#xD;
Participants will be followed up to one (1) year after study treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenvatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Pill taken by mouth, once daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib + Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lenvima</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous injection through a vein (IV).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib + Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Keytruda</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have histologically or cytologically confirmed respiratory&#xD;
             papillomas that involves the trachea, lungs, and/or larynx. If a subject is enrolled&#xD;
             with laryngeal disease only, the subject must have undergone at least 3 or more&#xD;
             surgeries/procedures in any one year to remove the lesions from their larynx. Subjects&#xD;
             must have at least evaluable disease either based on RECIST 1.1 and/or endoscopic&#xD;
             parameters, as discussed above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be required to provide tissue from a newly obtained biopsy of a lesion. Newly obtained&#xD;
             is defined as a specimen obtained up to 6 weeks (42 days) prior to study registration.&#xD;
             Subjects for whom newly-obtained samples cannot be provided (e.g. inaccessible or&#xD;
             subject safety concern) may submit an archived specimen only upon agreement from the&#xD;
             PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have confirmed human papillomavirus-associated lesions based on in-situ hybridization&#xD;
             testing and/or polymerase chain reaction which may be performed on a newly obtained&#xD;
             biopsy or archived sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status of 0 to 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Table 1 Adequate Organ Function Laboratory Values&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  System Laboratory Value&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematological&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1500/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Platelets ≥100 000/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Hemoglobin ≥9.0 g/dL or ≥5.6 mmol/L (a)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Renal&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Creatinine OR Measured or calculated (b) creatinine clearance (GFR can also&#xD;
                       be used in place of creatinine or CrCl) ≤1.5 × institutional ULN OR ≥30&#xD;
                       mL/min for participant with creatinine levels &gt;1.5 × institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatic&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Total bilirubin ≤1.5 × institutional ULN OR direct bilirubin ≤ institutional&#xD;
                       ULN for participants with total bilirubin levels &gt;1.5 × institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  AST (SGOT) and ALT (SGPT) ≤2.5 × ULN (≤5 × institutional ULN for&#xD;
                       participants with liver metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Thyroid&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  TSH Institutional normal limit&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Free T4 Institutional normal limit&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pancreatic&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Amylase &lt; 1.5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Lipase &lt; 1.5 x institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Coagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  International normalized ratio (INR) OR prothrombin time (PT) Activated&#xD;
                       partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) ≤1.5 × institutional ULN unless&#xD;
                       participant is receiving anticoagulant therapy as long as PT or aPTT is&#xD;
                       within therapeutic range of intended use of anticoagulants&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT (SGPT)=alanine aminotransferase (serum glutamic pyruvic transaminase); AST&#xD;
             (SGOT)=aspartate aminotransferase (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase);&#xD;
             GFR=glomerular filtration rate; ULN=upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Criteria must be met without erythropoietin dependency and without packed red&#xD;
                  blood cell (pRBC) transfusion within last 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Creatinine clearance (CrCl) should be calculated per institutional standard.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Note: This table includes eligibility-defining laboratory value requirements for&#xD;
             treatment; laboratory value requirements should be adapted according to local&#xD;
             regulations and guidelines for the administration of specific chemotherapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with known history or current symptoms of cardiac disease, or&#xD;
                  history of treatment with cardiotoxic agents, should have a clinical risk&#xD;
                  assessment of cardiac function using the New York Heart Association Functional&#xD;
                  Classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible for this trial, participants should be class 2B or better.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequately controlled blood pressure with or without antihypertensive medications&#xD;
             defined as systolic BP ≤ 150 mmHg and diastolic BP ≤ 90 mmHg at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subject of childbearing potential should have a negative urine or serum&#xD;
             pregnancy test within 28 days of study registration*. If the urine test is positive or&#xD;
             cannot be confirmed as negative, a serum pregnancy test will be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
             *Please refer to the study calendar for requirements regarding a pregnancy test 72&#xD;
             hours prior to receiving any dose of study medication upon subject enrollment into the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of childbearing potential should be willing to use 2 methods of birth&#xD;
             control or be surgically sterile, or abstain from heterosexual activity for the course&#xD;
             of the study through 120 days after the last dose of study medication. Subjects of&#xD;
             childbearing potential are those who have not been surgically sterilized or have not&#xD;
             been free from menses for &gt; 1 year. The methods of surgical sterilization include&#xD;
             having had a hysterectomy (removal of the uterus), bilateral oophorectomy (removal of&#xD;
             both ovaries), tubal ligation (having your tubes tied), and transvaginal occlusion&#xD;
             (blocking the tubes with a coil).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men treated or enrolled on this protocol must also agree to use adequate contraception&#xD;
             prior to the study, for the duration of study participation, and 4 months after&#xD;
             completion of study drugs administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to complete Patient Medication and Blood Pressure diaries by themselves or&#xD;
             with assistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior systemic anti-cancer therapy including investigational agents&#xD;
             within 4 weeks prior to study enrollment. Note: Participants must have recovered from&#xD;
             all AEs due to previous therapies to ≤Grade 1 or baseline. Participants with ≤Grade 2&#xD;
             neuropathy may be eligible. Note: If participant received major surgery, they must&#xD;
             have recovered adequately from the toxicity and/or complications from the intervention&#xD;
             prior to starting study treatment.Endoscopic debridement of RRP lesions is NOT&#xD;
             considered a major surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior radiotherapy within 2 weeks of start of study treatment.&#xD;
             Participants must have recovered from all radiation-related toxicities, not require&#xD;
             corticosteroids, and not have had radiation pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Examples of live vaccines include, but are not limited to, the following: measles, mumps,&#xD;
        rubella, varicella/zoster (chicken pox), yellow fever, rabies, Bacillus Calmette-Guérin&#xD;
        (BCG), and typhoid vaccine. Seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are generally killed&#xD;
        virus vaccines and are allowed; however, intranasal influenza vaccines (eg, FluMist®) are&#xD;
        live attenuated vaccines and are not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently participating in or has participated in a study of an investigational&#xD;
             agent within 4 weeks prior to the first dose of study treatment. NOTE: Participants&#xD;
             who have entered the follow-up phase of an investigational study may participate as&#xD;
             long as it has been 4 weeks after the last dose of the previous investigational agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a diagnosis of immunodeficiency or is receiving chronic systemic steroid therapy&#xD;
             (in dosing exceeding 10 mg daily of prednisone equivalent) or any other form of&#xD;
             immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the first dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known additional malignancy that is progressing or has required active treatment&#xD;
             within the past 3 years. NOTE: Participants with basal cell carcinoma of the skin,&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, well-differentiated thyroid cancer, follicular&#xD;
             lymphoma, carcinoma in situ (e.g. breast carcinoma, cervical cancer in situ) or other&#xD;
             indolent malignancy not requiring active treatment are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with invasive squamous cell carcinoma derived from their RRP who are not&#xD;
             considered appropriate for surgery, radiation therapy, or chemotherapy by their&#xD;
             treating oncology team may be considered eligible for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions (&gt; Grade 3) attributed to compounds of similar chemical&#xD;
             or biologic composition to pembrolizumab or lenvatinib and/or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has active autoimmune disease that has required systemic treatment in the past 2 years&#xD;
             (i.e. with use of disease modifying agents, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             drugs). Replacement therapy (e.g., thyroxine, insulin, or physiologic corticosteroid&#xD;
             replacement therapy for adrenal or pituitary insufficiency, etc.) is not considered a&#xD;
             form of systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or has current&#xD;
             pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection. Note: No HIV&#xD;
             testing is required unless mandated by local health authority.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of Hepatitis B (defined as Hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg]&#xD;
             reactive) or known active Hepatitis C virus (defined as HCV RNA is detected)&#xD;
             infection. NOTE: No testing for Hepatitis B and Hepatitis C is required unless&#xD;
             mandated by local health authority.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of active TB (Bacillus Tuberculosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled blood pressure (systolic BP&gt;150 mmHg or diastolic BP &gt;90 mmHG) in spite&#xD;
             of an optimized regimen of antihypertensive medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant cardiovascular impairment: history of congestive heart failure greater&#xD;
             than New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II, unstable angina, myocardial&#xD;
             infarction or stroke within 6 months of the first dose of study drug, or cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia requiring medical treatment at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has QTc prolongation &gt;480 msec, as calculated by either the Bazett or Fridericia&#xD;
             formula, as per institutional standard&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding or thrombotic disorders or subjects at risk for severe hemorrhage. The degree&#xD;
             of tumor invasion/infiltration of major blood vessels (e.g. carotid artery) should be&#xD;
             considered because of the potential risk of severe hemorrhage associated with tumor&#xD;
             shrinkage/necrosis following lenvatinib therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has &gt;1+ proteinuria on urine dipstick testing unless a 24-hour urine collection for&#xD;
             quantitative assessment indicates that the urine protein is &lt; 1g/24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has clinically significant gastrointestinal malabsorption syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of colitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of posterior reversible encephalopathy syndrome (PRES).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with history or current evidence of any condition, therapy, or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that might confound the results of the study, interfere with the subject's&#xD;
             participation for the full duration of the study, or is not in the best interest of&#xD;
             the subject to participate, in the opinion of the treating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance&#xD;
             with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is pregnant or breastfeeding, or expecting to conceive or father children within the&#xD;
             projected duration of the study, starting with the screening visit through 120 days&#xD;
             after the last dose of trial treatment. Pregnant women are excluded from this study&#xD;
             because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants&#xD;
             secondary to treatment of the mother with pembrolizumab and/or lenvatinib, and&#xD;
             breastfeeding should be discontinued.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sara I Pai, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sara I Pai, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>617-726-5251</phone>
    <email>sara.pai@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sara I Pai, MD, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>617-726-5251</phone>
      <email>sara.pai@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sara I Pai, MD, PHD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sara Pai, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Human Papilloma Virus</keyword>
  <keyword>Recurrent Respiratory Papillomatosis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Papillomavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Papilloma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lenvatinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The Dana-Farber / Harvard Cancer Center encourages and supports the responsible and ethical sharing of data from clinical trials. De-identified participant data from the final research dataset used in the published manuscript may only be shared under the terms of a Data Use Agreement. Requests may be directed to: [contact information for Sponsor Investigator or designee]. The protocol and statistical analysis plan will be made available on Clinicaltrials.gov only as required by federal regulation or as a condition of awards and agreements supporting the research.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data can be shared no earlier than 1 year following the date of publication</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Contact the Partners Innovations team at http://www.partners.org/innovation</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

