<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04647981</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2018-A03392-53</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04647981</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Diagnostic Performance Evaluation Study of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor Test.</brief_title>
  <acronym>Xpert Bladder</acronym>
  <official_title>Diagnostic Performance Evaluation Study of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor Test in the Surveillance of Patients With Non-Invasive Bladder Urothelial Carcinoma.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Clinique Beau Soleil</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cepheid</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Team Languedoc Mutualité / Nouvelles technologies</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Clinique Beau Soleil</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Non-muscle invasive bladder tumor is a condition that can recur with a risk of progression to&#xD;
      an infiltrating tumor of the muscle. Regular follow-up is therefore essential to detect any&#xD;
      recurrence or progression of the disease as early as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, the monitoring of this type of tumor is done by cystoscopy (examination that&#xD;
      allows visualization of the bladder wall) associated with urinary cytology (analysis of urine&#xD;
      to detect an abnormality). These examinations have their limits, they may not detect certain&#xD;
      types of tumors or may be painful.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To reduce the number of cystoscopies and replace urinary cytology, several urinary markers&#xD;
      have been developed in recent years. This is the case of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor&#xD;
      test, which is a non-invasive, in vitro diagnostic urine test dedicated to the monitoring of&#xD;
      patients with bladder cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the diagnostic performance of the Xpert® Bladder&#xD;
      Cancer Monitor test for the detection of bladder tumor recurrence, compared to reference&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study consists of a urine sample. During the participant's medical consultation with&#xD;
      his/her urologist, for the monitoring of his/her non-invasive bladder tumor(s), a cystoscopy&#xD;
      is performed. Before the examination, the participant gives a urine sample, which will be&#xD;
      analyzed by the Xpert®Bladder Cancer Monitor test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this non-interventional monocentric study is to compare the sensitivity&#xD;
      of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor test performed on the GeneXpert® system to the&#xD;
      sensitivity of cytology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reference test is a combination of cystoscopy and histology. The algorithm is as follows:&#xD;
      if the cystoscopy is negative, it will be considered that there is no recurrence; if the&#xD;
      cystoscopy is positive, a biopsy of the &quot;abnormal&quot; area will be performed and histology will&#xD;
      be requested. If the histology is positive, it will be considered that there is a recurrence;&#xD;
      otherwise, it will be considered that there is no recurrence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The gold standard is, therefore, the couple: cystoscopy +/- histology&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A cystoscopy will be considered positive if to the naked eye the urologist sees a&#xD;
           macroscopically suspicious lesion (e.g. a budding lesion).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the cystoscopy is positive, the urologist will take a sample of the suspect lesion&#xD;
           and have it analyzed by the pathologist. If the lesion analyzed has the same histology&#xD;
           as the original lesion, it will be considered a recurrence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 22, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 15, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare sensitivities of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor Test and the urinary cytology test.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The two tests, the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor and the urinary cytology, made during the follow-up of patients with non-invasive-muscle bladder tumor are compared to the gold standard, which is the reference examination: the couple cystoscopy/histology.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor test.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor test for the detection of bladder tumor recurrence (stage, grade).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">320</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-Invasive Bladder Urothelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Non-Invasive Bladder Papillary Urothelial Carcinoma, Low Grade</condition>
  <condition>Non-Invasive Bladder Papillary Urothelial Carcinoma, High Grade</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Xpert® Bladder Test</arm_group_label>
    <description>A urine sample is collected before cystoscopy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor Test</intervention_name>
    <description>The urine sample is analyzed with the Xpert® Bladder Cancer Monitor test.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Xpert® Bladder Test</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A person with antecedents of non-invasive bladder tumors and who has had previous&#xD;
        transurethral resection of bladder tumor.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a social security scheme.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has signed a form of no objection to the use of the data.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had a transurethral resection of bladder tumor revealing&#xD;
             non-invasive-muscle bladder tumor prior to inclusion within a maximum of 5 years from&#xD;
             the date of diagnosis to the absence of recurrence since then.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is seen for a follow-up cystoscopy on the day of the visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Non-Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vulnerable persons (Article L 1121-6 of the Public Health Code).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults subject to legal protection or unable to express their consent (Article 1121-8&#xD;
             of the Public Health Code).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons with a bladder tumor other than a non-invasive bladder tumor (i.e., invasive&#xD;
             bladder cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A person who has undergone bladder tumor resection or therapy with Calmette-Guerin&#xD;
             bacilli or with Mitomycin C less than 6 weeks (42 days) prior to inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Participant no longer wishing to participate in the study, or in the course of the study&#xD;
        with a refusal to use the data until exit from the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohamed Trabelssi, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinique Beau Soleil</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinique Beau Soleil</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <state>Hérault</state>
        <zip>34070</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.cepheid.com/en/tests/Oncology-Genetics/Xpert-Bladder-Cancer-Monitor</url>
    <description>Qualitative monitoring for recurrence in patients previously diagnosed with bladder cancer in 90 minutes.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bladder</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

