<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04641624</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CengizGWCH11</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04641624</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>sFlt- 1, PIGF, and Niacin Levels in Women With Premature Ovarian Insufficiency</brief_title>
  <acronym>POİ&amp;niacin</acronym>
  <official_title>Soluble Fms-like Tyrosine Kinase-1, Proangiogenic Protein Placental Growth Factor, and Niacin Levels in Women With Premature Ovarian Insufficiency</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim: To evaluate serum soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1, proangiogenic protein placental&#xD;
      growth factor, and niacin levels in women with premature ovarian insufficiency (POI) and to&#xD;
      compare the results with those of healthy subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: This prospective study will be included 45 women with idiopathic premature ovarian&#xD;
      insufficiency and 45 controls. The blood for analysis will be obtained at the early&#xD;
      follicular phase of the menstrual cycle and serum soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1,&#xD;
      proangiogenic protein placental growth factor, and niacin levels will be measured using a&#xD;
      commercially available ELISA kit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This will be an observational prospective cohort study conducted at Obstetrics and Gynecology&#xD;
      Department of Cengiz Gokcek Obstetrics and Children's Hospital between November 2020 and&#xD;
      April 2021. The investigators will be recruited 45 subjects with idiopathic POI, and 45&#xD;
      healthy patients were selected for the control group. All patients will be given their oral&#xD;
      and written informed consent before their inclusion in the study. The protocol was approved&#xD;
      by the Ethics Committee for Clinical Research of Gaziantep University (Reference number:&#xD;
      2020/320). The study strictly will be adhered to the principles of the Declaration of&#xD;
      Helsinki.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Women between the ages of 18-39 will be included. A volunteer group of healthy women who will&#xD;
      be visited the gynecology clinic for routine examinations and women who will be admitted for&#xD;
      pre-pregnancy tests will be invited randomly to this research as a control group. Healthy&#xD;
      women, who will be returned during their early follicular phase of the menstrual cycle, will&#xD;
      be recruited as the control group subjects. The exclusion criteria will be as follows: women&#xD;
      with evidence for karyotypic, metabolic, toxic, or iatrogenic cause of the ovarian&#xD;
      insufficiency and any women who use any medication for POI treatment. At enrollment, for both&#xD;
      groups, the investigators will be collected data about age, height, weight, BMI, age of&#xD;
      menarche, obstetrics history, history of smoking, regular exercise and family history of POI.&#xD;
      At enrolment, all patients will be underwent vaginal ultrasonography for the assessment of&#xD;
      antral follicle count (AFC) and venous blood sample from the antecubital veins for measuring&#xD;
      serum concentration of soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1, proangiogenic protein placental&#xD;
      growth factor, and niacin, Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH), E2, anti-mullerian hormone&#xD;
      (AMH) and complete blood count (CBC). In control subjects venous blood samples and AFC will&#xD;
      be collected during the early follicular phase of the menstrual cycle. The serum samples will&#xD;
      be stored in aliquots at -80°C prior to the analyses of sFlt- 1, PIGF, and niacin. The serum&#xD;
      soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1, proangiogenic protein placental growth factor, and niacin&#xD;
      level will be measured using a commercially available enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay&#xD;
      (ELISA) kit. Then, this study will be determined maternal serum soluble fms-like tyrosine&#xD;
      kinase-1, proangiogenic protein placental growth factor, and niacin levels in women with POI&#xD;
      (n=45) compared to those of volunteer healthy women (n=45). Then, these three markers levels&#xD;
      will be compared in both group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>sFlt- 1 levels</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure in this analysis will compare sFlt- 1 levels in the idiopathic POI group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PIGF levels</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure in this analysis will compare PIGF levels in the idiopathic POI group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>niacin levels</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure in this analysis will compare niacin levels in the idiopathic POI group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Premature Ovarian Insufficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Premature ovarian insufficiency (POI)</arm_group_label>
    <description>POI is a clinical syndrome defined by loss of ovarian activity before the age of 40 years. POI is characterized by menstrual disturbance (amenorrhea or oligomenorrhea) with raised gonadotrophins and low estradiol.&#xD;
The study population will be consisted of 45 women with POI as study group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>45 patients with normal healthy women as control group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ultrasound assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1, proangiogenic protein placental growth factor, and niacin measurementswith a commercially available enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) kit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Premature ovarian insufficiency (POI)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>soluble fms-like tyrosine kinase-1, proangiogenic protein placental growth factor, and niacin measurements</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators consecutively will be recruited 45 subjects with POI, and 45 healthy&#xD;
        women will be selected for the control group.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  women with POI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy women&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. women with any systemic condition (such as chronic hypertension, renal disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. history of using any medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. drug user&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. history/presence of malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. history of Radiotherapy/chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. polycystic ovary syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. women who had any other acute/chronic infection or fever&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients whose chromosome analysis result is not normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. history of ovarian surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Ovarian cysts/mass&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. lactation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>POI is a clinical syndrome defined by loss of ovarian activity before the age of 40 years. POI is characterized by menstrual disturbance (amenorrhea or oligomenorrhea) with raised gonadotrophins and low estradiol. It is estimated to affect 1% of women under the age of 40, 0.1% under 30 and 0.01% under 20.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>39 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Child's hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gaziantep</city>
        <zip>27010</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>European Society for Human Reproduction and Embryology (ESHRE) Guideline Group on POI, Webber L, Davies M, Anderson R, Bartlett J, Braat D, Cartwright B, Cifkova R, de Muinck Keizer-Schrama S, Hogervorst E, Janse F, Liao L, Vlaisavljevic V, Zillikens C, Vermeulen N. ESHRE Guideline: management of women with premature ovarian insufficiency. Hum Reprod. 2016 May;31(5):926-37. doi: 10.1093/humrep/dew027. Epub 2016 Mar 22.</citation>
    <PMID>27008889</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang S, Sun M, Yu L, Wang Y, Yao Y, Wang D. Niacin Inhibits Apoptosis and Rescues Premature Ovarian Failure. Cell Physiol Biochem. 2018;50(6):2060-2070. doi: 10.1159/000495051. Epub 2018 Nov 9.</citation>
    <PMID>30415247</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Maclaran K, Horner E, Panay N. Premature ovarian failure: long-term sequelae. Menopause Int. 2010 Mar;16(1):38-41. doi: 10.1258/mi.2010.010014. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20424285</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tarasevičienė V, Grybauskienė R, Mačiulevičienė R. sFlt-1, PlGF, sFlt-1/PlGF ratio and uterine artery Doppler for preeclampsia diagnostics. Medicina (Kaunas). 2016;52(6):349-353. doi: 10.1016/j.medici.2016.11.008. Epub 2016 Nov 29.</citation>
    <PMID>27940029</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ali Ovayolu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Menopause, Premature</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Primary Ovarian Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>November 16, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/24/NCT04641624/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

