<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04645225</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MEFV gene in jSLE</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04645225</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Characteristic and MEFV Gene Mutations in Patient With Juvenile Onest Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Characteristic and MEFV Gene Mutations in Patient With Juvenile Onset- Systemic Lupus Erythematosus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim and objectives of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To summarize the main clinical characteristics of patients with jSLE admitted and&#xD;
           followed up in Assiut University children's Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare the MEFV gene mutations in patients with jSLE versus a control group of&#xD;
           healthy children in upper-Egypt a country with a considerably high carrier rate for the&#xD;
           MEFV gene variants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the prevalence and clinical significance of jSLE patients carrying MEFV&#xD;
           variants and assess the impact of MEFV gene mutation on disease severity as assessed by&#xD;
           systemic lupus erythematous disease activity index (SLEDAI).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess if there is a specific MEFV gene mutations that are more associated with jSLE&#xD;
           and/or certain disease manifestations, such as serositis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is a chronic autoimmune inflammatory disease characterized&#xD;
      by the presence of multiple auto antibodies and is associated with a multisystemic illness.&#xD;
      The clinical presentation of SLE ranges from mild to severe and the course of the disease is&#xD;
      unpredictable, with periods of remission and flares. (1) Juvenile-onset systemic lupus&#xD;
      erythematosus (jSLE) patients present more frequently in teenage years and accounts for&#xD;
      15%-20% of lupus population, and they typically have severe disease course than adult&#xD;
      patients. A considerable number of jSLE patients have significant renal or central nervous&#xD;
      system(CNS) involvement at the time of diagnosis.(1) It is slightly more common in girls,&#xD;
      with a sex ratio about 4:3 before puberty; however after puberty, the sex difference&#xD;
      increases to about 4:1.(2) The disease is more common in Native Americans,African Americans,&#xD;
      and Asians. (3) Prevalence rate of jSLE have varied from 4-250 per 100,000 population.(4,5)&#xD;
      JSLE is not rare in Egypt and Africa, representing an important subset that is commonly&#xD;
      overlooked and requires special attention. (6,7) SLE ranges from an insidious, slowly&#xD;
      progressive, chronic disease with exacerbations and remissions,to an acute and rapidly fatal&#xD;
      disease. Constitutiona lfeatures such as fever, fatigue, anorexia, myalgia,weight loss are&#xD;
      common both at onset and during exacerbations of the disease. (8,9) Familial Mediterranean&#xD;
      fever (FMF), an autosomal recessively inherited autoinflammatory disorder, is characterized&#xD;
      by recurrent, self-limited inflammatory attacks involving mainly serosal membranes. The&#xD;
      disease has been associated with variations in the MEFV gene, which encodes the pyrin&#xD;
      protein, in the great majority of patients.(10) FMF is the most common autoinflammatory&#xD;
      disorder, and the rate of heterozygous carrier for MEFV gene variations is quite high in&#xD;
      Eastern Mediterranean countries, including Turkey, Israel, and Armenia.(11,12) A higher acute&#xD;
      phase response has been reported in asymptomatic heterozygous carriers, and heterozygosity&#xD;
      for MEFV variations has been suggested to affect the course of other autoinflammatory&#xD;
      disorders.(13,14) A connection between FMF and collagen diseases were suggested previously by&#xD;
      multiple studies as that MEFV mutations M694V and M680I were observed to be associated with&#xD;
      Behcet's Disease (BD), (15)Also the MEFV variants in exon 10 were suggested to affect the&#xD;
      clinical presentation of Henoch-Schönleinpurpurain populations where FMF is common. (16) The&#xD;
      mutation p.M694V/I in MEFV gene might be a risk factor for systemic onset juvenile idiopathic&#xD;
      arthritis sJIA, (17)and M694V is accepted to be associated with more severe inflammation as&#xD;
      compared to other mutations in patients with Polyarteritis nodosa.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MEFV gene mutations in jSLE</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>compare the MEFV gene mutations in patients with jSLE versus a control group of healthy childrenin upper-Egypt a country with a considerably high carrier rate for the MEFV gene variants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>SLE (Systemic Lupus)</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>. MEFV genetic testing</intervention_name>
    <description>For mutation analysis, 2 ml blood will be with drawn from both patient and control groups in order to obtain genomic DNA. Extraction of DNA molecule from peripheral blood lymphocytes will be done using standard procedures, then amplification of MEFV gene will be done by polymerase chain reaction(PCR). Reversed hybridization technique will be used for identification of MEFV gene mutation.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Sixty patients diagnosed and followed up as jSLE will be consecutively recruited from the&#xD;
        inpatient and outpatient clinic of Immunology and rheumatology department at Assuit&#xD;
        University children's hospital. A control group of 40 age and sex matched control will be&#xD;
        recruited from the surgery outpatient clinic or relatives of the patients. The study will&#xD;
        be conducted during from Jan 2021 to Jan 2022.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age at enrollment ≤18 years old but they should be diagnosed as jSLE before the age of&#xD;
             16 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Both sexes&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The Patients should be diagnosed as jSLE according to 2019 European league against&#xD;
             rheumatism (EULAR)/ American college of rheumatology (ACR) SLE classiﬁcation criteria,&#xD;
             (20) or previous ACR 1997 SLE classification criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No suggestive symptoms of FMF as stated by Tel Hashomer criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1- Patients diagnosed as FMF or receiving colchicine for possibility of FMF. 2-&#xD;
             Patients with other autoimmune disease. 3- Patients not fulfilling the criteria for&#xD;
             diagnosis of SLE&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shrouk A Sayed, Resident</last_name>
    <phone>01157376393</phone>
    <email>mshts4@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gamal A Askar, professor</last_name>
    <phone>01111686162</phone>
    <email>gamal.asker@med.au.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tucker LB, Uribe AG, Fernández M, Vilá LM, McGwin G, Apte M, Fessler BJ, Bastian HM, Reveille JD, Alarcón GS. Adolescent onset of lupus results in more aggressive disease and worse outcomes: results of a nested matched case-control study within LUMINA, a multiethnic US cohort (LUMINA LVII). Lupus. 2008 Apr;17(4):314-22. doi: 10.1177/0961203307087875.</citation>
    <PMID>18413413</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Serdula MK, Rhoads GG. Frequency of systemic lupus erythematosus in different ethnic groups in Hawaii. Arthritis Rheum. 1979 Apr;22(4):328-33.</citation>
    <PMID>426879</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Shrouk Ahmed Mostsfa Sayed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident pediatric</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lupus Erythematosus, Systemic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

