<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04642716</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10840098-327</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04642716</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Free Aminoacids in Saliva as A Diagnostic Biomarker of Periodontal Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Free Aminoacids in Saliva as A Diagnostic Biomarker of Periodontal Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Amino acids (AAs) are organic molecules that are associated with inflammation and innate&#xD;
      immunity diseases with critical roles in the cell repair and protection process. Our aim was&#xD;
      to identify the free amino acids in saliva of a group of periodontitis patients and healthy&#xD;
      individuals and additionally to assess their levels in different periodontal disease types&#xD;
      and compare it to the healthy individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study consisted of three groups: healthy individuals (control(C); n=20), Stage III Grade&#xD;
      B generalized periodontitis (GP-B; n=20), and Stage III Grade C generalized periodontitis&#xD;
      (GP-C; n=20). Clinical periodontal parameters (plaque index (PI), gingival index (GI),&#xD;
      probing depth (PPD), gingival recession (GR), clinical attachment level (CAL) and bleeding on&#xD;
      probing (BOP)) were measured. The amino acid analysis in saliva was accomplished by liquid&#xD;
      chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC MS/MS) as mean concentration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 20, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 3, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Saliva of periodontitis patients collected for analyzing free amino acids.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pocket probing depth</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of the depth of a sulcus or periodontal pocket determined by measuring distance from a gingival margin to the base of the sulcus or pocket with a calibrated periodontal probe.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical attachment level</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical attachment level (or loss, CAL) is a more accurate indicator of the periodontal support around a tooth than probing depth alone. CAL is measured from a fixed point on the tooth that does not change, the CEJ.&#xD;
To calculate CAL, two measurements are needed: distance from the gingival margin to the CEJ and probing depth.&#xD;
In recession: probing depth (+) gingival margin to the CEJ (add). In tissue overgrowth: probing depth (-) gingival margin to the CEJ (subtract)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding on probing</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>referring to bleeding that is induced by gentle manipulation of the tissue at the depth of the gingival sulcus, or interface between the gingiva and a tooth.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Amino acid Analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The AA analysis of the saliva was performed by LC-MS/MS by using the Thermo Scientific TSQ Quantum Access MAX (Thermo Scientific, Schaumburg, IL, USA) according to a modified version of Le et al.'s method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Periodontitis</condition>
  <condition>Diagnoses Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Salivary free amino acids profile observation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Saliva samples of periodontitis patients and healthy controls were collected. The AA analysis of the saliva was performed by LC-MS/MS by using the Thermo Scientific TSQ Quantum Access MAX (Thermo Scientific, Schaumburg, IL, USA) .</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saliva collection of patients and salivary free amino acids analysis</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Salivary free amino acids profile observation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Salivary free amino acids in patients with periodontitis</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        systemically healthy, clinical diagnosis of periodontitis, clinical diagnosis of&#xD;
        periodontal health&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        history of regular use of systemic antibiotics, anti-inflammatory, or antioxidant drugs&#xD;
        (previous 3 months); nonsurgical periodontal treatment (previous 6 months); surgical&#xD;
        periodontal treatment (previous 12 months); presence of &lt;10 teeth; current medications&#xD;
        affecting gingival health (calcium channel blockers, phenytoin, cyclosporine, and hormone&#xD;
        replacement therapy); diabetes diagnosis; rheumatoid arthritis diagnosis; and pregnancy,&#xD;
        lactating, smoking, or excessive alcohol consumption.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istanbul Medipol University, School of Dentistry</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <zip>34083</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Erratum for Wang et al. Glycine stimulates protein synthesis and inhibits oxidative stress in pig small intestinal epithelial cells. J Nutr 2014;144:1540-8. J Nutr. 2016 Sep;146(9):1813. doi: 10.3945/jn.116.236612.</citation>
    <PMID>27587752</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Li P, Yin YL, Li D, Kim SW, Wu G. Amino acids and immune function. Br J Nutr. 2007 Aug;98(2):237-52. Epub 2007 Apr 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17403271</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cruzat VF, Krause M, Newsholme P. Amino acid supplementation and impact on immune function in the context of exercise. J Int Soc Sports Nutr. 2014 Dec 14;11(1):61. doi: 10.1186/s12970-014-0061-8. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>25530736</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Song Zh, Tong G, Xiao K, Jiao le F, Ke Yl, Hu Ch. L-cysteine protects intestinal integrity, attenuates intestinal inflammation and oxidant stress, and modulates NF-κB and Nrf2 pathways in weaned piglets after LPS challenge. Innate Immun. 2016 Apr;22(3):152-61. doi: 10.1177/1753425916632303. Epub 2016 Feb 25.</citation>
    <PMID>26921254</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sido B, Seel C, Hochlehnert A, Breitkreutz R, Dröge W. Low intestinal glutamine level and low glutaminase activity in Crohn's disease: a rational for glutamine supplementation? Dig Dis Sci. 2006 Dec;51(12):2170-9. Epub 2006 Nov 1.</citation>
    <PMID>17078002</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Önder C, Kurgan Ş, Altıngöz SM, Bağış N, Uyanık M, Serdar MA, Kantarcı A, Günhan M. Impact of non-surgical periodontal therapy on saliva and serum levels of markers of oxidative stress. Clin Oral Investig. 2017 Jul;21(6):1961-1969. doi: 10.1007/s00784-016-1984-z. Epub 2016 Nov 2.</citation>
    <PMID>27807715</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dede FÖ, Ozden FO, Avcı B. 8-hydroxy-deoxyguanosine levels in gingival crevicular fluid and saliva in patients with chronic periodontitis after initial periodontal treatment. J Periodontol. 2013 Jun;84(6):821-8. doi: 10.1902/jop.2012.120195. Epub 2012 Aug 16.</citation>
    <PMID>22897655</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rajda C, Tajti J, Komoróczy R, Seres E, Klivényi P, Vécsei L. Amino acids in the saliva of patients with migraine. Headache. 1999 Oct;39(9):644-9.</citation>
    <PMID>11279959</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Le A, Ng A, Kwan T, Cusmano-Ozog K, Cowan TM. A rapid, sensitive method for quantitative analysis of underivatized amino acids by liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS). J Chromatogr B Analyt Technol Biomed Life Sci. 2014 Jan 1;944:166-74. doi: 10.1016/j.jchromb.2013.11.017. Epub 2013 Nov 18.</citation>
    <PMID>24316529</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nur Balci, DDs, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr. Nur Balci</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Saliva</keyword>
  <keyword>Amino acids</keyword>
  <keyword>Periodontitis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Periodontitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Periodontal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

