<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04647890</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CER-FT011-SSc01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04647890</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of FT011 in Systemic Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Randomised, Double Blind, Placebo-controlled Study of the Pharmacokinetics, Pharmacodynamic Effects, and Safety, of Oral FT011 in Participants With Diffuse Systemic Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Certa Therapeutics</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Certa Therapeutics</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      FT011 is an anti-fibrotic drug that is being tested as a treatment for scleroderma. This&#xD;
      study is being conducted to see what the body does to the drug (pharmacokinetics), and what&#xD;
      the drug does to the body (pharmacodynamics).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FT011 levels in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 2, 3, 4, 5 ,6 ,7, and 8 hours post dose on Day one and at Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of maximum concentration (cmax) of FT011</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FT011 levels in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 2, 3, 4,5 ,6 ,7, and 8 hours post dose on Day one and at Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of time to cmax (tmax)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FT011 levels in plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 2, 3, 4, 5 ,6 ,7, and 8 hours post dose on Day one and at Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of area under the concentration time curve (AUC)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs) from Baseline to End of Study</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>TEAEs per arm during study treatment and follow up periods</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mRSS change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12, and Week 16</time_frame>
    <description>The mRSS is a validated physical evaluation of patient's skin thickness rated by clinical palpation using a 0-3 scale (0 = normal skin; 1 = mild thickness; 2 = moderate thickness; 3 = severe thickness with inability to pinch the skin into a fold) for each of 17 surface anatomic areas of the body: face, anterior chest, abdomen, and, with right and left sides of the body separately evaluated, the fingers, forearms, upper arms, thighs, lower legs, dorsum of hands and feet. Individual values are summed and defined as the total skin score. Total score is 0 to 51 with higher scores indicating worse symptomology</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>%FVC change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Percent predicted FVC is calculated using equations incorporating age, gender, and race. It is calculated as (FVC Observed / FVC predicted) x 100, where FVC predicted is calculated relative to a reference population</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physician Global Assessment change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>The physician's assessment of the patient's SSc status will be scored on a 100-mm horizontal VAS, ranging from 0 on the extreme left end of the scale indicating &quot;no disease activity&quot; (symptom free), and 100 on the extreme right end indicating &quot;worst imaginable disease activity&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Global Assessment change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient's Global Assessment represents the patient's overall assessment of current SSc status on a 100-mm horizontal VAS, ranging from 0 on the extreme left end of the scale indicating &quot;no disease activity&quot; (symptom free), and 100 on the extreme right end indicating &quot;worst imaginable disease activity&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Scleroderma HAQ-DI change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>The HAQ-DI consists of 20 questions referring to eight component sets consisting of dressing/grooming, arising, eating, walking, hygiene, reach, grip, and activities. Each item is scored from 0 to 3. The eight scores of the eight sections are summed and divided by 8. The total score indicates the patient's self-assessed level of disability - higher scores indicate worse symptomology. A negative change from baseline indicates improvement. The Scleroderma HAQ (SHAQ) includes an additional five scleroderma-specific visual analogue scales (VAS), addressing overall disease activity, Raynaud's phenomenon, finger ulcers, breathing, and intestinal problems. A composite VAS score is not created nor are the individual VAS scores incorporated into the HAQ DI score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Combined Response Index in Diffuse Cutaneous Systemic Sclerosis (CRISS) at Week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>CRISS components include modified Rodnan skin score (mRSS), forced vital capacity percent predicted (%FVC), Physician Global Assessment, Patient Global Assessment, and Health Assessment Questionnaire Disability-Index (HAQ-DI). The exponential algorithm determines the predicted probability of improvement from baseline, incorporating change in these 5 components. The outcome is a continuous variable between 0.0 and 1.0 (0 - 100%). A higher score indicates greater improvement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Scleroderma Clinical Trial Consortium Damage Index (SCTC-DI) change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>The SCTC-DI is a 23-item composite damage index to quantify organ damage in systemic sclerosis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5-D Itch Scale change from Baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 4, Week 8, Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>The 5-D itch scale is a validated brief multidimensional questionnaire designed to be useful as an outcome measure in clinical trials. The five dimensions are degree, duration, direction, disability, and distribution.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Scleroderma, Systemic</condition>
  <condition>Scleroderma, Diffuse</condition>
  <condition>Sclerosis, Systemic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FT011 200mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>200mg once daily for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FT011 400mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>400mg once daily for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo once daily for 12 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>FT011</intervention_name>
    <description>Two x 100mg capsules once daily for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>FT011 200mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>FT011</intervention_name>
    <description>Two x 200mg capsules once daily for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>FT011 400mg</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Two placebo capsules once daily for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Provide written informed consent prior to any study procedures and who agree to adhere&#xD;
             to all protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged 18 to 75 years inclusive at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have a classification of systemic sclerosis, as defined by American College of&#xD;
             Rheumatology (ACR) and European League Against Rheumatism (EULAR) criteria with&#xD;
             disease duration ≤5 years from first non-Raynaud phenomenon manifestation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have a diagnosis of diffuse cutaneous SSc defined as systemic sclerosis with skin&#xD;
             thickening on the upper arms proximal to the elbows, on the upper legs proximal to the&#xD;
             knees, or on the trunk.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have skin thickening in a body area suitable for repeat biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have a mRSS at Screening of ≥15 to ≤40.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. FVC ≥50% of predicted at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. If on azathioprine, mycophenolate mofetil, or hydroxychloroquine, have been on a&#xD;
             stable dose for at least 2 months prior to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Women of childbearing potential (WOCPB) and males with partners of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential must agree to use highly effective contraception (a failure rate of &lt;1%),&#xD;
             for the duration of the study and until three months after their last dose of IMP.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant or breast-feeding, or plan to become pregnant during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have received any IMP within 30 days or 5 half-lives prior to randomisation (4 months&#xD;
             if the previous drug was a new chemical entity), whichever is longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have known or suspected contraindications to the IMP.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have severe or unstable SSc or end-stage organ involvement as evidenced by:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. On an organ transplantation list or has received an organ transplant including&#xD;
                  autologous stem cell transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Renal crisis within 1 year prior to Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Interstitial lung disease or pulmonary hypertension requiring constant oxygen therapy.&#xD;
             This excludes oxygen used to aid sleep or exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Gastrointestinal dysmotility requiring total parenteral nutrition or requiring&#xD;
             hospitalisation within the 6 months prior to Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Concomitant inflammatory myositis, rheumatoid arthritis, or systemic lupus&#xD;
             erythematosus when definite classification criteria for those diseases are met (Bohan&#xD;
             and Peter criteria for polymyositis and dermatomyositis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. SSc-like illnesses related to exposures or ingestions&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The use of the following drugs within the specified periods:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Methotrexate in the 2 weeks prior to Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Other anti-fibrotic agents including D-penicillamine or tyrosine kinase&#xD;
                  inhibitors (nilotinib, imatinib, dasatinib) in the month prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Biologic drugs such as tumour necrosing factor (TNF) inhibitors, tocilizumab, or&#xD;
                  Janus kinase (JAK) inhibitors, in the 3 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Rituximab in the 6 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Cyclophosphamide oral or IV in the 3 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Oral prednisolone &gt;10 mg per day or IV steroids in the month prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Have any malignancy not considered cured (except basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma&#xD;
             of the skin, or carcinoma in situ of the cervix); a subject is considered cured if&#xD;
             there has been no evidence of cancer recurrence for the 6 years prior to&#xD;
             randomisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Have aspartate transaminase (AST), alanine transaminase (ALT), gamma-glutamyl&#xD;
             transferase (GGT), lactate dehydrogenase (LDH), or bilirubin values above the upper&#xD;
             limit of normal (ULN) at Screening or Baseline, or evidence of hepatic disease as&#xD;
             determined by any one of the following: history of hepatic encephalopathy, history of&#xD;
             oesophageal varices, or history of portacaval shunt.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;60mL/min, urinary albumin/creatinine&#xD;
             ratio &lt;30mg/g.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Haemoglobin &lt; 80 g/L, platelets &lt; 90 x 109/L, or neutrophil count &lt; 1.4 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Other than SSc, have any other medical condition or significant co-morbidities,&#xD;
             clinically relevant social or psychiatric conditions, or any finding during Screening,&#xD;
             which in the investigator's opinion may put the subject at risk or interfere with the&#xD;
             study objectives.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nicole Kruger</last_name>
    <phone>+61 3 425846036</phone>
    <email>nkruger@certatherapeutics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Adelaide Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Adelaide</city>
        <state>South Australia</state>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cindy Hall</last_name>
      <phone>08 7074 4068</phone>
      <email>cindy.hall@sa.gov.au</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Susanna Proudman</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Vincent's Hospital Melbourne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fitzroy</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3065</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wendy Burnside</last_name>
      <phone>03 9231 3983</phone>
      <email>wendy.burnside@svha.org.au</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wendy Stevens</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Localized</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

