<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04648566</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Immunomodulation</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04648566</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Endometrium Immunomodulation by in Utero Administration of Peripheral Blood Mononuclear Cells</brief_title>
  <official_title>Endometrium Immunomodulation Using in Utero Administration of Peripheral Blood Mononuclear Cells</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fertilys</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Recherche Scientifique - Centre Armand Frappier Santé Biotechnologie</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fertilys</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      One of the most limiting factors in the field of assisted reproduction is implantation&#xD;
      failure. A new approach to increase the chances of success involves the use of cells from the&#xD;
      patient's blood, peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC), which once isolated can be&#xD;
      cultured for a few days and then inseminated back into the uterine cavity prior to embryo&#xD;
      implantation. It has been shown that the immune system plays a major role in the process of&#xD;
      embryo implantation. To date, at least three international clinical trials appear to confirm&#xD;
      the usefulness of intrauterine administration of PBMC in the setting of repeated implantation&#xD;
      failure (RIF) in in vitro fertilization (IVF) (RIF: absence of active pregnancy after ≥ 3&#xD;
      embryo transfers). The clinical pregnancy rate would be doubled or even tripled. This&#xD;
      treatment has never been studied in a randomized double-blind clinical trial, in the context&#xD;
      of fertilization without RIF or in a classic treatment such as intrauterine insemination&#xD;
      (IUI) with the partner sperm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our hypothesis is that the creation of an endometrial inflammatory reaction by the&#xD;
      administration of PBMC in the uterine cavity allows a better receptivity and consequently a&#xD;
      better implantation following an embryo transfer as part of an IVF treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective is to evaluate whether intrauterine administration of PBMC improves embryo&#xD;
      implantation following assisted reproduction treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators plan to recruit 148 women undergoing IVF and 220 patients undergoing UII&#xD;
      with partner sperm to test our hypothesis. The investigators also plan to recruit all RIF&#xD;
      patients accepting to participate in the clinical trial. The study will be prospective,&#xD;
      randomized and double-blind. The treated group will receive an intrauterine administration of&#xD;
      PBMC while the control group will be administered with sperm washing medium only. PBMC will&#xD;
      be obtained from a blood sample (maximum 10 ml) a few days before embryo transfer in IVF&#xD;
      cases or on the day of sperm insemination in IUI cases. PBMC will then be isolated in the&#xD;
      laboratory on a Ficoll gradient in order to eliminate platelets, polynuclear cells and red&#xD;
      blood cells. PBMCs will then be stimulated with phytohemagglutinin (PHA) and human chorionic&#xD;
      gonadotropin hormone (hCG) for 48 hours. Lymphocyte phenotyping will be assessed before and&#xD;
      after cell activation. In addition, the cytokine profile will be established from the&#xD;
      supernatant of the stimulated cells. These data will make it possible to establish a link&#xD;
      between the pro-versus anti-inflammatory cytokine profile and implantation success versus&#xD;
      failure for each patient. Two days after cell seeding, PBMC will be administered into the&#xD;
      uterine cavity of the patient. Embryo transfer will be performed in the same way as the&#xD;
      standard treatment on day 3 or 5 according to the criteria established by the IVF laboratory&#xD;
      and in agreement with the doctor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 22, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Biochemical pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Two weeks following embryo transfer or 3 weeks following intrauterine insemination</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Six to 8 weeks of gestation</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral blood mononuclear cells populations distribution at Day 0</measure>
    <time_frame>The day of the patient's ovulation</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peripheral blood mononuclear cells populations distribution at Day 2</measure>
    <time_frame>After 48 hours of culture</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokines expression levels</measure>
    <time_frame>After 48 hours of culture</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">423</enrollment>
  <condition>Infertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IIU control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>IIU PBMC group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FIV control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FIV PBMC group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RIF group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intrauterine administration of hCG-activated peripheral blood mononuclear cells</intervention_name>
    <description>Administration of hCG-activated peripheral blood mononuclear cells in the uterine cavity of the patient</description>
    <arm_group_label>FIV PBMC group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>IIU PBMC group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RIF group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intrauterine administration of sperm washing medium</intervention_name>
    <description>Administration of sperm washing medium instead of PBMC in the uterine cavity of the patient</description>
    <arm_group_label>FIV control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>IIU control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All infertile patients undergoing in vitro fertilization (IVF) or intrauterine&#xD;
             insemination (IUI) with partner's sperm at Fertilys, agreeing to participate in the&#xD;
             study and having signed the study participation consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Study participants must be over 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the recurrent implantation failure (RIF) group only: Patients described as having&#xD;
             RIF, i.e. having had ≥ 3 good quality embryo transfers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For the randomized IUI and IVF groups only: Patients described as having RIF, i.e.&#xD;
             having had ≥ 3 embryo transfers or having had a transfer of more than 3 embryos of&#xD;
             good quality.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients requiring a donation of gametes (eggs or spermatozoa).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Couples in which one or the other has a chromosomal abnormality.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are starting an IUI cycle under ovulation testing.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pierre Miron, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fertilys inc</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fertilys inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Laval</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H7S1Z5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

