<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04643002</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ACT16482</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-003024-16</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1244-2598</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04643002</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Isatuximab in Combination With Novel Agents in RRMM - Master Protocol</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1-2 UMBRELLA Trial Evaluating Isatuximab With or Without Dexamethasone in Combination With Novel Agents Compared to Isatuximab With Pomalidomide and Dexamethasone in Relapsed or Refractory Multiple Myeloma (RRMM) - Master Protocol</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sanofi</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sanofi</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 1 (dose finding, experimental substudies):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine or confirm the recommended dose of novel agents when combined with&#xD;
           isatuximab with or without dexamethasone in participants with RRMM.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Part 2 (expansion, experimental substudies):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To demonstrate the clinical benefit of novel agents combined with isatuximab with or&#xD;
           without dexamethasone in terms of rate of very good partial response (VGPR) or better.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the overall response rate (ORR) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the clinical benefit rate (CBR) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the duration of response (DOR) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the time to first response (TT1R) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the time to best response (TTBR) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess safety and tolerability in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess progression free survival (PFS) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess overall survival (OS) in each treatment arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the potential immunogenicity of isatuximab and novel agents when applicable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To characterize the PK of isatuximab and novel agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess disease and treatment related symptoms, cancer and disease specific&#xD;
           health-related quality of life, global impact of side effects and confirm/establish&#xD;
           clinically meaningful change scores for clinical outcome assessments (COAs)/domain&#xD;
           scores.&#xD;
&#xD;
           -Substudy 1 (Control Arm):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess clinical outcomes assessments (COAs).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the incidence of skeletal related events (SREs).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the time to first occurrence of SRE.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess health care resource utilization related with SREs.&#xD;
&#xD;
           -Substudy 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess pain intensity related to skeletal related events (SREs).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the incidence of SREs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the time to first occurrence of SRE.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess health care resource utilization related with SREs.&#xD;
&#xD;
           -Substudy 3:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess patient-reported visual functioning&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Duration of study is approximately 28 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 11, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 11, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part 1 (dose finding, experimental substudies): Determination of recommended dose of novel agents in combination with isatiximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Through the end of cycle 1 (approximately 6 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Determination or confirmation of the dose will be based on: safety and tolerability in terms of treatment emergent adverse events and serious adverse events (TEAEs/SAEs), dose-limiting toxicity occurrence, and laboratory parameters available information on pharmacokinetic (PK) (if appropriate) and biomarkers. Determination of the dose will be based on: safety and tolerability in terms of treatment-emergent adverse events/serious adverse events (SAEs), dose limiting toxicity occurrence, laboratory parameters, including pharmacokinetic and pharmacodynamic information vital signs, and findings from physical examination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>VGPR Rate (Rate of Very Good Partial Response Rate or Better) in experimental substudies</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Part 2: (Arm B) VGPR or better rate is defined as the percentage of participants with a VGPR or better as defined by the 2016 International Myeloma Working Group (IMWG) response criteria, assessed by Investigator based on central laboratory values.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR) in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>ORR, defined as the proportion of participants with stringent complete response (sCR), complete response (CR), VGPR, and partial response (PR), according to the 2016 IMWG criteria assessed by Investigator based on central laboratory values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the clinical benefit rate (CBR) in each treatment arm.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>CBR, defined as the proportion of participants with sCR, CR, VGPR, PR, or minimal response, according to the 2016 IMWG criteria assessed by Investigator based on central laboratory values.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR) in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>DOR, defined as the time from the date of the first response that is subsequently confirmed for patients achieving PR or better to the date of first documented progressive disease (PD) or death, whichever happens first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to First Response (TT1R) in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>TT1R, defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first response (PR or better) that is subsequently confirmed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Best Response (TTBR) in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>TTBR, defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first occurrence of best overall response (PR or better) that is subsequently confirmed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and Tolerability in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 30 days after last study treatment administration (up to approximately 28 months after first study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability assessed in terms of adverse events/SAEs, including second primary malignancies, laboratory parameters, vital signs, and findings from physical examination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS) in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is defined as the time from the date of randomization to disease progression based on the Investigator assessment according to 2016 IMWG criteria or death from any cause, whichever happens first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS) in each treatment arm</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 28 months after the First patient in or scheduled assessment</time_frame>
    <description>OS is defined as the time from the date of randomization to death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Immunogenicity of isatuximab and novel agents</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 day 1, Day 2 (only substudy 03), Day8, Day15, day 22/29; from Cycle2 to Cycle4 day 1 and day 15 and from Cycle5 and after day 1 only. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of anti-drug antibodies (ADAs) for novel agents (experimental arms) and isatuximab.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics (PK) Parameters for Novel agents and isatuximab</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1 day 1, Day 2 (only substudy 03), Day8, Day15, day 22/29; from Cycle2 to Cycle4 day 1 and day 15 and from Cycle5 and after day 1 only. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Concentration of novel agents (experimental arms) and isatuximab</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease-specific HRQL will be assessed using the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC) core quality of life questionnaire (QLQ-C30)</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC core quality of life questionnaire (QLQ-C30) will be used to assess cancer-specific health-related quality of life (HRQL), disease and treatment-related symptoms and impact of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease- and treatment-related quality of life will be assessed using the EORTC multiple myeloma module (QLQ-MY20) questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC quality of life questionnaire will be used to measure myelomaspecific HRQL, disease and treatment -related symptoms and impact of symptoms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global impact of side effects will be assessed using the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy (FACT-G) (GP5)</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>A single item from the FACT-G GP5 will be used to assess the global impact of side effects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The intensity of skeletal-related events (SRE)-related bone pain will be assessed using the skeletal-related bone pain numeric rating scale (SRE-BP-NRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>he SRE-BP-NRS) will be used to assess the intensity of SRE-related bone pain (on average and at its worst) for control arm only</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimate/Confirm established clinically meaningful change scores for clinical outcome assessments (COAs)/domain scores using the Patient Global Impression of Severity (PGIS)</measure>
    <time_frame>n Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Global Impression of Severity (PGIS) scale will be utilized as anchors to estimate/confirmestablished clinically meaningful change scores for clinical outcome assessments (COAs)/domain scores.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimate/Confirm established clinically meaningful change scores for clinical outcome assessments (COAs)/domain scores using the Patient Global Impression of Change (PGIC) scales</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Global Impression of Change (PGIC) scale will be utilized as anchors to estimate/confirm established clinically meaningful change scores for clinical outcome assessments (COAs)/domain scores.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SRE Incidence for control and experimental arms</measure>
    <time_frame>Continuous throughout study assessment (up to approximately 28 months)</time_frame>
    <description>SRE incidence, defined as the proportion of participants who experienced pathological fracture, radiation to bone, spinal cord compression, or surgery to bone as a first bone event.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to First Occurrence of SRE Assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Continuous throughout study assessment (up to approximately 28 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Time to first occurrence of SRE is defined as time from the date of randomization to the occurrence of first SRE.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of Health care resource utilization related with SREs</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, then every 2 cycles for the first year; then every 3 cycles thereafter, at end of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>The Health Care Resource Use-SREs questionnaire (HCRU-SREs) will be used to assess the use of health care resources associated with these events.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess patient-reported visual functioning-for experimental arm only</measure>
    <time_frame>On Day1 Cycle 1, End of treatment and at first follow-up visit. The cycle is 28 days.</time_frame>
    <description>An NEI VFQ-25 will be used to assess patient-reported visual functioning</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">117</enrollment>
  <condition>Plasma Cell Myeloma Refractory</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Arm: isatuximab + pomalidomide + dexamethasone (Substudy 1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Isatuximab dose, intravenous (IV) weekly (QW) × 4 weeks (Cycle 1), followed by Q2W (subsequent cycles).&#xD;
Pomalidomide dose os (PO) daily Day 1 to Day 21.&#xD;
Dexamethasone dose PO QW.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + SAR439459 + dexamethasone) (Substudy 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Part 1 SAR439459 in combination with isatuximab+dexamethasone 3 dose levels (DLs) of IV SAR439459&#xD;
DL1 SAR439459 dose Q2W&#xD;
DL2 SAR439459 dose Q2W&#xD;
DL3 SAR439459 dose Q2W&#xD;
Isatuximab dose IV every week (QW)x5 weeks (Cycle 1) followed by Q2W (subsequent cycles)&#xD;
Dexamethasone fixed dose/schedule: QW per os (PO) In Cycle 1, first administration of SAR439459 (Day 1) will precede isatuximab by 1 week (first dose of isatuximab at Cycle 1 Day 8). When isatuximab+SAR439459 are administered same day, SAR439459 is administered first, at least 60 min before isatuximab.&#xD;
Part 2&#xD;
SAR439459 dose, IV Q2W&#xD;
Isatuximab dose, IV QWx5 weeks (Cycle 1) followed by Q2W (subsequent cycles)&#xD;
Dexamethasone fixed dose/schedule:QW PO In Cycle 1, first administration of SAR439459 (Day 1) will precede isatuximab by 1 week (first dose of isatuximab at Cycle 1 Day 8). When isatuximab+SAR439459 are administered same day, SAR439459 is administered first, at least 60 min before isatuximab.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + dexamethasone + belantamab mafodotin (Substudy 3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Isatuximab dose, intravenous (IV)&#xD;
Dexamethasone fixed dose and schedule: QW PO.&#xD;
belantamab mafodotin dose IV Q4W</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isatuximab SAR650984</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmaceutical form:Solution for injection Route of administration: intravenous</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Arm: isatuximab + pomalidomide + dexamethasone (Substudy 1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + SAR439459 + dexamethasone) (Substudy 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + dexamethasone + belantamab mafodotin (Substudy 3)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sarclisa®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmaceutical form:Tablet Route of administration: Oral</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Arm: isatuximab + pomalidomide + dexamethasone (Substudy 1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + SAR439459 + dexamethasone) (Substudy 2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + dexamethasone + belantamab mafodotin (Substudy 3)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pomalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmaceutical form:Capsule Route of administration: Oral</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Arm: isatuximab + pomalidomide + dexamethasone (Substudy 1)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Pomalyst®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SAR439459</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmaceutical form:Solution for injection Route of administration: intravenous</description>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + SAR439459 + dexamethasone) (Substudy 2)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Belantamab mafodotin</intervention_name>
    <description>Pharmaceutical form:Solution for injection Route of administration: intravenous</description>
    <arm_group_label>isatuximab + dexamethasone + belantamab mafodotin (Substudy 3)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BLENREP®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be 18 years of age inclusive or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with relapsed or refractory MM who have received at least 3 prior lines&#xD;
             of therapy for MM, including PIs and IMiDs or at least 2 prior lines if at least one&#xD;
             of these lines consisted of 2 or more multiagent regimens (eg, Induction regimen with&#xD;
             autologous stem cell transplant followed by maintenance).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  RRMM with measurable disease:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum M protein ≥0.5 g/dL measured using serum protein immunoelectrophoresis and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Urine M protein ≥200 mg/24 hours measured using urine protein immunoelectrophoresis&#xD;
             and/or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum free light chain (sFLC) MM without measurable M protein in serum or urine per&#xD;
             previous criteria (serum Ig free light chain ≥10 mg/dL and abnormal serum Ig kappa&#xD;
             lambda free light chain ratio &lt;0.26 or &gt;1.65).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men or woman or childbearing potential should agree to use contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substudy 01, 02, 03: Anti-CD38 therapy naïve or prior exposure to such drugs without&#xD;
             being refractory but with a wash out of at least 6 months after the last dose.&#xD;
             &quot;Refractory&quot; is defined as progressing within 60 days of last dose of anti-CD38&#xD;
             targeting therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary systemic amyloid light chain amyloidosis, plasma cell leukemia, monoclonal&#xD;
             gammopathy of undetermined significance, or smoldering myeloma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled infection within 14 days prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically significant cardiac (including valvular) or vascular disease within 3&#xD;
             months prior to randomization, eg, myocardial infarction, unstable angina, coronary&#xD;
             (eg, coronary artery bypass graft, percutaneous coronary intervention) or peripheral&#xD;
             artery revascularization, left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;40%, heart failure New&#xD;
             York Heart Association Classes III and IV, stroke, transient ischemic attack,&#xD;
             pulmonary embolism, other thromboembolic event, or cardiac arrhythmia (Grade 3 or&#xD;
             higher by NCI CTCAE Version 5.0).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known acquired immunodeficiency syndrome-related illness or known human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV) disease requiring antiviral treatment or active hepatitis&#xD;
             A.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled or active hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following within 3 months prior to randomization: treatment resistant&#xD;
             peptic ulcer disease, erosive esophagitis or gastritis, infectious or inflammatory&#xD;
             bowel disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Second malignancy other than basal cell or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin or in&#xD;
             situ carcinoma, unless they are successfully treated with curative intent for more&#xD;
             than 3 years before randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any anti-MM drug treatment within 14 days before randomization, including&#xD;
             dexamethasone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a contraindication to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vaccination with a live vaccine 4 weeks before the start of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &lt;8 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &lt;50 × 109/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &lt;1.5 × 109/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance &lt;30 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin &gt;1.5 × ULN, except for known Gilbert syndrome in which direct&#xD;
             bilirubin should be ≤2.5 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase and/or alanine aminotransferase &gt;3 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with grade 3 or 4 hypercalcemia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Substudy 01:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Malabsorption syndrome or any condition that can significantly impact the absorption of&#xD;
        pomalidomide.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Substudy 02:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of resected/ablated basal or squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) of the skin or&#xD;
             carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or other local tumors, even if considered cured by&#xD;
             local treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Therapeutic doses of anticoagulants or antiplatelet agents within 7 days prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of SAR439459.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prothrombin time or INR &gt;1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Substudy 03:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current corneal epithelial disease except mild punctate keratopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received prior therapy with belantamab mafodotin&#xD;
&#xD;
        The above information is not intended to contain all considerations relevant to a patient's&#xD;
        potential participation in a clinical trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Clinical Sciences &amp; Operations</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sanofi</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Trial Transparency email recommended (Toll free number for US &amp; Canada)</last_name>
    <phone>800-633-1610</phone>
    <phone_ext>option 6</phone_ext>
    <email>Contact-US@sanofi.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :8400001</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :8400007</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :8400004</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :0360006</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wollongong</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <zip>2500</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :0360002</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fitzroy</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3065</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :0360003</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg West</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3081</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :0360005</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3004</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :0360001</name>
      <address>
        <city>Richmond</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>3121</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :2500002</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille</city>
        <zip>59037</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :2500001</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nantes</city>
        <zip>44093</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :2500004</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :3000002</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <zip>10676</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :3000001</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <zip>11528</zip>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :3800001</name>
      <address>
        <city>Meldola</city>
        <state>Forlì-Cesena</state>
        <zip>47014</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :3800002</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <zip>40138</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :5780001</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oslo</city>
        <zip>0450</zip>
        <country>Norway</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Investigational Site Number :8400005</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hato Rey</city>
        <zip>00917</zip>
        <country>Puerto Rico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Norway</country>
    <country>Puerto Rico</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pomalidomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Qualified researchers may request access to patient level data and related study documents including the clinical study report, study protocol with any amendments, blank case report form, statistical analysis plan, and dataset specifications. Patient level data will be anonymized and study documents will be redacted to protect the privacy of trial participants. Further details on Sanofi's data sharing criteria, eligible studies, and process for requesting access can be found at: https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com/</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

