<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04646798</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R&amp;D Study No: 2011059</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04646798</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Hemiarthroplasty Or Total Elbow Arthroplasty in the Elderly.</brief_title>
  <acronym>HOT</acronym>
  <official_title>Hemiarthroplasty Or Total Elbow Arthroplasty for Unreconstructible Distal Humerus Fractures in the Elderly (HoT Elbow): a Feasibility Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Royal Devon and Exeter NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Royal Devon and Exeter NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A feasibility study to assess the practicality, and obtain preliminary data to inform, a&#xD;
      definitive Randomise Control Trial (RCT) in patients over the age of 65 diagnosed with&#xD;
      un-reconstructible distal humeral fractures, to determine if there are differences in&#xD;
      functional outcomes between those undergoing a hemiarthroplasty and a total elbow&#xD;
      arthroplasty? Over an 18 month recruitment period the investigators will assess recruitment&#xD;
      rates and participants willingness to be randomised to one of two routine clinical&#xD;
      treatments. During a 1 year routine clinical follow up period (at 3 time points), routinely&#xD;
      collected orthopaedic outcome data will be recorded and differences between groups explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Comminuted intra-articular distal humerus fractures (DHF) in the elderly population (over 65&#xD;
      years) have long been a treatment dilemma. Fixation of the fracture often results in&#xD;
      development of arthritis and is associated with severe arthrofibrosis (stiffness) and pain.&#xD;
      As a consequence, it has become standard practice that elderly patients with these injuries&#xD;
      are treated with either elbow hemiarthroplasty (HA) or total elbow arthroplasty (TEA). Both&#xD;
      allow immediate mobilisation of the affected arm, with good long term pain and range of&#xD;
      motion outcomes reported for both implants in a variety of articles. However each implant has&#xD;
      its own advantages and disadvantages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Elbow HA allows full lifting and loading activities to continue in the operated elbow.&#xD;
      However, the concern is that the metal articulation on native cartilage may result in wear&#xD;
      and pain associated with this resulting in the need for conversion to a total elbow&#xD;
      prosthesis. As this is revision surgery it carries additional risks over first time surgery.&#xD;
      Secondly the collateral ligaments have to be reattached and this risks instability following&#xD;
      the surgery if this fails.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with TEA are required to avoid lifting and loading activities with the affected arm&#xD;
      from the point of surgery and this is ongoing. Such activity can result in failure of the&#xD;
      implant with bushing wear, or early progression to aseptic loosening. However, with complete&#xD;
      resection of cartilage there is no concern of progressive ulna wear or pain and some&#xD;
      literature has suggested a better range of motion due to the semi-constrained nature of the&#xD;
      implant meaning condyle retention is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date no study has directly compared the two arthroplasty options for DHF's in elderly&#xD;
      patients. Both implants are currently offered in the Royal Devon and Exeter, National Health&#xD;
      Service Foundation Trust (RD&amp;E NHS FT), while other trusts locally are known to offer only&#xD;
      one approach. This reflect the uncertainty around which treatment may be better: current&#xD;
      provision options are based on the operating surgeon's skills and clinical experience.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To address this state of clinical and personal equipoise will require a large, multi-centred,&#xD;
      randomised controlled trial of HA vs TEA, for patients over the age of 65 diagnosed with&#xD;
      un-reconstructible DHF's. Before this can be considered the investigators need to assess the&#xD;
      feasibility of such a study, and obtain preliminary data to inform its development.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>To assess the feasibility of undertaking a randomised controlled trial of hemiarthroplasty versus total elbow arthroplasty for patients over the age of 65 who have an unreconstructible distal humeral fracture</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participant and clinician will not be masked. Data outcomes will be assessed by the research team utilising unique study Identifiers only and group allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recruitment rates</measure>
    <time_frame>1-18 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of patients willing to be recruited to the study will be presented as a percentage of the number who were approached, as having met the study inclusion criteria, and invited to join the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>randomisation/retention rates</measure>
    <time_frame>1-30 months</time_frame>
    <description>The number of participants randomised to either of the treatment arms will be presented as a percentage of those recruited (randomisation rate). The number of participants completing all stages of the data collection phases will be presented as a percentage of the number of participants randomised and recruited (retention rate).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in clinical outcomes between groups as measured by the Oxford Elbow Score (OES) .</measure>
    <time_frame>30-36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The OES is a short 12-item Patient Recorded Outcome measure specifically designed to assess outcomes of elbow surgery across 3 unidimensional domains: Elbow function, Pain and Social-psychological.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Distal Humerus Fracture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hemi Arthroplasty (HA) of the elbow.</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hemi Arthroplasty (HA) of the elbow, where the surgeon replaces the bottom of the humerus bone at the elbow.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Total Elbow Arthroplasty (TEA).</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Total Elbow Arthroplasty (TEA), where the surgeon fits a new elbow joint replacing damaged parts of the humerus bone and forearm bone that it joins onto.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hemiarthroplasty</intervention_name>
    <description>standard surgical approaches to repair of fractured elbows</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hemi Arthroplasty (HA) of the elbow.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Total elbow arthroplasty</intervention_name>
    <description>standard surgical approaches to repair of fractured elbows</description>
    <arm_group_label>Total Elbow Arthroplasty (TEA).</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 65 or over at time of surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scheduled for operative repair by TEA or HA if fracture deemed unfixable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to be randomly allocated to one of two surgical options&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to return for local routine clinical follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged under 65 at time of surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to independently consent for inclusion for any reason&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had previous elbow joint infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who will be unable or unlikely to be able to attend for local routine&#xD;
             clinical follow-up (e.g. foreign nationals or holidaymakers who will seek follow-up&#xD;
             away from our centre).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christopher Smith, MBBCH</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Royal Devon and Exeter National Health Service Foundation trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christopher Smith, MBBch,</last_name>
    <phone>+44 1392403560</phone>
    <email>christophersmith3@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Bridget A Knight, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+44 1392408172</phone>
    <email>B.A.Knight@ex.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NIHR Exeter Clinical Research Facility</name>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <zip>EX2 5DW</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Devon and Exeter NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Exeter</city>
        <state>Devon</state>
        <zip>EX2 5DW</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christopher Smith, MBBch</last_name>
      <phone>+44 1392403560</phone>
      <email>christophersmitht3@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Joanne Lowe</last_name>
      <phone>+44 139240</phone>
      <email>joanne.lowe3@nhs.net</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>McKee MD, Veillette CJ, Hall JA, Schemitsch EH, Wild LM, McCormack R, Perey B, Goetz T, Zomar M, Moon K, Mandel S, Petit S, Guy P, Leung I. A multicenter, prospective, randomized, controlled trial of open reduction--internal fixation versus total elbow arthroplasty for displaced intra-articular distal humeral fractures in elderly patients. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2009 Jan-Feb;18(1):3-12. doi: 10.1016/j.jse.2008.06.005. Epub 2008 Sep 26.</citation>
    <PMID>18823799</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McKee MD, Wilson TL, Winston L, Schemitsch EH, Richards RR. Functional outcome following surgical treatment of intra-articular distal humeral fractures through a posterior approach. J Bone Joint Surg Am. 2000 Dec;82(12):1701-7.</citation>
    <PMID>11130643</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Driscoll SW. Optimizing stability in distal humeral fracture fixation. J Shoulder Elbow Surg. 2005 Jan-Feb;14(1 Suppl S):186S-194S.</citation>
    <PMID>15726080</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang TL, Chiu FY, Chuang TY, Chen TH. The results of open reduction and internal fixation in elderly patients with severe fractures of the distal humerus: a critical analysis of the results. J Trauma. 2005 Jan;58(1):62-9.</citation>
    <PMID>15674152</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>John H, Rosso R, Neff U, Bodoky A, Regazzoni P, Harder F. [Distal humerus fractures in patients over 75 years of age. Long-term results of osteosynthesis]. Helv Chir Acta. 1993 Sep;60(1-2):219-24. German.</citation>
    <PMID>8226060</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Korner J, Lill H, Müller LP, Hessmann M, Kopf K, Goldhahn J, Gonschorek O, Josten C, Rommens PM. Distal humerus fractures in elderly patients: results after open reduction and internal fixation. Osteoporos Int. 2005 Mar;16 Suppl 2:S73-9. Epub 2004 Oct 29.</citation>
    <PMID>15517186</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pereles TR, Koval KJ, Gallagher M, Rosen H. Open reduction and internal fixation of the distal humerus: functional outcome in the elderly. J Trauma. 1997 Oct;43(4):578-84.</citation>
    <PMID>9356051</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Srinivasan K, Agarwal M, Matthews SJ, Giannoudis PV. Fractures of the distal humerus in the elderly: is internal fixation the treatment of choice? Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2005 May;(434):222-30.</citation>
    <PMID>15864057</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nestorson J, Ekholm C, Etzner M, Adolfsson L. Hemiarthroplasty for irreparable distal humeral fractures: medium-term follow-up of 42 patients. Bone Joint J. 2015 Oct;97-B(10):1377-84. doi: 10.1302/0301-620X.97B10.35421.</citation>
    <PMID>26430013</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Phadnis J, Watts AC, Bain GI. Elbow hemiarthroplasty for the management of distal humeral fractures: current technique, indications and results. Shoulder Elbow. 2016 Jul;8(3):171-83. doi: 10.1177/1758573216640210. Epub 2016 Apr 21. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27583016</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Egol K, Koval K, Zuckerman J. Handbook of fractures Fifth Edition. Wolters Kluwer Press</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McKee MD, Jupiter JB. Fractures of the distal humerus. In: Browner B, Jupiter J, Levine A, Trafton P, editors. Skeletal trauma. 3rd ed. Philadelphia: Lippincott; 2002. p. 765-82</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Humeral Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>feasibility study only</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

