<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04647474</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>284473</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04647474</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mental Wellbeing and Quality of Life in Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>MIND-P</acronym>
  <official_title>A Prospective and Longitudinal Cohort Study Assessing Mental wellbeIng and Quality of Life in Prostate Cancer - the MIND-P Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>King's College London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>King's College Hospital NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medway NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Lewisham and Greenwich NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Surrey and Sussex Healthcare NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>King's College London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The complex relationship that exists between physical and mental health in prostate cancer is&#xD;
      increasingly being understood. Psychiatric symptoms are common in this group and have&#xD;
      important consequences for the quality of life and cancer outcomes for patients with prostate&#xD;
      cancer. However, less is understood about the severity of disease and which patient factors&#xD;
      and treatment options are risk factors for developing problems. Additionally, the impact&#xD;
      these conditions have on problems such as urinary incontinence or sexual function is less&#xD;
      well understood. The investigators anticipate that different patient characteristics and&#xD;
      treatment options increase an individuals risk of developing problems after a prostate cancer&#xD;
      diagnosis. Therefore, this study aims to further investigate these specific factors to&#xD;
      improve follow up care in patients with prostate cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This observational study will follow up newly diagnosed prostate cancer patients for a period&#xD;
      of 12 months to evaluate these outcomes. Participants will be identified across seven&#xD;
      hospitals in London and South England. After being recruited participants will be invited to&#xD;
      undergo repeated online or postal questionnaires at baseline, 3, 6, 9 and 12 months. These&#xD;
      will assess depressive and anxiety symptom load, body image issues, fear of recurrence,&#xD;
      masculinity perception and functional symptoms (including urinary, bowel and sexual symptoms)&#xD;
      load.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis of these findings will allow for identification of 1) Which subgroups of patients&#xD;
      appear to have worse mental wellbeing and quality of life outcomes, and 2) How mental health&#xD;
      issues impact functional outcomes. This will provide important information for guiding future&#xD;
      research within the subject area and further inform clinicians about these issues.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prostate cancer represents a large proportion of global cancer incidence, accounting for&#xD;
      13.5% of all male cancers. However, with high survival rates, which are still improving,&#xD;
      there is growing acceptance that living longer does not always equate to living well. The&#xD;
      mental health aspect of the disease is unfortunately sometimes neglected with research&#xD;
      focusing on the physical symptoms after disease much more prominent and frequently conducted.&#xD;
      Previous research has already demonstrated that mental health issues are common in patient&#xD;
      with prostate cancer, however, less is known about which patients are at greater risk of&#xD;
      developing problems after being diagnosed with prostate cancer. Additionally, the association&#xD;
      between mental health conditions and what are called 'functional outcomes' (i.e. bladder,&#xD;
      bowel and sexual function) after treatment are less well understood. A greater knowledge of&#xD;
      these factors can help clinicians to make better assessments of patients and also will help&#xD;
      the future development of additional tools which are able to help with diagnosis in future.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With these factors in mind the primary aims of the research study is :&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. To evaluate the association between prostate cancer patients undergoing different&#xD;
      treatments and overall mental wellbeing in the initial cancer follow-up stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary aims of the study are to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Identify high risk time-frames post diagnosis for worsening of mental wellbeing&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Assess the impact of depressive and anxiety symptoms on functional, clinical and other&#xD;
           mental wellbeing outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Explore patient and cancer related factors conferring a risk for the development of&#xD;
           significant mental wellbeing problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesis is that prostate cancer patients experience a high psychological&#xD;
      symptom load in the initial follow up period after diagnosis. Additionally, based on previous&#xD;
      prostate cancer and mental health research the investigators hypothesise that certain&#xD;
      subgroups (e.g. certain treatment or patient groups) are at increased risk of developing&#xD;
      significant psychological symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To explore these aims and hypothesis the investigators will conduct a questionnaire based,&#xD;
      longitudinal and observational cohort study of participants recently diagnosed with prostate&#xD;
      cancer. There is no interventional element to the study. The investigators will identify&#xD;
      newly diagnosed patients, who have not yet received treatment from multiple hospital sites in&#xD;
      London and the South East of England. This will include patients allocated to surgery,&#xD;
      radiotherapy, surveillance or hormone therapy depending on prostate cancer characteristics.&#xD;
      Participants will be identified by the clinical team during the hospital outpatient&#xD;
      appointment, with contact details taken at this stage. The investigators are aiming to&#xD;
      recruit 440 participants for this study based on power calculations (80% power with 0.05&#xD;
      significance) for the primary outcomes taking into account a maximum drop out rate of 25%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following identification, screening and consenting for inclusion into the study participants&#xD;
      will begin data collection through serial questionnaires. Participants will have the option&#xD;
      of either undergoing postal or electronic follow up, depending on preference. Questionnaires&#xD;
      will include numerous validated measures to evaluate mental and social wellbeing as well as&#xD;
      functional symptoms of disease/treatment including bladder, bowel and sexual function as per&#xD;
      the outcome measures described.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of data will occur at set intervals for the duration of the study and will include&#xD;
      the same questionnaire being filled at the beginning of the study, 3, 6, 9 and 12 months.&#xD;
      Additionally, at the outset of the study some further information will be asked from the&#xD;
      participant including demographics and previous medical or psychiatric history. The research&#xD;
      team will in addition collect data from the medical files at the beginning of the study about&#xD;
      the cancer characteristics and then again at the end of the study at 12 months. At 12 months&#xD;
      participants will complete the study and data analysis along the primary and secondary&#xD;
      outcome measures will be conducted once all participants have completed this.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference of mental wellbeing measures between four management groups</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3, 6, 9 and 12 months post diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Mental wellbeing validated tools scores including Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9), Generalised Anxiety Disorder-7 (GAD-7), Body Image Scale, Fear of Recurrence Scale, Masculine Self-Esteem Prostate Cancer-Related Quality of Life (PC-QOL) Subset Scale and Short Form-12 Mental Component Scale (SF-12 MCS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative incidence of significant depressive or anxiety symptoms stratified per treatment cohort</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Binary outcome of the development of significant depressive or anxiety symptoms as defined by PHQ-9 or GAD-7 Score ≥ 10</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mean difference of mental wellbeing measures within same treatment group at each follow up time</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3, 6, 9 and 12 months post diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Mental wellbeing validated tools scores including PHQ-9, GAD-7, Body Image Scale, Fear of Recurrence Scale, Masculine Self-Esteem PC-QOL Subset Scale and SF-12 MCS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relationship between depression and anxiety scores and other mental wellbeing and functional outcome scores stratified per treatment cohort</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3, 6, 9 and 12 months post diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Depression (PHQ-9) and Anxiety (GAD-7) scores evaluated against other mental wellbeing measures (Body Image Scale, Fear of Recurrence Scale, Masculine Self-Esteem PC-QOL Subset Scale, SF-12 MCS), social wellbeing (Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy - General Social Wellbeing Subset) and functional outcome scores (All Expanded Prostate Cancer Index Composite-26 Subsets and Short Form-12 Physical Component Scale)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk of developing significant depressive or anxiety symptoms per clinical or baseline patient characteristics</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3, 6, 9 and 12 months post diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Baseline and patient (Age at diagnosis, ethnicity, co-morbidities burden, previous mental health history, family history of prostate cancer) and oncological characteristics (Mode of diagnosis, Gleason grade, Prostate Specific Antigen (PSA), stage at diagnosis) evaluated against binary outcome for the development of significant depressive or anxiety symptoms (PHQ-9 and GAD-7 Score ≥ 10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Subgroup analysis on individual treatment cohorts evaluating the impact of significant depression and anxiety symptoms on oncological outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Development of significant depressive or anxiety symptoms (PHQ-9 and GAD-7 Score ≥ 10) evaluated against oncological or treatment outcomes (o Positive Surgical Margins (for radical prostatectomy cohort), Biochemical progression, conversion from active surveillance to active treatment)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">440</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Radical Prostatectomy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants undergoing any curative surgical treatment option for prostate cancer irregardless of approach (open, laparoscopic or robotic)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Surveillance</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants undergoing active surveillance as the management option for prostate cancer as defined by regular surveillance attendance at the primary treating site.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Androgen Deprivation Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants undergoing medical (Gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonists or antagonists) or surgical castration (e.g. orchidectomy) options as the primary treatment for prostate cancer.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Radical Radiotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants undergoing primary radiotherapy treatment for prostate cancer irregardless of delivery methods (e.g. External beam radiation therapy or brachytherapy).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The population of study are patients with a recently newly confirmed diagnosis, or&#xD;
        clinically likely diagnosis of prostate cancer in a secondary care setting. Four separate&#xD;
        sub-cohorts based on treatment or management allocated will be recruited with identical&#xD;
        inclusion and exclusion criteria, with the exception of treatment specific characteristics.&#xD;
        The four cohorts to be recruited will be newly diagnosed men with prostate are those&#xD;
        described in the eligibility criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New diagnosis of histologically proven or clinically likely prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No limits on grade, histology type or risk stratification classification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post Multi Disciplinary Team discussion with allocation of a suggested treatment or&#xD;
             follow up strategy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing one of the following four treatment/management options:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radical Prostatectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiotherapy (External beam radiation therapy or brachytherapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Active Surveillance&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Androgen Deprivation Therapy (Medical or Surgical castration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Follow up undertaken by urology, oncology or mixed uro-oncology teams&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is pre-Multi Disciplinary Team discussion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has already undergone the allocate intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Post-surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Post first radiotherapy dose&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Attended second active surveillance follow up&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Received &gt;1 dose (initial dose) of Gonadotropin-releasing hormone&#xD;
                  agonist/antagonist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving the following therapies:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Palliative patients on symptom control only&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients allocated to watchful waiting&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any type of Focal therapy e.g. high intensity focused ultrasound (HIFU)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients receiving adjuvant combination therapy e.g. Androgen deprivation therapy&#xD;
                  or chemotherapy pre radiotherapy or surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Metastatic patients undergoing chemotherapy alone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with recurrence or progression of prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent management for another cancer diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent admission to an inpatient psychiatric facility within the previous 12 months&#xD;
             prior to diagnosis of prostate cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients lacking capacity to consent or undertake in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those unable to complete the required surveys, such as those not able to understand&#xD;
             English or those with severe learning disability&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>King's College London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
    <phone>+447434672408</phone>
    <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
    <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
    <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <zip>SE1 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+447434672408</phone>
      <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
      <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Prokar Dasgupta</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lewisham and Greenwich NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <zip>SE18 4QH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+447434672408</phone>
      <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
      <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mohamed Hammadeh</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>King's College Hospital NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <zip>SE5 9RS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+447434672408</phone>
      <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
      <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imperial College Healthcare NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <zip>W2 1NY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+447434672408</phone>
      <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
      <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hashim Ahmed</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medway NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gillingham</city>
        <state>Kent</state>
        <zip>ME7 5NY</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+447434672408</phone>
      <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
      <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matin Sheriff</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Surrey and Sussex Healthcare NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Redhill</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <zip>RH1 5RH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Oliver Brunckhorst, MBBS, MRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+44 7434672408</phone>
      <email>Oliver.brunckhorst@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Kamran Ahmed, MBBS, FRCS</last_name>
      <phone>+44207 188 5906</phone>
      <email>kamran.ahmed@kcl.ac.uk</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shahid Khan</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.kclmind-u.org.uk/the-mind-p-study/</url>
    <description>Study Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 23, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prostate Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Mental Wellbeing</keyword>
  <keyword>Functional Outcomes</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Wellbeing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Anonymised individual participant data pertaining to any analysis conducted by this research will be made available publicly without restriction after the conductance of the study through the King's Research Data Repository.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>All raw data will be made available by the time of publication of the research study in a peer reviewed journal. This will be archived for a duration of 20 years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Openly available through the King's Research Data Repository.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

