<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02589366</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HRPP #141163</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02589366</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lymphoseek as Lymphoid Tissue Targeting Agent in Patients With Cancer of the Endometrium</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I, Prospective, Open-Label, Comparison Study of Lymphoseek® and Vital Blue Dye as Lymphoid Tissue Targeting Agents in Patients With Known Cancer of the the Endometrium Who Are Undergoing Lymph Node Dissection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cardinal Health 414, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Part of standard treatment for endometrial cancer is to remove one or more groups of lymph&#xD;
      nodes (lymph node dissection). Lymph nodes are small, bean-shaped organs located within the&#xD;
      body throughout the lymphatic system (the tissues and organs involved in immunity, which aids&#xD;
      in the fight against infection and cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to compare the safety and ability of Lymphoseek and a Vital Blue&#xD;
      Dye (tracing agent) to find lymph nodes that may carry cancer from the tumor through the&#xD;
      lymphatic system. Lymphoseek will be injected into the tumor on the day before surgery to&#xD;
      remove lymph nodes. Vital Blue Dye will be administered during surgery to trace the cancer as&#xD;
      well. The surgeon will remove the lymph nodes as part of routine surgery and will keep track&#xD;
      of which lymph nodes are identified by Lymphoseek and Vital Blue Dye. These nodes will be&#xD;
      sent to another doctor to view them under a microscope and see if the nodes contain cancer&#xD;
      cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that Lymphoseek can be used safely and will be at least as effective as&#xD;
      blue dye in identifying the lymph nodes that may have cancer cells.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, single center, intra-patient safety and comparison study of Lymphoseek&#xD;
      (Technetium Tc 99m Tilmanocept) and vital blue dye for the detection of lymph nodes in&#xD;
      patients with endometrial cancer that are undergoing a lymph node dissection as part of their&#xD;
      standard medical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The day before surgery, patients will have their tumor injected with 50 µg Lymphoseek&#xD;
      radiolabeled with 75 megabecquerel (MBq) Tc 99m. Vital signs will be monitored for thirty&#xD;
      minutes and then patients will undergo a whole body scan and single photon emission computed&#xD;
      tomography/ x-ray computed tomography (SPECT/CT) one to two hours after Lymphoseek injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fourteen to twenty hours after injection of Lymphoseek, patients will have a physical exam&#xD;
      and clinical laboratory tests assessed prior to undergoing surgery. Sentinel lymph node&#xD;
      identification begins with injection of Vital Blue Dye. Surgical access will be made to the&#xD;
      lymphatic basins where nodes are expected to be. Sentinel lymph nodes will be identified by a&#xD;
      hand-held gamma counter and/or blue appearance. The threshold criterion for positive &quot;hot&quot;&#xD;
      nodes based on radioactivity is a count greater than the quantity of 3 square roots of the&#xD;
      mean background count (i.e., standard deviation) added to the mean background count (referred&#xD;
      to as the &quot;3σ rule&quot;). Once a lymph node has been identified, in vivo counts should be taken&#xD;
      prior to excision. In vivo counts will consist of a set of three 1-second counts over the&#xD;
      lymph node. A positive finding (i.e., localization) is a designated &quot;hot&quot; node (described&#xD;
      above). Any lymph node count not meeting this threshold criterion will be considered a&#xD;
      negative (non-localized) finding. To confirm the in vivo procedure, a set of three 1-second&#xD;
      counts will be recorded for the excised lymph nodes. The count of the ex vivo lymph nodes&#xD;
      will be compared to the room background counts, and the threshold criterion used to determine&#xD;
      a positive finding for the in vivo nodes will be applied to the ex vivo specimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A thorough evaluation of the remaining lymphatic basin will be complete when all selected&#xD;
      node counts are negative by use of the threshold criterion. The surgeon will continue with&#xD;
      visualization and palpation according to local practice to ensure that no grossly positive&#xD;
      lymph nodes remain at the site of resection. After identifying the sentinel lymph nodes,&#xD;
      standard lymph node dissection will be performed. All removed lymph nodes are sent to&#xD;
      pathology for further evaluation. All removed lymph nodes will be sent to pathology and will&#xD;
      be confirmed for radioactive status (due to Lymphoseek) and blue appearance (due to vital&#xD;
      blue dye. The pathological evaluation of lymph node(s) will include serial sectioning with&#xD;
      H&amp;E staining as well as immuno-histochemistry (IHC) stain according to institutional&#xD;
      practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will return for a routine post-operative follow-up visit 7-14 days after surgery for&#xD;
      assessment of adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is safety of Lymphoseek as measured by the incidence of adverse events,&#xD;
      changes in laboratory values, vital signs and physical exam findings, and the radiation&#xD;
      absorbed dose. Secondary evaluations include (1) the number of lymph nodes detected as &quot;hot&quot;&#xD;
      by preoperative imaging (whole body scan and SPECT/CT) and intraoperative gamma detection,&#xD;
      and (2) the rate of concordance between Lymphoseek and Vital Blue Dye in the in vivo&#xD;
      detection of excised lymph nodes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>0-15 days Postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events experienced by the participants and radiation absorbed dose of injected Lymphoseek.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Lymphoseek positive lymph nodes detected preoperatively and intraoperatively.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 days</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of the number of lymph nodes detected with Lymphoseek by preoperative whole body scan and SPECT/CT imaging and by intraoperative laparoscopic hand held gamma detection device</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of lymph nodes identified intraoperatively as assessed by visualization and handheld gamma probe detection</measure>
    <time_frame>2 days</time_frame>
    <description>Concordance of intraoperative detection rates of Lymphoseek and vital blue dye in histological evaluation and ultrastaging of resected lymph nodes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek plus Vital Blue Dye</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lymphoseek plus Vital Blue Dye: Single dose of 50 µg Lymphoseek radiolabeled with 75 MBq Tc 99m injected pre-operatively followed by next day intra-operative administration of vital blue dye.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lymphoseek plus Vital Blue Dye</intervention_name>
    <description>intrapatient comparison of Lymphoseek with Vital Blue Dye in detecting lymph node metastases</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lymphoseek plus Vital Blue Dye</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Technetium TC 99M</other_name>
    <other_name>Tilmanocept</other_name>
    <other_name>Lymphazurin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The patient has provided written informed consent with Health Insurance Portability&#xD;
             and Accountability Act (HIPAA) authorization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient has diagnosed cancer of the endometrium.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The patient is a candidate for surgical intervention, with lymph node dissection being&#xD;
             a part of the surgical plan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient is at least 18 years of age at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The patient has an Eastern Cooperative Group (ECOG) performance status of Grade 0 - 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The patient has a clinical negative node status at the time of study entry (i.e.,&#xD;
             Tis-4, N0, M0).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. If of childbearing potential, the patient has a negative pregnancy test within 72&#xD;
             hours before administration of Lymphoseek, has been surgically sterilized, or has been&#xD;
             postmenopausal for at least 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The patient is pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient has clinical or radiological evidence of metastatic cancer including&#xD;
             palpably abnormal or enlarged lymph nodes (i.e., all patients should be any T, N0,&#xD;
             M0).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. The patient has a known hypersensitivity to Lymphazurin or Lymphoseek.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. The patient has participated in another investigational drug study within 30 days of&#xD;
             scheduled surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael McHale, MD, FACS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California, San Diego</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Diego Moores Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92093</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 20, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 28, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 10, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 10, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 15, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michael McHale</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Physician Diplomate</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Lymphoseek</keyword>
  <keyword>endometrial cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>sentinel lymph node</keyword>
  <keyword>lymph node dissection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

