<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02588326</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB201500381 - F</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>HHSF223201310220C</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>OCR19758</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02588326</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sensitivity of Pharmacokinetics to Differences in Particle Size Distribution of Suspension-based Nasal Sprays</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of the Sensitivity of Pharmacokinetics to Differences in the Particle Size Distribution of Two Different Formulations of a Locally-acting Mometasone Furoate Suspension-based Nasal Spray</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Florida</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Food and Drug Administration (FDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Florida</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Currently FDA does not accept pharmacokinetic studies to show bioequivalence of&#xD;
      locally-acting nasal suspension formulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, bioequivalence is defined as the absence of significant differences in&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics of therapeutically equivalent drug products compared to the matching&#xD;
      originally invented drug formulation. These there-called &quot;generic drugs&quot; are then&#xD;
      interchangeable. Drug companies have to show that their generic version has the same active&#xD;
      ingredient, the same label, is intended to be used for the same conditions or diseases and&#xD;
      works at the same rate in the body.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to determine if pharmacokinetics is sensitive to differences in the&#xD;
      particle size distribution of two different nasal suspension formulations of mometasone&#xD;
      furoate during charcoal block. The result from this study will aid the FDA in finding methods&#xD;
      to ensure that generic products are the same as the trade name drugs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For every subject in this research study the following procedures and scheduling will take&#xD;
      place.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the screening visit the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be reviewed to ensure&#xD;
      the subject is appropriate for the study. A physical examination will be performed after the&#xD;
      vital sign measurements are obtained. Also, nasal spray application training will be&#xD;
      performed and tolerability to charcoal block will be determined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Screening tests will be performed within 30 days of study visit 1 and no later than 2 days&#xD;
      before study visit 1. There will be 2 study visits in addition to the screening visit, a&#xD;
      minimum period of 7 days should lapse between the subsequent study visits but no more than 3&#xD;
      weeks. The total study duration for each subject will be about 4-7 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood sample collection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples will be drawn by inserting an indwelling catheter for blood sample collection.&#xD;
      Blood samples will be taken approximately 15 minutes prior to the dosing of the product&#xD;
      (pre-dose sample) and at approximately 5, 10, 15, 30, 45, 60 minutes, 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10,&#xD;
      12 and 14 hours post dosing. At each time point about 10 mL of blood sample will be collected&#xD;
      via vacutainer tubes for plasma preparation and storage. At each study visit a total of&#xD;
      approximately 160 mL blood will be collected, which makes a total of 320 mL of blood during&#xD;
      study visits 1 and 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total amount of blood drawn in this study, including the screening visit, will be 327 ml.&#xD;
      Additionally, up to approximately 15 mL of blood may be drawn for medically needed additional&#xD;
      assessments to follow up the screening results. Therefore, in total up to approximately 342&#xD;
      mL of blood may be drawn from each subject.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 21, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 16, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 8, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC) of mometasone furoate formulation 1</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min pre-dose and 5, 10, 15, 30, 45, 60 minutes and 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 14 hours post-dose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC) of mometasone furoate formulation 2</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min pre-dose and 5, 10, 15, 30, 45, 60 minutes and 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 14 hours post-dose</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of mometasone furoate formulation 1</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min pre-dose and 5, 10, 15, 30, 45, 60 minutes and 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 14 hours post-dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of mometasone furoate formulation 2</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min pre-dose and 5, 10, 15, 30, 45, 60 minutes and 1.5, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12 and 14 hours post-dose</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypersensitivity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MFF 1, then MFF 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 1 will be administered by suspension-based nasal spray. After a wash out period then Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 2 will be administered by suspension-based nasal spray. All formulations will be a 200 mcg single dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MFF 2, then MFF 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 2 will be administered by suspension-based nasal spray. After a wash out period then Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 1 will be administered by suspension-based nasal spray. All formulations will be a 200 mcg single dose.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 1</intervention_name>
    <description>Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 1 will be administered by suspension-based nasal spray.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MFF 1, then MFF 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MFF 2, then MFF 1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nasonex re-engineered version</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 2</intervention_name>
    <description>Mometasone furoate drug formulation (MFF) 2 will be administered by suspension-based nasal spray.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MFF 1, then MFF 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>MFF 2, then MFF 1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Nasonex re-engineered version</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy male or female subjects aged 18 to 50 years (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females will be eligible only if they are currently non-lactating and demonstrate a&#xD;
             negative urine pregnancy test. Female subjects must be willing to use highly effective&#xD;
             methods of contraception throughout the study. A highly effective method of birth&#xD;
             control is defined as one which results in a low failure rate (i.e. less than 1% per&#xD;
             year) when used consistently and correctly e.g. no sexual intercourse, using&#xD;
             contraceptive foam AND a condom (double-barrier). [NOTE: for this study, use of&#xD;
             hormonal contraception is an exclusion]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index (BMI) between 18.5 and 30.0 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-smoker for at least 12 months prior to study screening and a maximum smoking&#xD;
             history of less than ten-pack years (i.e. the equivalent of one-pack per day for ten&#xD;
             years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Free of significant abnormal findings as determined by medical history, physical&#xD;
             examination, vital signs, and laboratory tests (including serum cortisol at&#xD;
             screening), complete blood count (CBC) with differential , urinalysis and basic&#xD;
             metabolic panel.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to read, comprehend and sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability and willingness to comply with all study procedures, discontinue and/or&#xD;
             withhold medications as specified in the protocol, and attend scheduled study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No history of major respiratory disease (such as cystic fibrosis or COPD).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to demonstrate correct nasal spray technique at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history and/or conditions that might interfere with drug absorption, distribution,&#xD;
             metabolism or excretion of MF, e.g., preexisting lung and liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected sensitivity or allergic reaction to MF, or related compounds in&#xD;
             that class, or one of the excipients, or to activated charcoal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected sensitivity to benzalkonium chloride or to products containing this&#xD;
             salt.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a history and/or currently having the medical condition in the opinion of&#xD;
             medically accountable investigator and hence taking any medication for the following&#xD;
             (including but not limited to):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant cardiac, dermatologic, gastrointestinal, hepatic, renal,&#xD;
                  hematological, neurological and psychiatric disease (determined by physical exam,&#xD;
                  CBC with differential, urinalysis, basic metabolic panel and medical history).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of glaucoma, cataracts, ocular herpes simplex or carcinoma (other than&#xD;
                  basal cell).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of tuberculosis and other respiratory diseases (including but not&#xD;
                  limited to intermittent or persistent asthma, emphysema and chronic bronchitis);&#xD;
                  or respiratory infection, common cold, sinusitis or ear infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Based on the medical interview, physical examination or screening investigations,&#xD;
             subject is unfit for the study in the opinion of the medically accountable&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of hormone replacement therapy (HRT), hormonal contraceptives (oral,&#xD;
             implants, or IUDs) and/or use corticosteroid within the last 2 month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Atrophic rhinitis or rhinitis medicamentosa within the last 60 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of nasal surgery or known clinically relevant abnormalities, such as&#xD;
             rhinitis medicamentosa, polyposis, septum deviation with clinical symptoms, recent&#xD;
             nasal trauma, or nasal structural abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of recurrent epistaxis, or any epistaxis requiring medical intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known perennial airway allergies or vasomotor rhinitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known seasonal airway allergies within the last six weeks prior to the start of the&#xD;
             study or seasonal airway allergies that likely become acute during the study period.&#xD;
             Subjects may be included in the study, if e.g. a mild or unlikely seasonal airway&#xD;
             allergy does not interfere with the nasal absorption of mometasone furoate in the&#xD;
             opinion of the medically accountable investigator and principal investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute sinusitis within the last six weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of chronic sinus disease or sinusitis within the last year prior to the start&#xD;
             of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any systemic, topical, inhaled, or nasal corticosteroid within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any prescription, over-the-counter, or complementary nasally administered&#xD;
             products within 30 days prior to enrollment and for the duration of the study (i.e.,&#xD;
             corticosteroids, decongestants, antihistamines, saline sprays, sinus washes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any topically applied agents to the nasal mucosa (i.e., antibacterial creams,&#xD;
             Vaseline) within 30 days of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of malignancy within the past five years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any concurrent medication or any medication within 2 weeks preceding the start of the&#xD;
             study (infrequent intake/use of drugs may be accepted, if judged by the investigator&#xD;
             to have no clinical relevance and no influence on study outcome).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exposure to any investigational drug within 30 days of enrollment. Exposure to any&#xD;
             medication/food that alters the CYP 3A4 activity within last 2 weeks (e.g. any&#xD;
             grapefruit products, azole anti-fungals, or rifampin).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have donated 14.85 ounces (450 mL) blood or more within the previous 8&#xD;
             weeks prior to study administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of current drug or alcohol abuse, which would interfere with the subject's&#xD;
             completion of the study and with adherence to the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject reports a regular xanthine consumption of &gt; 5 cups of coffee or black tea per&#xD;
             day (or equivalent xanthine consumption per day using other products).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject reports strict dietary habits, which would preclude the subject's acceptance&#xD;
             of standardized meals.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A subject will not be eligible for this study if he/she is an immediate family member&#xD;
             of the participating investigator, co-investigators, study coordinator, or employee of&#xD;
             the participating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The subject is a student of the Principal Investigator or co-investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of willingness to have personal study related data collected, archived and&#xD;
             transmitted according to the protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jurgen Bulitta, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Florida jbulitta@cop.ufl.edu</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Pharmaceutics, University of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 26, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 27, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bioequivalence</keyword>
  <keyword>Suspension nasal spray</keyword>
  <keyword>Mometasone furoate</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Particle size distribution</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypersensitivity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Mometasone Furoate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

