<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00309192</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2005-001385-14</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>PI071701</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00309192</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety Study of Intravitreal Triamcinolone to Treat Diffuse Diabetic Macular Edema</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Safety of Intravitreal Triamcinolone as Treatment of the Diffuse Diabetic Macular Edema</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Instituto Universitario de Oftalmobiología Aplicada (Institute of Applied Ophthalmobiology) - IOBA</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Instituto Universitario de Oftalmobiología Aplicada (Institute of Applied Ophthalmobiology) - IOBA</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether intravitreal injection of Triamcinolone&#xD;
      Acetonide is effective in the treatment of Clinically Significant Diffuse Macular Edema due&#xD;
      to Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Diabetes mellitus and its complications represent nowadays an important issue in Public&#xD;
      Health terms. The WHO expectations indicate that around 2025 the European population with&#xD;
      diabetes will reach about 12%, and it has been estimated that the percent in the USA will be&#xD;
      around 10% (King, 1995).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The severe complications of proliferant diabetic retinopathy and its disastrous effects on&#xD;
      vision seem to be solved with retinal panphotocoagulation. The most relevant issue regarding&#xD;
      diabetes´ ocular complications seems to be macular edema. We define macular edema as retinal&#xD;
      thickening between 1500 microns central to fovea. It is found in about 10% diabetics, of whom&#xD;
      about 40% will have an important visual acuity loss (Klein, 1984) In our environment,&#xD;
      diabetes retinopathy affects nearly 21% of all the diabetics, and among them, about 6% has a&#xD;
      clinically significant macular edema (Lopez, 2001).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Until now the only treatment available with proved efficacy for diffuse edema was grid&#xD;
      photocoagulation, stablished as standard treatment since the publication of results from&#xD;
      &quot;Early Treatment Diabetic Retinopathy Study&quot; (Olk 1990). A maximum 3 laser treatments with 3&#xD;
      to 4 months intervals between treatment has been accepted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nevertheless, the results with the treatment haven´t been considered satisfactory as the main&#xD;
      aim is to preserve visual function, and only 15% of the patients get any improvement (Mc&#xD;
      Donald, 1985).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because of that more alternatives have been studied, among them victrectomy and intraocular&#xD;
      corticosteroyd injections. Though, vitrectomy seems to provide significative improvements&#xD;
      only if the patient has a thickened posterior hyaloid able to make a traction over the&#xD;
      macular area (Tachi, 1996) and that doesn´t happen in the majority of diabetic patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The identification of Vascular Endothelial Growth Factor (VEGF) as the main responsible agent&#xD;
      of angiogenesis and its role in the pathogenia of diabetic macular edema has opened new&#xD;
      approach methods in the treatment of this complication (Adamis 1994). This factor, also known&#xD;
      as Vascular Permeability Factor (VPF), interacts with &quot;tight junctions&quot; of retinal&#xD;
      endothelial cells, producing a disruption of hematoretinal barrier.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is known that corticosteroids are not only the more powerful antiangiogenetic agents, but&#xD;
      are also capable of reversing the effects mentioned before over the retinal endothelial by&#xD;
      acting at phosphorilation and expression of tight-junctions´ proteins. They also inhibit VEGF&#xD;
      expression (Fisher 2001).&#xD;
&#xD;
      It seems logical that its use has been proposed in the treatment of this diabetes&#xD;
      complication. Though, its side effects, either local or systemical, and its intraocular&#xD;
      biodisponibility issues have obligated the use of intravitreal administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In 2001 was published the first work about intravitreal triamcinolone after vitrectomy in&#xD;
      proliferative diabetes retinopathy patients, in an attempt to reduce the inflammatory&#xD;
      response what sometimes occurs in these patients after surgery (Jonas, 2001). A series of 29&#xD;
      eyes shows a good tolerance of the drug administered this way.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The next year, and after the presentation at ARVO meeting, some other authors present a&#xD;
      prospective work without control group with 16 eyes of patients who have been injected&#xD;
      triamcinolone acetonide after grid laser failure, applied according to ETDRS criteria. The&#xD;
      results show a visual acuity improvemente and a reduction of macular edema evaluated with&#xD;
      ocular coherence tomography, with an effect loss in a 6 months interval (Martidis, 2002).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since then more clinical series have been published, but yet without any prospective,&#xD;
      randomized and control group studies done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These series seem to show a positive effect of triamcionlone either in 25 mg dosage (Jonas,&#xD;
      2002) or 4 mg dosage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is remarkable that the majority of the studies have been published by Heidelberg Group,&#xD;
      although series from other authors are also being published (Massin, 2004).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There has also been published side effects as ocular hypertension and endophthalmitis, that&#xD;
      seem not to be infectious in the majority of the cases (Roth, 2003) but due to its high&#xD;
      prevalence they need to be studied in depth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This approach is being taken by some pharma industries with variations; intraocular&#xD;
      controlled liberation implants of fluocionola acetonide or dexametasone biodegradable&#xD;
      implants have been developed (Jaffe 2000).&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is also being investigated the potential effect of Anecortave acetate, a cortisol&#xD;
      derivate, and there are also some other alternatives under research: VEGF inhibitors as&#xD;
      adaptamers, andibodies or fragments, PKC inhibitors or angiopoiteins, some of which are&#xD;
      currently being evaluated in Phase III Clinical Trials.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the lack of clinical trials similar to the one proposed here, the topic has provoked&#xD;
      a lot of interest in the international and national ophthalmological community and there are&#xD;
      evidences of some of these treatments being used in our country.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Comparisons:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Group: TRIGON DEPOT (Bristol Mayers Squibb Labs) 4 mg intravitreal injection followed&#xD;
      by ETDRS grid laser technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control Group: ETDRS grid laser technique.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>April 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 2008</completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual acuity stabilization or improvement 6 months after treatment.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Macular edema reduction or stabilization 6 months after treatment.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety of the treatment.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerance of the treatment.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment>292</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <condition>Macular Edema</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Triamcinolone Acetonide 4 mg intravitreal injection</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ETDRS grid laser technique</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Type II Diabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mild-moderate diabetes retinopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diffuse clinically significant macular edema (demonstrated by angiofluoresceingraphy,&#xD;
             associated or not to cystic changes).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 50 to 75 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Foveal thickening greater than 300 microns tested with Optical Coherence Tomography&#xD;
             (OCT).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visual acuity better than 0,05.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None of the exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent signed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Data protection consent signed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bad metabolic control in recruitment stage (as criteria from Endocrinology Department&#xD;
             of each Center) or Glicosilated Hemoglobine greater than 9%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension. Greater than 150/90.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic treatment with oral corticosteroids, diuretics or immunosupressors 3 months&#xD;
             before or during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Record of ocular hypertension induced by corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glaucoma or ocular hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unbalanced heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other pathology that could cause macular edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Associated ischemic maculopathy. (Parafoveal avascular area thickening greater than&#xD;
             1000 microns)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Clinically Significant Macular Edema with posterior hyaloid thickening&#xD;
             or macular traction in biomicroscopy or OCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with panretinophotocoagulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that will probably need a panretinophotocoagulation during the study (6 to 12&#xD;
             months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Record of ocular herpes infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lens opacification that may interfere with clinical, photographical or OCT&#xD;
             examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Toxoplasmosis, active or not in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vitrectomy in either eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Record of Central Serose Coroidopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pseudophakic patients with less than 6 months since surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any other situation that may interfere in study completion based in&#xD;
             Investigator´s opinion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>José Carlos Pastor Jimeno, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>IOBA - Instituto de Oftalmobiología Aplicada - Universidad de Valladolid</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>José Carlos Pastor Jimeno, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>34 983 424761</phone>
    <email>pastor@ioba.med.uva.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Francisco Blázquez Araúzo, MD</last_name>
    <phone>34 983 423238</phone>
    <email>blazquez@ioba.med.uva.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>INGO - Instituto Galego de Oftalmoloxia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago de Compostela</city>
        <state>La Coruña</state>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francisco Gómez Ulla de Irazabal, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica Universitaria de Navarra</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pamplona</city>
        <state>Navarra</state>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alfredo García Layana, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Oftalmológico de Alicante</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alicante</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>José María Ruiz Moreno, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital de la Vall D´Hebrón</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>José García Arumí, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clínico Universitario San Carlos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan Donate López, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital General Universitario Reina Sofía</name>
      <address>
        <city>Murcia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Inmaculada Selles, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IOBA - Instituto Universitario de Oftalmobiología Aplicada</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valladolid</city>
        <zip>47005</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>José Carlos Pastor Jimeno, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>34 9834761</phone>
      <email>pastor@ioba.med.uva.es</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Francisco Blázquez Araúzo, MD</last_name>
      <phone>34 983 423238</phone>
      <email>blazquez@ioba.med.uva.es</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>José Carlos Pastor Jimeno, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>María Isabel López Gálvez, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Miguel Ángel De la Fuente, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Enrique Rodríguez de la Rua, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2006</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 30, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 31, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2006</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2006</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 14, 2006</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Diabetes, Macular Edema, Triamcinolone</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Edema</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Edema</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone Acetonide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone hexacetonide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Triamcinolone diacetate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

