<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04535076</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MC 68/2017</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04535076</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cognitive Outcome After Surgical and Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement</brief_title>
  <acronym>COSTA</acronym>
  <official_title>Cognitive Outcome After Surgical and Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Heart and Brain Research Group, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Heart and Brain Research Group, Germany</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aortic valve stenosis is one of the most common types of heart disease in the aging Western&#xD;
      population. While surgical cardiac valve replacement (SAVR) is a standard therapy for&#xD;
      patients with aortic stenosis, catheter-assisted aortic valve implantation (TAVI) has&#xD;
      developed as an alternative to open-heart surgery, especially for high-risk patients.&#xD;
      Recently, increased surgeon experience and improved transcatheter valve systems have led to a&#xD;
      global trend to use TAVI in patients with low or intermediate risk. Although cognitive&#xD;
      impairment after cardiac surgery is well known, the effect of TAVI on cognitive function has&#xD;
      not yet been adequately investigated. The aim of this study is to compare the occurrence and&#xD;
      progression of delirium, postoperative cognitive decline (POCD), cerebral infarction, and&#xD;
      health-related quality of life (QOL) in patients with intermediate risk for catheter-assisted&#xD;
      (TAVI) and surgical (SAVR) aortic valve replacement.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The present project is a substudy of the DEDICATE Trial (ID: NCT03112980). It is a randomized&#xD;
      intervention study taking place at the Kerckhoff-Klink Bad Nauheim Germany (Campus Justus&#xD;
      Liebig University Giessen) involving 100 patients undergoing aortic valve replacement (TAVI&#xD;
      vs. SAVR) with a focus on cognitive outcome. A detailed assessment of psychological and&#xD;
      health-related functions will be performed before intervention, during hospitalization and 3&#xD;
      months after intervention. During hospitalization, the occurrence and progression of delirium&#xD;
      will be assessed with the Intensive Care Delirium Screening Checklist (ICDSC). Other&#xD;
      cognitive data will be collected before and 3 months after surgery with a selected and&#xD;
      comprehensive neuropsychological test battery, including the evaluation of attention, word&#xD;
      fluency, executive functions and various functional areas of memory. In addition, parameters&#xD;
      of health-related QOL will be collected before and 3 months after the intervention using the&#xD;
      SF-36, and information on anxiety and depression will be collected using the Hospital Anxiety&#xD;
      and Depression Scale (HADS). A few days after the intervention, magnetic resonance images of&#xD;
      the brain will be acquired to assess cerebral infarction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 28, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with postoperative cognitive decline at 3 months after surgery, defined as a decrease between pre- and postoperative examinations of one standard deviation in at least 20% of all objective neuropsychological parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately pre-surgery to 3 months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The objective neuropsychological parameters measure cognitive domains like immediate memory span, free recall, recognition memory, selective attention, working memory, inhibition and word fluency. These cognitive domains will be measured with the following instruments: &quot;Verbaler Lern- und Merkfähigkeitstest&quot; (VLMT), &quot;Trail Making Test A/B&quot; (TMT), &quot;Letter Number Span Test&quot; (LNS), Block Tapping Test (BTT), &quot;Regensburger Wortflüssigkeits-Test&quot; (RWT), and &quot;Syndrom-Kurz Test&quot; (SKT).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with postoperative cognitive decline at the time of discharge from the acute clinic, defined as a decrease between the pre- and postoperative examinations of one standard deviation measured with the &quot;Montreal Cognitive Assessment&quot;</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately pre-surgery to approximately 1 week post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The &quot;Montreal Cognitive Assessment&quot; (MOCA) is a screening procedure for general cognitive function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with postoperative delirium during the stay in the intensive care unit as assessed by the &quot;Intensive Care Delirium Screening Checklist&quot; (ICDSC)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately post-surgery to approximately 7 days post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative delirium is defined as the occurrence of at least one delirious episode during a stay in the intensive care unit. The &quot;Intensive Care Delirium Screening Checklist&quot; (ICDSC) record the clinical symptoms of consciousness, attention, orientation, hallucinations, psychomotor retardation or agitation, speech, and changing symptoms by observing behavior and asking concrete questions to the patient.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline cognitive failures in everyday life at 3 months after surgery as assessed by the &quot;Cognitive Failures Questionnaire&quot; (CFQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately pre-surgery to 3 months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The &quot;Cognitive Failures Questionnaire&quot; (CFQ) measure the frequency of failures in daily living in terms of memory, attention, action, and perception. It comprises 29 questions, which are answered on a 5-step Likert scale. Higher scores mean a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline health-related quality of life at 3 months after surgery as assessed by the &quot;36-Item Short Form Health Survey&quot; (SF36)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately pre-surgery to 3 months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The &quot;36-Item Short Form Health Survey&quot; (SF36) includes 36 questions covering 8 health-related factors: vitality, physical functioning, bodily pain, general health perception, physical role function, emotional role function, social role functioning, and mental health. An aggregated percentage score is calculated for each of the eight factors. The percentage scores range from 0% to 100%. Higher scores mean a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline anxiety at 3 months after surgery as assessed by the &quot;Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale&quot; (HADS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately pre-surgery to 3 months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>With the &quot;Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale&quot; (HADS), an instrument will be used that refers to the psychological core aspects of depression and anxiety. Each scale contains 7 questions to be answered on a 4-step Likert scale by the patients themselves. After inverting negative questions, higher scores mean a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline depression at 3 months after surgery as assessed by the &quot;Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale&quot; (HADS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately pre-surgery to 3 months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>With the &quot;Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale&quot; (HADS), an instrument will be used that refers to the psychological core aspects of depression and anxiety. Each scale contains 7 questions to be answered on a 4-step Likert scale by the patients themselves. After inverting negative questions, higher scores mean a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with postoperative acute ischemic lesions at the time of discharge from the acute clinic as assessed by magnetic resonance images (MRI).</measure>
    <time_frame>Once within the 6th-10th day immediately post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Cranial MRI will be performed using a 3-T scanner (Skyra; Siemens, Erlangen, Germany). The protocol of imaging will include a T2-weighted turbo spin-echo sequence, a T2-weighted turbo spin-echo sequence for dark fluid, a T1-weighted FLASH sequence and a diffusion-weighted echo-planar imaging sequence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with postoperative microemboli at the time of discharge from the acute clinic as assessed by magnetic resonance images (MRI).</measure>
    <time_frame>Once within the 6th-10th day immediately post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Cranial MRI will be performed using a 3-T scanner (Skyra; Siemens, Erlangen, Germany). The protocol of imaging will include a T2-weighted turbo spin-echo sequence, a T2-weighted turbo spin-echo sequence for dark fluid, a T1-weighted FLASH sequence and a diffusion-weighted echo-planar imaging sequence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Postoperative Delirium</condition>
  <condition>Postoperative Cognitive Dysfunction</condition>
  <condition>Transcatheter Aortic Valve Replacement</condition>
  <condition>Surgical Aortic Valve Replacement</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical Aortic Valve Replacement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation</intervention_name>
    <description>Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Surgical Aortic Valve Replacement</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical Aortic Valve Replacement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical Aortic Valve Replacement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Heart team decision that both TAVI and SAVR are medically justified based on&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Degenerative aortic valve stenosis:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Mean gradient &gt; 40 mmHg or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Jet velocity &gt; 40 m/s or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Surface of aortic valve &lt; 1.0 cm²&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient shows symptoms of aortic stenosis&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  NYHA functional class ≥ II or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Angina pectoris or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Syncope&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Low to intermediate surgical risk (STS: 2-6%)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A transfemoral or alternative access for TAVI can be implemented&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient has agreed in writing to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient is able to understand the patient information and sign it personally&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient agrees to undergo SAVR if randomization into the control group occurs&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Readiness for MRT examination and neuropsychological testing after 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients aged 65 to 85 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Native German speaker (since a neuropsychological test is language dependent)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Congenital aortic valve defects&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Untreated clinically significant coronary artery disease or severe mitral or tricuspid&#xD;
             insufficiency or mitral stenosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Previous heart surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Percutaneous coronary intervention performed within one month prior to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Hemodynamic instability requiring inotropic support or mechanical circulatory support&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ischemic stroke or intracranial bleeding within the month before the start of the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Severe ventricular dysfunction with left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 20% as&#xD;
             measured by echocardiogram&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Hypertrophic obstructive cardiomyopathy or severe basal septum hypertrophy&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Echocardiographic detection of intracardiac mass, thrombus, vegetation, or&#xD;
             endocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any other atherosclerotic disease that is considered as a contraindication for&#xD;
             isolated aortic valve surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Symptomatic carotid or vertebral artery disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Existing neurological or psychiatric disease (particularly cerebral infarction,&#xD;
             cranio- cerebral trauma, manifest depression or dementia) that may interfere with&#xD;
             neuropsychological testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Contraindications for MRI examination (e.g. cardiac pacemaker, vena cava filter,&#xD;
             claustrophobia)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martin Jünemann, Dr.med.M.Sc.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinic for Neurology, University Hospital Giessen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marius Butz, Dipl.-Psych.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, Kerckhoff Clinic Bad Nauheim</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tibo Gerriets, Prof.Dr.med.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Neurology, Gesundheitszentrum Wetterau</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Markus Schönburg, Prof.Dr.med.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, Kerckhoff Clinic Bad Nauheim</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Won-Keun Kim, Dr.med.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Cardiac Surgery, Kerckhoff Clinic Bad Nauheim</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Martin Jünemann, Dr.med.M.Sc.</last_name>
    <phone>+49641 98545301</phone>
    <email>Martin.Juenemann@neuro.med.uni-giessen.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Marius Butz, Dipl.-Psych.</last_name>
    <phone>+496032 996 5812</phone>
    <email>m.butz@kerckhoff-klinik.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Cardiac Surgery, Kerckhoff-Klinik GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Nauheim</city>
        <zip>61231</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marius Butz</last_name>
      <phone>+496032 996 5812</phone>
      <email>m.butz@kerckhoff-klinik.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Delirium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Cognitive Complications</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

