<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04535557</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Mobocertinib EAP</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1257-1911</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04535557</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Expanded Access Protocol for Mobocertinib in Refractory Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC) Participants With Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor (EGFR) Exon20 Insertion Mutations</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Expanded Access Protocol for Mobocertinib in Refractory Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer Patients With EGFR exon20 Insertion Mutations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to provide expanded compassionate use access to mobocertinib, in&#xD;
      participants with locally advanced or metastatic NSCLC harboring EGFR in-frame exon 20&#xD;
      insertion mutations and who have received at least 1 prior line of therapy for locally&#xD;
      advanced or metastatic disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The drug being tested in this study is called mobocertinib. Mobocertinib is being tested to&#xD;
      treat people who have NSCLC with EGFR exon-20 insertion mutations who have failed the current&#xD;
      standard of care (SOC) have no approved treatment therapies. Participants will be treated&#xD;
      with mobocertinib until they experience progressive disease (PD) that requires an alternate&#xD;
      therapy in the opinion of the physician, intolerable toxicity, or another discontinuation&#xD;
      criterion. Treatment may be continued after PD if, in the opinion of the physician, the&#xD;
      participant continues to experience clinical benefit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will enroll approximately 100 participants. Enrollment will be based on unsolicited&#xD;
      participant requests. All participants will be assigned to receive-&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Mobocertinib 160 milligram (mg)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dose interruptions or reductions (first dose reduction- 120 mg and second dose reduction- 80&#xD;
      mg) will be implemented for participants who experience treatment-related adverse events&#xD;
      (TEAEs), based on the clinical judgment of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This multi-center trial will be conducted in the United States. The overall time to&#xD;
      participate in this expanded access study is 4 months. The follow-up period for survival&#xD;
      begins at the end of treatment (up to 30 days past last dose) and continues until participant&#xD;
      discontinues.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Approved for marketing</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <condition>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mobocertinib 160 mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Mobocertinib 160 mg, capsule, orally, once daily in 28-day treatment cycles for up to approximately 4 months.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Have histologically or cytologically confirmed locally advanced (and not a candidate&#xD;
             for definitive therapy) or metastatic NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have a documented EGFR in-frame exon 20 insertion mutations&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. . Must have received at least 1 prior line of therapy for locally advanced or&#xD;
             metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status 0 to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Normal QT interval on screening electrocardiogram (ECG), defined as QT interval&#xD;
             corrected Fridericia (QTcF) of less than or equal to (&lt;=) 450 milliseconds (ms) in&#xD;
             males or &lt;=470 ms in females&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Received small-molecule anticancer therapy (including cytotoxic chemotherapy and&#xD;
             investigational agents) &lt;=14 days prior to first dose of mobocertinib (except for&#xD;
             reversible EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKIs) [that is, erlotinib or gefitinib],&#xD;
             which are allowed up to 7 days prior to the first dose of mobocertinib)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received radiotherapy &lt;=14 days prior to the first dose of mobocertinib or has not&#xD;
             recovered from radiotherapy-related toxicities. Palliative radiation administered&#xD;
             outside the chest and brain, stereotactic radiosurgery (SRS), and stereotactic body&#xD;
             radiotherapy are allowed up to 7 days prior to the first dose&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have known active brain metastases. Brain metastases are allowed if they have been&#xD;
             treated with surgery and/or radiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have current spinal cord compression or leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have significant, uncontrolled, or active cardiovascular disease, including, but not&#xD;
             restricted to:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction (MI);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congestive heart failure (CHF);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant arrhythmia;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ventricular arrhythmia; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cerebrovascular accident;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Transient ischemic attack.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac ejection fraction less than (&lt;) 50 percent (%) by echocardiogram or&#xD;
                  multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have prolonged QTcF interval, or being treated with medications known to be associated&#xD;
             with the development of Torsades de Pointes&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have presence of diarrhea that can be related to anti-tumoral treatment (including&#xD;
             EGFR TKI, immune therapy, chemotherapy, and investigational therapies)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Millennium Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Drug Therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

