<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04535141</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LCCC2037</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-0833</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04535141</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Olanzapine for Nausea/Vomiting Prophylaxis in Recipients of Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplants</brief_title>
  <official_title>Addition of Olanzapine to Standard CINV Prophylaxis in Hematopoietic Stem Cell Transplant</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>UNC Lineberger Comprehensive Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research study is to see if olanzapine helps to prevent nausea and/or&#xD;
      vomiting (throwing up) when it is added to other medicines in subjects having stem cell&#xD;
      transplants. Subjects will either be given olanzapine or an inactive pill (called a placebo)&#xD;
      before getting any chemotherapy that is known to cause nausea and vomiting. During the study,&#xD;
      the study coordinators will ask the subjects to complete surveys to understand if the patient&#xD;
      is having nausea and vomiting, and if so, how bad it is making the patient feel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial will split subjects into two groups: one group will be given an inactive pill&#xD;
      (placebo), and the other group will be given the active pill (olanzapine). Study coordinators&#xD;
      will collect surveys every morning before chemotherapy and 5 days after the last dose of&#xD;
      chemotherapy. These surveys may be given by members of the study team or possibly on a mobile&#xD;
      device.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects may benefit from being in this research study because olanzapine may reduce the&#xD;
      frequency or severity of chemotherapy-induced nausea and vomiting (CINV). The most common&#xD;
      risks of using olanzapine include possibly becoming more tired, mild dizziness, mild low&#xD;
      blood pressure, and mild muscle &quot;quivering.&quot; Other possible adverse effects include low blood&#xD;
      pressure, muscle weakness, increased appetite, weight gain, constipation, and liver function&#xD;
      test changes however these risks are less common in subjects with cancer. In addition, there&#xD;
      may be a change detected in heart rhythm however subjects will be screened for this ahead of&#xD;
      time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chemotherapy induced nausea and vomiting (CINV) occurs in up to 80% of patients on active&#xD;
      therapy and remains a significant barrier to quality of life. CINV can alter electrolytes and&#xD;
      enteral nutrition which can have a detrimental effect on patient adherence and health&#xD;
      outcomes. HCT patients are at increased risk for CINV because many of the conditioning&#xD;
      regimens require multiple days of high-dose chemotherapy that are, in many cases, associated&#xD;
      with highly-emetogenic potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, most conditioning regimens require a 3-drug regimen for optimal CINV prophylaxis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current Standard of Care Current guidelines support the use of olanzapine in addition to a 3&#xD;
      drug CINV regimen for highly emetogenic chemotherapy, however some controversy remains as to&#xD;
      olanzapine's place in therapy with moderately emetogenic chemotherapy. In HCT, current&#xD;
      practice at UNC utilizes an neurokinin-1 receptor antagonist (NK1 RA), serotonin receptor&#xD;
      antagonists (5-HT3 RA) and corticosteroid for CINV prophylaxis in conditioning regimens&#xD;
      including moderate and highly emetogenic chemotherapy in accordance with ASCO and NCCN&#xD;
      recommendations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Olanzapine, an atypical antipsychotic, antagonizes dopamine, serotonin, catecholamines,&#xD;
      acetylcholine, and histamine receptors which helps prevent acute, breakthrough and delayed&#xD;
      nausea. Olanzapine has shown benefit when used as prophylaxis in solid tumor patients&#xD;
      receiving single-day highly emetogenic chemotherapy. The addition of olanzapine to 5HT-3&#xD;
      antagonist, NK-1 antagonist, and dexamethasone resulted in significantly more complete&#xD;
      responses (CR) and more patients without CINV when compared to placebo in the acute, delayed&#xD;
      and overall time periods. Data with olanzapine as CINV prophylaxis is not clear in HCT&#xD;
      patients, but one retrospective study by Trifilio et. al. illustrates possible benefit in&#xD;
      HCT. They compared an aprepitant-based regimen (aprepitant, ondansetron, and steroid) to an&#xD;
      olanzapine-based regimen (olanzapine, ondansetron, and steroid) and found that patients in&#xD;
      the olanzapine group had significantly less acute and delayed nausea. In addition, the&#xD;
      olanzapine-based regimen required significantly less PRN rescue medication compared to the&#xD;
      aprepitant based regimen. These results ultimately provided the foundation for the FOND-O&#xD;
      study, a prospective trial that added olanzapine as part of CINV prophylaxis in both&#xD;
      hematologic malignancies and HCT patients. The FOND-O study compared fosaprepitant,&#xD;
      ondansetron, and dexamethasone (FOND) to fosaprepitant, ondansetron, dexamethasone and&#xD;
      olanzapine (FOND-O). The inclusion of olanzapine resulted in significantly less delayed and&#xD;
      overall nausea but did not affect the acute phase. While the FOND-O study was the first to&#xD;
      look at utilizing olanzapine as part of 4 drug CINV prophylaxis in HCT, there were only 68&#xD;
      HCT patients included in the study. Only 24 allogeneic transplants and 44 autologous&#xD;
      transplants were enrolled, and only 34 of these patients actually received olanzapine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the FOND-O study utilized an olanzapine dose of 10 mg on each day of&#xD;
      chemotherapy continued through chemotherapy day 3. Rationale for Clinical Study The purpose&#xD;
      of our proposed study is to build upon the FOND-O results by doing a prospective, randomized,&#xD;
      placebo-controlled study, focused entirely on HCT recipients, and powered to detect&#xD;
      olanzapine's potential role in CINV prophylaxis in recipients of HCT. Based upon the&#xD;
      available literature in both solid and hematologic malignancies the benefit outweighs the&#xD;
      risk of adding olanzapine to standard CINV prophylaxis. The primary endpoint is complete&#xD;
      response- defined as no emesis and no more than minimal nausea starting with the first dose&#xD;
      of highly or moderately emetogenic conditioning chemotherapy and continuing 5 days beyond the&#xD;
      last dose of highly or moderately emetogenic conditioning chemotherapy. Secondary endpoints&#xD;
      are defined explicitly&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 18, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Complete Response</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study assessment period, 5 days after last chemotherapy administration</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the overall rate of complete response amongst study subjects</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of rescue medications needed for breakthrough CINV between the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study assessment period, 5 days after last chemotherapy administration</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the total number of rescue medications needed for breakthrough CINV between the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients achieving minimal nausea between the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study assessment period, 5 days after last chemotherapy administration</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the number of patients achieving minimal nausea between the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period for the same assessment period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of nausea between patients on the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period for the same assessment period</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study assessment period, 5 days after last chemotherapy administration</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the patient reported frequency of nausea between patients on the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period for the same assessment period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient reported severity of nausea between patients in the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study assessment period, 5 days after last chemotherapy administration</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the patient reported severity of nausea between patients the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period for the same assessment period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of episodes of emesis between patients the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period for the same assessment period</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study assessment period, 5 days after last chemotherapy administration</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the number of episodes of emesis between patients the experimental and standard of care arms for the same assessment period for the same assessment period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Endpoint: To document the number of patients who experience somnolence based on CTCAE v5</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study period, 10 days after transplant</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the number of patients who experienced somnolence due to the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Endpoint: Qtc Prolongation</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study period, 10 days after transplant</time_frame>
    <description>To determine a potential change in the Qtc prolongation of the patient</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Chemotherapy-induced Nausea and Vomiting</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Olanzapine Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Olanzapine 5mg tablet with chemotherapy, and 3 days after</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Olanzapine 5 MG</intervention_name>
    <description>It will be a de-identified pill created by investigational drug services at UNC</description>
    <arm_group_label>Olanzapine Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Zyprexa</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>It will be a de-identified pill created by investigational drug services at UNC</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Written informed consent obtained to participate in the study and HIPAA authorization&#xD;
             for the release of personal health information.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Recipients receiving autologous or allogeneic HCT for any disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any conditioning chemotherapy regimen considered a standard BMT conditioning regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG Performance Status of 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The subject is willing and able to comply with study procedures based on the judgement&#xD;
             of the investigator or protocol designee.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 1. Patients must not have started conditioning chemotherapy prior to consent. Note:&#xD;
             test dose Busulfan is not part of conditioning chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known allergy to olanzapine&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Baseline QTc &gt;500 msec as calculated by Fridericia formula&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients receiving post-transplant cyclophosphamide as planned GVHD prophylaxis&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnant or breastfeeding (NOTE: patients pregnant or breast-feeding are not eligible&#xD;
             to proceed to transplant).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Has a known additional malignancy that is active and/or progressive requiring&#xD;
             treatment; exceptions include basal cell or squamous cell skin cancer, in situ&#xD;
             cervical or bladder cancer, or other cancer for which the subject has been&#xD;
             disease-free for at least five years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Treatment with any investigational drug within 7 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject is receiving prohibited medications (ciprofloxacin or fluvoxamine) that cannot&#xD;
             be discontinued/replaced by an alternative therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Ptachcinski, PharmD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>jonathan.Ptachcinski@unchealth.unc.edu</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Veronica Nguyen</last_name>
    <phone>(919) 962-0026</phone>
    <email>venguyen@email.unc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UNC Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27514</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jonathan Ptachcinski, PharmD, PhD, CPP</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Monson T, Greer D, Kreikemeier E, Liewer S. Olanzapine as a rescue antiemetic in hematopoietic stem cell transplant. J Oncol Pharm Pract. 2020 Jun;26(4):918-922. doi: 10.1177/1078155219879215. Epub 2019 Oct 21.</citation>
    <PMID>31635549</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Navari RM, Qin R, Ruddy KJ, Liu H, Powell SF, Bajaj M, Dietrich L, Biggs D, Lafky JM, Loprinzi CL. Olanzapine for the Prevention of Chemotherapy-Induced Nausea and Vomiting. N Engl J Med. 2016 Jul 14;375(2):134-42. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1515725.</citation>
    <PMID>27410922</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hesketh PJ, Kris MG, Basch E, Bohlke K, Barbour SY, Clark-Snow RA, Danso MA, Dennis K, Dupuis LL, Dusetzina SB, Eng C, Feyer PC, Jordan K, Noonan K, Sparacio D, Somerfield MR, Lyman GH. Antiemetics: American Society of Clinical Oncology Clinical Practice Guideline Update. J Clin Oncol. 2017 Oct 1;35(28):3240-3261. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2017.74.4789. Epub 2017 Jul 31. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28759346</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trifilio S, Welles C, Seeger K, Mehta S, Fishman M, McGowan K, Strejcek K, Eiten E, Pirotte C, Lucier E, DeFrates S, Mehta J. Olanzapine Reduces Chemotherapy-induced Nausea and Vomiting Compared With Aprepitant in Myeloma Patients Receiving High-dose Melphalan Before Stem Cell Transplantation: A Retrospective Study. Clin Lymphoma Myeloma Leuk. 2017 Sep;17(9):584-589. doi: 10.1016/j.clml.2017.06.012. Epub 2017 Jun 20.</citation>
    <PMID>28694084</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Navari RM, Aapro M. Antiemetic Prophylaxis for Chemotherapy-Induced Nausea and Vomiting. N Engl J Med. 2016 Apr 7;374(14):1356-67. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1515442. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27050207</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clemmons AB, Orr J, Andrick B, Gandhi A, Sportes C, DeRemer D. Randomized, Placebo-Controlled, Phase III Trial of Fosaprepitant, Ondansetron, Dexamethasone (FOND) Versus FOND Plus Olanzapine (FOND-O) for the Prevention of Chemotherapy-Induced Nausea and Vomiting in Patients with Hematologic Malignancies Receiving Highly Emetogenic Chemotherapy and Hematopoietic Cell Transplantation Regimens: The FOND-O Trial. Biol Blood Marrow Transplant. 2018 Oct;24(10):2065-2071. doi: 10.1016/j.bbmt.2018.06.005. Epub 2018 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>29906570</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Basch E, Dueck AC, Rogak LJ, Mitchell SA, Minasian LM, Denicoff AM, Wind JK, Shaw MC, Heon N, Shi Q, Ginos B, Nelson GD, Meyers JP, Chang GJ, Mamon HJ, Weiser MR, Kolevska T, Reeve BB, Bruner DW, Schrag D. Feasibility of Implementing the Patient-Reported Outcomes Version of the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events in a Multicenter Trial: NCCTG N1048. J Clin Oncol. 2018 Sep 11:JCO2018788620. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2018.78.8620. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>30204536</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chemotherapy-induced Nausea and Vomiting</keyword>
  <keyword>Chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Nausea and Vomiting</keyword>
  <keyword>Olanzapine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nausea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Olanzapine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

