<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04532060</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FoAr</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04532060</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical Trial Evaluating Chlorine e6 Derivative-mediated Antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy as a Treatment for Denture Stomatitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Clinical Trial Evaluating Chlorine e6 Derivative-mediated Antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy as a Treatment for Denture Stomatitis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>São Paulo State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>São Paulo Research Foundation (FAPESP)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>São Paulo State University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objective: This randomized clinical trial assessed antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy (aPDT)&#xD;
      mediated by Photodithazine (PDZ) to treat patients with denture stomatitis (DS).&#xD;
      Methodologies: Patients with DS were randomly assigned to the groups: aPDT (n=30) and&#xD;
      nystatin (NYS, n=35). aPDT patients received 6 aPDT sessions, three times a week for 15 days,&#xD;
      which involved PDZ (200 mg/L) topical application (20 min) on the palate and upper denture,&#xD;
      followed by light emitting diode (LED) illumination (660 nm, 50 J/cm²). NYS patients were&#xD;
      instructed to rinse one dropper of this medication for one minute, four times a day, for 15&#xD;
      days. Microbiological collections of dentures and palates were performed and cultured on&#xD;
      blood agar and CHROMAgar Candida. Microbial viability was determined, and photographs of the&#xD;
      palates were taken for clinical evaluation. Data were analyzed by Repeated Measure Linear&#xD;
      Model and Bonferroni (p≤0.05).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial Viability at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>The recovery of microorganisms was performed before the tretaments (at the baseline - initial).</time_frame>
    <description>The efficacy of the treatments was verified microbiologically at the baseline (initial). For each patient, oral swabs were rubbed onto the palatal mucosa and on the tissue surface of the denture for 1 minute to recover the microorganisms. Each swab was placed into a Falcon tube (Corning, New York, USA) containing 5 mL of 0.9% sterile saline solution and vortexed for 1 minute to suspend the microorganisms from the swab. To evaluate Candida spp. survival and to presumptively identify Candida species by colony color, serial 10-fold dilutions from 100 to 103 were plated in duplicate on Chromagar Candida and incubated at 30 °C for 5 days. Additionally, to assess the total microbiota survival (fungal and bacteria), serial 10-fold dilutions from 102 to 104 were plated onto Blood agar.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial Viability at the end of the treatments</measure>
    <time_frame>The recovery of microorganisms was performed immediately at the end of the treatments.</time_frame>
    <description>The efficacy of the treatments was verified microbiologically immediately at the end of the treatments. For each patient, oral swabs were rubbed onto the palatal mucosa and on the tissue surface of the denture for 1 minute to recover the microorganisms. Each swab was placed into a Falcon tube (Corning, New York, USA) containing 5 mL of 0.9% sterile saline solution and vortexed for 1 minute to suspend the microorganisms from the swab. To evaluate Candida spp. survival and to presumptively identify Candida species by colony color, serial 10-fold dilutions from 100 to 103 were plated in duplicate on Chromagar Candida and incubated at 30 °C for 5 days. Additionally, to assess the total microbiota survival (fungal and bacteria), serial 10-fold dilutions from 102 to 104 were plated onto Blood agar.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial Viability on day 15</measure>
    <time_frame>The recovery of microorganisms was performed on day 15 after the end of the treatments.</time_frame>
    <description>The efficacy of the treatments was verified microbiologically on day 15 after the end of the treatments. For each patient, oral swabs were rubbed onto the palatal mucosa and on the tissue surface of the denture for 1 minute to recover the microorganisms. Each swab was placed into a Falcon tube (Corning, New York, USA) containing 5 mL of 0.9% sterile saline solution and vortexed for 1 minute to suspend the microorganisms from the swab. To evaluate Candida spp. survival and to presumptively identify Candida species by colony color, serial 10-fold dilutions from 100 to 103 were plated in duplicate on Chromagar Candida and incubated at 30 °C for 5 days. Additionally, to assess the total microbiota survival (fungal and bacteria), serial 10-fold dilutions from 102 to 104 were plated onto Blood agar.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial Viability on day 30</measure>
    <time_frame>The recovery of microorganisms was performed on day 30 after the end of the treatments.</time_frame>
    <description>The efficacy of the treatments was verified microbiologically on day 30 after the end of the treatments. For each patient, oral swabs were rubbed onto the palatal mucosa and on the tissue surface of the denture for 1 minute to recover the microorganisms. Each swab was placed into a Falcon tube (Corning, New York, USA) containing 5 mL of 0.9% sterile saline solution and vortexed for 1 minute to suspend the microorganisms from the swab. To evaluate Candida spp. survival and to presumptively identify Candida species by colony color, serial 10-fold dilutions from 100 to 103 were plated in duplicate on Chromagar Candida and incubated at 30 °C for 5 days. Additionally, to assess the total microbiota survival (fungal and bacteria), serial 10-fold dilutions from 102 to 104 were plated onto Blood agar.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial Viability on day 45</measure>
    <time_frame>The recovery of microorganisms was performed on day 45 after the end of the treatments.</time_frame>
    <description>The efficacy of the treatments was verified microbiologically on day 45 after the end of the treatments. For each patient, oral swabs were rubbed onto the palatal mucosa and on the tissue surface of the denture for 1 minute to recover the microorganisms. Each swab was placed into a Falcon tube (Corning, New York, USA) containing 5 mL of 0.9% sterile saline solution and vortexed for 1 minute to suspend the microorganisms from the swab. To evaluate Candida spp. survival and to presumptively identify Candida species by colony color, serial 10-fold dilutions from 100 to 103 were plated in duplicate on Chromagar Candida and incubated at 30 °C for 5 days. Additionally, to assess the total microbiota survival (fungal and bacteria), serial 10-fold dilutions from 102 to 104 were plated onto Blood agar.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>Standardized photographs of the palates were taken prior to the beginning of the treatments (initial) and up to 45 days after the end of the treatments.</time_frame>
    <description>To verify the clinical efficacy of the treatments, the oral lesions on the palatal mucosal were evaluated. For this, standardized photographs of the palates were taken prior to the beginning of the treatments (initial) and up to 45 days after the end of the treatments. All the photographs were taken with the same digital camera (NIKON D7000, Tokyo, Japan), by the same operator, under the same conditions (place, light, position). After that, all photographs were analyzed by two individuals blinded to the treatment performed, to classify the oral lesion in type I, II or III in all time intervals.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">65</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Care Associated Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients treated with Antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nystatin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients treated with Nystatin antifungal drug.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nystatin</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Nystatin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Antimicrobial Photodynamic Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Edentulous denture wearers clinically diagnosed with denture stomatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who received antibiotics, antifungal or steroids in the past 3 months prior&#xD;
             to the beginning of the research, women in the reproductive phase, patients who had&#xD;
             worn the same denture in the past 10 years, diabetics, anemics, immunocompromised and&#xD;
             under cancer treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cross Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatitis, Denture</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anti-Infective Agents</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nystatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anti-Bacterial Agents</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

