<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04538222</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202007050RIND</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04538222</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Workplace Physical Activity Intervention</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Effectiveness Study of Workplace Physical Activity Intervention for Staff in a Hospital Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, it investigates the effectiveness of workplace physical activity intervention&#xD;
      for staff in a 100-bed hospital in Taipei City, Taiwan. The physical activity program takes&#xD;
      group coaching and includes aerobic exercise, muscle strength and stretching in combination&#xD;
      with nutrition education. The duration of the program is three months (8 sessions per month).&#xD;
      The subjects of the study were recruited from full-time employees working at the hospital who&#xD;
      attend the program. The recruited employees can take part in the program freely and chose&#xD;
      types of activity by themselves. This study measures body mass index, muscle strength, body&#xD;
      fat percentage, muscle strength, body mass index, daily energy expenditure, and exercise&#xD;
      self-efficacy as the baseline. After 3-month program, we will evaluate the effectiveness of&#xD;
      the program. The result is anticipated the greater frequent attendance, the more obvious&#xD;
      effectiveness in outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A three-month group coaching physical activity program in combination with nutrition&#xD;
      education was developed for full-time employees working on a 100-bed hospital in Taipei City,&#xD;
      Taiwan. Due to the setting that employees can take part in the program freely and chose types&#xD;
      of activity by themselves. So participants may have various intensity of participation. This&#xD;
      study aims to evaluate the effectiveness of pre- and post- 3-month workplace physical&#xD;
      activity programs in body fat percentage, Muscle strength, body mass index, daily energy&#xD;
      expenditure, and exercise self-efficacy. One group pretest-posttest design was used for the&#xD;
      study by convenience sampling technique. Subjects were recruited from participants of the&#xD;
      program. The intervention consists of : (1)education on nutrition: 2 times per month for 3&#xD;
      months, 1 hour/time ; and (2)physical activity: a three-month group coaching program (24&#xD;
      sessions), including three types of exercise courses such as aerobic exercise, muscle&#xD;
      strength and stretching. All analyses were performed using Statistics Analysis System version&#xD;
      9.3 and the effects of the intervention were assessed by the paired t-test. Multiple&#xD;
      regression analysis was used to determine the contribution of attendances of activities and&#xD;
      behavior change stage to effectiveness of workplace physical activity. The level of&#xD;
      significance was set at p &lt; 0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 7, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 14, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Body fat percentage at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 month after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Body fat percentage was the total mass of fat divided by total body mass, multiplied by 100. Estimate for body fat percentage was measured by dual frequency bio-electric impedance(BIA) body composition analyzer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Muscle strength at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 month after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Muscle strength was assessed by hand grip strength using a grip strength dynamometer. The grip strength dynamometer can measure range from 5 to 100 kg. During the measurement, the subject stood upright and was asked to hold the grip with the dynamometer with the greatest strength. Take the maximum value after two measurements.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline exercise self-efficacy at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 month after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The five-item self-efficacy questionnaire designed to measure confidence in one's ability to persist with exercising in various situations which included the following: tired, bad mood, don't have the time, on vacation, raining or snowing. An 7-point scale was used to rate each item of self-efficacy, scores range from 5 &quot;not at all confident&quot; to 35 &quot;very confident&quot;. A score of 0 means &quot;extremely low self-efficacy&quot; and a score of 35 means&quot; &quot;extremely high self efficacy&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline body mass index at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 month after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Body mass index (BMI) was calculated as body weight (kg) divided by the square of the body height (meter) (m2). BMI was assessed using a body composition analyzer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from Baseline Daily energy expenditure at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 3 month after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Daily energy expenditure as an estimate of total kilo-calories of energy expended per day. Calculation from the seven-day physical activity recall questionnaire. Subjects were asked to list total activities in each category and quantifying the time spent (hour) in each activity over a seven-day period. Activities were classified by their energy requirements, expressed in terms of Metabolic Equivalent of Task (MET). Sleep = 1 MET; light activity = 1.0-2.9 MET (MET level: 1.5); moderate activity = 3.0-5.0 MET (MET level: 4); hard activity =5.1-6.9 MET (MET level: 6); very hard activity = 7.0 or greater MET (MET level: 10). Each activity's total kilo-calories of energy expended per day was calculated by the following equation: activity MET * times of having activity time(hours)*body weight(kg)/7 (day).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Promotion</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>physical activity</intervention_name>
    <description>aerobic exercise, muscle strength and stretching, nutrition education</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        individuals who participate hospital self-developed workplace physical activity&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  full-time employees&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  accepted or are participating participate other weight control related research or&#xD;
             interventional medicine&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei City</city>
        <state>新店區</state>
        <zip>231</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 4, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>workplace</keyword>
  <keyword>health promotion</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

