<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04535479</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>00095077-A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04535479</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dry Needling for Spasticity in Stroke</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neurophysiological Characterization of Dry Needling in People With Spasticity Due to Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medical University of South Carolina</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medical University of South Carolina</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study team is recruiting 20 adults with spasticity due to chronic stroke and 20 adults&#xD;
      with no neurological injuries for a 2 day study. In people with chronic stroke, one of the&#xD;
      most common and disabling problems is spasticity (increased muscle tone or muscle stiffness).&#xD;
      The purpose of this research study is to examine effects of dry needling on the nervous&#xD;
      system (pathways between the muscle, spinal cord, and brain) in people with spasticity due to&#xD;
      chronic stroke. Dry needling is a procedure in which a thin, stainless steel needle is&#xD;
      inserted into your skin to produce a muscle twitch response. It is intended to release a knot&#xD;
      in your muscle and relieve pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total study duration is 2 days. The first visit will take about 3 hours, during which dry&#xD;
      needling will take place, and the second visit will take about 1 hour. During both visits you&#xD;
      will be asked to participate in examinations of reflexes (muscle responses to non-invasive&#xD;
      nerve stimulation) and arm/leg function.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the H-reflex amplitude in response to nerve stimulation</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, immediately after DDN, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>H-reflex amplitude (mV) reflects the excitability of its reflex pathway. Changes in the H-reflex amplitude indicate that DDN influences the spinal reflex excitability. In the lower extremity this will be measured in the tibialis anterior and the triceps surae. In the upper extremity this will be measured in flexor carpi ulnaris and flexor carpi radialis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>2. Changes in cutaneous reflexes elicited by non-noxious stimulation of cutaneous or mix nerves</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, immediately after DDN, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in the cutaneous reflex amplitudes would indicate that DDN can influence the spinal processing of cutaneous information.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>3. Changes in perception of cutaneous stimuli as measured by perception and radiating threshold of cutaneous nerve stimulation</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, immediately after DDN, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in thresholds of cutaneous nerve stimulation would imply that DDN can affect the perception of cutaneous input.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ability to move the arm or leg as measured by the Fugl-Meyer Assessment (FMA)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>An increase in the FMA score indicates better movement of the arm or leg.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in spasticity as measured by the Modified Ashworth Scale (mAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>The mAS score ranges from 0: normal muscle tone to 4: rigid in flexion or extension. A decrease in mAS indicates decreased spasticity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the ability to move the limb as measured by range of motion (ROM)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, immediately after DDN, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>ROM is measured in degrees using a standard goniometer. Increased ROM, which will be measured both passively (moved by the assessor) and actively (participant moves the arm themselves), indicates improved ability to move the limb.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pain level as measured by the visual analog scale (VAS) for pain</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, immediately after DDN, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>Pain is rated by the participant on a scale from 0 (no pain) to 10 (worst pain imaginable). Decreased score on the VAS for pain indicates decreased pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in brain activity as measured by electroencephalography (EEG)</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, during DDN, immediately after DDN, 90 minutes after DDN, and 72 hours after DDN</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in EEG (brain wave) activity in response to DDN would suggest that the intervention has an effect on the central nervous system and the brain. Knowing if and how the brain activity changes will help investigators understand the potential impact of this type of intervention.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <condition>Muscle Spasticity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Individuals with spasticity resulting from stroke</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an experimental intervention in which individuals will receive dry needling to relieve spasticity in the target muscle. The study team will examine the effects of this treatment on the nervous system by performing assessments just prior to, immediately after, 90 minutes after, and 72 hours after dry needling. These assessments will examine how you move your arm or leg and how your nervous system responds to non-invasive nerve stimulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Individuals with no known neurological injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This is an experimental intervention in which individuals will receive dry needling of an arm or leg muscle. The study team will examine the effects of this treatment on the nervous system by performing assessments just prior to, immediately after, 90 minutes after, and 72 hours after dry needling. These assessments will examine how you move your arm or leg and how your nervous system responds to non-invasive nerve stimulation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dry Needling</intervention_name>
    <description>Dry needling is a procedure in which a thin, stainless steel needle is inserted into the skin to produce a muscle twitch response. It is intended to release a knot in a muscle and relieve pain.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Individuals with no known neurological injury</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Individuals with spasticity resulting from stroke</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For adults with no known neurological conditions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no known neurological injuries.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For individuals after stroke:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  neurologically stable for &gt;6 months (and &gt;1 yr post stroke)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  medical clearance to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unilateral ankle and/or wrist spasticity, confirmed by Modified Ashworth Scale (MAS) &gt;&#xD;
             1 and the presence of spastic hyperreflexia&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  motoneuron injury (i.e. the neurons that give rise to the axons innervating the&#xD;
             muscles) with inadequate response to stimulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a cardiac condition ( history of myocardial infarction, congestive heart failure,&#xD;
             pacemaker use, coronary artery disease, atrial fibrillation, congenital heart disease,&#xD;
             uncontrolled hypertension)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a medically unstable condition (including temporary infections and pregnancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &lt;18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cognitive impairment sufficient to interfere with informed consent or successful&#xD;
             completion of the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  metal allergies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  needle phobias&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lymphedema over a limb (due to risk of infection/cellulitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  abnormal bleeding tendencies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  compromised immune system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  uncontrolled diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of epilepsy (as DDN generates strong somatosensory sensation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  anxiety disorders or in distress.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aiko K Thompson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Blair Dellenbach, MSOT</last_name>
    <phone>843-792-6313</phone>
    <email>stecb@musc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of South Carolina</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>South Carolina</state>
        <zip>29405</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Blair Dellenbach, MSOT</last_name>
      <phone>843-792-6313</phone>
      <email>stecb@musc.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medical University of South Carolina</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aiko Thompson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dry Needling</keyword>
  <keyword>Nervous System</keyword>
  <keyword>Central Nervous System</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muscle Spasticity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

