<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04537416</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017P001215/PHS</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04537416</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fertility, Hypercoagulability, and Inflammation (FREYA) Registry</brief_title>
  <acronym>FREYA</acronym>
  <official_title>Multidisciplinary Team-Based Study to Optimize the Evaluation and Treatment of Women With Thrombophilia and Recurrent Pregnancy Loss</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brigham and Women's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brigham and Women's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A PubMed search of &quot;thrombophilia&quot; and &quot;infertility&quot; yields only 98 articles, the majority&#xD;
      found in foreign medical journals and subspecialty journals with narrow readerships. Outside&#xD;
      of Assisted Reproduction Clinics at academic medical centers, health care providers have&#xD;
      limited awareness of the literature supporting thrombophilia evaluation and treatment in&#xD;
      patients with recurrent pregnancy loss. As a result, women may suffer through years of&#xD;
      repeated miscarriages before a thrombophilia evaluation is performed. By the time&#xD;
      thrombophilia has been diagnosed as the cause of recurrent pregnancy loss, couples have often&#xD;
      exhausted their personal savings on costly assisted reproductive therapies and present&#xD;
      frustrated and psychologically exhausted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, we will evaluate the frequency of thrombophilia as a cause of recurrent&#xD;
      pregnancy loss and provide insights into our patient care experience at BWH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Over a 2-year period, we will perform a retrospective observational cohort analysis of 1000&#xD;
      patients referred to the BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery for evaluation&#xD;
      of recurrent pregnancy loss. This cohort will include a retrospective analysis of 200&#xD;
      infertility patients referred to Dr. Piazza's Cardiovascular Medicine clinic for evaluation&#xD;
      of thrombophilia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will also enroll prospectively for 18 months patients referred to the BWH Center for&#xD;
      Infertility and Reproductive Surgery for evaluation of recurrent pregnancy loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will include a study population that is representative of the ethnic and racial diversity&#xD;
      of women who receive care at BWH. We will not enroll post-menopausal women, men or children&#xD;
      because recurrent pregnancy loss specifically affects women of child-bearing potential. We do&#xD;
      not plan to enroll pregnant women because we are specifically focused on women with recurrent&#xD;
      pregnancy loss presenting for assisted reproductive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective Cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For our retrospective analysis we will include 800 consecutive women at least 18 years old&#xD;
      but not greater than 40 years old with a chief complaint of recurrent pregnancy loss referred&#xD;
      to the BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery and 200 consecutive patients&#xD;
      referred to Dr. Piazza's Cardiovascular Medicine clinic for evaluation of thrombophilia as a&#xD;
      cause of recurrent pregnancy loss. This will provide a total of 1000 patients for the&#xD;
      retrospective cohort analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Age 18-40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 2 or more pregnancy losses (including chemical pregnancies but not ectopic pregnancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Evaluated at the BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery or the Watkins&#xD;
           Cardiovascular Clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Infertility due to uterine factors (such as Asherman's Syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Known translocation carrier&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Prior venous thromboembolism on anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Abnormal uterine cavity on hysterosalpingogram/hysteroscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective Cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the 18-month prospective cohort analysis, we will enroll consecutive patients evaluated&#xD;
      at the BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery for recurrent pregnancy loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Age 18-40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 2 or more pregnancy losses (including chemical pregnancies but not ectopic pregnancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Evaluated at the BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Infertility due to uterine factors (such as Asherman's Syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Known translocation carrier&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Prior venous thromboembolism on anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Abnormal uterine cavity on hysterosalpingogram/hysteroscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      From the EPIC Electronic Health Record (EHR), we will record demographic characteristics,&#xD;
      comorbid conditions, details about the presentation of infertility, pregnancy losses, and&#xD;
      prior assisted reproductive treatments, thrombophilia panel results, treatments, and&#xD;
      outcomes, including successful pregnancies and deliveries. We will calculate the prevalence&#xD;
      of thrombophilia in patients referred to BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery&#xD;
      for evaluation of recurrent pregnancy loss. We will describe the outcomes of patients&#xD;
      receiving prophylactic low-dose anticoagulation, including bleeding, thrombotic events, and&#xD;
      live births. We will perform multivariable regression analyses to answer additional key&#xD;
      questions of predictors of thrombophilia as a cause of recurrent pregnancy loss and&#xD;
      successful treatment of infertility due to thrombophilia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed retrospective and prospective cohort analysis will provide information about the&#xD;
      standard of care at BWH for patients with recurrent pregnancy loss who may have&#xD;
      thrombophilia. The registry will not change the standard of care for diagnosis and treatment&#xD;
      of the patients at BWH in any way. The registry will not mandate any testing or treatments.&#xD;
      There will be no required study visits, follow-up, or subject or provider contact.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis Plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will describe the results of patients receiving prophylactic anticoagulation, including&#xD;
      frequency of bleeding and thrombotic events. We will calculate the prevalence of&#xD;
      thrombophilia in patients referred to BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery for&#xD;
      evaluation of recurrent pregnancy loss. We will perform multivariable regression analyses to&#xD;
      answer additional key questions of predictors of thrombophilia as a cause of recurrent&#xD;
      pregnancy loss, chemical pregnancy after assisted reproductive therapy, and successful&#xD;
      treatment of infertility due to thrombophilia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of laboratory diagnosed thrombophilia</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory diagnosed acquired or inherited thrombophilia</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Thrombophilia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Women with recurrent pregnancy loss</arm_group_label>
    <description>consecutive women at least 18 years old but not greater than 40 years old with a chief complaint of recurrent pregnancy loss</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>No intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>Women with recurrent pregnancy loss</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women at least 18 years old but not greater than 40 years old with a chief complaint of&#xD;
        recurrent pregnancy loss&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 18-40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. 2 or more pregnancy losses (including chemical pregnancies but not ectopic pregnancy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evaluated at the BWH Center for Infertility and Reproductive Surgery or the Watkins&#xD;
             Cardiovascular Clinic&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Infertility due to uterine factors (such as Asherman's Syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Known translocation carrier&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Prior venous thromboembolism on anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Abnormal uterine cavity on hysterosalpingogram/hysteroscopy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>It is a study on miscarriage. Hence can only be women.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brigham and Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gregory Piazza, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-732-6984</phone>
      <email>gpiazza@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 3, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brigham and Women's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Samuel Z.Goldhaber, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Thrombosis Research Group</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombophilia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

