<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04536064</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LVA+LIPOSUCTION IN LYMPHEDEMA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04536064</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COMBINATION OF LYMPHATICO-VENULAR ANASTOMOSIS AND LIPOSUCTION IN TREATING LYMPHEDEMA</brief_title>
  <official_title>COMBINATION OF LYMPHATICO-VENULAR ANASTOMOSIS AND LIPOSUCTION TO TREAT CANCER-RELATED LYMPHEDEMA: RATIONALE FOR A REGIONAL APPROACH</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Siena</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Siena</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      -  cooperation of an International team with many years of experience in surgical&#xD;
           management of lymphedema&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  description of an effective surgical strategy to treat cancer-related lymphedema, a high&#xD;
           incidence pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the combination of LVA and liposuction guarantees long lasting results&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cancer-related lymphedema represents one of the major complications of cancer treatment,&#xD;
      especially for breast and gynecologic cancers. Moreover, it has high impact on cancer&#xD;
      survivors and healthcare systems. Lymphedema management still remains challenging. The better&#xD;
      understanding of lymphedema physiopathology as well as the development of sophisticated&#xD;
      surgical and diagnostic techniques have led to effective strategies to address lymphedema&#xD;
      patients but, despite the considerable interest in international literature, no consensus&#xD;
      exist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The authors present a retrospective analysis of 24 consecutive patients affected by&#xD;
      cancer-related lymphedema treated by the combination of LVA and liposuction in the same&#xD;
      surgical session. Patients data regarding limb volume, lymphangitis rate and quality of life&#xD;
      index were assessed before surgery and 1 year after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One year after surgery an average volume reduction of 37,9% was registered. Lymphangitis rate&#xD;
      significantly decreased after surgery to 0.95 per year. Quality of life score improved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CONCLUSIONS The combination of LVA and liposuction represents an effective strategy in&#xD;
      treating patients with cancer-related lymphedema, ensuring a significant decrease in volume&#xD;
      and reduction of lymphangitis rate as well as stable results in time. In addition, it appears&#xD;
      to be minimally invasive and well tolerated by patients, since it can be performed under&#xD;
      local anesthesia with low risk of complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Volume reduction of the limb</measure>
    <time_frame>one year after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>mesurement of volume reduction</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Description of an Effective Surgical Strategy to Treat Cancer Related Lymphedema, a High Incidence Pathology</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LVA and liposuction</intervention_name>
    <description>Tumescent technique in lymph-sparing fashion was adopted. Areas were infiltrated with a mix of a standard tumescent solution consisting for each liter of in 1000 ml of saline solution, 50 ml lidocaine 1%, 1 ml epinephrine 1:1000, 10 ml bicarbonate 8,4%. Infiltration volume was approximately from 0,5 to 1 liter for the upper extremities and 1-2 liters for lowers. Three to 4 mm 3 holes blunt cannulas were employed. Aspiration technique was as parallel as possible along the lymphatic network pattern and from superficial to deep layers.&#xD;
Lymphatic vessels identified at ICG lymphography were spared. Volume of the aspirate was aimed to approximate 80 percent of the volume difference between the affected and non affected side.&#xD;
The number and type of anastomosis were recorded as well as amount of removed lipoaspirate versus the excess limb volume.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        24 patients with secondary lymphedema&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        previous lymphadenectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        free from cancer related pathology&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Guido Gabriele</name>
      <address>
        <city>Siena</city>
        <state>SI</state>
        <zip>54100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Siena</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Guido Gabriele</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lymphedema</keyword>
  <keyword>lva</keyword>
  <keyword>liposuction</keyword>
  <keyword>treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphedema</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

