<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04536506</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>60116787-020/66911</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04536506</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bobath and Vojta Therapy for DS</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Effectiveness of Bobath Therapy and Vojta Technique in Babies With Down Syndrome Aged 0-24 Months: A Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pamukkale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pamukkale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Different physiotherapy approaches and education programs are applied to minimize motor and&#xD;
      mental impairment in children with Down syndrome (DS). The present study was conducted with&#xD;
      the aim of comparing the effectiveness of two different physiotherapy approaches in babies&#xD;
      with Down syndrome in the early period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 23 babies with DS aged between 0-24 months were included in the study. Infants&#xD;
      were randomly divided to two groups: Bobath therapy (BT) group included 12 infants (6 girls&#xD;
      and 6 boys) and Vojta technique (VT) group included 11 infants (4 girls and 7 boys). The&#xD;
      infants were applied a total of 12 sessions of physiotherapy (twice weekly during 6 weeks).&#xD;
      Alberta Infant Motor Scale (AIMS) was used for comparison of motor development level before&#xD;
      and after the therapy. Emotional status of the mothers was evaluated with Beck Depression&#xD;
      Scale (BDS) and quality of life was evaluated with Nottigham Health Profile (NHP).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 26, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 26, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 26, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alberta Infant Motor Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Alberta Infant Motor Scale is a tool which evaluates the infants from baby to independently walking children and measures delay in motor performance, enables families and clinicians to obtain data about motor performance of the infant, compares motor performance before and after therapy. The child is observed when performing spontaneous behaviors with a certain postural control. The scale measures weight transfer, posture and anti-gravity movements at supine, prone, sitting and standing positions with 58 items. The child receives 1 point for the movements he/she can perform and 0 point for the ones that he/she cannot perform. It is a reliable test with norm reference and suitable for clinical use due to taking short time.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Beck Depression Scale is a scale used for evaluating emotional status of the mothers and it was arranged so as to include the symptoms of depression. Items of the scale were prepared based on clinical observations and data, not based on any hypothetical opinion. The Likert type scale is composed of 21 symptom categories. Each symptom category is scored between 0 and 3 with the highest possible score of 63. Higher scores indicates more severe depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nottingham Health Profile</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Nottingham Health Profile was used for assessment of quality of life of the mothers. This is a scale which is commonly used in clinical practice and includes 38 items that evaluate quality of life in 6 sections (pain, energy level, social isolation, emotional reaction, physical activity). Ratio of the &quot;yes&quot; answers is evaluated and each section is scored between 0 and 100 where 0 is the best and 100 is the worst score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">23</enrollment>
  <condition>Down Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Motor Performance</condition>
  <condition>Bobath Therapy</condition>
  <condition>Vojta Technique</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Bobath group received 45 min of sessions three times weekly for 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Vojta group received the following three times weekly for 12 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bobath Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Bobath group received 45 min of sessions three times weekly for 12 weeks. An individual program was scheduled for each case following pre-assessment. It was targeted to enable normal posture, facilitation of corrective balance and protective responses and development of normal movement patterns</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vojta technique</intervention_name>
    <description>Vojta group received the following three times weekly for 12 weeks: 1. Reflex crawling, 2. First stage of reflex turning, 3. Second stage of reflex turning. Stimuli (pressure and stretch) for 30-60 sec were given by using the main stimulus points and auxiliary stimulus points together.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  being between 0 and 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  being diagnosed with DS&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having an additional neuro-motor disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>24 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pamukkale University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denizli</city>
        <zip>20070</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Pamukkale University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>AYŞE ÜNAL</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research assistant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>infant with Down Syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>Bobath therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Vojta technique</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Down Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

