<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04536454</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>iFIT-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04536454</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess Safety and PET Imaging Characteristics of a Novel Senescence-specific Radiotracer [18F]FPyGal (2-[Fluorine-18]Fluoro-3-pyridinyl-β-D-galactopyranoside)</brief_title>
  <acronym>SenPET</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 1/2, Open-label Study to Assess Safety, Tolerability, Biodistribution, Radiation Dosimetry and PET Imaging Characteristics of [18F]FPyGal in Comparison to in Vitro Diagnostics for the Assessment of Senescence in Oncological Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital Tuebingen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital Tuebingen</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is of particular interest to find out whether it is possible to use the novel radiotracer&#xD;
      [18F]FPyGal to be tested to detect areas after standard tumor therapy that contain resistant&#xD;
      (therapy-resistant) tumor cells. This resistance phenomenon in tumor tissues, which may be&#xD;
      visualized with the radiotracer [18F]FPyGal, is called tumor senescence.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The so-called tumor senescence is described as a resistance mechanism, which can be the basis&#xD;
      for the non-response to most common chemotherapies. It is believed that the identification of&#xD;
      so-called senescent tumors could improve treatment strategies for solid tumors and, in&#xD;
      particular, avoid inefficient treatment of patients with highly toxic drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to investigate the safety, radiation exposure (dosimetry) and&#xD;
      diagnostic accuracy of the novel diagnostic substance [18F]FPyGal if it is used before tumor&#xD;
      imaging imaging (here: positron emission tomography combined with magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
      (PET / MRT) or in combination with computed tomography (PET / CT)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diagnostic substances used in imaging such as [18F]FPyGal are known as radiotracers, since&#xD;
      their distribution in the tumor tissue can provide information about the special tumor&#xD;
      biological processes taking place there.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the context of this study, it is of particular interest to find out whether it is possible&#xD;
      to use the novel radiotracer [18F]FPyGal to detect areas after standard tumor therapy that&#xD;
      contain particularly resistant (therapy-resistant) tumor cells. This resistance phenomenon in&#xD;
      tumor tissues, which may be visualized with the radiotracer [18F]FPyGal, is called tumor&#xD;
      senescence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The latest research results show that senescent tumor cells can not only evade different&#xD;
      forms of chemotherapy or radiation therapy. Senescent tumor cells can also cause the cancer&#xD;
      to come back later. That is why current therapeutic research is concentrating on developing&#xD;
      new approaches to combat such senescent tumor cells. For this it is relevant to be able to&#xD;
      first diagnose senescent tumor cells as well as possible using imaging.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 28, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and severity of adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and severity of adverse events (AEs) (CTCAE V5.0) over 7 days Grade 1: no interruption; Grade 2: interrupt until Grade 0/1; Grade 3 and &gt;3: interruption of study</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients exhibiting positive signals for senescent tumor cells in PET-imaging and/or tumor histopathology</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 6 month</time_frame>
    <description>Positive [18F]FPyGal-PET-imaging of patient's tumor will be correlated with histopathology using senescence specific biomarkers against SABG (senescence-associated ß-galactosidase), p16, p21, and p53</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>[18F]FPyGal</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cancer patients will first be treated with a tumor type-specific neo-adjuvant chemotherapy regimen (standard-of-care); subsequently, they will undergo surgical resection of their primary tumors in a curative intention.&#xD;
After the end of the neo-adjuvant therapy a tracer injection with [18F]FPyGal solution will be administered (study intervention). Immediately after the injection a dynamic PET/MR imaging of the tumor sites including heart or large arterial blood pools will be conducted over 90 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[18F]FPyGal</intervention_name>
    <description>Radiotracer for PET-imaging</description>
    <arm_group_label>[18F]FPyGal</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>non-invasive imaging of tumor senescence</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female patients ≥ 18 years of age at the time of signing the informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with locally advanced primary non-operable solid tumors (AEGs, rectum&#xD;
             cancers, NSCLCs, NUT midline carcinomas (NMC))&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance (ECOG) Status ≤ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate bone marrow, renal, and hepatic function defined by laboratory tests within&#xD;
             14 days prior to study treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥ 100,000/µl&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT (alanine transaminase) and AST (aspartate transaminase) ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PT-INR (prothrombin time and international normalized ratio) /PTT (partial&#xD;
                  thromboplastin time)= ≤ 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatine kinase ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dl or creatinine clearance ≥ 60 ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients scheduled for neo-adjuvant (radio-) chemotherapy and subsequent tumor surgery&#xD;
             (Groups a-c) or tumor biopsy (Group d)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understand and voluntarily sign an informed consent document prior to any study&#xD;
             related assessments/ procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to adhere to the study visit schedule and other protocol requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent to practice double-barrier contraception until end of the study (28 days after&#xD;
             last [18F]FPyGal injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Females of childbearing potential (FCBP) must agree&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  to use two reliable forms of contraception simultaneously or practice&#xD;
                       complete abstinence from heterosexual contact for at least 28 days before&#xD;
                       starting study drug, while participating in the study (including dose&#xD;
                       interruptions), and for at least 28 days after end of study treatment and&#xD;
                       must agree to pregnancy testing during this timeframe&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  to abstain from breastfeeding during study participation and 7 days after&#xD;
                       end of study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Males must agree&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  to use a latex condom during any sexual contact with FCBP while&#xD;
                       participating in the study and for at least 28 days after end of study&#xD;
                       treatment, even if he has undergone a successful vasectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  to refrain from donating semen or sperm while participating in the study and&#xD;
                       for at least 28 days after end of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any contraindication for MRI (impaired renal function and / or known hypersensitivity&#xD;
             to gadolinium-containing contrast agent are not considered as contraindication, since&#xD;
             then imaging will be performed without gadolinium contrast agent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to [18F]FPyGal or its components or to any drug with similar&#xD;
             chemical structure or to any excipient present in the pharmaceutical form of the&#xD;
             investigational medicinal product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administration of any kind of PET tracer within a period corresponding to 8 half-lives&#xD;
             of the representative radionuclide (e.g. for fluorine-18: 109.77 min, 8x109.77 min&#xD;
             =14.7 h)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent toxicity (&gt;Grade 2) according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse&#xD;
             Events [CTCAE] version 5.0, caused by previous cancer therapy, excluding alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical signs of active infection (&gt; Grade 2 according to CTCAE version 5.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunocompromised patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or chronic viral hepatitis (HBV or HCV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of autoimmune disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of relevant CNS pathology or current relevant CNS (central nervous system)&#xD;
             pathology (e.g. seizure, paresis, aphasia, cerebrovascular ischemia/hemorrhage, severe&#xD;
             brain injuries, dementia, Parkinson's disease, cerebellar disease, organic brain&#xD;
             syndrome, psychosis, coordination or movement disorder) Epilepsy requiring&#xD;
             pharmacologic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Therapeutic anticoagulation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 4 weeks of starting study treatment. Patients must have recovered&#xD;
             from any effects of major surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving any systemic chemotherapy or radio-therapy within 2 weeks prior to&#xD;
             study treatment or a longer period depending on the defined characteristics of the&#xD;
             agents used&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Heart failure NYHA (New York Heart Association) III/IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe obstructive or restrictive ventilation disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of GI-perforation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not able to declare meaningful informed consent on their own&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women during pregnancy and lactation; female patients of childbearing potential or&#xD;
             male patients with female partners of childbearing potential not willing to practice&#xD;
             effective contraception by using a double-barrier method from Day 0 until 28 days&#xD;
             post-dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male patients planning to donate sperm while participating in the study and for at&#xD;
             least 28 days after end of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in other clinical trials or observation period of competing trials&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lars Zender, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital of Tübingen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christian la Fougere, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+49-7071 29-0</phone>
    <email>christian.lafougere@med.uni-tuebingen.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ulrich M Lauer, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+49-7071 29-0</phone>
    <email>ulrich.lauer@med.uni-tuebingen.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Tübingen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tübingen</city>
        <state>BW</state>
        <zip>72076</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christian la Fougere, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+49 7071 29-86553</phone>
      <email>christian.lafougere@med.uni-tuebingen</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lars Zender, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+49 7071 29-83675</phone>
      <email>lars.zender@med.uni-tuebingen.de</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 31, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Senescence</keyword>
  <keyword>[18F]FPyGal</keyword>
  <keyword>PET / CT</keyword>
  <keyword>PET / MRI</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

