<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04530149</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019-03-17</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04530149</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vital Capacity in Ultrasound Guided Serratus Plane Block in ED Patients With Multiple Rib Fractures</brief_title>
  <official_title>Vital Capacity in Ultrasound Guided Serratus Plane Block in Emergency Department Patients With Multiple Rib Fractures: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Antonios Likourezos</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maimonides Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      I. Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with multiple rib fractures are challenging from both pulmonary and analgesia&#xD;
      perspectives. Adequate pain management is essential in prevention of complications secondary&#xD;
      to decreased inspiratory volume. Significant morbidity and mortality of rib fractures is&#xD;
      secondary to severe pain that limits ribcage movement, decreases inspiratory volumes and&#xD;
      causes inadequate cough. Decreased vital capacity predisposes patients to atelectasis,&#xD;
      abnormal mucous clearance and pneumonia. The objective of this study is to assess the&#xD;
      efficacy of the serratus anterior plane block (SAPB) in improvement of vital capacity in&#xD;
      patients with multiple unilateral rib fractures when compared to conventional management with&#xD;
      medications. Currently, evidence of efficacy of SAPB in managing pain secondary to multiple&#xD;
      rib fractures is limited to case reports and series, none of which evaluate vital capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. Significance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The findings of this study may indicate that SAPB is superior to pharmacological management&#xD;
      in increasing vital capacity in patients with multiple unilateral rib fractures and suggest&#xD;
      SAPB for first line therapy in patients with rib fractures. The findings may decrease the&#xD;
      risk of pulmonary complications as well as the use of opiates in management of multiple rib&#xD;
      fractures in the Emergency Department especially in patients with numerous comorbidities and&#xD;
      contraindications to conventional treatment modalities. This study may support the need for&#xD;
      training emergency medicine physicians in bedside SAPB in order to provide the optimal&#xD;
      therapy for patient with multiple unilateral rib fractures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Study Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objectives are to evaluate whether ultrasound guided SAPB results in a greater&#xD;
      improvement in percent predicted vital capacity compared to standard therapy with a sham&#xD;
      injection. The investigators will also evaluate pain scores and the safety profile of the&#xD;
      SAPB procedure compared to those receiving standard analgesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary hypothesis is that SAPB is superior to sham injection in improving the percent of&#xD;
      predicted vital capacity. The secondary hypothesis is that SAPB will have greater improvement&#xD;
      in pain scores and have a superior safety profile compared to placebo injection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STUDY DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a single center prospective, randomized, blinded clinical trial with a convenience&#xD;
      sample that will be conducted in the Emergency Department of an urban level I trauma center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. Identify and enroll all patients coming in to the ED patient with presumed or clinically&#xD;
      apparent 2 or more unilateral rib fractures between T3 to T9, with a resting pain score of&#xD;
      ≥5. All patients meeting exclusion criteria will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. Randomization procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Pharmacy will dispense 30mL of injectate which will be randomized in block of 10 to&#xD;
           either the SAPB group (30mL of 0.25% bupivacaine with epinephrine) or sham group (30mL&#xD;
           of normal saline).&#xD;
&#xD;
      C. Injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patient consent will be obtained and time out will be performed on all patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients will be placed on cardiac monitor and placed in lateral decubitus or if unable&#xD;
           to turn, they will be supine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Under the usual sterile technique, the serratus anterior muscle overlying the 5th rib at&#xD;
           the mid-axillary line will be identified with ultrasound.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. A spinal needle will be introduced in-plane under ultrasound guidance and advanced until&#xD;
           the needle tip is located in the fascial plane just above the serratus anterior muscle.&#xD;
           The needle tip will not be advanced unless completely visualized under ultrasound.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Normal saline will be injected first to determine correct location of the needle tip.&#xD;
           Spreading of fluid along the fascial plane will confirm the correct location of the&#xD;
           needle tip.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The normal saline will then be switched to the study drug of which 30mL of either normal&#xD;
           saline or 0.25% bupivacaine with epinephrine which will then be injected into the&#xD;
           fascial plane as described in Blanco et al, and Hetta et al.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. The study drug will be injected 5mL at a time and the patient will be asked if any&#xD;
           symptoms of Local Anesthetic Systemic Toxicity (LAST toxicity) are present (perioral&#xD;
           numbness, tinnitus, dizziness).&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. After injection is completed the needle will be withdrawn and patient will remain on the&#xD;
           cardiac monitor for another 30 minutes to monitor for symptoms of LAST toxicity (Di&#xD;
           Gregorio).&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. This procedure was based on the serratus anterior plane block protocol from Khalil et&#xD;
           al.&#xD;
&#xD;
      D. Slow Vital Capacity (SVC) Measurement&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. SVC will be performed using spirometer that has been internally validated&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. SVC will be performed by physicians trained by the respiratory therapy department and&#xD;
           who have demonstrated validation compared to respiratory therapist obtained SVC values&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The patient will be sitting up when performing SVC and a script will be followed as to&#xD;
           how to educate and coach the patient on performing appropriate incentive spirometry&#xD;
           technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. At least 3 SVC measurements within 150mL of each other are required to qualify for an&#xD;
           accurate measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The maximum of these 3 SVC values and a corresponding % predicted SVC will be obtained&#xD;
           and considered the maximum % predicted SVC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. % Predicted SVC will be obtained based on the National Health and Nutrition Examination&#xD;
           Survey (NHANES III) calculator through the CDC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      E. Pain scores&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Subjects will be asked to rate their maximum pain score from 0-10 with resting breathing&#xD;
           and with deep breaths.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. Potential study patients will be identified through review of the emergency department&#xD;
      (ED) electronic board, and ED physicians will also screen for potential study patients. Pain&#xD;
      scores are assessed in triage as is standard in the ED.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. If the patient has pain from presumed or clinically apparent 2 or more unilateral rib&#xD;
      fractures between T3 to T9, and he/she has a resting pain score of ≥5 on the Numeric Pain&#xD;
      Rating Scale, where 0 is no pain, 5 is moderate pain, and 10 is the worst possible pain upon&#xD;
      initial assessment, then he/she will be eligible to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will then be asked to participate if he/she does not have any exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      C. At time of enrollment, the patient will have recorded pain scores, vital signs, and slow&#xD;
      vital capacity measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      D. All patients will then receive as their initial analgesic oral acetaminophen 975 mg&#xD;
      followed by morphine sulfate 0.05 mg/kg IV rounded to the nearest milligram.&#xD;
&#xD;
      E. Each patient will then be randomized in either of two arms:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Ultrasound guided serratus anterior plane block (SAPB) with 30mL 0.25% bupivacaine with&#xD;
           epinephrine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Ultrasound guided serratus anterior plane injection with placebo injection with 30mL of&#xD;
           normal saline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6. Investigators will be blinded to the arm that the patient has been randomized to, as the&#xD;
      randomization will occur through the pharmacy dispensing the medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7. Using an online randomizer in blocks of 10, the pharmacy will dispense either 30mL of&#xD;
      normal saline for the sham group, or 30mL of 0.25% bupivacaine with epinephrine for the nerve&#xD;
      block group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8. All patients will receive either SAPB or placebo injection within an hour of receiving the&#xD;
      initial analgesics of acetaminophen and morphine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      9. If the patient still has a pain score ≥5 thirty minutes after the injection, the treating&#xD;
      physician will be informed and the patient will be medicated at the treating physician's&#xD;
      discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      10. The patient will be followed up with up to 24 hours throughout their hospital stay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A. Demographics 1. Age, sex, ethnicity, height B. Past medical history 1. Smoking status&#xD;
      (current, prior, never smoker), diabetes, cirrhosis, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&#xD;
      (COPD), asthma, if patient uses home oxygen C. Injury Mechanism&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Occupant in motor vehicle collision, fall from an elevation, fall down stairs, fall from&#xD;
           standing, pedestrian or bicyclist struck by moving vehicle, bike collision or fall from&#xD;
           bike while riding, driver or passenger in motorcycle/ATV/motorized scooter collision,&#xD;
           assault, unknown mechanism, or other&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Date and time of injury&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. GCS score&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Injury Severity Scale D. Imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Side of rib fractures&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Number of rib fractures on x-ray and on CT chest&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Rib fracture location: anterior, lateral, posterior, T1-12&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Type of imaging showing rib fractures&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Presence of following: atelectasis, hemothorax, infiltrate (right/left), interstitial&#xD;
           edema, pneumothorax, pulmonary contusion E. Medication&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Any medications type and dose given prior to randomization&#xD;
&#xD;
      F. At Time 0 (time of enrollment):&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Resting pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Deep breath pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Slow Vital Capacity (SVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
           a. Measured until 3 measurements are within 150mL of each other b. % predicted SVC is&#xD;
           measured based on NHANES III Calculator using age, sex, ethnicity and height. If&#xD;
           ethnicity not included in calculator will select Caucasian.&#xD;
&#xD;
           c. Maximum SVC and maximum % predicted SVC&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Symptoms after injection: sedation, dizziness, dysarthria, nausea, new cardiac rhythm&#xD;
           (significant tachycardia or bradycardia, SVT, etc), new significantly increased&#xD;
           shortness of breath, perioral numbness, pruritis, seizure, syncope, tinnitus, vomiting&#xD;
           G. At Time 30 minutes post injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Resting pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Deep breath pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Slow Vital Capacity (SVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Measured until 3 measurements are within 150mL of each other&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Percentage predicted SVC is measured based on NHANES III Calculator using age, sex,&#xD;
                ethnicity and height. If ethnicity not included in calculator will select&#xD;
                Caucasian.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Maximum SVC and maximum % predicted SVC&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Symptoms after injection: sedation, dizziness, dysarthria, nausea, new cardiac rhythm&#xD;
           (significant tachycardia or bradycardia, SVT, etc), new significantly increased&#xD;
           shortness of breath, perioral numbness, pruritis, seizure, syncope, tinnitus, vomiting&#xD;
           H. At Time 60 minutes post injection&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Resting pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Deep breath pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Slow Vital Capacity (SVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Measured until 3 measurements are within 150mL of each other&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. % predicted SVC is measured based on NHANES III Calculator using age, sex, ethnicity and&#xD;
           height. If ethnicity not included in calculator will select Caucasian.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Maximum SVC and maximum % predicted SVC&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. Symptoms after injection: sedation, dizziness, dysarthria, nausea, new cardiac rhythm&#xD;
      (significant tachycardia or bradycardia, SVT, etc), new significantly increased shortness of&#xD;
      breath, perioral numbness, pruritis, seizure, syncope, tinnitus, vomiting I. At Time 3-6&#xD;
      hours post injection&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Vital signs 2. Resting pain score from 0-10 3. Deep breath pain score from 0-10 4. Slow&#xD;
      Vital Capacity (SVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Measured until 3 measurements are within 150mL of each other&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. % predicted SVC is measured based on NHANES III Calculator using age, sex, ethnicity and&#xD;
           height. If ethnicity not included in calculator will select Caucasian.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Maximum SVC and maximum % predicted SVC 4. Symptoms after injection: sedation,&#xD;
           dizziness, dysarthria, nausea, new cardiac rhythm (significant tachycardia or&#xD;
           bradycardia, SVT, etc), new significantly increased shortness of breath, perioral&#xD;
           numbness, pruritis, seizure, syncope, tinnitus, vomiting J. At Time 12 hours post&#xD;
           injection 1. Vital signs 2. Resting pain score from 0-10 3. Deep breath pain score from&#xD;
           0-10 5. Slow Vital Capacity (SVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Measured until 3 measurements are within 150mL of each other&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. % predicted SVC is measured based on NHANES III Calculator using age, sex,&#xD;
                ethnicity and height. If ethnicity not included in calculator will select&#xD;
                Caucasian.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Maximum SVC and maximum % predicted SVC&#xD;
&#xD;
           5. Symptoms after injection: sedation, dizziness, dysarthria, nausea, new cardiac rhythm&#xD;
           (significant tachycardia or bradycardia, SVT, etc), new significantly increased&#xD;
           shortness of breath, perioral numbness, pruritis, seizure, syncope, tinnitus, vomiting&#xD;
           J. On 24 hours post injection&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Vital signs&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Resting pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Deep breath pain score from 0-10&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Slow Vital Capacity (SVC)&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Measured until 3 measurements are within 150mL of each other&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. % predicted SVC is measured based on NHANES III Calculator using age, sex, ethnicity and&#xD;
           height. If ethnicity not included in calculator will select Caucasian.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Maximum SVC and maximum % predicted SVC 5. Symptoms after injection: sedation,&#xD;
           dizziness, dysarthria, nausea, new cardiac rhythm (significant tachycardia or&#xD;
           bradycardia, SVT, etc), new significantly increased shortness of breath, perioral&#xD;
           numbness, pruritis, seizure, syncope, tinnitus, vomiting K. Slow vital capacity&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Researchers will be trained on appropriate incentive spirometry technique by the&#xD;
           respiratory therapy team and their accuracy will be confirmed 2. Patients will then be&#xD;
           instructed to perform SVC, we will get 3 SVC measurements within 150mL of each other and&#xD;
           then record the maximum SVC.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3. Percent predicted vital capacity will be calculating using NHANES III L. Time to&#xD;
           first rescue analgesia post injection M. Medications during first 24 hours of hospital&#xD;
           stay&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. 24 hour total morphine milligram equivalent consumption&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Calculated based on CDC Morphine Milligram Equivalence (MME) Calculator:&#xD;
           https://www.cdc.gov/drugoverdose/prescribing/app.html 2. Any antemetics used after&#xD;
           injection within 24 hours after enrollment 3. Time to administration of first rescue&#xD;
           analgesia post injection N. Nerve Block performed during inpatient stay&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. List date/time/type of any additional nerve blocks performed for rib fracture pain&#xD;
           after the study injection during the patient's hospital stay&#xD;
&#xD;
           O. Pulmonary complications:&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. New O2 requirement, BIPAP or intubation, transfer to ICU for respiratory issue,&#xD;
           development of pneumonia, readmission for pulmonary issue, new need for home O2 P. Nerve&#xD;
           Block Complications&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Development of cellulitis at site of block during hospital stay 2. Pneumothorax&#xD;
           occurring within 12 hours of injection Q. Discharge Data&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. If cellulitis developed at the site of injection during hospital stay&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. If a pneumothorax on the same side of the injection occurred within 12 hours of&#xD;
                block R. Imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
           1. Videos of the nerve block performance will be recorded in each patient. These images&#xD;
           will later be de-identified and reviewed by two independent reviewers not involved in&#xD;
           the study to determine visually whether the planar spread of anesthetic was correctly&#xD;
           placed or not correctly placed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vital Capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Vital Capacity will be by a trained respiratory therapist using a spirometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain Control</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Pain score on 11 point Numeric Rating Scale ranging 0-10 with 0 being no pain, 5 being moderate pain, and 10 being very severe pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Opiate Usage</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of patients using opiates for pain management</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>serratus anterior plane block group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The injection of bupivicaine into the chest muscle is performed with an ultrasound machine which can see the needle as it enters the muscle. The skin is cleaned with a sterile solution and the needle is guided right next to the chest muscle where either the bupivicaine injected. After the injection, the needle is taken out.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placeoo injection group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The injection of normal saline into the chest muscle is performed with an ultrasound machine which can see the needle as it enters the muscle. The skin is cleaned with a sterile solution and the needle is guided right next to the chest muscle where saline is injected. After the injection, the needle is taken out.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acetaminophen</intervention_name>
    <description>receive ketamine 0.15 mg/kg IV in 100 mL normal saline over 30 minutes for pain</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placeoo injection group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>serratus anterior plane block group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacain</intervention_name>
    <description>The injection of bupivicaine into the chest muscle is performed with an ultrasound machine which can see the needle as it enters the muscle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>serratus anterior plane block group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>The injection of saline into the chest muscle is performed with an ultrasound machine which can see the needle as it enters the muscle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placeoo injection group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presumed/Clinically apparent 2 or more acute unilateral rib fractures between T3-T9&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pain Score 5 or greater&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. GCS&lt;13&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Penetrating trauma&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unable to give consent due to dementia or altered mental status&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Unable to perform spirometry&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Requiring immediate surgical intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Known allergy to amide-type local anesthetics&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Signs of infection or laceration at injection site&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Systolic BP &lt;100 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of chronic pain, chronic use of analgesics&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Painful distracting injury (injury causing significant pain that distracts the patient&#xD;
             from having reliable scoring of rib fracture pain, i.e. femur fracture, dislocated&#xD;
             joint)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. If patient received any other pain medication besides ketamine prior to the block&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Only posterior rib fractures present&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. known allergy to acetaminophen&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Known allergy to morphine sulfate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>120 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Judy Lin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Maimonides Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Antonios Likourezos, MA, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>718-283-6896</phone>
    <email>alikourezos@maimonidesmed.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Judy Lin, MD</last_name>
    <phone>718-283-6000</phone>
    <email>julin@maimonidesmed.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Maimonides Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Antonios Likourezos</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Manager</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain management</keyword>
  <keyword>Rib</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rib Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>March 4, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/49/NCT04530149/Prot_SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

