<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04535505</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BRD1.0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04535505</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pathogenic Bordetella Rapid Detection</brief_title>
  <official_title>Establishment a Nucleic Acid Rapid Detection Technology Platform for Detecting Pathogenic Bordetella and Its Drug Resistance Genes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's Hospital of Fudan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's Hospital of Fudan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A CPA platform based on the CRISPR technology is going to established to achieve the goal of&#xD;
      detecting pathogenic bordetella and drug resistance genes in one step. The accuracy of this&#xD;
      platform will be checked through prospective diagnostic test evaluation methods. Bordetella&#xD;
      pertussis isolation culture and identification would be set as a gold standard method.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Pertussis is an acute respiratory infectious disease caused by bordetella pertussis. Although&#xD;
      it is a vaccine-preventable disease, outbreaks and epidemic cases of whooping cough worldwide&#xD;
      have been reported from time to time. Bordella parapertussis, Bodella bronchiseptica, and&#xD;
      bordetella hosei can cause pertussis-like diseases with symptoms similar to those of whooping&#xD;
      cough. The clinical manifestations are difficult to distinguish, and they are easily reported&#xD;
      as cases of whooping cough through the infectious disease network.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The diagnosis of the infectious diseases caused by the four pathogenic bodella mainly relies&#xD;
      on laboratory pathogenic testing. At present, the laboratory tests of bordetella that can be&#xD;
      carried out in the clinical microbiology laboratory include culture, bordetella pertussis&#xD;
      specific antibody (PT-IgG) serological detection, and bordetella pertussis nucleic acid PCR&#xD;
      detection. However, none of them meet the requirements of early diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cross primer constant temperature amplification (CPA) is nucleic acid constant temperature&#xD;
      amplification technology with independent property rights. The fully automated nucleic acid&#xD;
      detection platform equipped with CPA technology would make the detection of four pathogenic&#xD;
      bordetella easy, quick and safe and accurate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As pathogenic bodella is difficult to cultivate and there is no standard for drug&#xD;
      susceptibility test. Studies have shown that 57.4% of the isolated clinical isolates of&#xD;
      bordetella pertussis have MIC value for erthomycin ≥256 μg/mL , and 23s rRNA 2047 site&#xD;
      adenine (A) were mutated to guanine (G).CRISPR/Cas is an immune system in bacteria that can&#xD;
      specifically recognize invading nucleic acids and shear them. The CRISPR technology developed&#xD;
      based on the CRISPR/Cas principle can detect single point mutations in genes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis that 4 pathogenic bordetella and their erythromycin resistance would be&#xD;
      detected in one testing platform simultaneously. The accuracy, reliability, predictive value&#xD;
      of this platform would be checked through prospective diagnostic test evaluation methods.&#xD;
      Bordetella pertussis isolation culture and identification would be as the gold standard&#xD;
      method.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the new CPA platform based on CRISPR technology, including sensitivity and specificity</measure>
    <time_frame>At enrollment</time_frame>
    <description>Bordetella pertussis isolation culture and identification would be taken as gold standard. The enrolled subjects would receive the detection of this research platform detection method and the gold standard at the same time. The measurement indexes are sensitivity and specificity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Pertussis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>pertussis test population</arm_group_label>
    <description>People with clinical diagnosis of suspected pertussis in outpatient and ward in the Children's Hospital of Fudan University will be collected as study subjects. Their nasopharyngeal swabs will be collected. Bordetella isolation culture and identification method is the gold standard, and the new CPA platform based on CRISPR technology is the method to be tested. Diagnostic values of this research platform would be detected.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Detection pathogenic pertussis by cross primer constant temperature amplification (CPA) and drug resistant genes of erythromycin by CRISPR technology</intervention_name>
    <description>This is an observational study and there are no interventions. The purpose of the study is to compare the accuracy （including sensitivity and specificity）of the new CPA platform based on CRISPR technology detection method and the gold standard in detecting pertussis patients.</description>
    <arm_group_label>pertussis test population</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Nasopharyngeal swab of a suspected pertussis patient&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        600 cases of suspected pertussis clinically diagnosed in the outpatient clinic and ward of&#xD;
        Children's Hospital of Fudan University would be enrolled. The enrollment would start in&#xD;
        October 2021 and end in June 2022. Patients who are admitted to the Children's Hospital of&#xD;
        Fudan University during the enrollment period and are clinically suspected of pertussis&#xD;
        would be the research objects. There are no special requirements for gender of the enrolled&#xD;
        patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with continuous cough (paroxysmal cough) for more than 1 week, peripheral&#xD;
             white blood cell 18×109/L (infants and young children), or&gt; 15×109/L (children),&#xD;
             ineffective use of cephalosporin antibacterial drugs，and these patients whose&#xD;
             nasopharyngeal swabs are collected for routine bordetella culture identification and&#xD;
             drug susceptibility testing would be included as research object.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with pertussis are suspected clinically but no nasopharyngeal swab specimens&#xD;
             are collected or patients with pertussis are clinically excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chuanqing Wang, Phd</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Hospital of Fudan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chuanqing Wang, Phd</last_name>
    <phone>+86 18017591167</phone>
    <email>Chuanqing523@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Fudan University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <zip>201102</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chunaqing Wang</last_name>
      <phone>+86 18017591167</phone>
      <email>Chuanqing523@163.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chunaqing Wang</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Qimin You</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pan Fu</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chunling Li</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Saige Chen</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Leiyan He</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yuan Jiang</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pertussis；Children；Diagnostic test；CPA; CRISPR</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Whooping Cough</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Erythromycin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Erythromycin Estolate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Erythromycin Ethylsuccinate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Erythromycin stearate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

