<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04532879</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HGP-0009</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04532879</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>HygiRelief Procedure and HygiSample Evaluation for Functional Constipation</brief_title>
  <official_title>HygiRelief Procedure and HygiSample Evaluation for Patients Diagnosed With Rome IV Functional Constipation Previously Managed With Linzess</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>HyGIeaCare, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>HyGIeaCare, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study has a single center, prospective, open label design. The population will include&#xD;
      patients diagnosed with Rome IV Functional Constipation who are at the time of study&#xD;
      enrollment being managed with a stable dose of Linzess. They will stop taking their Linzess,&#xD;
      undergo monitoring of bowel habits for 2 weeks, have a HygiRelief procedure and then undergo&#xD;
      an additional 2 weeks of bowel habit monitoring.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      After undergoing a 5-7 day Linzess washout period, patients will record their bowel habits in&#xD;
      a daily diary for 2 weeks. Patients will have the HygiRelief procedure with a HygiSample&#xD;
      evaluation, then they will record their bowel habits in a daily diary for 2 weeks following&#xD;
      the HygiRelief procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HygiSamples (stool samples) will be collected throughout the HygiRelief procedure and the&#xD;
      samples will be sent for microbiome evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will complete multiple questionnaires - Happiness Scale, Hospital Anxiety and&#xD;
      Depression Scale (HADS), and a personal assessment which includes the Constipation Symptom&#xD;
      Score and Adverse Event Screening. These will be completed at Baseline, after the 2 week&#xD;
      PRE-HygiRelief period, and after the 2 week POST-HygiRelief period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    decided not to do the study due to Covid staffing restrictions&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, single center, open label. Patients will serve as their own control by comparing their bowel habits using a specific diary 2 weeks after the Linzess washout period to the 2 weeks after their HygiRelief procedure.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess change in bowel movements PRE and POST HygiRelief procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate the clinical effectiveness of the HygiRelief procedure to relieve functional constipation in patients previously managed with a stable dose of Lizess</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess colon effluent samples (HygiSample) collected during the HygiRelief procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Samples will be evaluated for their microbiological and biochemical content, as well as to identify microbiome changes throughout the colon</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Rome IV Functional Constipation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All patients enrolled</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Bowel habits before and after the HygiRelief procedure will be assessed.&#xD;
Samples will be sent for microbiome evaluation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HygiPrep (HyGIeaCare System)</intervention_name>
    <description>Controlled gravity-based high-volume colon irrigation</description>
    <arm_group_label>All patients enrolled</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HygiSample (stool collection for microbiome evaluation)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient's age is between 18 and 80 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient diagnosed with Rome IV Functional Constipation (Attachment C2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient is currently managed with Linzess and willing to stop taking it for study&#xD;
             duration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient has functional bowel disorders characterized by alternating bowel habits&#xD;
             (diarrhea/constipation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient has any other condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, may&#xD;
             adversely affect the compliance or safety of the patient or would limit the patient's&#xD;
             ability to complete the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient has any of the contraindications listed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cardiac: Congestive heart failure (NYHA class III or IV or EF &lt;50%)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. GI: Intestinal perforation, carcinoma of the rectum, fissures or fistula, severe&#xD;
                  hemorrhoids, abdominal hernia, recent colon, rectal, or abdominal surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. GU: Renal insufficiency (CC &lt; 60 ml/min/173m2), cirrhosis with ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Abdominal surgery within the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient took antibiotics within two months of starting the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

