<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04532021</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CengizGWCH9</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04532021</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Matrix Metalloproteinase 14, Neopterin, and Orosomucoid 1 Levels in PPROM</brief_title>
  <acronym>MMP-14&amp;PPROM</acronym>
  <official_title>Umbilical Cord and Maternal Blood Concentrations of Matrix Metalloproteinase 14, Neopterin, and Orosomucoid 1 in Pregnancy Complicated by Preterm Premature Rupture of the Membranes and Histological Chorioamnionitis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: To evaluate the maternal blood serum matrix metalloproteinase 14, neopterin,&#xD;
      and orosomucoid 1 levels in pregnant women complicated by preterm premature rupture of&#xD;
      membranes (PPROM) and to compare the results with healthy pregnancies. In addition, to&#xD;
      determine whether maternal/umbilical cord blood concentrations of matrix metalloproteinase&#xD;
      14, neopterin, and orosomucoid 1 are of value in the diagnosis of histological&#xD;
      chorioamnionitis in patients with preterm premature rupture of membranes (PPROM).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: This cohort study will be included 44 pregnant women with PPROM and 44 gestational&#xD;
      age-matched healthy subjects in 24-32 weeks of pregnancy. The blood for analysis will be&#xD;
      firstly obtained in maternal blood on the day of diagnosis at the study group. Healthy&#xD;
      subjects who have a normal pregnancy and outcomes without any fetal-neonatal complications&#xD;
      will be accepted into the control group. Forty-four gestational age-matched healthy pregnant&#xD;
      women who will be delivered at term will be included in the study as the control group. In&#xD;
      the control group, the pregnant women will be taken the maternal blood at the admission day.&#xD;
      The women in both groups will be observed until the delivery and perinatal data will be&#xD;
      noted. Then, the blood for analysis will be secondly obtained in maternal blood during&#xD;
      termination of the pregnancy (or spontaneous labor) at the study group. Lastly, the blood for&#xD;
      analysis will be also obtained in umbilical cord blood at the study group. These three&#xD;
      markers levels will be measured using a commercially available enzyme-linked immunosorbent&#xD;
      assay (ELISA) kit. The placenta will be sent to histological examination in the study group.&#xD;
      These three markers levels in women with PPROM will be compared to those of volunteer healthy&#xD;
      pregnant women. In the study group, these three markers levels at maternal serum and cord&#xD;
      serum will be evaluated for histological chorioamnionitis and maternal/neonatal outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This observational case-control study will be conducted at the Department of Obstetrics and&#xD;
      Gynecology, Cengiz Gokcek Public Hospital, Gaziantep, Turkey, between August 2020 and August&#xD;
      2021. The protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee for Clinical Research of Gaziantep&#xD;
      University (reference no: 2020/212). The study strictly will be adhered to the principles of&#xD;
      the Declaration of Helsinki. All subjects will be included in the study gave oral and written&#xD;
      informed consent. Membrane rupture before labor and before 37 weeks of gestation is referred&#xD;
      to as preterm premature rupture of membranes (PPROM). Every woman in the study population&#xD;
      will be undergone obstetric ultrasound examination and fetal-maternal assessment will be&#xD;
      carried out. The blood for analysis will be firstly obtained in maternal blood on the day of&#xD;
      diagnosis at the study group. Healthy subjects who had a normal pregnancy and outcomes&#xD;
      without any fetal-neonatal complications will be accepted into the control group. Forty-four&#xD;
      gestational age-matched healthy pregnant women who will be delivered at term will be included&#xD;
      in the study as the control group. In the control group, the pregnant women will be taken the&#xD;
      maternal blood at the admission day. The women in both groups will be observed until the&#xD;
      delivery and perinatal data will be noted. All The participants with PPROM will be also&#xD;
      hospitalized. Then, the protocols for pregnant women with PPROM in our hospital are as&#xD;
      follows: All patients with PPROM are hospitalized and expectant protocol is applied. After&#xD;
      hospitalization until the delivery of baby, all pregnant women with PPROM receive&#xD;
      prophylactic antibiotics for 1 week and betamethasone injection. The non-stress test and&#xD;
      fetal movement determined by the mother are used for the detection of fetal well-being. The&#xD;
      signs for clinical chorioamnionitis such as uterine tenderness, fever, purulent discharges&#xD;
      from the cervical canal and inflammatory markers like white blood cell count (WBC) and&#xD;
      C-reactive protein (CRP) levels are monitored carefully during the hospitalization. After a&#xD;
      latency period, PPROM pregnancy will gone to spontaneous delivery or will be applied&#xD;
      termination procedure. In the study group, the placenta will be stained with&#xD;
      hematoxylin-eosin and will be examined under a light microscope for histological signs of&#xD;
      neutrophil infiltration and chorioamnionitis. Then, this study will be determined maternal&#xD;
      serum matrix metalloproteinase 14, neopterin, and orosomucoid 1 levels in women with&#xD;
      PPROM(n=44) compared to those of volunteer healthy pregnant women (n=44). Then, these three&#xD;
      markers levels at maternal serum and cord serum will be evaluated for histological&#xD;
      chorioamnionitis and maternal/neonatal outcomes in the study group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 25, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MMP-14 levels in PPROM</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome in these analyses will compare maternal serum matrix metalloproteinase 14, neopterin, and orosomucoid 1 concentrations in PPROM group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>neopterin levels in PPROM</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The other primary outcome in these analyses will compare maternal serum neopterin concentrations in PPROM group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>orosomucoid 1 levels in PPROM</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome in these analyses will compare maternal serum orosomucoid 1 concentrations in PPROM group and control group.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>markers levels for histological chorioamnionitis in PPROM</measure>
    <time_frame>1 week</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary result in these analyzes will compare whether there is a difference at the levels of these three markers in maternal serum and cord serum for the presence of histological chorioamnionitis in the study group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">88</enrollment>
  <condition>Preterm Premature Rupture of Membranes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>preterm premature rupture of membranes</arm_group_label>
    <description>Preterm premature rupture of membranes is the rupture of membranes during pregnancy before 37 weeks' gestation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy subjects who had a normal pregnancy and outcomes without any fetal-neonatal complications will be accepted into the control group. Forty-four gestational age-matched healthy pregnant women who will be delivered at term will be included in the study as the control group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>matrix metalloproteinase 14, neopterin, and orosomucoid 1 measurements</intervention_name>
    <description>These three markers levels will be measured using a commercially available enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) kit.</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>preterm premature rupture of membranes</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The investigators consecutively will be recruited 44 subjects with PPROM, and 44 healthy&#xD;
        pregnancies will be selected for the control group.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women complicated with PPROM&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy pregnant women who will be delivered at term&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Singleton pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. pregnant women with any systemic condition (such as chronic hypertension, renal&#xD;
             disease and )&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. women who have dyed their hair in the last 9 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. history of using any medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. presence of gestational hypertension or gestational diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. drug user&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. patients who had fetal congenital abnormalities or genetic syndromes&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. multiple-gestation pregnancies&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. intrauterine fetal death&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. women who had any other infection or fever&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. fetal distress at admission&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. cord prolapse&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. active labor&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. antenatal bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. cervical or uterine anomaly&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>PPROM Preterm premature rupture of membranes (PPROM) is defined as the prelabor rupture of membranes before 37 weeks' gestation. Preterm PROM complicates about 1% of deliveries overall.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gaziantep</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.degruyter.com/view/journals/pteridines/14/1/article-p1.xml</url>
    <description>a Citation</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ekström B, Berggård I. Human alpha1-microglobulin. Purification procedure, chemical and physiochemical properties. J Biol Chem. 1977 Nov 25;252(22):8048-57.</citation>
    <PMID>72071</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Nergiz Avcıoğlu S, Demircan Sezer S, Küçük M, Zafer E, Yüksel H, Akcan B, Turgut O. Maternal serum concentrations of s-Endoglin and IL-6 in pregnancy complicated by preterm premature membrane rupture. J Matern Fetal Neonatal Med. 2016;29(12):1957-62. doi: 10.3109/14767058.2015.1070137. Epub 2015 Aug 13.</citation>
    <PMID>26169712</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hawinkels LJ, Kuiper P, Wiercinska E, Verspaget HW, Liu Z, Pardali E, Sier CF, ten Dijke P. Matrix metalloproteinase-14 (MT1-MMP)-mediated endoglin shedding inhibits tumor angiogenesis. Cancer Res. 2010 May 15;70(10):4141-50. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-09-4466. Epub 2010 Apr 27.</citation>
    <PMID>20424116</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Committee on Practice Bulletins-Obstetrics. ACOG Practice Bulletin No. 188: Prelabor Rupture of Membranes. Obstet Gynecol. 2018 Jan;131(1):e1-e14. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000002455. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29266075</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cengiz Gokcek Women's and Children's Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ali Ovayolu</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fetal Membranes, Premature Rupture</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 15, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/21/NCT04532021/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

