<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02983149</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>14-7478-A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02983149</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Clinical Comparison of Two New Bronchial Blockers vs. Double Lumen Tubes in One Lung Ventilation</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Clinical Comparison of Two New Bronchial Blockers vs. Double Lumen Tubes in One Lung Ventilation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Health Network, Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Health Network, Toronto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients undergoing thoracic surgery require selective ventilation of one lung, which allows&#xD;
      surgery to proceed on the operative lung that is deflated, and no longer moving. One-lung&#xD;
      ventilation (OLV) may be achieved by the use of a double lumen endotracheal tube (DLT) or the&#xD;
      placement of a bronchial blocker (BB) via a single lumen endotracheal tube, both of which are&#xD;
      in routine clinical use at University Health Network.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, the Endobronchial Blocker (EZ blocker) has been marketed, with a forked tip design&#xD;
      and two balloons, one of which is designed to fall into each of the right and left sides, it&#xD;
      may require less repositioning. Initial clinical experience with the EZ Blocker suggests that&#xD;
      it may be less likely than other blockers to become malpositioned during surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will compare the EZ blocker to the Fuji blocker, the most frequently used blocker&#xD;
      at this institution, and to double-lumen tubes, the most commonly used devices to provide&#xD;
      lung isolation, with respect to intra-operative malpositioning and the speed of lung&#xD;
      separation and efficacy of lung collapse during thoracic surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be randomly assigned, to one of the three study groups: EZ Blocker, Fuji, or&#xD;
      left-sided DLT, immediately prior to induction of anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary end points of time to lung isolation and number of required repositioning&#xD;
      maneuvers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STUDY END POINTS The time required to achieve lung separation, from beginning of laryngoscopy&#xD;
      to lung isolation (inflation of the bronchial cuff or blocker), will be recorded. The&#xD;
      thoracic surgeons, using a verbal analogue scale, will assess the lung collapse(lung collapse&#xD;
      scores-LCS, 0=no collapse, to 10=complete collapse). The LCS will be assessed and recorded as&#xD;
      they open the pleura during the procedure (LCS 0), and at 10 min., (LCS 10), and 20 min. (LCS&#xD;
      20) after opening the pleura. The surgeons will be blinded to the lung isolation device used&#xD;
      in the patient. If the lung collapse is not satisfactory, the FOB will be passed to assess&#xD;
      the lung isolation, and if necessary reposition the device. A malposition will be defined as&#xD;
      a clinically obvious relocation of the devise in the trachea or bronchus and a loss of lung&#xD;
      isolation interfering with surgery. The number of repositions of the lung isolation device&#xD;
      after initial supine placement, airway pressures, tidal volumes, duration of surgery, and the&#xD;
      arterial blood gases 20 minutes after pleural opening will be noted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the primary end points of time to lung isolation and number of required&#xD;
      repositioning maneuvers, the following variables will be recorded: Age, gender, weight,&#xD;
      height, BMI, ASA, airway Mallampati score, pulmonary spirometry (if clinically performed:&#xD;
      TLC, FEV1, FVC, DLCO), LCS 0/10/20, ventilatory parameters on OLV (airway pressure, tidal&#xD;
      volume, respiratory rate, compliance, duration of OLV and surgery, arterial blood gas 20&#xD;
      minutes after opening the pleura (pH, paO2, pCO2 bicarbonate, base excess, oxygen&#xD;
      saturation), and finally the dimensions of the left main bronchus (LMB) and the right main&#xD;
      bronchus (RMB) using the on-screen program of the radiology server on the pre-operative chest&#xD;
      imaging, by the anesthesiologist.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 10, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time required for lung separation</measure>
    <time_frame>From initial laryngoscopy to lung isolation will be measured for 0 hours (procedure start) to 3 hours (procedure end time)</time_frame>
    <description>The time required to achieve lung separation, from beginning of laryngoscopy to lung isolation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of repositioning maneuvers of the device</measure>
    <time_frame>After initial patient's supine position for the duration of the operation 0-3 hours will be recorded</time_frame>
    <description>The number of repositions of the lung isolation device after initial supine placement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Lung collapse scores</measure>
    <time_frame>The thoracic surgeons, using a verbal analogue scale, will be assessing the lung collapse score (LCS), from 0=no collapse to 10=complete collapse. LCS will be assessed just after opening the pleura, at 10 min., and 20 min. after opening the pleura.</time_frame>
    <description>Time Frame: After opening the pleura, the lung collapse scores will be measured at 0, 10 and 20 minutes (from pleura opening)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Thoracic Surgery, Lung Isolation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Double lumen tube</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>One lung ventilation will be achieved using a double lumen tube</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fuji blocker</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>One lung ventilation will be achieved using the Fuji blocker</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EZ blocker</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>One lung ventilation will be achieved using the EZ blocker</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Double lumen tube</intervention_name>
    <description>Use an double lumen tube to achieve one lung ventilation in thoracic surgeries</description>
    <arm_group_label>Double lumen tube</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fuji blocker</intervention_name>
    <description>Use the Fuji blocker to achieve one lung ventilation in thoracic surgeries</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fuji blocker</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>EZ blocker</intervention_name>
    <description>Use the EZ blocker to achieve one lung ventilation in thoracic surgeries</description>
    <arm_group_label>EZ blocker</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt;18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thoracic surgery requiring one-lung ventilation for &gt; 30 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide first party consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known prior difficult intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Upper airway exam suggestive of difficult intubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgical procedure requiring a right double lumen endotracheal tube (such as left&#xD;
             pneumonectomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence on clinically required radiologic imaging of abnormal lower airway anatomy,&#xD;
             such as right upper lobe origin of the bronchus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior thoracic surgery or pleurodesis of the operative side (would delay lung&#xD;
             collapse).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe restrictive lung disease (such as pulmonary fibrosis or emphysema)&#xD;
             which may affect inflation/deflation times.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Trauma patients requiring video-assisted thoracoscopic surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has condition(s) that contraindicate a double lumen endotracheal tube (DLT) or the&#xD;
             placement of a bronchial blocker (BB) via a single lumen endotracheal tube.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with communication difficulties.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Peter Slinger, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Toronto General Hospital, University Health Network</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Toronto General Hospital, 200 Elizabeth St.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>B3H 1V7</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 14, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 1, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 6, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Health Network, Toronto</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jo Carroll</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Manager Anesthesia Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

