<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04262024</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Clinical trial</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04262024</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nurse's Role in the Management of Hyperprolactinemia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Nurse's Role in the Management of Hyperprolactinemia: A Prospective Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Woman's Health University Hospital, Egypt</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Woman's Health University Hospital, Egypt</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Many women despite being well-treated in proper dose, with proper drug and for proper&#xD;
      duration, may not respond to different forms of prolactin normalizing drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will lead to extension of the treatment duration up to months or even years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Doctors usually increase the dose of the drug with high possibility of side effects and even&#xD;
      complications. Some doctors change drug group to another without any significant improvement&#xD;
      of hyperprolactinemia. hyperprolactinemia can indicate a deeper issue, about 10 percent of&#xD;
      the population has hyperprolactinemia. Life style, feeding habits and sexual behaviors are&#xD;
      usually not included in the management protocols of hyperprolactinemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be aimed to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Evaluate the effect of nursing role in the management of hyperprolactinemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Give health education for women underlying forms of prolactin normalizing drugs for&#xD;
           hyperprolactinemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1- Health education for women under drugs of hyperprolactinemia is effective in reduce level&#xD;
      of prolactine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      H0- Health education for women under drugs of hyperprolactinemia is not effective in reduce&#xD;
      level of prolactin&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Subjects and methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All women diagnosed to have hyperprolactinemia as diagnosed by one laboratory (lab of the&#xD;
      Woman's Health University Hospital).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective study (randomized controlled trial) .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be conducted at the out patient clinic of the Woman's Health University&#xD;
      Hospital, Assiut University.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: convenience sample started from April 2019 to April 2020 or reaching 100 cases,&#xD;
      50 in each arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tools of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tool (1) Structured interviewing questionnaire include&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Women's personal data will include: Name, age, residence, educational level, occupation,&#xD;
           duration of marriage,Number of phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Medical history will include: the history of diabetes, hypertension, renal disease,&#xD;
           cardiac disease, hepatic disease, and any other diagnosed medical disease. 8&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Menstrual history will include: Age of menarche, Duration, Interval, and rhythm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Infertility history will include: years of infertility, type of infertility, cause of&#xD;
           it.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Obstetric history will include: number of gravidity, number of parity, number of&#xD;
           abortion, No of living children, time since last delivery or abortion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Medication history.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tool (2) Health education including:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Life style: Habits what to do. What not do.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diet to eat to reduce prolactine level:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diet to avoid to increase prolactine level .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Acts to avoid during sex practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tool (3): follow up (first visit after month with measurement of serum prolactin level&#xD;
      again).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
      Administrative phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An official permission will be obtained from the manager of Women health hospital after&#xD;
           explaining the purpose of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study will be conducted at the out patient clinical Unit of Women health hospital&#xD;
           and will include convenient sample of Women undergoing treatment using Cabergoline 0.5&#xD;
           mg twice weekly for one month.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the investigator will apply the randomized selection of the participant as the&#xD;
           following: give the participant an envelope contains two choice of (A or B ). labeled&#xD;
           papers then according to her choice she will engaged in the group: Group A will be take&#xD;
           medications for hyperprolactinemia with nurse health education. and 9 group B will be&#xD;
           will be take medications for hyperprolactinemia without nurse health education.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pilot study&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pilot study will be carried out on 10% of the study sample to test the clarity of the study&#xD;
      tool. The sample of pilot study will be excluded from the total sample if any modification&#xD;
      done on the tools. The necessary modifications will be done if needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical considerations:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Research proposal will be approved from Ethical Committee in the Faculty of Nursing&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. There is no risk for study subject during application of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The study will follow common ethical principles in clinical research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Written consent will be obtained from patient or guidance that is willing to participate&#xD;
           in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. confidentiality and anonymity will be assured.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. study subjects have the right to refuse to participate and/or withdraw from the study&#xD;
           without any rational any time&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. study subject privacy will be considered during collection of data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data entry and statistical analysis will be done using the statistical package for social&#xD;
      science program (SPSS. version 22). Qualitative variables will be presented as number and&#xD;
      percentage. Quantitative variables will be presented as mean +SD. Comparison between&#xD;
      qualitative variables will be done by using chi-square. Comparison between quantitative&#xD;
      variables will be done by using student t-test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 5, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective study ( randomized controlled trial)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Hyperprolactinemic women receiving cabergoline therapy will be divided into 2 groups: with health education and without health education.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Achievement of normoprolactinemia after one month of therapy of hyperprolactinemia</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>response of hyperprolactinemic women to carbergoline o.5 mg for one month with or without health education by a nurse to achieve normoprolactinemia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Health Education</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cabergoline with health education by a nurse</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Women with hyperprolactiemia scheduled for cabergoline therapy 0.5 mg twice weekly for one month plus health education by a nurse.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cabergoline without health education by a nurse</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Women with hyperprolactiemia scheduled for cabergoline therapy 0.5 mg twice weekly for one month without health education by a nurse.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabergoline 0.5Mg orally daily for 1 month plus health education by a nurse</intervention_name>
    <description>Women with hyperprolactiemia scheduled for cabergoline therapy 0.5 mg daily for one month will be offered health education by a nurse to help minimize prolactin level(group A)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cabergoline with health education by a nurse</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cabergoline 0.5Mg orally daily for 1 month without health education by a nurse</intervention_name>
    <description>Women with hyperprolactiemia scheduled for cabergoline therapy 0.5 mg daily for one month will not offered health education by a nurse (group B)</description>
    <arm_group_label>cabergoline without health education by a nurse</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pathologic hyperprolactinemia due to any cause.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Non-pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Not lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Physiologic hyperprolactinemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Women who don't consent for follow up.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Atef M Darwish, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Prof.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Atef M Darwish</last_name>
    <phone>01001572723</phone>
    <email>atef_darwish@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Dina AM Darwish</last_name>
    <phone>01001572723</phone>
    <email>dodidodo@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Woman's Health University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>71111</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Atef MM Darwish, MD PhD</last_name>
      <phone>0201001572723</phone>
      <email>atef_darwish@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 7, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 7, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 7, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Woman's Health University Hospital, Egypt</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Professor Atef Darwish</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Obstetrics and Gynecology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Nursing</keyword>
  <keyword>health education</keyword>
  <keyword>prolactin</keyword>
  <keyword>hyperprolactinemia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperprolactinemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cabergoline</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

