<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02390674</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R&amp;D 6327</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-002628-29</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>BH120771</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>14/NE/1070</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02390674</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ciclosporin to Reduce Reperfusion Injury in Primary PCI</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAPRI</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of Intravenous Ciclosporin on Reducing Reperfusion Injury in Patients Undergoing Primary Percutaneous Intervention: a Double-blind Randomised Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Newcastle-upon-Tyne Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute for Health Research, United Kingdom</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Newcastle University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Newcastle-upon-Tyne Hospitals NHS Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Routine primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PPCI) for a heart attack involves opening&#xD;
      a blocked artery with a balloon then inserting a metal scaffold (stent) to hold the artery&#xD;
      open. During this procedure inflammation can occur causing further damage to the heart. The&#xD;
      objective of this trial is to determine whether administration of the drug ciclosporin prior&#xD;
      to PPCI reduces the amount of damage to the heart relative to treatment with placebo. The&#xD;
      damage to the heart is assessed after 12 weeks by an magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan.&#xD;
      Patients are followed-up after 12 months participation in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a single centre study looking to recruit 68 patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronary heart disease is a condition in which the supply of blood and oxygen to the heart is&#xD;
      reduced due to the narrowing of the arteries supplying the heart. A heart attack is caused&#xD;
      when one of these arteries becomes blocked. Modern treatment for a heart attack is called&#xD;
      primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PPCI). PPCI involves opening the blocked artery&#xD;
      with a balloon and placing a stent (a small metal tube) in the artery to hold it open.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research has shown that after opening the blocked artery, inflammation develops within the&#xD;
      heart. This inflammation is generated by the immune system. Initial studies have suggested&#xD;
      that certain immune system cells (T-cells) may be involved in causing much of the damage that&#xD;
      occurs in the heart following a heart attack. The drug ciclosporin temporarily inhibits the&#xD;
      immune system and it has been shown in a small number of patients that it reduces the size of&#xD;
      the heart attack. The aim of this clinical trial is to investigate in a larger number of&#xD;
      patients whether the size of the heart attack is reduced in patients treated with the drug&#xD;
      ciclosporin prior to PPCI relative to patients treated with a placebo (saline).&#xD;
&#xD;
      To participate in the trial you must be having a large heart attack (STEMI - ST segment&#xD;
      elevation myocardial infarction) and be undergoing a PPCI to unblock your artery. You must&#xD;
      also be aged over 18 years. You will be randomised to receive either a single dose of the&#xD;
      drug ciclosporin or placebo before your blocked artery is opened. Half the people will get&#xD;
      the drug ciclosporin. This randomisation will enable us to compare the results to see whether&#xD;
      treatment with ciclosporin reduces the size of the heart attack compared with placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There may be no immediate benefit from taking part in the trial but the information we get&#xD;
      from this trial will help improve the treatment of people having a heart attack in the&#xD;
      future. As far as we know there are no disadvantages of taking part in the trial. If you are&#xD;
      randomised to the 'drug' group, there is a very small risk of side effects from ciclosporin,&#xD;
      such as high blood pressure and slight worsening of kidney function. We do not expect any&#xD;
      side effects as the ciclosporin is only given once in the trial. On rare occasions allergic&#xD;
      reactions have been observed. If any ciclosporin-related side effects were to occur, they&#xD;
      would be expected soon after the drug was administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a single centre, randomised, double-blind, parallel group, placebo-controlled phase&#xD;
      II/III trial comparing the efficacy of ciclosporin versus placebo in 68 patients with acute&#xD;
      myocardial infarction undergoing PPCI. The trial is set in a tertiary care centre (Freeman&#xD;
      Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK) and patients will be recruited over a period of 18 months.&#xD;
      The trial is designed to show superiority regarding its primary endpoint. During initial&#xD;
      hospitalisation following myocardial infarction, treatment is given once prior to performing&#xD;
      the PPCI in the catheter laboratory. The duration of study for each patient is 12 months&#xD;
      until final follow-up (12 weeks randomised controlled trial (RCT) followed by 9 months study&#xD;
      follow-up). Should treatment with ciclosporin look promising, a larger trial will be designed&#xD;
      to evaluate ciclosporin treatment fully. In contrast to the previous study, this trial is not&#xD;
      restricted to anterior STEMI patients. It will also analyse changes in inflammatory response&#xD;
      following reperfusion and will use MRI (current gold standard) in every patient to quantify&#xD;
      infarct size, ejection fraction and microvascular obstruction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 11, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in infarct size</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after primary percutaneous coronary intervention (PPCI)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in infarct size 12 weeks post-PPCI as measured by cardiac MRI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in microvascular obstruction</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once between day 2 and day 7 after PPCI</time_frame>
    <description>Microvascular obstruction after 2-7 days as measured by a single cardiac MRI scan</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in salvage index</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured once between day 2 and day 7 after PPCI</time_frame>
    <description>Salvage index after 2-7 days as measured by a single cardiac MRI scan</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in T lymphocyte count</measure>
    <time_frame>5, 15, 30, 60 and 90 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Change in T lymphocyte counts relative to baseline at 5, 15, 30, 60 and 90 minutes post-reperfusion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">54</enrollment>
  <condition>Myocardial Reperfusion Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ciclosporin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single intravenous administration of ciclosporin (2.5mg per kilogram body weight) immediately prior to reperfusion during primary percutaneous coronary intervention. Ciclosporin is dissolved in saline (maximum concentration 2.5mg per millilitre)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single intravenous administration of placebo (saline) immediately prior to reperfusion during primary percutaneous coronary intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ciclosporin</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparison between ciclosporin and placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ciclosporin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sandimmun</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients presenting with acute myocardial infarction (STEMI) and undergoing primary&#xD;
             percutaneous coronary intervention (PPCI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age above 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presenting within 6 hours of the onset chest pain and ST segment elevation. The&#xD;
             culprit coronary artery has to be a major coronary artery with a diameter of at least&#xD;
             3mm and has to be proximally occluded (TIMI flow grade 0-1) at the time of admission&#xD;
             coronary angiography&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any disorder associated with immunological dysfunction (acute or chronic&#xD;
             inflammatory or neoplastic co-existing disease, known positive serology for HIV, or&#xD;
             hepatitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically unstable patients (haemodynamically unstable, cardiogenic shock,&#xD;
             unconscious patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with evidence of coronary collaterals to the infarct area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an open (TIMI &gt; 1) culprit coronary artery at the time of angiography.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous thrombolytic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known hypersensitivity to ciclosporin or to egg, peanut or soya-bean&#xD;
             proteins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known renal insufficiency (either known glomerular filtration rate (GFR)&#xD;
             &lt;30 ml/min/1.73m2) or current medical care for severe renal insufficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known liver insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension (&gt;180/110 mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated with any compound containing hypericum perforatum, stiripentol,&#xD;
             Aliskiren, Bosentan or Rosuvastatin or with an active treatment that might modify&#xD;
             blood concentration of ciclosporin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients currently pregnant or women of childbearing age who are not using&#xD;
             contraception (verbal diagnosis). Female patients of childbearing potential who are&#xD;
             using contraception but are subsequently found to have a positive urine pregnancy test&#xD;
             (pregnancy test performed as soon as reasonably practicable after investigational&#xD;
             medicinal product (IMP) administration).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to cardiac MRI:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Implantable defibrillator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to undergo cardiac MRI for any of the following reasons:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Frailty - as judged by the clinician. Frailty is defined as meeting three out of&#xD;
                  the five following criteria: low grip strength, low energy, slowed walking speed,&#xD;
                  low physical activity and/or unintentional weight loss. Due to the tight time&#xD;
                  constraints and emergency setting of this trial the clinician cannot test all&#xD;
                  these parameters and will need to exercise their judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Claustrophobic - patients who cannot take elevators or who are afraid of narrow&#xD;
                  or enclosed spaces.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Breathlessness - patients who suffer from breathlessness at rest or low exercise&#xD;
                  level (e.g. while walking on the level).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of other investigational study drugs within 30 days prior to trial entry (defined&#xD;
             as date of randomisation into trial). Co-enrolment with other studies is not allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of capacity to give initial verbal consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy &lt;1year due to non-cardiac illness&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ioakim Spyridopoulos, PhD, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Newcastle University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Newcastle Clinical Trials Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newcastle upon Tyne</city>
        <state>Tyne And Wear</state>
        <zip>NE2 4AE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 16, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 17, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 27, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 27, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Reperfusion Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cyclosporine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cyclosporins</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

