<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02395120</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1-14-15</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U01DE024167-01</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02395120</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Family Access to Dentist Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>FADS</acronym>
  <official_title>Family Intervention With Caregivers of Children With Dental Needs</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Case Western Reserve University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Dental and Craniofacial Research (NIDCR)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Harvard University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Case Western Reserve University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study is a multi-site, double blind, parallel arm, community-based randomized controlled&#xD;
      trial (phase III RCT) to evaluate the effectiveness of new referral approaches to increase&#xD;
      receipt of dental care among inner-city urban and rural elementary school children who were&#xD;
      screened at school and have restorative treatment needs. The study has 5 arms: The&#xD;
      experimental intervention is the use of a theoretically driven CSM referral letter alone, the&#xD;
      letter plus a Dental Information Guide, a reduced CSM referral letter alone, or a reduced CSM&#xD;
      referral letter plus a reduced Dental Information Guide. The control strategy is the use of a&#xD;
      standard referral letter. All participating K-4 grade children will receive a screening at&#xD;
      the beginning of the school year and at the study end point 7 months later to determine if&#xD;
      the child received dental care. Due to lower than expected enrollment in both the Ohio and&#xD;
      Washington sites, a second year of recruitment was added to include Bedford School District&#xD;
      and East Cleveland School District (only KG and other grades if they did not enroll in the&#xD;
      first year). The same study procedures, schedule and design was utilized for the second year&#xD;
      of recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim is to evaluate the effectiveness of experimental (new) versus standard&#xD;
      referral approach given to parents/caregivers in increasing receipt of dental care among&#xD;
      their children in grades K-4. The secondary aim is to assess changes in parent/caregiver&#xD;
      illness representation/perception and behavioral intention between enrollment (beginning of&#xD;
      school year) and follow-up (end of school year) to understand the underlying mechanisms of&#xD;
      the new vs. standard referral approach that result in receipt of dental care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis is that CSM-based interventions will increase receipt of dental care compared&#xD;
      to the standard referral letter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the effectiveness of new referral approaches to&#xD;
      increase receipt of dental care among inner-city urban and rural elementary school children&#xD;
      who were screened at school and have restorative treatment needs. The primary outcome is the&#xD;
      assessment of dental care receipt through dental exams. The secondary outcomes are change in&#xD;
      caregiver illness perception, measured through the IPQ-RD, and behavioral intention measured&#xD;
      through items in the caregiver questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will utilize a multi-site, double-blind, parallel arm, community-based randomized&#xD;
      trial design. The experimental intervention will be based upon the Common Sense Model of&#xD;
      Self-Regulation (CSM) to address parent/caregiver illness perception and navigation of&#xD;
      resources to increase receipt of dental care during a 7-month follow-up period for children&#xD;
      with restorative dental needs. In this five arm study the new CSM theory-driven referral&#xD;
      letter alone, the new CSM referral letter and Dental Information Guide (DIG), the new CSM&#xD;
      theory-driven reduced referral letter alone, and the new CSM theory-driven reduced referral&#xD;
      letter and reduced Dental Information Guide (DIG) will each be compared to a standard&#xD;
      referral letter to increase receipt of dental care among inner-city urban African American,&#xD;
      and rural Hispanic and White elementary school children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be parents/caregivers and their children in grades K-4 in one of four school&#xD;
      districts; East Cleveland City School District (OH), Cowlitz County School Districts (WA),&#xD;
      Lewis County School Districts (WA), and Bedford (OH). The study will be offered to all&#xD;
      caregivers and their children including those children with special health care needs. At the&#xD;
      Ohio site, only English-speaking caregivers and their children will be enrolled while both&#xD;
      English- and Spanish-speaking caregivers and their children will be included at the&#xD;
      Washington site. At the beginning of the school year dental screening, primary caregivers&#xD;
      will be randomized if their child has a tooth with an International Caries Detection and&#xD;
      Assessment System (ICDAS) active lesion score of 2 or greater. Caregivers with multiple&#xD;
      children in K-4 will receive the same intervention assignment. The second year of recruitment&#xD;
      included Bedford School District in Ohio and East Cleveland School District KG and other&#xD;
      grade families if they did not enroll in the first year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Caregivers will be recruited at the beginning of the school year and complete baseline forms&#xD;
      (consent form, Illness Perception Questionnaire-Revised for Dental (IPQ-RD) questionnaire,&#xD;
      and caregiver questionnaire) prior to dental screening and randomization. Children in K-4&#xD;
      whose parents have consented will receive a screening exam in early October 2015 (October&#xD;
      2016 for the second year of recruitment). After screening exams, eligible caregivers of&#xD;
      children with restorative referrals will be randomized into one of five study arms. Different&#xD;
      referral letter with/without Dental Information Guide according to study arms will be sent&#xD;
      home with the child on the day of screening and mailed to the caregiver address within 24&#xD;
      hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Caregivers will be followed at 2 time points: 2 weeks after the receipt of the intervention&#xD;
      letter and 2 weeks prior to the final (exit) study visit examinations in May 2016 (May 2017&#xD;
      for the second year of recruitment)-approximately 7 months after the initial dental exam. At&#xD;
      both time points caregivers will complete the IPQ-RD and the caregiver questionnaire. A small&#xD;
      sub-sample of 60 caregivers will be randomly sampled from three arms (standard letter,&#xD;
      intervention letter, and intervention letter+DIG) to complete the IPQ-RD 1 month after&#xD;
      enrollment for fidelity purposes. All questionnaires will be mailed to the home address and&#xD;
      asked to be returned to the class-room teacher or the outreach staff. Further, outreach staff&#xD;
      will ensure that the caregivers received and returned the materials through follow-up calls.&#xD;
      Children will have a follow-up dental exam in May 2016 (May 2017 for the second year of&#xD;
      recruitment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis Plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Statistical Analysis: Descriptive statistics will include frequencies (categorical&#xD;
      variables) and means (continuous variables) of baseline covariates among the five&#xD;
      intervention groups. Chi-square tests (for categorical variables) and t-tests (for continuous&#xD;
      variables) will be performed to test for group differences (by site and overall). In our&#xD;
      primary analysis, we will fit multivariate generalized linear (specifically, logistic&#xD;
      regression) models with dental care receipt as the (binary) outcome and the child as the unit&#xD;
      of analysis (as receipt of dental care will be determined for each child). A generalized&#xD;
      estimating equations (GEE) approach (with an exchangeable working correlation structure) will&#xD;
      be used to allow for correlations among multiple children for a given caregiver. Secondarily,&#xD;
      we will fit a model with a site by intervention group interaction, and the latter will be&#xD;
      tested to formally assess possible intervention effect heterogeneity over sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will also consider working correlation structures (e.g., alternating logistic regressions)&#xD;
      that allow for second-level clusters, namely schools (within which the first-level cluster,&#xD;
      caregiver, is nested). We will determine final models based on the quasi-likelihood&#xD;
      information criterion (QIC). Intervention (and other covariate) effects will be tested using&#xD;
      generalized score statistics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis of Secondary Outcomes (Questionnaire data): Summary statistics (including means and&#xD;
      standard errors) for questionnaire responses for both the IPQ-RD and behavioral intention&#xD;
      items within the caregiver questionnaire will be calculated by site and intervention group.&#xD;
      This will be done for the overall questionnaire (IPQ-RD and behavioral intention), for each&#xD;
      of the five IPQ-RD cognitive constructs, and the two behavioral intention questions. Analyses&#xD;
      will be done by site and overall (controlling for site). A summary measure approach, based on&#xD;
      the mean questionnaire response, will be used to compare questionnaire outcomes across&#xD;
      intervention groups, for the overall questionnaire and by construct. Specifically, for each&#xD;
      construct (or overall) a linear regression model will be used with the mean response as the&#xD;
      dependent variable, and intervention group indicators and selected baseline (control)&#xD;
      covariates as independent variables. Inferences (that is, p-values and confidence intervals)&#xD;
      will be performed assuming summary measures are normally distributed. This assumption will be&#xD;
      tested using the Shapiro-Wilk statistic and if violated a suitable transformation of the&#xD;
      summary measure used or a nonparametric approach (e.g., using ranks of the summary measures)&#xD;
      conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Missing Data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the event of missing questionnaire responses, we will first assess whether the data are&#xD;
      missing completely at random (MCAR), that is, whether missingness for a given item is&#xD;
      dependent only on participant baseline characteristics and not further on any other item&#xD;
      responses. This will be done using a generalized estimating equations (GEE) approach, that&#xD;
      is, by fitting a multivariate generalized linear (e.g., logistic regression) model to missing&#xD;
      data indicators for each item, including as explanatory variables selected baseline&#xD;
      covariates and other item responses, and testing for an effect of the latter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If the MCAR assumption is deemed reasonable (no significant effect found), we will conduct&#xD;
      the above regression analyses with mean outcomes based on available data. A weighted analysis&#xD;
      (that is, regression with the use of the weighted least squares criterion) will be conducted&#xD;
      to adjust for differential missingness (thus, non-homogeneous summary measure variances)&#xD;
      among participants. If the MCAR assumption is found to be violated we will use a multiple&#xD;
      imputation approach (in conjunction with the summary measure approach) using a suitable&#xD;
      imputation model (i.e., using other item responses). For each construct (or overall) we will&#xD;
      perform an F-test for a difference in the mean summary measure among the three intervention&#xD;
      groups, and obtain nominal 95% confidence intervals for pairwise mean differences. If&#xD;
      necessary, we will include a random effect for school.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Management:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data for this study are captured using examinations, forms, questionnaires, and audio&#xD;
      recordings. Study data will be collected and stored using the REDCap platform. REDCap is a&#xD;
      secure, web-based application designed to support remote data capture for research studies,&#xD;
      providing: 1) an intuitive interface for validated data entry, 2) audit trails for tracking&#xD;
      data manipulation and export procedures, 3) automated export procedures for seamless data&#xD;
      downloads to common statistical packages, and 4) procedures for importing data from external&#xD;
      sources.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study forms will be completed by study personnel on paper, and subsequently entered into&#xD;
      REDCap by study staff. Because randomization is contingent upon the computer, no paper&#xD;
      randomization forms will be completed. Paper forms will be securely stored in a locked file&#xD;
      cabinet at both sites when they are not in use. Completed paper forms will be transferred&#xD;
      between sites via courier or other secure document service. Similarly, questionnaires used in&#xD;
      the study (IPQ-RD, Caregiver Questionnaire) will be completed by subjects on paper sheets and&#xD;
      returned to Outreach Workers in each school. Study staff will enter the information into the&#xD;
      database. All data forms, questionnaires will be entered into database stored in a secure&#xD;
      password protected computer. Recorded audios will be stored in secured/locked cabinets in one&#xD;
      of the Project Coordinators' offices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dental examination and study questionnaire data will be reviewed for accuracy and&#xD;
      completeness after each study visit. The Outreach Workers will review the questionnaires&#xD;
      after the participants have completed them, and the Project Coordinators and the Data and&#xD;
      Statistics Team will do a final review after the documents have been transmitted. An annual&#xD;
      report (or as requested by the DSMB or NIDCR Program Official) will also be generated for&#xD;
      sharing progress of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Data &amp; Statistics Team will generate regular reports showing enrollment and potential&#xD;
      data anomalies, which will be sent to PIs, Project Coordinators, and other relevant study&#xD;
      staff. The Data Manager will work with the PIs at each site to resolve any data anomalies&#xD;
      that arise during recruitment. The Data &amp; Statistics Team will also respond to data queries&#xD;
      generated by the PIs, Project Coordinators, or other study staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analyses and summary reports will be generated by the study Biostatistician&#xD;
      during the course of the study. At the end of the study, the study Biostatistician will&#xD;
      conduct analyses of the data and assist in preparation of study publications and&#xD;
      presentations. The Data Manager will provide technical and data support for the&#xD;
      Biostatistician throughout the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Receipt of Dental Care - restoration or extraction of at least one tooth previously identified with an active ICDAS ≥2 at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Between baseline and follow-up (7 months after baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as restoration or extraction of at least one tooth previously identified with an active ICDAS ≥2 at baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Illness Perception assessed by IPQ-RD</measure>
    <time_frame>Between baseline, two week and final follow-up (7 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in the overall Illness Perception Questionnaire-Revised fore Dental (IPQ-RD), cognitive (identity, consequences, timeline, cause, cure/controllability) representation sub-scale scores</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Behavioral Intention</measure>
    <time_frame>Between baseline, two week and final follow-up (7 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral intention is measured by the summative score of 2 items (&quot;I want to take my child to the dentist&quot;, and &quot;I plan to take my child to the dentist&quot;) on a 5 point scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">611</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Caries</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Modified standard letter will be sent to caregivers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The CSM-based referral letter alone will be sent to caregivers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced intervention letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The reduced (removing text corresponding to &quot;timeline&quot;) CSM-based referral letter alone will be sent to caregivers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention letter+DIG</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The CSM-based referral letter with the dental information guide will be sent to caregivers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced intervention letter+reduced DIG</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The reduced CSM-based referral letter with the reduced dental information guide will be sent to caregivers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard letter</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard referral letter according to Ohio Department of Health Bureau guidelines. This letter is consistent with others used across the country.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard letter</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intervention letter</intervention_name>
    <description>Referral letter based on the Common Sense Model of Self-Regulation (CSM). The letter includes the cognitive dimensions of the CSM (identity, cause, timeline, consequences and control).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention letter+DIG</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Reduced intervention letter</intervention_name>
    <description>Reduced (removing text corresponding to &quot;timeline&quot;) CSM theory-based referral letter. The letter includes the remaining cognitive dimensions of the CSM (identity, cause, consequences and control).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced intervention letter</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced intervention letter+reduced DIG</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DIG</intervention_name>
    <description>Dental information guide (DIG) to reinforce/change illness perception, knowledge about dental caries, and resources to seek care. DIG is a brochure with illustrations which provides myths and facts about dental caries, hints for getting dental care, making appointments and Medicaid access, transportation and dentist availability resources.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention letter+DIG</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Reduced DIG</intervention_name>
    <description>Text and illustrations related to the &quot;timeline&quot; construct of the CSM have been removed in the reduced dental information guide.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Reduced intervention letter+reduced DIG</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: (parents/caregivers and their children)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide signed and dated consent form (also assent form for children 7 and older)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to comply with all study procedures and be available for the duration of the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female child, grades K-4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child in good general health as evidenced by parent report (including children with&#xD;
             special health care needs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Based on the beginning of the school year dental screening, caregivers will be&#xD;
             randomized if their child has tooth with an International Caries Detection and&#xD;
             Assessment System (ICDAS) active lesion score of ≥ 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: (parents/caregivers)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Illiterate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaking (in East Cleveland Public Schools)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under 18 years of age&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>5 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Suchitra Nelson, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Case Western Reserve University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Case Western Reserve University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Washington</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seattle</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98195-7475</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 17, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 20, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 16, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 16, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 17, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Case Western Reserve University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Suchitra Nelson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dental Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Caregiver Illness Perception</keyword>
  <keyword>Common Sense Model of Self-Regulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Dental Access</keyword>
  <keyword>Referral letter</keyword>
  <keyword>Dental Caries</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

