<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02398487</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>VAPECIG 2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02398487</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personal Vaporizer vs Cigalike</brief_title>
  <acronym>VAPECIG 2</acronym>
  <official_title>Head-To-Head Comparision of Personal Vaporizers Versus Cigalike: Prospective 6-Month Randomized Control Design Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universita degli Studi di Catania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universita degli Studi di Catania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a pilot study to compare efficiency and tolerability of a personal vaporizers (PV)&#xD;
      new generation electronic cigarette loaded with nicotine e-liquid with cigalike new&#xD;
      generation electronic cigarette loaded with nicotine and usual smoking habits, in a group of&#xD;
      well characterized regular smokers unwilling to quit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      RATIONALE&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of ECLAT - the first randomized controlled trial addressing the impact of&#xD;
      electronic cigarette use in relation to smoking reduction, smoking abstinence and safety&#xD;
      long-term - have revealed important and persistent modifications in the smoking habits of 300&#xD;
      smokers (not intending to quit) with significant reduction in tobacco cigarettes' consumption&#xD;
      (1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surprisingly, the reduction in cig/day use in ECLAT was not much different among study&#xD;
      groups, with the non-nicotine study group performing much like both high and low nicotine&#xD;
      study groups. This was because, with the products used in ECLAT, saliva cotinine levels were&#xD;
      well below the concentration threshold considered to be representative for regular smokers&#xD;
      (2) or experienced electronic cigarette users (3) in both high and low nicotine study groups.&#xD;
      Specifically, the model under investigation in ECLAT is not very efficient at delivering&#xD;
      nicotine (4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      With this in mind, we have designed a pilot study to compare efficiency and tolerability of a&#xD;
      personal vaporizers (PV) new generation electronic cigarette loaded with nicotine e-liquid&#xD;
      with cigalike new generation electronic cigarette loaded with nicotine and usual smoking&#xD;
      habits, in a group of well characterized regular smokers unwilling to quit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims of this pilot study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to assess if a Personal Vaporizers (PV) can effectively reduce tobacco smoking&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to compare if efficacy data with PV E-cigs are better than &quot;cigalike&quot; efficacy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to evaluate if PV E-cigs are safe to use&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population 200 regular smokers (smoking ≥ 10 cigarettes per day for at least the past 5&#xD;
      years; eCO ≥ 10 ppm), with an age of 18-70 years, in good general health; and committed to&#xD;
      follow the trial procedures will be recruited following placement of advertisements in local&#xD;
      newspapers and radio/TV network. Exclusion criteria will include: recent vaping history&#xD;
      (stopped vaping less than 3 months ago); use of any other form of non combustible nicotine&#xD;
      containing products (chewable tobacco or nicotine replacement therapy) symptomatic&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease; clinical history of asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease&#xD;
      (COPD); regular psychotropic medication use; current or past history of alcohol abuse; use of&#xD;
      smokeless tobacco or nicotine replacement therapy, and pregnancy or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Products&#xD;
&#xD;
      Personal Vaporizer electronic cigarette This new generation device consist of a large lithium&#xD;
      battery part (capacity of 2600 mAh) with an internal electronic circuit which includes a&#xD;
      current stabilizer and allows the user to manually adjust the energy applied to the atomizer.&#xD;
      A new-generation atomizer will be used and will be filled with approximately 2 ml of liquid.&#xD;
      The Energy delivery to the atomizer will be set to 9 watts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These electronic cigarettes will be provided free of charge by the manufacturer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The liquid will be provided free of charge by the manufacturer Alterna Farmaceutici, Francia&#xD;
      Farmaceutici group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;Cigarette-like Electronic Cigarette&quot; The Cigalike e-Cigarette is a disposable&#xD;
      battery-powered electronic nicotine delivery device (ENDD) - that closely resembles the shape&#xD;
      of a tobacco cigarette - designed for the purpose of nicotine (and/or aroma) delivery, where&#xD;
      no tobacco or combustion is necessary for its operation. This e-Cigarette contains a&#xD;
      propylene glycol-free liquid consisting of distilled water, FCC grade vegetable glycerin,&#xD;
      natural flavors, artificial flavors, citric acid and may also contain pharmaceutical grade&#xD;
      nicotine. The lithium battery has a capacity of 250 mAh and will be fully charged before use.&#xD;
      Cartomizers will be filled with approximately 1 ml of a nicotine containing liquid.These&#xD;
      electronic cigarettes will be provided free of charge by the manufacturer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design and Procedures Two hundred regular smokers, (not willing to quit) will be&#xD;
      recruited in our center following placement of advertisements in local newspapers and&#xD;
      radio/TV network. At baseline, participants will be randomized into three separate study&#xD;
      groups. Fifty participants randomized in study group A will receive a &quot;Personal Vaporizer&#xD;
      electronic cigarette&quot; and 24-weeks supply of e-liquid (active group); fifty subjects in study&#xD;
      group B, 24-week supply of &quot;Cigarette-like Electronic Cigarette&quot; (active group); one hundred&#xD;
      participants in study group C will continue usual smoking (control group).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Schedule Participants will attend their study visits at the smoking cessation clinic at&#xD;
      approximately the same time of day. With the exception of the baseline study day, most visits&#xD;
      will take approximately 10-15 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline (study visit 1), socio-demographic factors, a detailed smoking history and&#xD;
      craving will be annotated and individual pack-years (pack/yrs) calculated. Eligible&#xD;
      participants will be invited to sign an informed consent form. Cigarette dependence will be&#xD;
      measured by Fagerstrom Test for Cigarette Dependence (FTCD). Additionally, levels of carbon&#xD;
      monoxide in exhaled breath (eCO) will be measured using a portable device (Micro CO, Micro&#xD;
      Medical Ltd, UK). Vital signs (HR and BP), body weight, and adverse events will be also&#xD;
      recorded at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in group A and B will be given a free supply of electronic smoking (on average&#xD;
      2-week supply of ecigs) and instructed on how to correctly use them. Key troubleshooting&#xD;
      support will be provided and phone numbers will be supplied for medical assistance. They will&#xD;
      also be requested to fill a 2-weeks' study diary recording adverse events. No emphasis on&#xD;
      encouragement, motivation and reward for the smoking cessation effort will be provided since&#xD;
      this study was intended to monitor smokers (unwilling to quit) using in three different&#xD;
      situations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline visit (Visit 1) in brief&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inclusion/exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CRF (smoking Hx, FTND, eCO, HR, BP, weight, AEs)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Craving/VAS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Randomization into either study group A (with Nic) or B (no Nic)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Provide PV Ecig or Cigalike and dispense 2-weeks supply of electronic smoking (depending&#xD;
           on the study arm allocation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense 2-weeks' study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
      By and large, at week-2 (study visit 2), week-4 (study visit 3), week-8, week-12, and&#xD;
      week-24, participants will a) receive further study diaries for the residual study periods,&#xD;
      b) have their eCO levels and vital signs recorded, c) return their completed study diaries&#xD;
      and used study products. Additionally, saliva samples will be collected at week-12 and at&#xD;
      week-24 for cotinine measurement in those who stated they had not smoked (not even a puff)&#xD;
      and with an eCO ≤ 7ppm. Cotton rolls will be placed into polypropylene tubes and stored at&#xD;
      -20°C until use. Saliva samples will be analysed in duplicate for cotinine analysis by gas&#xD;
      chromatography. At the end of week-24 study visit, no more products will be provided by the&#xD;
      investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week-2 visit (Visit 2) in brief&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collect 2-weeks' study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CRF (no. cig/day, eCO, HR, BP)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Craving/VAS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Smokers' product preference survey&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense next 2-weeks supply of electronic smoking (depending on the study arm&#xD;
           allocation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense next 2-weeks' study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week-4/8 visit (Visits 3 and 4) in brief&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collect study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CRF (no. cig/day, eCO, HR, BP)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Craving/VAS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense next 4-weeks supply of electronic smoking (depending on the study arm&#xD;
           allocation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense next 4-weeks' study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week-12 visit (Visit 5) in brief&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collect study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CRF (no. cig/day, eCO, HR, BP and weight)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Craving/VAS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collect saliva sample* (only in those with zero cig/day and eCO ≤ 7ppm, * Times of&#xD;
           saliva sampling requires standardization, e.g. same time of the day, within 2 hrs from&#xD;
           last vape)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense next 12-weeks supply of electronic smoking (depending on the study arm&#xD;
           allocation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dispense next 12-weeks' study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week-24 visit (Visit 6)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collect study diary for AEs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CRF (physical examination, no. cig/day, eCO, HR, BP and weight)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Craving/VAS&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collect saliva sample* (only in those with zero cig/day and eCO ≤ 7ppm, * Times of&#xD;
           saliva sampling requires standardization, e.g. same time of the day, within 2 hrs from&#xD;
           last vape)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Smokers' product preference survey&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Outcome Measures A ≥50% reduction in the number of cig/day from baseline, defined as&#xD;
      self-reported reduction in the number of cig/day (≥50%) compared to baseline (together with&#xD;
      an eCO levels reduction, to objectively document a reduction from baseline), will be&#xD;
      calculated at each study visit (&quot;reducers&quot;).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abstinence from smoking, defined as complete self-reported abstinence from tobacco smoking -&#xD;
      not even a puff (together with an eCO concentration of ≤7 ppm), will be calculated at each&#xD;
      study visit (&quot;quitters&quot;). Failing to meet the above criteria defines smoking&#xD;
      reduction/cessation failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adverse events, symptoms thought to be related to tobacco smoking and e-Cigarette use and to&#xD;
      withdrawal from nicotine will be annotated at baseline and at each subsequent study visit on&#xD;
      the adverse event page of the study diary. Vital signs will be also recorded. Participants'&#xD;
      perception and liking of the product will be assessed by asking to rate their level of&#xD;
      satisfaction with the products compared to their own cigarettes using a visual analogue scale&#xD;
      (VAS) from 0 to 10 points (0 = being 'completely unsatisfied', 10 being = 'fully satisfied');&#xD;
      using the same scale, they will also rate how much they miss their own brand (0 = being 'did&#xD;
      not miss it at all', 10 being = 'missed too much') and whether they would recommend it to a&#xD;
      friend/relative (0 = being 'not recommended at all', 10 being = 'absolutely recommended').&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking Reduction</measure>
    <time_frame>24 week</time_frame>
    <description>50% reduction of cigarette smoked compared to baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Smoking Cessation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 week</time_frame>
    <description>complete abstinence</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Cigarette Addiction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Personal Vaporizer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Personal Vaporizer loaded with nicotine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cigalike</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cigalike loaded with nicotine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual smoking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cigalike with nicotine</intervention_name>
    <description>cigalike 24 mg nicotine or 16 mg nicotine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cigalike</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Personal Vaporizer with nicotine</intervention_name>
    <description>Personal Vaporizer 16 mg nicotine or 9 mg nicotine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Personal Vaporizer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  in good general health&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  committed to follow the trial procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  recent vaping history (stopped vaping less than 3 months ago)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of any other form of non combustible nicotine containing products (chewable&#xD;
             tobacco or nicotine replacement therapy) symptomatic cardiovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical history of asthma and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  regular psychotropic medication use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  current or past history of alcohol abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of smokeless tobacco or nicotine replacement therapy, and pregnancy or&#xD;
             breastfeeding.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro per la Prevenzione e Cura del Tabagismo University of Catania</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catania</city>
        <zip>95100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 24, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 25, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 1, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 1, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 2, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universita degli Studi di Catania</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Riccardo Polosa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Behavior, Addictive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nicotine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

