<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02367443</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CentralHMIA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02367443</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Hypofractionated Accelerated Radiotherapy With Concomitant Chemotherapy for NSCLC</brief_title>
  <official_title>Hypofractionated Accelerated Radiotherapy With Concomitant Full Dose Chemotherapy for Locally Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer: Phase I/II Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Independent Public Care Health Facility of the Ministry of the Interior and Warmian &amp; Mazurian Oncology Centre</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Independent Public Care Health Facility of the Ministry of the Interior and Warmian &amp; Mazurian Oncology Centre</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I/II trial on concomitant RT-full dose CHT using accelerated&#xD;
      hypofractionation schedule as currently being in routine use in Poland for sequential&#xD;
      combination or RT alone. Objectives of the study are: to estimate rate of grade ≥ 3 CTCAE&#xD;
      adverse effects related to treatment and to estimate tumor control, progression&#xD;
      free-survival, and overall survival in patients treated with this regimen. Stage III NSCLC&#xD;
      patients are treated according to the following schedule: RT: 58.8 Gy in 21 fractions (2.8&#xD;
      Gy/fraction, 5 times a week, 6 times in the third week; CHT concomitant with RT (2 cycle of&#xD;
      Cisplatinum and Vinorelbine, every 21 days). Feasibility of the studied approach is evaluated&#xD;
      by scoring the toxicity during RT-CHT and therafter, as well as percentage of treatment&#xD;
      completion; efficacity is evaluated by estimation of local control and survival. If toxicity&#xD;
      and efficacity are similar or better than those observed in modern series of conventionally&#xD;
      fractionated RT-CHT, the studied regimen will become a routine treatment schedule in our&#xD;
      institution in order to spare RT resources. In the future, a randomized comparison of the&#xD;
      studied schedule with conventionally fractionated RT-CHT for locally advanced NSCLC is also&#xD;
      planned.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Background Lung cancer is the most common malignancy in Poland. In 2013, the annual lung&#xD;
           cancer incidence in Poland was 175/100 000 in men and 95/100 000 in women, substantially&#xD;
           higher than the EU value. Poland and UK are the first countries in Europe, where the&#xD;
           mortality from lung cancer has overtaken the mortality from breast cancer and became the&#xD;
           first cause of mortality from cancer in women. Thus besides the problem of prevention,&#xD;
           the efficient and rational from economical point of view treatment of lung cancer is one&#xD;
           of the crucial problems in Polish healthcare system. Prolongation of overall treatment&#xD;
           time is deleterious for patients with locally advanced (LA) - non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
           (NSCLC) even if radio-chemotherapy (RT-CHT) is used. Current standard of treatment for&#xD;
           LA-NSCLC is concurrent radio-chemotherapy (RT-CHT), because survival benefit with the&#xD;
           increase of esophageal toxicity was demonstrated in a meta-analysis. Acceleration of&#xD;
           radiotherapy (RT) via hyperfractionation results in survival benefit as it was shown&#xD;
           also in a meta-analysis but at the expense of higher esophageal toxicity&#xD;
           Hyperfractionated RT schedules were used with low-doses of CHT, because of the fear of&#xD;
           accumulation of acute toxicity Hyperfractionation represents an additional burden for&#xD;
           equipment, staff and health care system and cannot be routinely realized, especially in&#xD;
           limited .resources setting. For patient, it is also associated with higher treatment&#xD;
           cost, i.e. by payment of cost of transport twice a day.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Alternative for acceleration of RT time is the use of hypofractionated RT schedule. Such&#xD;
           a radiation schedule is in the routine use in some countries. However, hypofractionation&#xD;
           has been often considered as palliative approach and even in limited resources countries&#xD;
           is still rarely proposed for curatively treated patients. In only three out of 36 (8%)&#xD;
           analysed Eastern and Central European centres that responded in the IAEA pattern of care&#xD;
           survey, the hypofractionation was used for curative treatment of LA-NSCLC. We have also&#xD;
           very few data from prospective studies that report on the concomitant hypofractionated&#xD;
           RTwith full dose CHT. The RTOG 0117 study arm that used slightly hypofractionated RT&#xD;
           schedule with dose escalation (75.25 Gy with 2.15 Gy fractional dose) and concomitant&#xD;
           full-dose CHT was interrupted because of the excessive toxicity. However, the total dose&#xD;
           escalation used in this study might be a reason for a failure of such an approach.&#xD;
           Recently, the concept of dose escalation with concomitant CHT has been compromised for&#xD;
           LA-NSCLC. When using hypofractionation, the total radiation dose should probably be&#xD;
           adapted to correspond to biological doses of around 66 Gy, because we have reports that&#xD;
           confrm safety of such a schedule. In opposite to that the dose escalation using&#xD;
           hypofractionation for central tumors led to the excessive long-term toxicity due to the&#xD;
           bronchial tree stenosis and perforations. In a few centers in Poland, the&#xD;
           hypofractionated RT with total dose of 58.8 Gy in 21 fractions (in 4 weeks; in the third&#xD;
           week 6 fractions are given) following two cycles of CHT or as RT alone is routinely&#xD;
           used. Safety and efficacy of this approach was established in a phase II prospective&#xD;
           trial. A question arises if such a RT schedule may be used concurrently with CHT. Given&#xD;
           the proven benefit of concurrent RT-(full dose)CHT in stage III NSCLC, data on the value&#xD;
           of overall treatment time and in order to spare RT resources we have decided to conduct&#xD;
           a phase I/II trial on concomitant RT-(full dose)CHT using accelerated hypofractionation&#xD;
           schedule as currently being in routine use in Poland for sequential combination or RT&#xD;
           alone. Confirmation that toxicity and outcome in terms of local control and overall&#xD;
           survival are similar to those observed in contemporary series of conventionally&#xD;
           fractionated RT-CHT will lead to the incorporation of this schedule into routine&#xD;
           practice in Poland. Such a schedule with shortened overall treatment time via&#xD;
           hypofractionation will contribute to essential sparing of RT resources, still&#xD;
           insufficient in Poland. Positive outcome of this study may be also a basis for future&#xD;
           conduction of phase III study that compares conventionally fractionated RT-CHT with&#xD;
           accelearated hypofractionated RT-CHT for stage III NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Objectives of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
           To estimate toxicity and efficacy of accelerated hypofractionated RT combined with&#xD;
           concurrent full-dose CHT for locally advanced NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
           STUDY HYPOTHESIS:&#xD;
&#xD;
           RTOG/EORTC grade III and higher esophageal or pulmonary acute toxicity will not be&#xD;
           higher than in conventionally fractionated concurrent RT-CHT i.e. 25%.&#xD;
&#xD;
           And Two-year overall survival rate will be at least 40% and median overall survival will&#xD;
           be higher than 20 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.1. Main endpoints: A. To estimate rate of RTOG/EORTC grade III and higher esophageal&#xD;
           and pulmonary toxicity and grade IV and higher CTCAE version 3.0 hematological toxicity&#xD;
           within 6 months from start of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
           B. To estimate overall survival two years after start of RT-CHT.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2.2. Secondary endpoints: A. Rate of two-year local control. B. All types of toxicity&#xD;
           (esophagus, lung, skin, kidney, heart) within two years after start of RT-CHT.&#xD;
&#xD;
           C. Feasibility of the study (percentage of completion of both planned cycles of CHT and&#xD;
           full dose of planned CHT delivery; completion of planned RT, breaks in treatment and&#xD;
           prolongation of overall treatment time).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Pathological or cytological confirmation of the diagnosis of NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Confirmation of clinical stage III based on: clinical examination, CT of the chest&#xD;
                and abdomen (PET-CT highly recommended), bronchoscopy, CT or MRI of the brain if&#xD;
                suspicion of brain metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  No abnormalities in blood count precluding administration of full doses of&#xD;
                Cisplatin and Vinorelbine (Neutrophils ≥1.5x109/L; Platelets ≥100 x109/L;&#xD;
                Hemoglobin &gt;11 g/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  No abnormalities in renal and hepatic function precluding administration of full&#xD;
                doses of Cisplatin and Vinorelbine (creatinine clearance &gt;50 ml/minute,&#xD;
                aminotransferases &lt; 1.5 of upper limit of normal value)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Age &lt;75&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  KPS: 80-100&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  FEV1 &gt; 1 liter (except cases with very low body surface, when FEV1 should be &gt;40%)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  No chronic diseases causing contraindication to the use of CHT&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  No previous RT on the thoracic region&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Informed consent of patient for the participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Lack of meeting all inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Presence of clinically examined supraclavicular lymph nodes&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Malignant pleural or pericardial effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Schema of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Stage III NSCLC patients who met inclusion criteria and signed informed consent are&#xD;
           treated according to following schedule:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  RT: 58.8 Gy in 21 fractions (2.8 Gy/fraction, 5 times a week, 6 times in the third&#xD;
                week [treatment on Saturday])&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Two cycles of CHT concomitant with RT: D1 - Cisplatin i.v. 80 mg/m2, Vinorelbine 25&#xD;
                mg/m2 i.v.; D8 - Vinorelbine 25 mg/m2 i.v.; D22 - Cisplatin 80 mg/m2 i.v.;&#xD;
                Vinorelbine 25 mg/m2 i.v.; D29 - Vinorelbine 25 mg/m2 i.v.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Patients are followed once a week during RT-CHT for evaluation of toxicity, then one&#xD;
           month after treatment completion and every three months up two years after treatment,&#xD;
           every six months thereafter. CT of the chest is performed during f/up at every visit.&#xD;
           Blood tests for hematological toxicity will be performed at least once a week during&#xD;
           radiotherapy and at each follow-up visit thereafter. Other examinations will depend on&#xD;
           the clinical needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Chemotherapy (CHT) 6.1. General rules: Two cycles of CHT (Cisplatin &amp; Vinorelbine) will&#xD;
           be administered during RT every 21 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
           6.2. Antiemetics: All patients will receive antiemesis prophylaxis before and during&#xD;
           administration of CHT. This prophylaxis is mandatory sixty minutes before Cisplatin&#xD;
           infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Recommended drugs are: Dexamethasone (12 mg p.o. or i.v. D1 and 22; 8 mg p.o. or i.v.&#xD;
           D2, D3, D4; D23, D24, D25); 5-HT3 receptor antagonists, f.ex. Ondansetron 8 mg. i.v. D1,&#xD;
           D22; NK-1 receptor antagonists, f.ex. Aprepitant 125 mg p.o. D1, D22 and 80 mg D2, D3,&#xD;
           D23, and D24.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The use of all other and additional antiemetics and combinations are possible, depending&#xD;
           on the clinical indications and individual tolerance of drugs. Routine premedication&#xD;
           before administration of Vinorelbine is not required.&#xD;
&#xD;
           6.3. Doses of CHT and their modifications 6.3.1. Dose of Cisplatin is calculated based&#xD;
           on the body-surface area - 80 mg/m2; diluted in 1000 ml of sodium chloride 0.9% and&#xD;
           given over two-hours in i.v. infusion D1 and D22; Cisplatin will be administered after&#xD;
           i.v. injection of Vinorelbine.&#xD;
&#xD;
           6.3.2. Dose of Vinorelbine is calculated based on the body-surface area - 25 mg/m2;&#xD;
           diluted in 125 ml of sodium chloride 0.9% and given over 20 minutes in i.v. infusion D1,&#xD;
           D8, D22 and D29.&#xD;
&#xD;
           6.3.3. Doses of CHT will be modified in consecutive cycles depending of hematological&#xD;
           toxicity. Neutrophils level before each cycle of CHT should be ≥1.5x109/L and platelets&#xD;
           level should be ≥100 x109/L. In case of incidence of hematological toxicity, the drug&#xD;
           doses will be modified according to the schema presented in Table 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Table 1. CHT dose modifications for 2nd cycle of CHT depending on hematological toxicity&#xD;
           observed at the first CHT cycle.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Nadir of Platelets (x109/L) Nadir of Neutrophils (x109/L) Dose modification; Action&#xD;
           taken &gt;100 and &gt; 1.5 100% 75-100 or 1.0-1.5 One week deferral &lt;75 or &lt;1.0 One week&#xD;
           deferral and reduction of dose to 75% of initial dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
           Persistent Grade III or higher CTC toxicity up to end of RT Persistent Grade III or&#xD;
           higher CTC toxicity up to end of RT Discontinuation of Chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
           6.3.4. Hematopoietic growth factors won't be used for primary prophylaxis of febrile&#xD;
           neutropenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Radiotherapy (RT)&#xD;
&#xD;
           7.1. Target volume definition: Whole treatment will be planned in the three-dimensional&#xD;
           (3D) planning system, according to the requirement of ICRU recommendations of planning,&#xD;
           delivering and reporting doses of 3D-conformal radiotherapy (3D-CRT) [13]. IMRT&#xD;
           technique won't be used for planning in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           GTV will be considered as radiologically and bronchoscopically visualized tumor, as well&#xD;
           as pathological regional lymph nodes (LN). Mediastinal and hilar LN will be considered&#xD;
           as pathological if FDG-avid in PET-CT scan. In case of absence of abnormal FDG-uptake&#xD;
           all LN with short axis diameter ≥1.5 cm will be considered as pathological and included&#xD;
           in the GTV, unless clinical and radiological judgment will indicate with high&#xD;
           probability other than malignant etiology of lymph node enlargement. Pathological&#xD;
           confirmation of abnormal FDG up-take in regional lymph nodes won't be mandatory. In rare&#xD;
           cases of lack of PET-CT for staging, LN with short axis diameter &gt;1 cm will be&#xD;
           considered as pathological, unless the formal exclusion of their metastatic origin is&#xD;
           provided by radiologist, i.e. benign appearance.&#xD;
&#xD;
           CTV: will be created by adding 0.5 cm to the GTV of primary tumor. Nodal CTV will&#xD;
           consist of the whole LN station (LNS), in which pathological LN are found. Borders of&#xD;
           LNS will be designed according to the guidelines of Michigan Atlas [14] with&#xD;
           modification of Kepka et al. [15] for hilar motion uncertainty.&#xD;
&#xD;
           PTV: will be created by adding 1 cm margin to the CTV. Sometimes PTV margin will be&#xD;
           modified individually depending of respiratory motion and spirometry test's results of&#xD;
           the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
           7.1. Radiotherapy planning: CT for planning will be done in therapeutic patient's&#xD;
           position and immobilization as for all other thoracic localizations in the department.&#xD;
           Scan thickness is 3 mm. The i.v. contrast use for planning is not mandatory.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Dose will be prescribed in ICRU point; energy of 6 (or exceptionally 15) MV photons will&#xD;
           be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Dose per fraction: 2.8 Gy, RT once a day, 5 times a week in 1st, 2nd and 4th week of RT;&#xD;
           6 times a week in the 3rd week of RT (treatment on Saturday).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Total dose: 58.8 Gy Dose homogeneity criteria: 95-107% of the prescribed dose; minimum&#xD;
           dose of 90% will be also allowed in the PTV (as point dose).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Doses for critical structures:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Spinal cord: maximum dose - 45 Gy; 40 Gy for a length &lt; 5 cm. Lung: mean dose ≤20 Gy (or&#xD;
           less depending on individual physician decision if respiratory reserve of patient is&#xD;
           limited); 35% of total lung volume receives ≤20 Gy Heart: 50% of heart volume receives&#xD;
           less than 40 Gy; avoidance of hot-spot within this organ Esophagus: recommended mean&#xD;
           dose &lt;34 Gy; avoidance of hot-spots within this organ.&#xD;
&#xD;
           7.2. Radiotherapy delivery: Physician will be present at the first RT session. The&#xD;
           set-up verification with KV portals will be done and portal imaging for all therapeutic&#xD;
           portals will be done and fused with respective DRR at the first RT session. MV cone beam&#xD;
           verification will be possible at the request of the physician, but not mandatory. Next&#xD;
           KV set-up verification will be realized at least once a weak. On-line and off-line QA&#xD;
           procedures won't differ from those for other curative treatments in the RT Department.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Toxicity evaluation Early lung and esophageal toxicity will be scored according to the&#xD;
           RTOG/EORTC scale once a week during radiotherapy, next one month after completion of RT,&#xD;
           and in the third and sixth month after treatment. During the same follow-up visit all&#xD;
           types of toxicity from other organs, like skin, heart will be scored according to the&#xD;
           same scale [15].&#xD;
&#xD;
           Late radiation toxicity will be evaluated after 6 months of follow-up every three months&#xD;
           within two years and every six months thereafter according to the RTOG/EORTC scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Hematological toxicity will be evaluated according to the CTCAE vs 3.0 [17] in the same&#xD;
           intervals than esophageal and pulmonary toxicity during radiotherapy and thereafter, or&#xD;
           more often if clinically indicated. Other types of CHT toxicity will be also reported&#xD;
           according to the CTCAE scale, if they occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Evaluation of the outcome of RT-CHT CT of the chest will be done one month after&#xD;
           treatment completion. Then CT of the chest as well as the physical examination and blood&#xD;
           tests will be done at each follow-up visit. Other radiological examinations will be&#xD;
           prescribed if clinically indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Overall survival will be estimated according to the Kaplan-Meier method and calculated&#xD;
           from the first day of RT-CHT. Actual risk of loco-regional failure will also be&#xD;
           estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. Distant metastases occurrence and their sites&#xD;
           will be scored and reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Number of patients and study duration Study will be conducted in one institution. Ethic&#xD;
           Committee agreement for study conduction is required. It is planned to include 100&#xD;
           patients during first three years; minimum follow-up required after inclusion of last&#xD;
           patient is one year. Thus planned time of study conduction is four years, meant as the&#xD;
           time to the submission of publication that reports the outcome. Before that, the&#xD;
           publication of interim analyses is allowed if judged as clinically and scientifically&#xD;
           relevant by the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Predefined rules of study earlier halting or termination&#xD;
&#xD;
           Study will be earlier terminated or appropriately modified after Investigators Meeting&#xD;
           and consultation of Ethical Committee if:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  After completion of 6 months of follow-up for first 10 included patients, the CTCAE&#xD;
                hematological toxicity of grade IV or higher will occur in 3 or more patients&#xD;
                and/or the grade III or higher RTOG/EORTC pulmonary or esophageal toxicity will&#xD;
                occur in 3 or more patients, and also if two or more toxic deaths* will be&#xD;
                reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  After completion of 6 months of follow-up for first 30 included patients, the CTCAE&#xD;
                hematological toxicity of grade IV or higher will occur in ≥30% of patients and/or&#xD;
                the grade III or higher RTOG/EORTC pulmonary or esophageal toxicity will occur in&#xD;
                ≥30% of patients, and also if three or more toxic deaths* will be reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  -  Every toxic death will lead to the extra meeting of the study investigators in&#xD;
                     order to ascertain if immediate study modification is not necessary. Every&#xD;
                     death scored as for unknown reason will require an undertaking of all&#xD;
                     necessary steps to find all its circumstances to qualify with the highest&#xD;
                     possible probability its cause.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Expected outcomes of the study We expect to confirm prospectively the safety and&#xD;
           efficacy of studied approach, meant as esophageal and pulmonary toxicity not higher and&#xD;
           overall survival not lower than that observed in contemporary series with conventionally&#xD;
           fractionated concurrent RT-CHT. After confirmation of the study hypothesis, a phase III&#xD;
           study that compares the studied schedule with conventionally fractionated RT-CHT will be&#xD;
           justified. The studied accelerated hypofractionated RT-CHT schedule may become routine&#xD;
           treatment protocol for stage III NSCLC patients what will reduce treatment cost and&#xD;
           enable better sparing of accessible RT technological resources.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>March 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Grade III and higher</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">92</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>one group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Radiation: Hypofractionated accelerated Radiotherapy with concomitant full dose Chemotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Radiation</intervention_name>
    <description>Radiation: Accelerated Hypofractionated radiotherapy with full dose Chemotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>one group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Pathological or cytological confirmation of the diagnosis of NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Confirmation of clinical stage III based on: clinical examination, CT of the&#xD;
                  chest and abdomen (PET-CT highly recommended), bronchoscopy, CT or MRI of the&#xD;
                  brain if suspicion of brain metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No abnormalities in blood count precluding administration of full doses of&#xD;
                  Cisplatin and Vinorelbine (Neutrophils ≥1.5x109/L; Platelets ≥100 x109/L;&#xD;
                  Hemoglobin &gt;11 g/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No abnormalities in renal and hepatic function precluding administration of full&#xD;
                  doses of Cisplatin and Vinorelbine (creatinine clearance &gt;50 ml/minute,&#xD;
                  aminotransferases &lt; 1.5 of upper limit of normal value)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age &lt;75&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  KPS: 80-100&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  FEV1 &gt; 1 liter (except cases with very low body surface, when FEV1 should be&#xD;
                  &gt;40%)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No chronic diseases causing contraindication to the use of CHT&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No previous RT on the thoracic region&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Informed consent of patient for the participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lack of meeting all inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of clinically examined supraclavicular lymph nodes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignant pleural or pericardial effusion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Independent Public Health Care Facility and Warmian &amp; Mazurian Oncology Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Olsztyn</city>
        <zip>10-228</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 19, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 20, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 4, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 4, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 6, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Independent Public Care Health Facility of the Ministry of the Interior and Warmian &amp; Mazurian Oncology Centre</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lucyna Kepka</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>radiotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>therapeutic use</keyword>
  <keyword>Radiation</keyword>
  <keyword>non-small cell lung cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

