<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02362828</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EPiMAP Obstetrics</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02362828</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EPiMAP Obstetrics: European Practices in the Management of Accidental Dural Puncture in Obstetrics</brief_title>
  <acronym>EPiMAP</acronym>
  <official_title>EPiMAP Obstetrics: European Practices in the Management of Accidental Dural Puncture in Obstetrics: European Prospective Multicentre Observational Audit to MAP Out Current Practices in the Management of Patients Who Had Accidental Dural Puncture During EPIdural Insertion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>European Society of Anaesthesiology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>European Society of Anaesthesiology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aims of EPiMAP Obstetrics are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to identify risk factors for failure of epidural blood patch in the obstetric population&#xD;
           for management of post dural puncture headache.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  to describe European practices in the management of accidental dural puncture in the&#xD;
           Obstetric population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary aim of this prospective, international audit of practice is to identify risk&#xD;
      factors for failure of epidural blood patch (EBP) in the Obstetric population after&#xD;
      accidental dural puncture (ADP) with an epidural needle. Other aims are to describe the&#xD;
      epidemiology, management principles, side effects and complications of ADP and longer-term&#xD;
      effects of ADP on patients undergoing Obstetric anaesthesia and analgesia. Expectation is&#xD;
      that this audit of practice will provide important information in understanding the reasons&#xD;
      for failure of EBP and subsequently to better manage parturients affected by this&#xD;
      debilitating complication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postdural puncture headache (PDPH) is the most common serious complication of accidental&#xD;
      dural puncture (ADP), and feared by every Anaesthesiologist. It is associated with&#xD;
      significant peri-partum maternal distress, and poor bonding with the baby, which in turn&#xD;
      leads to physical disability for the mother and psychological and social implications for the&#xD;
      whole family. It is estimated that about 10,000 parturients in Europe may have an accidental&#xD;
      dural puncture (ADP) each year. Attitudes and practices in the management of ADP are based on&#xD;
      small studies, and sometimes driven by experience rather than evidence. Although several&#xD;
      methods have been described in the literature to treat PDPH, one common method used is an&#xD;
      epidural blood patch (EBP). This is believed to be successful in about 60-80% of parturients&#xD;
      on the first attempt, but results from most studies are based on a small numbers of patients.&#xD;
      The reasons and predisposing factors for success and failure of different management&#xD;
      strategies, specifically EBP, therefore needs to be investigated and described. Large&#xD;
      observational studies on post-dural puncture headache in the Obstetric population are&#xD;
      singularly absent from the literature.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>January 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To examine the risk factors for failed epidural blood patch (EBP) following post-dural puncture headache</measure>
    <time_frame>24 h after application of Epidural blood patch</time_frame>
    <description>To examine the risk factors for failed epidural blood patch (EBP) following post-dural puncture headache, in the obstetric population. Failure would be defined as lack of reduction in pain intensity by at least 50% at 24 h after application of EBP, compared to worst pain before EBP or a visual analogue pain score (VAS pain) of &gt; 3 at 24 h.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>European practices in the management of Post Dural Puncture Headache (PDPH)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 h after application of Epidural blood patch</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of significant Post Dural Puncture Headache (PDPH) and treatment failure in different countries in Europe</measure>
    <time_frame>24 h after application of Epidural blood patch</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Timing of the procedure (after diagnosis of PDPH) and the volume of blood injected in relation to success or failure</measure>
    <time_frame>24 h after application of Epidural blood patch</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications and side effects of Epidural blood patch (EBP)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 h after application of Epidural blood patch</time_frame>
    <description>Complications include : Chronic headache and backache, neurological injuries, audiological or visual other chronic impairments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Variation in practices for management of Accidental Dural Puncture (ADP) in different European countries</measure>
    <time_frame>24 h after application of Epidural blood patch</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1110</enrollment>
  <condition>Post-Dural Puncture Headache</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All women ≥ 18 years old, who develop classical symptoms of post-dural puncture headache&#xD;
        after epidural anaesthesia for labour or for caesarean section.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All women ≥ 18 years old, who develop classical symptoms of post-dural puncture&#xD;
             headache after epidural anaesthesia for labour or for caesarean section.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-dural puncture headache following deliberate dural puncture with a spinal needle&#xD;
             in women where there was no observed accidental dural puncture with an epidural&#xD;
             needle.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anil Gupta, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karolinska Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 12, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 13, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 14, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 14, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 15, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Post-Dural Puncture Headache</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood Patch, epidural</keyword>
  <keyword>Obstetrics</keyword>
  <keyword>European Society of Anaesthesiology (ESA)</keyword>
  <keyword>epidemiology</keyword>
  <keyword>Accidental Dural Puncture (ADP)</keyword>
  <keyword>Anaesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>childbirth complication</keyword>
  <keyword>epidural analgesia</keyword>
  <keyword>postdural puncture headache</keyword>
  <keyword>prophylactic epidural blood patch</keyword>
  <keyword>epidural</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Post-Dural Puncture Headache</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Headache</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

