<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02362464</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>150076</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-C-0076</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02362464</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long-Term TARP Vaccination Using a Multi-Epitope TARP Peptide Autologous Dendritic Cell Vaccination in Previously Vaccinated Men on NCI 09-C-0139</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study of Long Term TARP Vaccination Using A Multi-Epitope TARP Peptide Autologous Dendritic Cell Vaccine in Previously Vaccinated Men on NCI 09-C-0139.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Few studies or literature are available about the long-term safety of repeated peptide&#xD;
      vaccinations in people over a period of time. Long-term vaccination may be needed to control&#xD;
      tumors. Researchers gave a group of men a series of vaccine injections over 2 years. Now they&#xD;
      want to give those same men the new version of the vaccine. They want to see if it produces&#xD;
      different types of immune responses and also ensure that repeated vaccinations are safe.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To find out the long-term safety of repeated TARP peptide vaccinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Men who took part in NCI protocol 09-C-0139.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with blood tests, scans, physical exam, medical history,&#xD;
           and an evaluation of how well they perform everyday activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will have apheresis. Blood will be removed with a needle from one arm. A&#xD;
           machine will separate the white blood cells. The blood, minus the white cells, will be&#xD;
           returned through a needle in the other arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will have 14 visits. At each visit, they will have a physical exam and&#xD;
           blood tests. They will discuss any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will get vaccine injections at weeks 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, and 24. The vaccine&#xD;
           will be made from the participants own cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will get a Vaccine Report Card to complete after receiving vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study lasts 96 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      TARP&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  T-cell receptor gamma alternate reading frame protein (TARP) is an amino acid protein&#xD;
           expressed by both normal and malignant prostate cancer tissue; 95% of prostate cancer&#xD;
           specimens are positive for TARP expression. TARP is highly expressed in prostate cancers&#xD;
           of all Gleason types, in primary as well as metastatic disease, and in hormone sensitive&#xD;
           and castrate resistant prostate cancer. Therefore, TARP is an ideal tumor antigen target&#xD;
           for a vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A prospective, randomized pilot study of 1st generation TARP Peptide vaccination (NCI&#xD;
           09-C- 0139) utilizing TARP WT 27-35 and EE29-37-9V peptides was conducted in HLAA*&#xD;
           0201positive men with stage D0 prostate cancer (PSA biochemical recurrence) and a PSA&#xD;
           doubling time (PSADT) of greater than or equal to 3 months and less than or equal to 15&#xD;
           months. TARP vaccination was found to be immunogenic, safe and well tolerated, with&#xD;
           adverse events limited to injection site reactions less than or equal to Grade 2. TARP&#xD;
           vaccination was also associated with a decreased slope log PSA compared to&#xD;
           pre-vaccination baseline in 72% of subjects reaching 24 weeks and 74% reaching 48 weeks&#xD;
           (p=0.0012 and p=0.0004 for overall changes in slope log PSA, respectively); TARP&#xD;
           vaccination also resulted in a 50% decrease in calculated tumor growth rate constant:&#xD;
           prevaccine g = 0.0042/day, post-vaccine g = 0.0021/day (p=0.003); TARP-specific IFN- &gt;=&#xD;
           ELISPOT responses were detected in the majority of subjects but did not correlate with&#xD;
           decreases in slope log (PSA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multi-Epitope (ME) TARP Vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The vaccine platform includes the original two 9-mer HLA-A*0201 binding TARP peptide&#xD;
           epitopes (WT27-35 and EE29-37-9V) utilized in NCI 09-C-0139 as well as an additional&#xD;
           five 20-mer TARP peptides overlapping by 10 amino acids for a total of 7 peptides that&#xD;
           span the amino acid sequence of the entire TARP protein.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The advantage of this multi-epitope TARP peptide vaccine platform is that the&#xD;
           overlapping epitopes cover the entire TARP protein, resulting in potential for induction&#xD;
           of a multi-valent anti-TARP response. In addition, these longer synthetic peptides&#xD;
           include TARP-specific MHC class II CD4+ T cell helper epitopes that will allow&#xD;
           generation of better CD8+ T cell responses with improved functional avidity and&#xD;
           longevity as well as humoral anti-TARP antibody responses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -To assess the long-term safety of repeated TARP peptide vaccination following the use of a&#xD;
      1st generation bivalent (09-C-0139) and a 2nd generation ME TARP peptide vaccine.&#xD;
      Specifically, to document if less than 10% of enrolled patients experience a vaccine-related&#xD;
      Grade 3 adverse event (local injection site reactions or systemic reactions).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility Criteria All Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Males greater than or equal to 18 years of age with histologically confirmed&#xD;
           adenocarcinoma of the prostate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Prior enrollment in NCI protocol 09-C-0139 with receipt of at least 5 doses of TARP&#xD;
           peptide vaccine (i.e. completion of primary vaccination series).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Performance Status: ECOG 0-1 and life expectancy greater than or equal to 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 10.0 gm/dL, WBC greater than or equal to 2,500/mm3,&#xD;
           ALC greater than or equal to 500/ mm3, ANC greater than or equal to 1,000/mm3, platelet&#xD;
&#xD;
      count greater than or equal to 100,000/mm3, and PT/PTT less than or equal to 1.5X ULN unless&#xD;
      receiving clinically indicated anticoagulant therapy; SGPT/SGOT less than or equal to 2.5X&#xD;
      ULN, total bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5X ULN; creatinine less than or equal to 1.5X&#xD;
      ULN and estimated GFR (eGFR) greater than or equal to 60 ml/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Hepatitis B and C negative (unless the result is consistent with prior vaccination or&#xD;
           prior infection with full recovery); HIV negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  No use of investigational agents within 4 weeks of study enrollment or use of&#xD;
           immunosuppressive or immunomodulating agents within 8 weeks of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Standard of care medical management of current prostate cancer disease status by the&#xD;
           patient s local oncologist e.g. androgen deprivation therapy is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Must be able/willing to adhere to protocol requirements and vaccination timeline.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion Criteria All Patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with active infection or other significant or uncontrolled medical illness.&#xD;
           Patients with a remote history of asthma or active mild asthma may participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients on immunosuppressive therapy including systemic corticosteroid therapy for any&#xD;
           reason. Patients receiving inhaled or topical corticosteroids may participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator, have significant medical or&#xD;
           psychosocial problems that warrant exclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Open label, prospective, non-randomized, long-term follow-up pilot study of 96 weeks to&#xD;
           assess the long-term safety of repeated TARP vaccination in patients that have already&#xD;
           received the first generation TARP vaccine. Sample size: N equals 40 maximum.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All patients will undergo an 18L apheresis for mononuclear cell collection at Week 0.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All patients will receive a total of 6 doses of autologous ME TARP peptide DC vaccine:&#xD;
           20&#xD;
&#xD;
      x106 viable cells/dose) delivered intradermally at Weeks 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, and 24.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 12, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the long-term safety of repeated TARP peptide vaccination following the use of a 1st generation bivalent (09-C-0139) and a 2nd generation ME TARP peptide vaccine.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after week 24 vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>The quantity of AEs each subject experiences at least possibly related to the vaccine treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>assess and compare the change in slope log PSA from pre-study baseline (-12 months to entry on the current study) to the changein slope log PSA at weeks 3-24 and 3-48 post ME TARP vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>weeks 3-24 and 3-48 post ME TARP vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>change in slope log PSA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>compare the change in slope log PSA versus the same change in slope log PSA parameters following 1st generation TARP vaccination on protocol 09-C-0139</measure>
    <time_frame>at weeks 3-24 and 3-48 following ME TARP vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>change in slope log PSA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>assess reactivity to WT27-35 and EE29-37-9V TARP peptides</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24 and Week 48 following immunization with the 2nd generation ME TARP</time_frame>
    <description>measure of reactivity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>compare TARP WT27-35 and EE29-37-9V TARP peptide IFN-? ELISPOT reactivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 24 and 48 following ME TARP vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>characteristics of WT27-35 and EE29-37-9V TARP peptide IFN-gamma ELISPOT reactivity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">14</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostatic Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Neoplasms of Prostate</condition>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Cancer Of Prostate</condition>
  <condition>Stage D0 Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>intradermally given vaccine given at weeks 3, 6, 9, 12, 15 and 24.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ME TARP vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>dose of 20 x 10^6 viable cells multiepitope TARP dendritic cell vaccine given intradermally at weeks 3, 6, 9, 12, 15 and 24.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males greater than or equal to 18 years of age with histologically confirmed&#xD;
             adenocarcinoma of the prostate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior enrollment in NCI protocol 09-C-0139 with receipt of at least 5 doses of TARP&#xD;
             peptide vaccine (i.e. completion of primary vaccination series).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance Status: ECOG 0-1, life expectancy of greater than or equal to 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 10.0 gm/dL, WBC greater than or equal to&#xD;
             2,500/mm3, ALC greater than or equal to 500/mm3, ANC greater than or equal to&#xD;
             1,000/mm3, platelet count greater than or equal to 100,000/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PT/PTT less than or equal to 1.5X ULN unless receiving clinically indicated&#xD;
             anticoagulant therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SGOT/SGPT less than or equal to 2.5X ULN, total bilirubin less than or equal to 1.5X&#xD;
             ULN, Cr less than or equal to 1.5X ULN, estimated GFR (eGFR) greater than or equal to&#xD;
             60 ml/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatitis B and C negative, unless the result is consistent with prior vaccination or&#xD;
             prior infection with full recovery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV negative&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No use of investigational agents within 4 weeks of study enrollment or use of&#xD;
             immunosuppressive or immunomodulating agents (including IVIG) within 8 weeks of study&#xD;
             entry. Note: Use of topical, inhaled and intranasal steroid therapy is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Greater than or equal to 6 weeks since the receipt of chemotherapy or radiation&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Standard of care medical management of current prostate cancer disease status by the&#xD;
             patient s local oncologist, e.g. androgen deprivation therapy is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand and provide Informed Consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able and willing to adhere to protocol requirements, visits and vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
        timeline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a second malignancy requiring active treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an active infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on immunosuppressive therapy including:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Systemic corticosteroid therapy for any reason. Patients receiving inhaled,&#xD;
             intranasal or topical corticosteroids may participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other significant or uncontrolled medical illness. Patients with a remote history of&#xD;
             or active mild asthma may participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who, in the opinion of the Principal Investigator, have significant medical&#xD;
             or psychosocial problems that warrant exclusion including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other serious non-malignancy-associated medical conditions that may be expected&#xD;
                  to limit life expectancy to less than 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any condition- medical, psychiatric or otherwise, that would preclude informed&#xD;
                  consent, consistent follow-up or compliance with any aspect of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hoyoung M Maeng, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2015-C-0076.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 31, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 12, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 13, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Multi-epitope</keyword>
  <keyword>Tarp Peptide</keyword>
  <keyword>Dendritic Cell Vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>D0 Prostate Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

