<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01036711</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999902372</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>02-DA-N372</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01036711</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Nicotine on Cognitive Task Performance and Brain Activity as Measured by fMRI</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Nicotine on Cognitive Task Performance and Brain Activity as Measured by fMRI</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Many cigarette smokers claim that smoking improves their ability to think and concentrate,&#xD;
      and have reported problems in thinking and concentration after quitting smoking. Some&#xD;
      research has indicated that nicotine can enhance certain aspects of attention and memory in&#xD;
      humans. However, more research is needed to determine how nicotine affects different elements&#xD;
      of the brain s ability to think, pay attention, respond to rewards, and make decisions.&#xD;
      Researchers are interested in using functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) to study the&#xD;
      effects of nicotine on brain function and activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To determine the effects of nicotine on attentional and other thinking processes, including&#xD;
      reward-seeking behavior.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Individuals between 18 and 50 years of age who are either current smokers (10 or more&#xD;
      cigarettes per day for at least 1 year) or nonsmokers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study has four experiments. Each experiment requires two MRI scanning sessions and a&#xD;
           training session. Participant can do one or all of the experiments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will receive training on the types of computerized tests that will be given&#xD;
           during the active portion of the study. Participants will also fill out questionnaires&#xD;
           on nicotine use and other alcohol and drug use, and provide breath and urine samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  During the test sessions, participants will have fMRI scanning while performing up to&#xD;
           four different sets of tasks that test attention, memory, concentration, reward-seeking&#xD;
           behavior, and decision making. Smokers will wear a nicotine patch or placebo patch&#xD;
           during the test sessions, but will not be told which patch they are receiving. The order&#xD;
           of these sessions will be different for individual participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will provide blood and urine samples throughout the research study for&#xD;
           evaluation purposes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experiments in this protocol employ fMRI to address the interactions of nicotine with such&#xD;
      cognitive processes as working memory, attention, and the executive functions of inhibitory&#xD;
      control, conceptual reasoning and attention switching, in addition to reward and temporal&#xD;
      error reward processing. The effects of nicotine on these cognitive processes will also be&#xD;
      assessed outside the MRI scanner. Assessments of genetic variants will be done with the&#xD;
      hypothesis that these will account for some inter-individual differences in the brain imaging&#xD;
      data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population will consist of adult (18-50 y.o.) non-treatment seeking smokers and age&#xD;
      and gender matched non-smoking control subjects. The control subjects will provide normative&#xD;
      data on cognitive task performance and corresponding neural activation, as well as providing&#xD;
      control for any time effects (e.g. practice effect on repeated cognitive task performance).&#xD;
      Smokers will smoke at least 10 cigarettes per day for a period of 1 year. Both smokers and&#xD;
      controls will be suitable for fMRI scanning. Subjects may not be dependent on any other drug&#xD;
      except nicotine or caffeine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a within subjects design, experienced smokers will perform cognitive tasks involving&#xD;
      memory encoding and consolidation, selective/divided and sustained attention, as well as&#xD;
      reward and temporal error reward processing two hours following single blind application of a&#xD;
      nicotine patch (21 mg/24 hr) and during a separate session on a different day, following&#xD;
      application of a placebo patch. The tasks will be performed during fMRI scanning. Not all of&#xD;
      the tasks will be done at the same time, rather, groups of tasks are run in series as task&#xD;
      sets: Task set A: Selective/divided attention task and Intention/ attention task; Task set B:&#xD;
      The SARAT (Spatial Attentional Resource Allocation task) which is designed to enable&#xD;
      dissociation of top-down and stimulus driven processes of visuospatial selective attention as&#xD;
      well as the CEFER task which is a measure of central executive function task which isolates&#xD;
      the allocation of attentional resources within working memory; Task set C: Monetary Incentive&#xD;
      Delay and Temporal Delay Error processing tasks; Task set D: Affective Forecasting and Loss&#xD;
      Aversion task. Control subjects will do the tasks during scanning without a patch. Blood will&#xD;
      be drawn from all participants for analysis of genetic variants and for smokers, plasma&#xD;
      nicotine and cotinine will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will determine the acute effects of nicotine on attentional and other cognitive mechanisms&#xD;
      and how emotional processes such as the anticipation and receipt of reward affects the&#xD;
      neuronal activation properties of acute nicotine administration in experienced smokers. In&#xD;
      addition, we will determine whether genetic polymorphisms predict BOLD response during&#xD;
      cognitive tasks pertinent to nicotine addiction. Plasma nicotine and cotinine will be&#xD;
      included as a factor in analyses of nicotine-induced effects on fMRI signal to take account&#xD;
      of potentially large inter-individual variability in circulating nicotine concentrations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 17, 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date>November 26, 2012</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">249</enrollment>
  <condition>Nicotine Dependence</condition>
  <condition>Drug Abuse</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Subjects must be between the ages of 18-50.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subject must be in good health based on history and physical exams.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subjects must be right-handed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Smoking subjects must demonstrate that they are experienced users based upon&#xD;
                  urine cotinine levels of at least 100ng/ml, and must smoke a minimum of 10&#xD;
                  cigarettes/day with duration of use of at least 1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Subjects may be users of alcohol and/or marijuana but may not meet criteria for&#xD;
                  dependence on either substance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are pregnant or breast feeding. Urine pregnancy tests will be performed on all female&#xD;
             volunteers of child-bearing potential before each experimental session.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have implanted metallic devices (cardiac pacemaker or neurostimulator, some artificial&#xD;
             joints, metal pins, surgical clips or other implanted metal parts) or claustrophobia&#xD;
             rendering them unable to undergo fMRI scanning.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have major medical illnesses to include, but not limited to, hypertension,&#xD;
             cardiovascular disease, asthma, diabetes, peripheral vascular diseases,&#xD;
             coagulopathies, syncope, history of superficial or deep vein thrombosis, HIV, or other&#xD;
             clinically significant infectious diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have current major psychiatric disorders to include, but not limited to, mood,&#xD;
             anxiety, psychotic disorders, or substance-induced psychiatric disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Have neurological illnesses to including, but not limited to, seizure disorders,&#xD;
             migraine, multiple sclerosis, movement disorders, or history of head trauma, CVA, CNS&#xD;
             tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have significant alcohol or other drug use, other than nicotine dependence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have gros structural abnormalities onT1 weighted images.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Have cognitive impairment as assessed by screening WASI vocabulary subtest below 48,&#xD;
             corresponding to full IQ of 85 (in that case on screening, a full WASI will be done to&#xD;
             verify IQ of 85 or above). Justification: Cognitive impairment and learning&#xD;
             disabilities are associated with alterations in brain regions used to accomplish&#xD;
             tasks, and, therefore, may introduce significant variably into the data.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Are engaged in or actively seeking smoking cessation treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elliot Stein, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute on Drug Abuse, Biomedical Research Center (BRC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aceto MD, Martin BR. Central actions of nicotine. Med Res Rev. 1982 Jan-Mar;2(1):43-62. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>6125634</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Andrews B, Brewin CR, Ochera J, Morton J, Bekerian DA, Davies GM, Mollon P. The timing, triggers and qualities of recovered memories in therapy. Br J Clin Psychol. 2000 Mar;39(1):11-26.</citation>
    <PMID>10789025</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arinami T, Gao M, Hamaguchi H, Toru M. A functional polymorphism in the promoter region of the dopamine D2 receptor gene is associated with schizophrenia. Hum Mol Genet. 1997 Apr;6(4):577-82.</citation>
    <PMID>9097961</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 26, 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 18, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 18, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 21, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 4, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 4, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Attention</keyword>
  <keyword>Working Memory</keyword>
  <keyword>Central Executive Processes</keyword>
  <keyword>Response Preparation</keyword>
  <keyword>Cigarettes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tobacco Use Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

