<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01087346</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100076</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-HG-0076</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01087346</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mothers' Thoughts About Kids and Eating</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mothers' Thoughts About What Their Children Eat</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Summary:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A few studies have explored the effects of providing parents with health information&#xD;
           about their children. However, more information is needed about the relationship between&#xD;
           awareness of health information and changes in behavior. This study will investigate the&#xD;
           impact of health information on choices that parents make about food for their children.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mothers and fathers with a biological child between the ages of 3-7 years old may be&#xD;
           eligible for this study. Participants are recruited from the Washington, DC metropolitan&#xD;
           area.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In this study, before visiting the research center, participants will answer online&#xD;
           questionnaires about their children's health and eating habits and their own health and&#xD;
           eating habits.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the research center, participants will use a virtual reality model of a buffet to&#xD;
           make food choices for their children. Participants will be introduced to the&#xD;
           computer-based virtual buffet scenario as a training session to prepare for using the&#xD;
           buffet during the experimental context. While in the virtual environment, participants&#xD;
           wear a virtual reality helmet that allows them to see the virtual buffet scenario.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the training session, participants will watch an interactive computer presentation&#xD;
           about a health topic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will then visit the virtual buffet scenario again for the formal session,&#xD;
           and will choose a virtual lunch meal for their child as before.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the end of their visit, participants will complete post-test questionnaires about&#xD;
           their experiences during the experiment and other research-related information.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be asked to complete a follow-up questionnaire online a week after&#xD;
           their visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The total time for the study visit is approximately 90 minutes. The participants&#xD;
           children will not be asked to take part in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Men and Women at least 18 years of age who have a biological child between the ages of 3&#xD;
      and 7 who has no major diet-related health conditions, developmental delays, or disabilities.&#xD;
      You may not take part in the study if you have a history of seizures and/or are pregnant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Purpose&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will investigate the impact of health information on choices that parents make&#xD;
      about food for their children. Participants will use a virtual reality model of a buffet to&#xD;
      make food choices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mothers and fathers with a biological child between the ages of 3-7 years old may be eligible&#xD;
      for this study. Participants are recruited from the Washington, DC metropolitan area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study participants will complete THREE sets of surveys and one task. Participants will&#xD;
      complete a web-based survey before coming in for a study appointment. When participants&#xD;
      arrive for their appointment, they will watch an interactive presentation on health&#xD;
      information. Next, participants will interact in a virtual reality environment and will be&#xD;
      asked to select virtual lunch for their child from a buffet. While in the virtual&#xD;
      environment, a participant wears a head-mounted virtual reality headset that allows him/her&#xD;
      to see elements of the environment. Participants will complete an additional computer-based&#xD;
      survey. Finally, participants will be asked to complete an online questionnaire a week&#xD;
      following their visit. The total time for the study visit is approximately 90 minutes. The&#xD;
      participants children will not be asked to take part in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Detailed Description&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will investigate issues around the impact of health information on choices that&#xD;
      parents make about food for their children. Participants will perform tasks that include&#xD;
      completing computer-based surveys, watching an interactive computer-based presentation about&#xD;
      health information, participating in a virtual reality model by selecting virtual lunch for&#xD;
      their children from a buffet, and completing a computed-based exit survey. As part of the&#xD;
      study, participants will wear a virtual reality helmet and be immersed in a buffet where they&#xD;
      will select virtual lunch for their child.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this study, we are only recruiting men and women that have a biological child between the&#xD;
      ages of 3-7 years old. You may not take part in the study if you have a history of seizures&#xD;
      and/or are pregnant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 19, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 12, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 12, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of calories selected for participant's index child in a virtual buffet food selection task</measure>
    <time_frame>1 visit</time_frame>
    <description>The number of calories selected for participant's index child in a virtual buffet food selection task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1148</enrollment>
  <condition>Overweight</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Information about child health</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Family Environment Information</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Information about family environment factors in children's obesity risk</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gene times Family Environment Information</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Information about interactions between genetic and family environment factors in children's obesity risk</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Genetic Information</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Information about genetic factors in child obesity risk</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Reading Information</intervention_name>
    <description>Reading information about risk factors for obesity among children</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Family Environment Information</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Gene times Family Environment Information</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Genetic Information</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA :&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All participants will be healthy adult women over the age of 18 (though in practice the age&#xD;
        range is likely to be constrained naturally by the required age of the index child).&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. having a self-reported body mass index of greater than or equal to 25&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. having some amount of familiarity with their family health history&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. having a biological child between the ages of 4 and 5 inclusive, who lives in the same&#xD;
             household at least 1 day out of the past 30 days, and who has no major food allergies&#xD;
             or diet-related health conditions, developmental delays, or disabilities&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. having the ability to read and write in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. being able to come to the NIH Clinical Center for one visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. having a vestibular or seizure disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. having a high propensity for motion sickness;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. known pregnancy; (4) uncorrected low vision or hearing;&#xD;
&#xD;
        (5) inability to complete tasks in the virtual environment;&#xD;
&#xD;
        (6) past or current history of eating disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
        (7) NHGRI employees&#xD;
&#xD;
        Study 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All participants will be healthy adults over the age of 18 (though in practice the age&#xD;
        range is likely to be constrained naturally by the required age of the index child).&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. having a self-perception of being overweight&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. having a biological child between the ages of 3 and 7&#xD;
&#xD;
             inclusive (of any weight), who has no food allergies to buffet items (e.g., dairy,&#xD;
             wheat, fruit) or diet-related health conditions, developmental delays, or disabilities&#xD;
             that would severely limit food&#xD;
&#xD;
             choices on the virtual buffet and who does not have a vegan or gluten-free diet&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. self-reporting that the parent is responsible for feeding to the child to criterion&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. having the ability to read and write in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. being able to come to the NIH Clinical Center for one visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. having a vestibular or seizure disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. having a high propensity for motion sickness&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. known pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. uncorrected low vision or hearing&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. inability to complete tasks in the virtual environment&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. past or current history of eating disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. NHGRI employees&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. having another household member or another biological parent of their index child&#xD;
             having participated in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. women who report being pregnant&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan Persky, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2010-HG-0076.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 21, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 13, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 13, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 16, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Risk Perception</keyword>
  <keyword>Obesity Risk</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>HV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

