<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01087294</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100054</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-C-0054</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01087294</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Administration of Anti-CD19-chimeric-antigen-receptor-transduced T Cells From the Original Transplant Donor to Patients With Recurrent or Persistent B-cell Malignancies After Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Administration of Anti-CD19-Chimeric-Antigen-Receptor-Transduced T Cells From the Original Transplant Donor to Patients With Recurrent or Persistent B-Cell Malignancies After Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (alloHSCT) is a procedure that&#xD;
           transplants bone marrow cells (stem cells) from a matching donor into a recipient in&#xD;
           order to allow the donor stem cells to produce cells that will attack the recipient s&#xD;
           cancer cells. AlloHSCT is performed when chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or radiation&#xD;
           therapy do not adequately control cancer growth. However, cancers that are not&#xD;
           controlled by alloHSCT frequently become resistant to other standard treatment options.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The outcomes of alloHSCT might be improved if certain kinds of white blood cells (T&#xD;
           cells) could be manipulated so that they generate a more potent effect against the&#xD;
           cancer cells. This effect can be augmented by genetically engineering donor T cells to&#xD;
           specifically recognize cancerous cells in order to attack them. For this purpose,&#xD;
           researchers are studying a specific kind of genetically engineered T cell known as the&#xD;
           anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cell. More research is needed to determine if this T cell&#xD;
           will be an effective treatment for certain kinds of B cell cancer (such as non-Hodgkin s&#xD;
           lymphoma and chronic lymphocytic leukemia) that has not been controlled with alloHSCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To assess the safety and effectiveness of administering allogeneic anti-CD19-CAR-transduced&#xD;
      T cells to patients with B-cell cancer that has not responded to alloHSCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals between 18 and 75 years of age who have received allogeneic hematopoietic&#xD;
           stem cell transplantation for a B cell cancer, but whose cancer has either not responded&#xD;
           to or recurred after the transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recipients must have the same stem cell donor from their previous procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Before the start of the study, all participants will be screened with a medical history&#xD;
           and blood tests. Recipients will have tumor imaging scans, additional blood tests, and&#xD;
           other tests as directed by the study doctors.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Donor participants will undergo apheresis to provide white blood cells for researchers&#xD;
           to use in the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recipients will have dose escalation to determine the most effective yet safe dose of&#xD;
           anti-CD19 T cells. There will be six dose levels of anti-CD19 T cells. The first&#xD;
           patients enrolled will have the smallest dose, and the dose will be increased when a&#xD;
           level has been determined to be safe. .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recipients will be hospitalized for at least 9 days after receiving the cell infusion,&#xD;
           and will need to come to clinic for follow-up visits 2, 4, 8, and 12 weeks after the&#xD;
           infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Additional scans and frequent blood tests will be required for the first 3 months after&#xD;
           the infusion, followed by less frequent visits over time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Recipients will be followed for a maximum of 15 years after receiving the infusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many patients with advanced B-cell malignancies that cannot be cured by chemotherapy and&#xD;
      monoclonal antibodies have prolonged relapse-free survival after allogeneic hematopoietic&#xD;
      stem cell transplantation (alloHSCT); however, a substantial fraction of patients with B-cell&#xD;
      malignancies relapse following alloHSCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first therapeutic maneuver attempted when patients without graft-versus-host disease&#xD;
      (GVHD) relapse after alloHSCT is usually withdrawal of immunosuppressive drugs. If a&#xD;
      remission does not occur after withdrawal of immunosuppression, patients are often treated&#xD;
      with lymphocyte -DCI. Withdrawal of immunosuppression and DCI can lead to complete remissions&#xD;
      in patients with B-cell malignancies that relapse after alloHSCT. Unfortunately, a&#xD;
      substantial fraction of patients do not enter a complete remission after withdrawal of&#xD;
      immunosuppression followed by DCI, and these therapies are often complicated by GVHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The outcomes of alloHSCT might be improved if T cells could be manipulated so that they&#xD;
      generate a more potent graft-versus-malignancy (GVM) effect than unmanipulated T cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We hypothesize that the GVM effect against B-cell malignancies can be augmented by&#xD;
      genetically engineering donor T cells to express receptors that specifically recognize&#xD;
      antigens expressed by malignant B cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chimeric antigen receptors (CARs) consist of an antigen recognition moiety combined with&#xD;
      T-cell signaling domains. CARs are capable of activating T cells in an antigen-specific&#xD;
      manner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expression of the CD19 antigen is limited to B cells and perhaps follicular dendritic cells.&#xD;
      Most malignant B cells express CD19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have constructed a retroviral vector encoding an anti-CD19 CAR. Large numbers of T cells&#xD;
      that have been transduced with this retroviral vector can be generated in vitro for clinical&#xD;
      adoptive T cell therapy. These anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cells specifically recognize a&#xD;
      variety of CD19+ target cells and kill primary chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) cells in&#xD;
      vitro.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the safety of administering allogeneic anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cells to patients&#xD;
      with B-cell malignancies that are persistent or relapsed after alloHSCT. The allogeneic&#xD;
      anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cells will be derived from the original allogeneic transplant&#xD;
      donor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients with any CD19-expressing malignancy that is persistent or recurrent following&#xD;
      successful engraftment after HLA-identical or &gt;=9/10 matched sibling, 1-antigen mismatched&#xD;
      sibling, or 9/10-matched unrelated donor (URD) alloHSCT and withdrawal of immunosuppression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The same donor that provided cells for the alloHSCT must be willing and able to undergo&#xD;
      leukapheresis so that cells can be obtained to prepare the anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The recipient must have at most grade I acute GVHD or chronic GVHD with no organ site with a&#xD;
      score exceeding 1, except for the skin, for which a score of 1 or 2 will be allowable. The&#xD;
      recipient must not have received systemic immunosuppressive drugs given for graft versus host&#xD;
      disease for at least 28 days at the time of study enrollment. Patients must be on a dose of&#xD;
      corticosteroids of an equivalent of 5 mg/day or less of prednisone. Corticosteroid creams,&#xD;
      ointments, and eye drops are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The alloHSCT donor will undergo leukapheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo apheresis to obtain peripheral blood mononuclear cells. These cells&#xD;
      will be processed to produce anti-CD19 CAR stem memory T cells (anti-CD19 CAR Tscm). This&#xD;
      process involves sorting the cells and then culturing the cells in vitro for 9 days. During&#xD;
      the 9-day culture period, the cells will be transduced with gammaretroviruses encoding the&#xD;
      FMC63-28Z.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CAR recipients will be monitored for development of acute treatment-related toxicities for at&#xD;
      least 9 days after cell infusion as inpatients. Dose-limiting toxicities (DLTs) will include&#xD;
      severe acute GVHD and Grade 4 toxicities not associated with GVHD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A maximum of 126 evaluable patients (donors plus recipients) will be treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of safety is a primary objective of this clinical trial. Safety will be defined as&#xD;
      a lack of severe acute post-infusional toxicities and an incidence of GVHD that is not higher&#xD;
      than historical rates of GVHD occurring after standard DCI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T-cell persistence in the peripheral blood will be measured at&#xD;
      multiple time points from 1 week to 1 year after anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cell infusion by&#xD;
      flow cytometry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess for an anti-malignancy effect of the infused cells, patients will be staged using&#xD;
      standard staging systems.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 4, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the safety of allogeneic anti-CD19 CAR</measure>
    <time_frame>4-5 weeks after first dose</time_frame>
    <description>List of adverse event frequency</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To measure the persistence of anti-CD19-CAR- transduced T cells in the blood of patients after infusion</measure>
    <time_frame>Until the patient goes off-study for malignancy response assessment.</time_frame>
    <description>Amount of anti-CD19-CAR- transduced T cells in the blood of patients after infusion.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine if administering anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cells from the original transplant donor can cause regression of B-cell malignancies that are relapsed or persistent after alloHSCT</measure>
    <time_frame>at progression</time_frame>
    <description>Median amount of time subject survives without disease progression after treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Leukemia, B-cell</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma, Hodgkins</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma, Non-hodgkins</condition>
  <condition>Lymphoma, B-Cell</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1A/T cell Arm (closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of CAR+ T cells based on the patients actual body-weight</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1B/T memory stem cell arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose Escalation with 5 dose levels of CAR+ T memory cells based on the patients actual body-weight</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2/Donor arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Leukapheresis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Allogeneic stem cell transplant</intervention_name>
    <description>Allogeneic stem cell transplant</description>
    <arm_group_label>1A/T cell Arm (closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>1B/T memory stem cell arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anti-CD19-chimeric-antigen-receptor-transduced T cells</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients receive T cells genetically engineered to express an anti-CD19 CAR. The cells are cultured in media containing IL-21, IL-7, and TWS119.&#xD;
TWS119 is a glycogen synthase 3 inhibitor</description>
    <arm_group_label>1A/T cell Arm (closed)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>1B/T memory stem cell arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Leukapheresis</intervention_name>
    <description>Donors will undergo leukapheresis</description>
    <arm_group_label>2/Donor arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria: Recipient&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Recipients (patients with B-cell malignancy) must have received an HLA-identical or&#xD;
             9/10 matched sibling allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplant, a 1-antigen&#xD;
             mismatched related transplant, or a greater than or equal to 9/10-matched unrelated&#xD;
             donor (URD) alloHSCT for any CD19+ B-cell malignancy. Patients with any CD19+ B-cell&#xD;
             malignancy that is persistent or relapsed after all of the following interventions are&#xD;
             eligible:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Donor T cell engraftment after alloHSCT (&gt;50% donor chimerism of the T cell&#xD;
                  compartment and a peripheral blood T cell number from the NIH, CC clinical lab of&#xD;
                  at least 50 CD3+ cells/uL).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. A trial of withdrawal of immunosuppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Exception: Prior (DCI) DLI is not an eligibility requirement for patients with ALL,&#xD;
             Burkitt lyphoma, ALL like high-grade lymphomas, or diffuse large B-cell lymphoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
             At least 28 days weeks must have elapsed since the latest trial of withdraw of&#xD;
             immunosuppression or DLI until the patient can be deemed to have persistent disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. CD19 expression must be detected on the majority of the malignant cells by&#xD;
             immunohistochemistry or by flow cytometry in the Laboratory of Pathology, CCR, NCI,&#xD;
             NIH. Definition of which cells are malignant must be determined for each patient by&#xD;
             the Laboratory of Pathology using techniques to demonstrate monoclonality such as&#xD;
             kappa/lambda restriction (other techniques can be used to determine monoclonality at&#xD;
             the discretion of the Laboratory of Pathology). The choice of whether to use flow&#xD;
             cytometry or immuohistochemistry will be determined by what is the most easily&#xD;
             available tissue sample in each patient. Immunohistochemistry will be used for lymph&#xD;
             node biopsies and bone marrow biopsies. Flow cytometry will be used for peripheral&#xD;
             blood, fine needle aspirate, and bone marrow aspirate samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must be 18-75 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Performance status: ECOG less than or equal to 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Either no evidence of GVHD or minimal clinical evidence of acute GVHD and chronic GVHD&#xD;
             while off of systemic immunosuppressive therapy for at least 28 days. Minimal clinical&#xD;
             evidence of acute GVHD is defined as grade 0 to I acute GVHD. Minimal evidence of&#xD;
             chronic GVHD is defined as chronic GVHD with no organ site with a score exceeding 1,&#xD;
             except for the skin, for which a score of 1 or 2 will be allowable (as defined by the&#xD;
             2005 NIH consensus project) or no chronic GVHD. Subjects with disease that is&#xD;
             controlled to stage I acute GVHD or chronic GVHD meeting the above criteria with local&#xD;
             therapy only, e.g., topical cutaneous steroids, will be eligible for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Prior Therapy: Therapy with monoclonal antibodies and/or chemotherapy must be stopped&#xD;
             at least 7 days prior to anti-CD19 CAR-transduced T cell infusion, and recovery of&#xD;
             treatment-associated toxicity to less than or equal to grade 2 is required prior to&#xD;
             infusion of cells. For patients that have received prior DLI, the last dose must be at&#xD;
             least 28 days prior to anti-CD19 CAR-transduced T cell administration. Note that&#xD;
             patients can be enrolled on this study at any time after or during therapy, but at&#xD;
             least 14 days must elapse from the time of prior monoclonal antibody administration or&#xD;
             chemotherapy until anti-CD19 CAR-transduced T cells are infused, and at least 28 days&#xD;
             must elapse from the time of withdraw of immunosuppression, or DLI, or other&#xD;
             immunomodulatory therapies such as lenalidomide until anti-CD19 CAR-transduced T cells&#xD;
             are infused. Systemic immunosuppression given for graft versus host disease must be&#xD;
             stopped at least 28 days prior to protocol entry. There is no time restriction in&#xD;
             regard to prior intrathecal chemotherapy provided there is complete recovery from any&#xD;
             acute toxic effects of such.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Recipients of unrelated donor transplants from a National Marrow Donor Program (NMDP)&#xD;
             Center must sign a release of information form to authorize NMDP transfer of&#xD;
             information to the NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Previous allogeneic donor must be willing and available to donate again.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients of childbearing or child-fathering potential must be willing use an effective&#xD;
             method of contraception while being treated on this study and for 4 months after the&#xD;
             last cell infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Normal left ventricular function as evaluated by echocardiograph within 4 weeks of&#xD;
             anti- CD19-CAR-transduced T cell infusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria: Donor&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Donors greater than or equal to 18 years of age must be the same individual whose&#xD;
             cells were used as the source for the patient s original stem cell transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Adequate venous access for peripheral leukapheresis, or consent to use a temporary&#xD;
             central venous catheter for leukapheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Donors must be HIV negative, hepatitis B surface antigen negative, and hepatitis C&#xD;
             antibody negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Donor selection will be in accordance with NIH/CC Department of Transfusion Medicine&#xD;
             (DTM) criteria and, in the case of an unrelated donor from a Transplant Center, the&#xD;
             National Marrow Donor Program (NMDP) standards. When a potentially eligible recipient&#xD;
             of an unrelated donor product from an NMDP Center is identified, the recipient will&#xD;
             complete an NMDP search transfer request to allow NIH NMDP staff to contact the NMDP&#xD;
             Coordinating Center, who will, in turn, contact the donor s prior Donor Center. The&#xD;
             NMDP Policy for Subsequent Donation Requests will be followed and the appropriate&#xD;
             forms (Subsequent Donation Request form) and Therapeutic T Cell Collection&#xD;
             Prescription will be submitted as required.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Recipients&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Active infection that is not responding to antimicrobial therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Sero positive for HIV antibody. (The experimental treatment being evaluated in this&#xD;
             protocol depends on an intact immune system. Patients who are HIV seropositive can&#xD;
             have decreased immune -competence and thus are less responsive to the experimental&#xD;
             treatment and more susceptible to its toxicities.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Sero positive for hepatitis B antigen, positive hepatitis B tests can be further&#xD;
             evaluated by confirmatory tests (HBV DNA), and if confirmatory tests are negative, the&#xD;
             patient can be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Sero positive for hepatitis C antibody unless antigen negative. If hepatitis C&#xD;
             antibody test is positive, then patients must be tested for the presence of RNA by&#xD;
             RT-PCR and be HCV RNA negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Active psychiatric disorder which may compromise compliance with the treatment&#xD;
             protocol, or which does not allow for appropriate informed consent (as determined by&#xD;
             Principal Investigator and/or his designee).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant or lactating. The effects of the immunosuppressive medications that could be&#xD;
             required to treat GHVD are likely to be harmful to a fetus. The effects upon breast&#xD;
             milk are also unknown and may be harmful to an infant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Serum total bilirubin &gt; 2.5 mg/dl, serum ALT and AST values greater than or equal to&#xD;
             2.5 times the upper limit of normal based on age-specific normal values. If the&#xD;
             abnormal liver function is attributable to liver involvement by malignancy, patients&#xD;
             may be eligible with serum total bilirubin up to 5.0 mg/dl, and serum ALT and AST&#xD;
             values up to 5.0 times the upper limit of normal, provided the patient has no evidence&#xD;
             of impending hepatic failure (encephalopathy or prothrombin time &gt;2 times the upper&#xD;
             limit of normal).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Serum creatinine greater than 1.6 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Absolute neutrophil count of less than 1000 cells/microL unless low neutrophil count&#xD;
             is thought to be due to malignancy in the bone marrow and malignancy is documented in&#xD;
             the bone marrow.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Active cerebrospinal fluid involvement with malignancy or brain metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Platelet count less than 30,000/microL unless low platelet count is thought to be due&#xD;
             to malignancy in the bone marrow and malignancy is documented in the bone marrow.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Hemoglobin less than 8.0 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Receiving systemic corticosteroids including prednisone, dexamethasone or any other&#xD;
             corticosteroid at doses of higher than 5 mg/day of prednisone within 28 days prior to&#xD;
             anti-CD19-CAR-transduced T cell administration. Corticosteroid creams, ointments, and&#xD;
             eye drops are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Blood blast percentage higher than 5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Donors&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of psychiatric disorder which may compromise compliance with this protocol or&#xD;
             which does not allow for appropriate informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of hypertension that is not controlled by medication, stroke, or severe heart&#xD;
             disease (donors with symptomatic angina will be excluded). Donors with a history of&#xD;
             coronary artery bypass grafting or angioplasty who are symptom free will receive a&#xD;
             cardiology evaluation and be considered on a case-by-case basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Donors must not be pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Anemia (Hb &lt; 11 gm/dl) or thrombocytopenia (platelets &lt; 100,000 per microL). However,&#xD;
             potential donors with Hb levels &lt; 11 gm/dl that is due to iron deficiency will be&#xD;
             eligible as long as the donor is initiated on iron replacement therapy. The NIH&#xD;
             Clinical Center, Department of Transfusion Medicine/NMDP physicians will determine the&#xD;
             appropriateness of individuals as donors.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James N Kochenderfer, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jo H Hurtt, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 858-7012</phone>
    <email>jo.hurtt@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>James N Kochenderfer, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 760-6062</phone>
    <email>kochendj@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>(888) NCI-1937</phone>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Referral Line NCI Experimental Transplantation and Immunology Branch</last_name>
      <phone>(301) 435-5942</phone>
      <email>nci-transplant@mail.nih.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Marrow Donor Program</name>
      <address>
        <city>Minneapolis</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55401</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>John Miller, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>763-406-8566</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2010-C-0054.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 31, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 13, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 13, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 16, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CD19</keyword>
  <keyword>Chimeric-Antigen-Receptor</keyword>
  <keyword>Gene Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Adoptive T Cell Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Allogeneic Stem Cell Transplantation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Non-Hodgkin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, B-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hodgkin Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

