<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01999452</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SwePaD</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01999452</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Swedish Study on Paleolithic Diet for Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>SwePaD</acronym>
  <official_title>The Swedish Study on Paleolithic Diet for Type 2 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lund University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Region Skane</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lund University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background Paleolithic diet is a modern dietary regimen based on food eaten during the&#xD;
      Paleolithic (2.5 million-10.000 years before present); lean meats, fish, shellfish, fruits,&#xD;
      vegetables, root vegetables, eggs and nuts. Food that was not eaten during the Paleolithic is&#xD;
      avoided; cereals, dairy products, salt, refined sugar and fat. The rationale for Paleolithic&#xD;
      diet is based on the lack of type 2 diabetes and associated diseases among hunter-gatherer&#xD;
      populations. Our group have previously studied effects of Paleolithic diet in an&#xD;
      observational study in humans, an intervention study in animals and two intervention studies&#xD;
      in patients with type 2 diabetes or lowered glucose tolerance and ischaemic heart disease.&#xD;
      Our intervention studies showed significant improvement of glucose tolerance, HbA1c, blood&#xD;
      lipids, blood pressure, weight, waist circumference and satiety on Paleolithic diet compared&#xD;
      with a Mediterranean-type diet and diabetes diet. Studies by other research groups on healthy&#xD;
      individuals found that Paleolithic diet lowered weight, waist circumference, blood pressure,&#xD;
      PAI-1, blood lipids and ectopic lipid deposition, and also improved glucose tolerance and&#xD;
      insulin sensitivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose and aims Our goal is to study effects of Paleolithic diet compared to recommended&#xD;
      diet on risk factors, morbidity and mortality from type 2 diabetes and associated diseases in&#xD;
      a sufficiently large and well executed study to be included in basis for future dietary&#xD;
      recommendations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Project descriptions SwePaD is a study with an initial 18 month long randomized cross-over&#xD;
      dietary intervention on 150 patients with type 2 diabetes where the whole study population&#xD;
      upon finishing the initial dietary intervention is studied as a cohort for another 5 years.&#xD;
      The initial 18 month long dietary intervention compares 6 months on Paleolithic diet with 6&#xD;
      months on recommended diabetes diet separated by 6 months wash-out period. After the initial&#xD;
      18 month long dietary intervention the study participants are recommended to follow&#xD;
      recommended diabetes diet with implementation of optional elements from a Paleolithic diet&#xD;
      for the remaining 5 years of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention, in the form of diet information, will be given orally and written by the&#xD;
      study participant's own diabetes nurse or doctor, based on similarly designed written&#xD;
      information on the two diets. The same intervention was successfully used in our pilot study.&#xD;
      The study participants will otherwise receive usual treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Power calculations show that 126 participants are needed to obtain significant results with&#xD;
      80% power at the 95% significance level for the primary outcome HbA1c. The pilot study with&#xD;
      the same intervention but slightly healthier participants than the average patient in&#xD;
      Diabetesregistret showed significant results on HbA1C with only 13 participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes are fasting glucose levels, weight, waist circumference, blood pressure,&#xD;
      blood lipids, urinary albumin, diabetes retinopathy, smoking, physical activity,&#xD;
      monofilaments (detection of peripheral neuropathy) and health related quality of life&#xD;
      assessed by the health survey questionnaire SF-36. Primary and secondary outcomes as well as&#xD;
      medication will be registered before and after each intervention diet. Data on primary and&#xD;
      secondary outcomes, morbidity and mortality from type 2 diabetes and associated diseases will&#xD;
      be retrieved for up to five years after participants' completion of the dietary intervention&#xD;
      from the Diabetes register, Cause of Death Register (Dödsorsaksregistret) and the Hospital&#xD;
      Discharge Register (Patientregistret) and compared to expected outcome from a statistical&#xD;
      model based on the Diabetes register (A new model for 5-year risk of cardiovascular disease&#xD;
      Cederholm et al 2011) and/or a matched control group from the Diabetes register.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be recruited nationwide through information to health care personnel in&#xD;
      primary health care and hospital diabetes clinics and to patient organisations. Participants'&#xD;
      registration, intervention and data gathering will be administered by the participants' own&#xD;
      diabetes nurse or doctor via REDCap, a web based tool for secure electronic data capture&#xD;
      hosted on secure servers with daily back-up by the Library and IKT department of the medical&#xD;
      faculty at Lund University.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dietary evaluation will be made using four day weighed food records on paperforms before and&#xD;
      after each intervention diet and 6 months after the last intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Recruitment problems&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>0, 6, 12 and 18 months and then yearly for another 5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Paleolithic diet first</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Starting with Paleolithic diet and then switching to Diabetes diet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetes diet first</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Starting with Diabetes diet and then switching to Paleolithic diet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paleolithic diet</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetes diet first</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Paleolithic diet first</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diabetes diet</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Diabetes diet first</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Paleolithic diet first</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adult patients with type 2 diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unaltered medical diabetes treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  weight change less than 5% since three months before start of study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c above 47 mmol/mol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  creatinine below130 µmol/L&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  liver enzymes below four times their respective upper reference value&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no chronic treatment with oral or injection steroid or warfarin or warfarin-analogue&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no acute coronary event or change in medication of beta blockers or thyroxin since six&#xD;
             months before start of study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  change in beta blocker or thyroxin medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic treatment with oral or injection steroid or warfarin or warfarin analogue&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  creatinine above 130 µmol/L or liver enzymes above four times their respective upper&#xD;
             reference value&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acute coronary event&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  physical or psychological illness or changes in personal circumstances which would&#xD;
             make further study participation impossible&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tommy Jönsson, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lund University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center for Primary Health Care Research, Clinical Research Centre (CRC), hus 28, plan 11, Jan Waldenströms gata 35</name>
      <address>
        <city>Malmö</city>
        <state>Skåne</state>
        <zip>205 02</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 26, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 26, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">December 3, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 14, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 14, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Lund University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tommy Jonsson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Paleolithic diet</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

