<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01991262</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CMC-13-0112-CTIL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01991262</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Nationwide Epidemiological, Educational Support Program for Improving Treatment Adherence in Patients With HBV</brief_title>
  <acronym>Help-B</acronym>
  <official_title>A Nationwide Epidemiological, Non-Interventional Study Evaluating an Educational Support Program for Improving Treatment Adherence in Patients With Hepatitis B Viral Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Carmel Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Carmel Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Protocol Title: A Nationwide Epidemiological, Non-Interventional Study Evaluating an&#xD;
      Educational Support Program for Improving Treatment Adherence in Patients with Hepatitis B&#xD;
      Viral Infection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective(s): The primary objectives of the study are to assess:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HBV treatment adherence rate in patients enrolled in the Support Program&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adherence rates at 6m, 12m.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives are to assess:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adverse events rate and profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Actual treatment duration and dose taken vs. prescribed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The impact of SMS reminders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design: Eligible patients will be randomized into one of four groups: Group 1 shall&#xD;
      receive both a weekly phone call from a supporter and a daily SMS reminder. Group 2 will&#xD;
      receive a weekly phone call only. Group 3 will receive a daily SMS reminder only and group 4&#xD;
      (Control) shall receive no support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population: Adult newly diagnosed with Hep B patients, eligible to begin treatment with&#xD;
      first line therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Supporter's documentations of patient's self assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Drugs dispense data from pharmacies&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Pills count.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Protocol Number: AI463-972 Date: 23-Oct-2013 Ver: 2 Observational Study Protocol AI463-972 -&#xD;
      Help-B&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Nationwide Epidemiological, Non-Interventional Study Evaluating an Educational Support&#xD;
      Program for Improving Treatment Adherence in Patients with Hepatitis B Viral Infection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prof. Eli Zuckerman; Dr. Yoram Menachem; Prof. Rifat Safadi; Prof. Assy Nimer; Dr. Rawi&#xD;
      Hazzan; Dr. Michal Carmiel&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment for Chronic HBV The objectives of HBV therapy are to improve upon the spontaneous&#xD;
      rates of sustained disease remission (as defined by long-term HBeAg and HBsAg seroconversion&#xD;
      rates off-treatment), thereby reducing the risk of disease progression, with resultant&#xD;
      improvements in quality of life and reductions in healthcare costs. Seven drugs are presently&#xD;
      approved in the USA and/or EU for the treatment of CHB in patients with HBeAg-positive and&#xD;
      -negative disease. They fall into 2 classes: antiviral/immunomodulators (IFNα and pegIFNα-2a)&#xD;
      and antiviral nucleos(t)ide analogs (NUCs).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EASL and AASLD Treatment Guidelines (2009) recommend that HBV therapy may be initiated with&#xD;
      any of the currently approved agents, but that IFNα (standard or pegylated), Tenofovir (TDF)&#xD;
      or Entecavir (ETV) are preferred first-line options for treatment of CHB patients with&#xD;
      HBeAg-positive and HBeAg-negative disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Poor adherence to therapy is a complex challenge for physicians treating patients with&#xD;
      chronic diseases. In clini¬cal practice, adherence rates averages 50%, falling most&#xD;
      dramatically after the first 6 mo of treatment. Guidelines on CHB therapy emphasise the need&#xD;
      for optimal adherence, with risk of resistant viral strains emerging if the virus has a drug&#xD;
      free holiday. For example, antiviral resistance has been reported in up to 70% patients after&#xD;
      4 years on Lamivudine, 29% after 5 years of Adefovir dipivoxil and 1% after 4 years of&#xD;
      Entecavir monohydrate. The number of dose omissions that may lead to this is variable but any&#xD;
      omission poses a po¬tential risk of viral replication breakthrough. Although, the data for&#xD;
      CHB are lacking, it is evident from the HIV literature that near-perfect adherence (&gt; 95%&#xD;
      adherence rates) is needed to achieve a non detectable viral load and avoid emergence of&#xD;
      resistant strains. Hence, in the clinical setting of CHB therapy, the goal of adherence&#xD;
      remains 100%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unlike other chronic conditions, the rapid viral rep¬lication potential and mutation rates of&#xD;
      hepatitis B virus require very high levels of adherence to achieve and maintain virological&#xD;
      suppression. Suboptimal adher¬ence risks exacerbating existing liver disease, which can be&#xD;
      life-threatening particularly in patients with advanced cirrhosis. Furthermore, it can lead&#xD;
      to the development of drug-resistant strains, limiting therapeutic options and additionally&#xD;
      poses the public health risks of transmission of drug-resistant viral strains to non-immune&#xD;
      individuals in the community, or to those whose previous vaccina¬tion are no longer&#xD;
      protective. Given the global burden of the disease, widespread transmission of drug-resistant&#xD;
      strains may have serious and wide-reaching consequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.1 Study Rationale Non- adherence to treatment is a well known issue across many therapeutic&#xD;
      areas. In Hep C, literature review shows that adherence in real life may reach 65%, with most&#xD;
      drop-outs during first 3 months, mainly due to minor side effects. In Hep B, reported&#xD;
      adherence studies show 50%-80% adherence, with an average of ~65%. Most drop-outs are during&#xD;
      first 6 months of treatment. Non-adherence to treatment is believed to contribute not only to&#xD;
      liver deterioration but also to emerging viral resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies for adherence support show an average improvement of around 10%-15% at the best.&#xD;
      Assessed methods are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient education&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients empowerment&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SMS reminders&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pills' boxes with electronic reminders&#xD;
&#xD;
      The lack of symptoms along with chronicity of treatment, financial burden and lack of&#xD;
      patient's education - are recognized as important factors for non-adherence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The abundance of new drugs for viral hepatitis, high disease prevalence and the close&#xD;
      relation between effective treatment and clinical outcomes - create a clear need for not only&#xD;
      providing treatment but also an efficient support system aimed at supporting patients'&#xD;
      adherence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.2 Research Question We expect that an ongoing patients' support system will contribute to&#xD;
      adherence increase. The support should be provided by HCPs, be continuous and provide&#xD;
      reminders, medical education and direct contact between patients and HCPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, study hypothesis is:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  An ongoing 6 months adherence support will increase adherence rates for Hep B patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adherence rate increase will be at least 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Direct weekly telephone contacts will contribute major improvement. Smart phone&#xD;
           application daily reminders will contribute as well and there is need to assess its&#xD;
           relative contribution.&#xD;
&#xD;
           2 OBJECTIVES 2.1 Primary Objectives At least 20% improvement in adherence rates for&#xD;
           newly treated Hep B patients. Adherence rate will be defined as the per cent of days the&#xD;
           patients took their hepatitis B virus medications during study treatment and the number&#xD;
           of missed doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2 Secondary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      The difference in adherence improvement among 3 types of adherence support:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Weekly telephone call + daily text messages reminders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Weekly telephone calls.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Daily text messages reminders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Control - no adherence support&#xD;
&#xD;
      3 STUDY DESIGN 3.1 Overview of Study Design This is an epidemiological non-interventional&#xD;
      study conducted in the community. Medical students (Hereinafter &quot;Supporters&quot;), attending&#xD;
      senior years (4th or 5th year) will receive training about the Educational Support Program.&#xD;
      In case not all vacancies can be filled with suitable medical students, senior years nursing&#xD;
      students will be approached. Every supporter will be supporting a maximum of 10 recruited&#xD;
      patients simultaneously. Every 5 supporters will report to a nurse. Every 2 nurses will&#xD;
      report to a Hepatologist (Hereinafter &quot;Investigator&quot;). Overall, every Hepatologist shall be&#xD;
      recruiting a maximum of 100 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the pre-study phase, eligible patients, who are prescribed with HBV treatment with&#xD;
      Entecavir by their respective Investigator, will be informed of the Support Program.&#xD;
      Interested patients will receive ICF for signature. Upon signature, the recruiting&#xD;
      Investigator will randomize the newly recruited patient into one of the four study groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization will be provided by CHS computerized system (Randomization engine).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients in the supported groups (Groups 1; 2 and 3) shall undergo the procedure described&#xD;
      hereby:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon recruitment, the patient will be introduced to the nurse, who will appoint a supporter&#xD;
      to the patient, install the smart-phone reminder application (to relevant groups - Group 1&#xD;
      and Group 3) and explain the support format according to patient's group:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Receive weekly phone calls from their supporters who will monitor HBV treatment adherence and&#xD;
      adverse events, respond to the patients' queries, suggest possible remedies to patients'&#xD;
      basic complaints (per definition and qualification in training), refer more complex queries&#xD;
      and/or complaints to respective nurse and refer patients to physicians for further treatment,&#xD;
      if required. The Supporter will record the data on a Patient Follow-Up Form and report, on a&#xD;
      monthly basis, to the respective nurse. In addition, patients in this group will install the&#xD;
      reminder application on their smart-phones and will be reminded on a daily basis, by the&#xD;
      application, to take their medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Receive weekly phone calls from their Supporters who will monitor HBV treatment adherence and&#xD;
      adverse events, respond to the patients' queries, suggest possible remedies to patients'&#xD;
      basic complaints (per definition and qualification in training), refer more complex queries&#xD;
      and/or complaints to respective nurse and refer patients to physicians for further treatment,&#xD;
      if required. The Supporter will record the data on a Patient Follow-Up Form and report, on a&#xD;
      monthly basis, to the respective nurse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 3:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients in this group will install the reminder application on their smart-phones and will&#xD;
      be reminded on a daily basis, by the application, to take their medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 4:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients in the 4th group (control group) will continue the SOC without any further support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every month, patients will receive a letter from their respective Investigators, summarizing&#xD;
      their study status in the previous month (Appendix A). Every quarter (3 months), each nurse&#xD;
      will report study progress to responsible Investigator and schedule a follow-up appointment&#xD;
      for the patient with the investigator. The patient will bring the pill boxes to the follow-up&#xD;
      appointment for counting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the supporting phase, the patients will continue HBV treatment according to&#xD;
      standard care and their physician's instructions. During the follow-up phase, all groups will&#xD;
      be handled as Group 4 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2 Study Population&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approximately 250 Naïve Hep B patients are expected to participate in the study and will be&#xD;
      divided into 4 study arms:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 1: 63 pts receiving weekly telephone contact &amp; daily text messages for 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2: 63 patients receiving weekly telephone contacts for 6 months. Group 3: 63 patients&#xD;
      receiving daily text messages for 6 months. Group 4: 63 patients receiving no adherence&#xD;
      support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2.1 Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adult male and female patient (&gt; 18 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Prescribed treatment of Entecavir for HBV&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Must have access to a smart-phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.2.2 Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with hepatitis C, hepatitis D or HIV co-infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Co-infected patients who require additional medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with prior liver transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with impaired renal function requiring dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Immune-suppressed patients receiving HBV antiviral prophylaxis&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Inability or unwillingness to provide informed consent or abide by the requirements of&#xD;
           the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Parallel participation in another clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who cannot take medication independently.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.3 Data Source/Data Collection Process&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adherence to treatment will be assessed by 3 methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Supporters' weekly documentations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Pill count - Patients will be instructed to bring the boxes to quarterly follow-up&#xD;
           visits with the Hepatologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Drugs dispense data from pharmacies - every 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety assessment will be completed by:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Supporters' weekly documentations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Documentation by treating hepatologists, during ongoing visits. 3.4 Definitions of Study&#xD;
           Variables Adherence will be quantified into percentage and will be calculated as the&#xD;
           percent of days in which the patient took the prescribed medication out of the number of&#xD;
           days the patient was instructed to take the medication by prescription.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.4.1 Outcomes/Endpoint Variables&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adherence rate will be defined as the percentage of days the patients took their hepatitis B&#xD;
      virus medications during study treatment and the number of missed doses. Adherence will be&#xD;
      measured as a combination of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Drug dispense at pharmacy (every month)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Self report by patient (every week)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Pills count (every 3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A responder will be defined as a patient with at least 80% adherence to drug treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The difference in adherence improvement among 3 types of adherence support&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Weekly Phone Call + Daily Application Reminder&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Weekly Phone Call&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Daily Application Reminder&#xD;
&#xD;
      4 STATISTICAL ANALYSIS 4.1 Statistical Analysis Methods All measured variables and derived&#xD;
      parameters will be listed individually and, if appropriate, tabulated by descriptive&#xD;
      statistics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For categorical variables summary tables will be provided giving sample size, absolute and&#xD;
      relative frequency and 95% CI (Confidence Interval) for proportions by study arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For continuous variables summary tables will be provided giving sample size, arithmetic mean,&#xD;
      standard deviation, coefficient of variation (if appropriate), median, minimum and maximum,&#xD;
      percentiles and 95% CI (Confidence Interval) by study arm for means of variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.1.1 Primary Objective Responders will be defined as patients with at least 80% adherence to&#xD;
      drug treatment. 95% Confidence Interval (95% CI) will be calculated for the rate of&#xD;
      responders per study arm (arms 1, 2 and 3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.1.2 Secondary Objectives Chi-square test or Fisher's Exact test (as is appropriate) will be&#xD;
      applied for testing the statistical significance of the difference in responders rate between&#xD;
      study arms 1 (Weekly Phone Call + Daily Application Reminder), 2 (Weekly Phone Call) and 3&#xD;
      (Daily Application Reminder) vs. group 4 (no support).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The effect of telephone call will be tested comparing groups 1+2 vs. groups 3+4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The effect of daily SMS will be tested comparing groups 1+3 vs. group 2+4. Logistic&#xD;
      Regression model will be applied for testing the statistical significance of the difference&#xD;
      in responders' rate between study arms 1, 2 and 3 vs. group 4 and between the active groups&#xD;
      with adjustment to suspected confounders related to study outcome which will be found&#xD;
      different between the arms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Logistic regression will be applied for analyzing the effect of telephone call and daily SMS&#xD;
      (as described above) with adjustment to suspected confounders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All tests will be two-tailed, and a p value of 5% or less will be considered statistically&#xD;
      significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data will be analyzed using the SAS ® version 9.1 (SAS Institute, Cary North Carolina).&#xD;
&#xD;
      4.2 Power/Sample Size Rational for Sample size calculation Sample size calculation is based&#xD;
      on demonstrating a difference of at least 21% in response rate in the comparison between&#xD;
      study arms 1, 2 and 3 vs. group 4. This difference reflects an odds ratio of 0.23 with&#xD;
      statistical significance of 5% with statistical power of 80% when the sample size is 252, 63&#xD;
      in each study arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size Justification A two group continuity corrected Chi square test with a 0.050&#xD;
      two-sided significance level will have 80% power to detect the difference between a Group 1&#xD;
      proportion and a Group 2 proportion (odds ratio of 0.231) when the sample size in each group&#xD;
      is 64.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reference: nQuery advisor 2.1&#xD;
&#xD;
      5 STUDY CONDUCT This study will be conducted in accordance with International Society for&#xD;
      Pharmacoepidemiology (ISPE) Guidelines for Good Pharmacoepidemiology Practices (GPP) and&#xD;
      applicable regulatory requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.1 Ethics Committee Review and Informed Consent&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.1.1 Ethics Committee Review The investigator must ensure that the required approvals from&#xD;
      Ethics Committees, Independent Review Committees, Regulatory Authorities, and/or other local&#xD;
      governance bodies are obtained before study initiation at the site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.1.2 Informed Consent In accordance with local regulations, subjects should provide either&#xD;
      written or oral consent before enrollment into the study. Investigators must ensure that&#xD;
      patients, or, in those situations where consent cannot be given by patients, their legally&#xD;
      acceptable representatives, are clearly and fully informed about the purpose of the study,&#xD;
      potential risks, the patient's rights and responsibilities when participating in this study.&#xD;
      If local regulations do not require an informed consent document to be signed by the patient,&#xD;
      the site staff should document key elements of the informed consent process in the patient's&#xD;
      chart.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study does not require that informed consent is obtained from patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.2 Responsibilities within the Study The study shall be conducted as described in this&#xD;
      approved protocol. All revisions to the protocol must be discussed with, and be prepared by&#xD;
      BMS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.3 Confidentiality of Study Data The confidentiality of records that could identify patients&#xD;
      within the database must be protected, respecting the privacy and confidentiality rules in&#xD;
      accordance with the applicable regulatory requirement(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the purposes of protecting a patient's identity, a unique code will be assigned to each&#xD;
      patient, such as a series of numbers and/or letters (for example, CA180330-0001-00001). The&#xD;
      data that is recorded with the patient's assigned code is called &quot;key-coded data&quot;. Key-coded&#xD;
      study data will be managed by the sponsor and/or its delegates in a study-specific electronic&#xD;
      database (the &quot;study database&quot;). Only the investigator and the site staff have access to the&#xD;
      link between patient's assigned code and the patient's identity. However, in case of an audit&#xD;
      or inspection, subject to local laws and regulations, government officials, IRB/EC&#xD;
      representatives and sponsor representatives may access this information at the study site. If&#xD;
      the study requires on-site monitoring, subject to local laws and regulations, sponsor&#xD;
      representatives will also access the primary data source at the study site (see section 6.4).&#xD;
      Data that could directly identify the patient will not be collected in the &quot;study database&quot;.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.4 Quality Control Power/Sample Size Representatives of BMS and/or its delegates must be&#xD;
      allowed to visit all study site locations to assess the data quality and study integrity. On&#xD;
      site, they will review study files and, if allowed by local laws and regulations, patient&#xD;
      medical charts to compare them with source documents, discuss the conduct of the study with&#xD;
      the investigator, and verify that the facilities remain acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the study may be evaluated by BMS internal auditors and government inspectors&#xD;
      who must be allowed access to CRFs, source documents, other study files, and study&#xD;
      facilities. BMS audit reports will be kept confidential.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator must notify BMS promptly of any inspections scheduled by regulatory&#xD;
      authorities, and promptly forward copies of inspection reports to BMS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.5 Database Retention and Archiving of Study Documents The investigator must retain all&#xD;
      study records and source documents for the maximum period required by applicable regulations&#xD;
      and guidelines, or institution procedures, or for the period specified by the sponsor,&#xD;
      whichever is longer. The investigator must contact BMS prior to destroying any records&#xD;
      associated with the study. Location of database and supporting documentation will be outlined&#xD;
      in the final observational study report.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6 ADVERSE EVENT REPORTING The INSTITUTION/PRINCIPAL INVESTIGATOR must notify BMS with the&#xD;
      related and non-related Serious Adverse Events (SAEs) and/or Pregnancies within 24 hours of&#xD;
      becoming aware of the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The INVESTIGATOR must notify BMS with the related and non-related non-serious Adverse Events&#xD;
      within 7 days of becoming aware of the event.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All Adverse Events and/or Serious Adverse Events must be reported to:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bristol-Myers Squibb Company Global Pharmacovigilance FAX Number: 609-818-3804 or Email:&#xD;
      WorldWide.Safety@bms.com&#xD;
&#xD;
      The INVESTIGATOR must notify BMS with all Adverse Events in aggregate in the Final Study&#xD;
      Report (FSR).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    the support group need to have some change&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>April 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hepatitis B treatment adherence rate in patients with support system</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>HBV Treatment Adherence by Support Program</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1 phone call and SMS reminder.</arm_group_label>
    <description>cloosed no one enrolled</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2 phone call only.</arm_group_label>
    <description>cloosed no one enrolled</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3 SMS reminder only .</arm_group_label>
    <description>cloosed no one enrolled</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4 (Control) no support</arm_group_label>
    <description>cloosed no one enrolled</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult newly diagnosed with chronic hepatitis B patients, eligible to begin treatment with&#xD;
        first line therapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult male and female patient (&gt; 18 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prescribed treatment of Entecavir for HBV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have access to a smart-phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patients with hepatitis C, hepatitis D or HIV co-infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Co-infected patients who require additional medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with prior liver transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with impaired renal function requiring dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immune-suppressed patients receiving HBV antiviral prophylaxis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Inability or unwillingness to provide informed consent or abide by the&#xD;
                  requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Parallel participation in another clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who cannot take medication independently.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>July 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 25, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 23, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 23, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 24, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Carmel Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Eli Zuckerman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Liver Unit</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

