<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01992042</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WIN-STOPCa_001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01992042</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Novel Window of Opportunity Trial to Evaluate the Impact of Statins to Oppose Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Novel Window of Opportunity Trial to Evaluate the Impact of Statins to Oppose Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Health Network, Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Health Network, Toronto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study provides a novel opportunity to examine the intra-prostatic tumour&#xD;
      inhibitory effects of statins in men with prostate cancer undergoing surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pre and post treatment effect on the Ki-67 proliferation index</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of immunohistochemical staining in Biopsy and post-RP tissues</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 8</time_frame>
    <description>Will measure:&#xD;
i. Apoptosis (caspase 3) ii. Signaling (Rap1A, Rap, RhoB) iii. Mevalonate pathway proteins (HMG-CoA reductase, HMG-CoA synthase, SREBP1/2, mevalonate decarboxylase, GGPS1, GGT, FT) iv. Tumour Infiltrating Lymphocytes (TILs), CD3 (T-cells), CD20 (B-cells), CD68 (macrophages), CD56 (NK cells), IDO (negative control)) v. Growth and survival signaling (AKT, P-AKT, ERK, P-ERK)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">33</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fluvastatin/Pimonidazole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will take 40mg BID of fluvastatin. The day before surgery patients will take a single dose of pimonidazole that will be calculate based on body surface area.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fluvastatin</intervention_name>
    <description>HMG-CoA reductase inhibitors that lowers cholesterol levels. 40mg twice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fluvastatin/Pimonidazole</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lescol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pimonidazole</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Fluvastatin/Pimonidazole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        The study population will consist of patients with localized prostate cancer that have&#xD;
        elected radical prostatectomy as a primary treatment. Eligible patients will have prostate&#xD;
        cancer that is Gleason Score ≥ 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who meet all of the following inclusion criteria will be eligible to participate&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Men &gt;18 and &lt; 75 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Willing and able to provide informed consent, either alone or with the aid of a&#xD;
             translator&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically confirmed prostate cancer as determined by transrectal ultrasound&#xD;
             (TRUS) guided prostate biopsy performed within 6 months of study enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prostate cancer that is Gleason grade ≥ 7 involving at least 30% of one unfragmented&#xD;
             biopsy core&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Candidates for radical prostatectomy considered surgically resectable, either open or&#xD;
             robotic, by urologic evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Normal organ and marrow function as defined by the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. absolute neutrophil count &gt;1,500/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
             ii. platelets &gt;100,000/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
             iii. total bilirubin &lt;1.5 X institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
             iv. AST (SGOT) or ALT (SGPT) &lt;1.5 X institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
             v. creatinine &lt;1.5 X institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0 to 1&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any patient meeting one or more of the following exclusion criteria may not be entered into&#xD;
        the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previous or current use of neo-adjuvant or hormonal management of prostate cancer&#xD;
             (surgical castration or other hormonal manipulation, including GnRH receptor agonists,&#xD;
             GnRH receptor antagonists, anti-androgens, estrogens, megestrol acetate and&#xD;
             ketoconazole)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of receiving radiation to the pelvic area&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Past or current use of 5-alpha reductase inhibitors finasteride and/or dutasteride&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of bilateral orchiectomy, adrenalectomy, or hypophysectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Statin use within 2 years of prostate cancer diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Known hypersensitivity towards any component of the investigational medicinal product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Previous history or presence of another malignancy, other than prostate cancer or&#xD;
             treated squamous / basal cell carcinoma of the skin, within the last five years&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Clinically significant laboratory abnormalities (e.g. severe renal or hepatic&#xD;
             impairment) which in the judgment of the Investigator would affect the patient's&#xD;
             health or the outcome of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Clinically significant disorder (other than prostate cancer) including, but not&#xD;
             limited to, renal, haematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, cardiac, neurological,&#xD;
             or psychiatric disease, and alcohol or drug abuse or any other condition, which may&#xD;
             affect the patient's health or the outcome of the trial as judged by the Investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Use of natural medicines thought to have endocrine effects on prostate cancer (e.g.&#xD;
             saw palmetto and St. John's Wort) 4 weeks prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Use of any drug listed in Prohibited Medications List&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Mental incapacity or language barrier precluding adequate understanding or co&#xD;
             operation&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Use of an investigational drug within the last 28 days preceding the Screening Visit&#xD;
             or longer if considered to possibly influence the outcome of the current trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients who are unable or unwilling to undergo MRI testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Health Network- The Princess Margaret Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G2M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 18, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 25, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 24, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 24, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

