<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01993615</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>213011</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01993615</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Physical Therapy Program Versus Surgery for Femoroacetabular Impingement: Randomized Clinical Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Supervised Physical Therapy Program vs. Arthroscopic Surgery for Femoroacetabular Impingement: A Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Madigan Army Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Madigan Army Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to compare the outcomes for patients that receive two different&#xD;
      treatments used for FAI (Femoroacetabular Impingement). The programs are 1) a 6-week&#xD;
      supervised physical therapy program and 2) arthroscopic surgery. Enrollment is limited to&#xD;
      patients that have already been determined surgical candidates. The study is following&#xD;
      patients for a 2-year period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study plans to enroll a total of 60 Tricare beneficiaries primarily from the Madigan&#xD;
      Healthcare System with a diagnosis of FAI that are surgical candidates and have already&#xD;
      failed at least six weeks of conservative treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a randomized controlled study comparing outcomes for the standard treatment for FAI&#xD;
      and/or acetabular labral pathology (arthroscopy with or without labral repair) versus&#xD;
      physical therapy. For subjects in the arthroscopy group, the surgery will be performed by the&#xD;
      Orthopedic Surgical Service at Madigan Army Medical Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects randomized to the physical therapy group will follow a treatment plan implemented by&#xD;
      a physical therapist within the Madigan Army Healthcare System.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After consent, subjects will be randomized into one of two arms (Group I = hip arthroscopy,&#xD;
      Group II = physical therapy). Group I will undergo hip arthroscopy with or without labral&#xD;
      repair. Group II will follow a FAI-based physical therapy program x 12 sessions (6 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The arthroscopy group will complete outcome measures at time of consent and following surgery&#xD;
      at 6 months, 1 year and 2 year time periods. Subjects in this group will follow a&#xD;
      standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The physical therapy group will complete outcomes measures at time of consent and at 6 month,&#xD;
      1 year and 2 year time periods following the initial physical therapy evaluation. Subjects in&#xD;
      this group will complete 6 weeks of an impairment-based physical therapy program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the outcome measures taken, healthcare utilization and associated costs for&#xD;
      hip-related care during this 2-year period will also calculated for comparison between the 2&#xD;
      groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hip Outcome Score - ADL Subscale at 24 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Hip Outcome Score is designed to assess higher-level activities (i.e. those required in athletics) and has demonstrated validity in a study of patients at a mean of three years following hip arthroscopy. Additionally, a 2011 study states that the HOS has the greatest amount of clinimetric evidence (rigor of rating scales and indexes for the description of clinical phenomena). Only three published patient-reported outcome instruments utilized to assess FAI and labral pathology use clinimetric evidence and the HOS was identified as the most proven instrument. The HOS ADL Subscale consisted of 19 questions, each scored on a 5-point scale from 0 (unable to do) to 4 (no difficulty). The final score is calculated by taking the raw score, dividing it by the number of total questions answered multipled by 4 x 100 for a final score that ranges from 0 to 100%, with lower scores associated with greater limitation in Activities of Daily Living (ADL).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hip Outcome Score - Sport Subscale at 24 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Hip Outcome Score is designed to assess higher level activities (i.e. those required in athletics) and has demonstrated validity in a study of patients at a mean of three years following hip arthroscopy. Additionally, a 2011 study states that the HOS has the greatest amount of clinimetric evidence (rigor of rating scales and indexes for the description of clinical phenomena). Only three published patient-reported outcome instruments utilized to assess FAI and labral pathology use clinimetric evidence and the HOS was identified as the most proven instrument. The HOS Sport Subscale consists of 9 questions, each scored on a 5-point scale from 0 (unable to do) to 4 (no difficulty). The final score is calculated by taking the raw score, dividing it by the number of total questions answered multipled by 4 x 100 for a final score that ranges from 0 to 100%, with lower scores associated with greater limitations in Sports-related activities.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Group Differences in International Hip Outcome Score (IHOT33) to 24 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The iHOT33 is a quality-of-life patient-reported outcome measure that uses a visual analog scale response format for young, active patients with hip pathology. This 33-item questionnaire includes four sections: symptoms and functional limitations, sports and recreational activities, job related concerns and social, emotional and lifestyle concerns. This outcome measure has shown to be reliable; shows face, content and contrast validity and is highly responsive to clinical change. It uses a visual analog scale with the verbal anchors &quot;no problems at all&quot; on the far right and &quot;significantly impaired&quot; on the left. The total score is calculated as a simple mean of the responses ranging from 0 to 100, with 100 representing the best possible quality-of-life score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global Rating of Change Score of 3+ or Higher (Minimum Clinically Important Change)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The GROC will be administered to patients at the 6 months, one year and two year time points. The GROC questionnaire is a common, feasible, and useful method for assessing short term outcomes and overall changes in quality of life and is a valid measurement of change in patient status in a variety of pain populations. The GROC has a 15-point scale with a change of positive three points or higher (3+) demonstrating clinically significant improvement in a patient's perception of quality of life. Scores of -1 to -7 indicate negative perception of improvement (worsening of condition), a 0 indicates no change, and scores of +1 through +7 indicate a positive perceived improvement in the patients condition.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Self-Motivation Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Self-Motivation Inventory is an outcome measure that was developed to determine level of motivation. The Self-Motivation Inventory is a 40-item tool that has been found to measure an individual's tendency to persevere independent of situational reinforcement. It has also been used to predict successful weight loss and may correlate with number of sessions attended in weight loss program [29]. This tool underwent refinement in 1980 with the original 60-item tool being tested in undergraduate male and females. Items correlating less than 0.30 were deleted. The final 40-item scale yielded an exceptionally high internal reliability (α = 0.91) suggesting that a unitary common concept is evident for the obtained factor structure. The tool is widely used and has been tested in weight loss and therapeutic exercise studies</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Changes From Baseline Pain Catastrophizing Scale at 24 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The PCS is a 13-item patient-report scale developed to measure the extent to which people catastrophize in response to pain. Each item is scored from 0 ('not at all') to 4 ('all the time'). The PCS is reported as a total score, with higher scores indicating greater catastrophizing, and is composed of three sub-scales: Rumination (four items; e.g. 'When I am in pain, I keep thinking about how badly I want the pain to stop'), Magnification (three items; e.g. 'When I am in pain, I become afraid that the pain will get worse'), and Helplessness (six items; e.g. 'When I am in pain, I feel I can't go on'). The PCS has been shown to have high levels of internal consistency and construct validity.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Femoroacetabular Impingement</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arthroscopic Surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physical Therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Arthroscopic Surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arthroscopic Surgery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physical Therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tricare beneficiaries between the ages of 18 and 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of FAI and/or labral pathology confirmed by a combination of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pain at the anterior hip or groin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pain with hip flexion&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive FADIR test&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient report relief of pain after intra-articular injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgical candidate for hip arthroscopy defined by (must have both):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No less than 2 mm of joint space based on imaging (CT scan, radiographs and MR&#xD;
                  arthrogram)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive crossover sign and/or alpha angle &gt;50 deg based on imaging (CT scan,&#xD;
                  radiographs and MR arthrogram)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failed 6 weeks of conservative management&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has other concurrent systemic disease that may affect the condition (cancer,&#xD;
             rheumatoid arthritis, or other systemic arthralgia/arthritis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had surgery on the same hip that will be analyzed in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of hip osteoarthritis is more likely&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clearing the lumbar spine reproduces the patient's hip symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plans to move/relocate out of the local area within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pending litigation for their hip condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to give informed consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to speak or read or write in English (due to inability to fill out outcome&#xD;
             measures)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nancy Mansell, PT, DPT</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Madigan Army Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Rhon, DPT, DSc</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Madigan Army Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Madigan Army Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tacoma</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98431</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 30, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 20, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 25, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>June 26, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>July 28, 2020</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">August 14, 2020</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 28, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 28, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Madigan Army Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dan Rhon</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director of Physical Therapy, Department of PM&amp;R</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>FAI</keyword>
  <keyword>femoroacetabular impingement</keyword>
  <keyword>hip pain</keyword>
  <keyword>hip arthroscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>physical therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Femoracetabular Impingement</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Any data sharing must go through a Data Sharing Agreement approved by the US Defense Health Agency</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <recruitment_details>Recruitment occurred from the orthopaedic clinic at Madigan Army Medical Center</recruitment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
          <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Physical Therapy</title>
          <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="40"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="40"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="39"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="40"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Death</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
          <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Physical Therapy</title>
          <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="40"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="40"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="80"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="29.7" spread="7.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="30.6" spread="7.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="30.1" spread="7.4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="19"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="14"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="33"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="21"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="26"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="47"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="6"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="5"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="30"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="28"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="58"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Hip Outcome Score - ADL Subscale at 24 Months</title>
        <description>The Hip Outcome Score is designed to assess higher-level activities (i.e. those required in athletics) and has demonstrated validity in a study of patients at a mean of three years following hip arthroscopy. Additionally, a 2011 study states that the HOS has the greatest amount of clinimetric evidence (rigor of rating scales and indexes for the description of clinical phenomena). Only three published patient-reported outcome instruments utilized to assess FAI and labral pathology use clinimetric evidence and the HOS was identified as the most proven instrument. The HOS ADL Subscale consisted of 19 questions, each scored on a 5-point scale from 0 (unable to do) to 4 (no difficulty). The final score is calculated by taking the raw score, dividing it by the number of total questions answered multipled by 4 x 100 for a final score that ranges from 0 to 100%, with lower scores associated with greater limitation in Activities of Daily Living (ADL).</description>
        <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
        <population>Intention to treat analysis including only participants that received any treatment (6 participants that were enrolled never returned for treatment)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
            <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Physical Therapy</title>
            <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Hip Outcome Score - ADL Subscale at 24 Months</title>
          <description>The Hip Outcome Score is designed to assess higher-level activities (i.e. those required in athletics) and has demonstrated validity in a study of patients at a mean of three years following hip arthroscopy. Additionally, a 2011 study states that the HOS has the greatest amount of clinimetric evidence (rigor of rating scales and indexes for the description of clinical phenomena). Only three published patient-reported outcome instruments utilized to assess FAI and labral pathology use clinimetric evidence and the HOS was identified as the most proven instrument. The HOS ADL Subscale consisted of 19 questions, each scored on a 5-point scale from 0 (unable to do) to 4 (no difficulty). The final score is calculated by taking the raw score, dividing it by the number of total questions answered multipled by 4 x 100 for a final score that ranges from 0 to 100%, with lower scores associated with greater limitation in Activities of Daily Living (ADL).</description>
          <population>Intention to treat analysis including only participants that received any treatment (6 participants that were enrolled never returned for treatment)</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Least Squares Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="37"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="37"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="69.3" lower_limit="62.5" upper_limit="76.2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="73.1" lower_limit="66.1" upper_limit="80.3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Hip Outcome Score - Sport Subscale at 24 Months</title>
        <description>The Hip Outcome Score is designed to assess higher level activities (i.e. those required in athletics) and has demonstrated validity in a study of patients at a mean of three years following hip arthroscopy. Additionally, a 2011 study states that the HOS has the greatest amount of clinimetric evidence (rigor of rating scales and indexes for the description of clinical phenomena). Only three published patient-reported outcome instruments utilized to assess FAI and labral pathology use clinimetric evidence and the HOS was identified as the most proven instrument. The HOS Sport Subscale consists of 9 questions, each scored on a 5-point scale from 0 (unable to do) to 4 (no difficulty). The final score is calculated by taking the raw score, dividing it by the number of total questions answered multipled by 4 x 100 for a final score that ranges from 0 to 100%, with lower scores associated with greater limitations in Sports-related activities.</description>
        <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
        <population>Intention to treat analysis including only participants that received any treatment (6 participants that were enrolled never returned for treatment)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
            <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Physical Therapy</title>
            <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Hip Outcome Score - Sport Subscale at 24 Months</title>
          <description>The Hip Outcome Score is designed to assess higher level activities (i.e. those required in athletics) and has demonstrated validity in a study of patients at a mean of three years following hip arthroscopy. Additionally, a 2011 study states that the HOS has the greatest amount of clinimetric evidence (rigor of rating scales and indexes for the description of clinical phenomena). Only three published patient-reported outcome instruments utilized to assess FAI and labral pathology use clinimetric evidence and the HOS was identified as the most proven instrument. The HOS Sport Subscale consists of 9 questions, each scored on a 5-point scale from 0 (unable to do) to 4 (no difficulty). The final score is calculated by taking the raw score, dividing it by the number of total questions answered multipled by 4 x 100 for a final score that ranges from 0 to 100%, with lower scores associated with greater limitations in Sports-related activities.</description>
          <population>Intention to treat analysis including only participants that received any treatment (6 participants that were enrolled never returned for treatment)</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Least Squares Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="37"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="37"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="55.3" lower_limit="46.2" upper_limit="64.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="57.1" lower_limit="47.8" upper_limit="66.3"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Group Differences in International Hip Outcome Score (IHOT33) to 24 Months</title>
        <description>The iHOT33 is a quality-of-life patient-reported outcome measure that uses a visual analog scale response format for young, active patients with hip pathology. This 33-item questionnaire includes four sections: symptoms and functional limitations, sports and recreational activities, job related concerns and social, emotional and lifestyle concerns. This outcome measure has shown to be reliable; shows face, content and contrast validity and is highly responsive to clinical change. It uses a visual analog scale with the verbal anchors &quot;no problems at all&quot; on the far right and &quot;significantly impaired&quot; on the left. The total score is calculated as a simple mean of the responses ranging from 0 to 100, with 100 representing the best possible quality-of-life score.</description>
        <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
        <population>Intention to treat analysis including only participants that received any treatment (6 participants that were enrolled never returned for treatment)</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
            <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Physical Therapy</title>
            <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Group Differences in International Hip Outcome Score (IHOT33) to 24 Months</title>
          <description>The iHOT33 is a quality-of-life patient-reported outcome measure that uses a visual analog scale response format for young, active patients with hip pathology. This 33-item questionnaire includes four sections: symptoms and functional limitations, sports and recreational activities, job related concerns and social, emotional and lifestyle concerns. This outcome measure has shown to be reliable; shows face, content and contrast validity and is highly responsive to clinical change. It uses a visual analog scale with the verbal anchors &quot;no problems at all&quot; on the far right and &quot;significantly impaired&quot; on the left. The total score is calculated as a simple mean of the responses ranging from 0 to 100, with 100 representing the best possible quality-of-life score.</description>
          <population>Intention to treat analysis including only participants that received any treatment (6 participants that were enrolled never returned for treatment)</population>
          <units>score on a scale</units>
          <param>Least Squares Mean</param>
          <dispersion>95% Confidence Interval</dispersion>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="37"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="37"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="51.2" lower_limit="42.5" upper_limit="59.9"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="44.9" lower_limit="35.9" upper_limit="53.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Secondary</type>
        <title>Global Rating of Change Score of 3+ or Higher (Minimum Clinically Important Change)</title>
        <description>The GROC will be administered to patients at the 6 months, one year and two year time points. The GROC questionnaire is a common, feasible, and useful method for assessing short term outcomes and overall changes in quality of life and is a valid measurement of change in patient status in a variety of pain populations. The GROC has a 15-point scale with a change of positive three points or higher (3+) demonstrating clinically significant improvement in a patient's perception of quality of life. Scores of -1 to -7 indicate negative perception of improvement (worsening of condition), a 0 indicates no change, and scores of +1 through +7 indicate a positive perceived improvement in the patients condition.</description>
        <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
            <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Physical Therapy</title>
            <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Global Rating of Change Score of 3+ or Higher (Minimum Clinically Important Change)</title>
          <description>The GROC will be administered to patients at the 6 months, one year and two year time points. The GROC questionnaire is a common, feasible, and useful method for assessing short term outcomes and overall changes in quality of life and is a valid measurement of change in patient status in a variety of pain populations. The GROC has a 15-point scale with a change of positive three points or higher (3+) demonstrating clinically significant improvement in a patient's perception of quality of life. Scores of -1 to -7 indicate negative perception of improvement (worsening of condition), a 0 indicates no change, and scores of +1 through +7 indicate a positive perceived improvement in the patients condition.</description>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="37"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="37"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="16"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="15"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Self-Motivation Inventory</title>
        <description>The Self-Motivation Inventory is an outcome measure that was developed to determine level of motivation. The Self-Motivation Inventory is a 40-item tool that has been found to measure an individual's tendency to persevere independent of situational reinforcement. It has also been used to predict successful weight loss and may correlate with number of sessions attended in weight loss program [29]. This tool underwent refinement in 1980 with the original 60-item tool being tested in undergraduate male and females. Items correlating less than 0.30 were deleted. The final 40-item scale yielded an exceptionally high internal reliability (α = 0.91) suggesting that a unitary common concept is evident for the obtained factor structure. The tool is widely used and has been tested in weight loss and therapeutic exercise studies</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
      </outcome>
      <outcome>
        <type>Other Pre-specified</type>
        <title>Changes From Baseline Pain Catastrophizing Scale at 24 Months</title>
        <description>The PCS is a 13-item patient-report scale developed to measure the extent to which people catastrophize in response to pain. Each item is scored from 0 ('not at all') to 4 ('all the time'). The PCS is reported as a total score, with higher scores indicating greater catastrophizing, and is composed of three sub-scales: Rumination (four items; e.g. 'When I am in pain, I keep thinking about how badly I want the pain to stop'), Magnification (three items; e.g. 'When I am in pain, I become afraid that the pain will get worse'), and Helplessness (six items; e.g. 'When I am in pain, I feel I can't go on'). The PCS has been shown to have high levels of internal consistency and construct validity.</description>
        <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Arthroscopic Surgery</title>
          <description>Arthroscopic surgery at the femoroacetabular joint, followed by a standardized post-operative rehabilitation protocol in physical therapy.&#xD;
Arthroscopic Surgery: The hip arthroscopy will consist of acetabular rim trimming, labral repair or debridement and femoroplasty, all as indicated based on the surgeon's clinical judgment with input from pre-operative imaging, exam findings and intra-operative findings.</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Physical Therapy</title>
          <description>An impairment-based supervised in-clinic physical therapy program.&#xD;
Physical Therapy: Subjects will participate in two 45-minute sessions for six weeks (total of 12 sessions). The physical therapy treatment plan will be based on individual impairments identified during the initial evaluation, and include manual therapy to the hip, lumbar spine, and pelvis, as well as therapeutic exercise all tailored to individual patient impairments.</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="1" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <default_assessment>Systematic Assessment</default_assessment>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
          <category>
            <title>Injury, poisoning and procedural complications</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Surgical complication</sub_title>
                <description>Heterotopic ossification or femur fracture</description>
                <counts group_id="E1" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" events="2" subjects_affected="2" subjects_at_risk="40"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Daniel Rhon</name_or_title>
      <organization>Madigan Army Medical Center</organization>
      <phone>253-968-0780</phone>
      <email>daniel.i.rhon.ctr@mail.mil</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

