<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03423368</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>POLI-14-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03423368</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Policaptil Gel Retard® in Overweight and Mild Obese Subjects</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of the Effects of Policaptil Gel Retard® on the Glycemic, Lipid and Weight Profile in Overweight and Mild Obese Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aboca Spa Societa' Agricola</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sprim Advanced Life Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aboca Spa Societa' Agricola</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, double blind, placebo controlled, interventional clinical study aimed&#xD;
      at evaluating the effects of the medical device Libramed (Policaptil Gel Retard®) on the&#xD;
      glycemic, lipid and weight profile in overweight and mild obese subjects&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, double blind, placebo controlled, interventional clinical study on a&#xD;
      medical device Visit schedule V1 (day -25) - Screening Visit During this visit (V1) the&#xD;
      Investigator will collect information regarding the medical history, the demography, the&#xD;
      concomitant medications. The eligibility criteria (inclusion and exclusion criteria) will be&#xD;
      verified and during this visit the subjects who will meet the eligibility criteria will be&#xD;
      enrolled after the signature of the informed consent form. Each subject will be informed&#xD;
      verbally and in writing about the nature and all the requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A brief clinical examination will be performed, including evaluation of vital signs (pulse,&#xD;
      systolic and diastolic pressure) and anthropometric parameters (body weight, height, BMI,&#xD;
      waist circumference, waist-to-hip and waist-to-height ratio).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine samples will be collected for safety routine analysis and for specific&#xD;
      analysis to test liver and kidney functionality, glycemic and lipid profile (i.e. glycemic /&#xD;
      lipid markers values). An Oral Glucose Tolerance Test (OGTT) will be also performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A diary will be given to each subject to record their daily food intake (they will be asked&#xD;
      to avoid some food and food supplements/ingredients) and physical activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The next visit will be scheduled after 15 days. V2 (day -10) - postprandial metabolic profile&#xD;
      short-term assessment - Policaptil Gel Retard® intake During this visit the Investigators&#xD;
      will perform a brief clinical examination evaluating pulse, systolic and diastolic pressure&#xD;
      and anthropometric parameters; a confirmation of eligibility will take place, on the basis of&#xD;
      laboratory tests results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A blood sample will be collected (t0) and then, after the intake of a standard dosage of&#xD;
      Libramed®, a standard meal will be supplied. In order to record the postprandial metabolic&#xD;
      profile blood samples will be collected 8 times: 30, 60, 90, 120, 150, 180, 240 and 300&#xD;
      minutes after the meal (t1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 and 8) to evaluate the postprandial glycemic and&#xD;
      lipid profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the first 10 subjects enrolled additional 2 ml of blood will be collected to evaluate&#xD;
      VLDL, IDL, LDL, HDL by Density Gradient Ultracentrifugation (DGU). This analysis will be&#xD;
      performed at Clinica Medica I, Azienda Ospedaliera di Padova.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on adverse events and concomitant medications will be collected and recorded by&#xD;
      the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjective appetite will be assessed using 100mm VASs that will have to be completed&#xD;
      before Libramed®, before meal and 150 minutes after consumption of meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The next visit will be scheduled after 10 days. V3 (day 0) - postprandial metabolic profile&#xD;
      short-term assessment - placebo and baseline / randomization During this visit the&#xD;
      Investigators will perform a brief clinical examination evaluating pulse, systolic and&#xD;
      diastolic pressure and anthropometric parameters; whole-body fat mass (through DXA technique)&#xD;
      will be also evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A blood sample will be collected (t0) and then, after the intake of a standard dosage of&#xD;
      placebo, a standard meal will be supplied. In order to record the postprandial metabolic&#xD;
      profile blood samples will be collected 8 times: 30, 60, 90, 120, 150, 180, 240 and 300&#xD;
      minutes after the meal (t1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7 and 8) to evaluate the postprandial glycemic and&#xD;
      lipid profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the first 10 subjects enrolled additional 2 ml of blood will be collected to evaluate&#xD;
      VLDL, IDL, LDL, HDL by Density Gradient Ultracentrifugation (DGU).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover a blood sample will be collected in the fasting state for specific analysis to test&#xD;
      liver and kidney functionality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjective appetite will be assessed using 100mm VASs that will have to be completed&#xD;
      before Libramed® or placebo, before meal and 150 minutes after consumption of meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All eligible subjects will be randomized to Policaptil Gel Retard® or placebo and a diet to&#xD;
      be followed will be given and explained by a dietitian to all the participants. The daily&#xD;
      dietary intake of participants during the intervention period will be set to 1200, 1500 or&#xD;
      1800 Kcal/day depending on the nutritional need of each participant (basal energy&#xD;
      expenditure), calculated by means of the Harris Benedict equation (see the protocol for&#xD;
      details). They will be asked also to make a daily walk (7000-10000 steps average, to be&#xD;
      counted by a pedometer that they will be given too).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects will be given enough study product, according to randomization, to reach the&#xD;
      following visit. Moreover a new diary will be given to each subject and the old one will be&#xD;
      collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on adverse events and concomitant medications will be collected and recorded by&#xD;
      the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The next visit will be scheduled after 30 days. V4 (day 30) - end of treatment visit and&#xD;
      postprandial metabolic profile long-term assessment - treatment During this visit the&#xD;
      Investigators will perform a brief clinical examination evaluating pulse, systolic and&#xD;
      diastolic pressure and anthropometric parameters; whole-body fat mass (through DXA technique)&#xD;
      will be also evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A blood sample will be collected (t0) and then, after the intake of a standard dosage of&#xD;
      placebo or Policaptil Gel Retard®, according to randomization, a standard meal will be&#xD;
      supplied. In order to record the postprandial metabolic profile blood samples will be&#xD;
      collected 8 times: 30, 60, 90, 120, 150, 180, 240 and 300 minutes after the meal (t1, 2, 3,&#xD;
      4, 5, 6, 7 and 8) to evaluate the postprandial glycemic and lipid profile. Moreover blood&#xD;
      samples will be collected in the fasting state for specific analysis to test liver and kidney&#xD;
      functionality, for safety routine analysis (also urine sample) and for specific analysis to&#xD;
      test liver and kidney functionality.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjective appetite will be assessed using 100mm VASs that will have to be completed&#xD;
      before Libramed® or placebo, before meal and 150 minutes after consumption of meal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on adverse events and concomitant medications will be collected and recorded by&#xD;
      the investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The diaries and all the unused or empty containers of the study products will have to be&#xD;
      brought back to the center, in order to evaluate the subject's adherence to the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A phone call will be scheduled after 7 days. Follow-up (day 37) A phone contact will take&#xD;
      place to assess the safety profile (AE/SAE will be evaluated). Information on concomitant&#xD;
      medications and a confirmation about dietary restrictions will be collected and recorded.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 26, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 9, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 22, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of changes in the postprandial glycemic profile - V4 versus V3 - OGTT</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>OGTT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of changes in the postprandial glycemic profile - V4 versus V3 - fasting insulin</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HOMA index and HbA1c values evaluation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of changes in the postprandial glycemic profile - V4 versus V3 - HOMA index</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HOMA index</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of changes in the postprandial glycemic profile - V4 versus V3 - HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial lipid profile - V4 versus V3</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Total cholesterol, LDL-cholesterol, HDL-cholesterol, triglycerides, Apo-B</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial glycemic profile after a single consumption of the product - V2 versus V3 - OGTT</measure>
    <time_frame>day -10 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>OGTT</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial glycemic profile after a single consumption of the product - V2 versus V3 - fasting insulin</measure>
    <time_frame>day -10 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>fasting insulin</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial glycemic profile after a single consumption of the product - V2 versus V3 - HOMA index</measure>
    <time_frame>day -10 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HOMA index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial glycemic profile after a single consumption of the product - V2 versus V3 - HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>day -10 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>HbA1c</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postprandial lipid profile after a single consumption of the product - V2 versus V3</measure>
    <time_frame>day -10 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Total cholesterol, LDL-cholesterol, HDL-cholesterol, triglycerides, Apo-B</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anthropometric parameters - body weight</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>body weight</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anthropometric parameters - BMI</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>body mass index - BMI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anthropometric parameters -Waist circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Waist circumference</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anthropometric parameters - waist-to-hip ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>waist-to-hip ratio</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anthropometric parameters - waist-to-height ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>waist-to-height ratio</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic /diastolic blood pressure - V4 versus V3</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of changes in the systolic /diastolic blood pressure - V4 versus V3 - comparison between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dual energy X-ray absorptiometry - V4 versus V3</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Measurement of whole-body fat mass, through dual energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) technique (Noakes et al., 2006; Frestedt et al., 2008) - V4 versus V3 - comparison between groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feeling of hunger and feeling of appetite - V4 versus V3</measure>
    <time_frame>day 30 Vs. day 0</time_frame>
    <description>100-mm Visual Analog Scale (VAS) evaluation. From 0 (very strong hunger feeling) to 100 (very weak hunger feeling)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">67</enrollment>
  <condition>Overweight and Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Libramed</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each patient will be admistered 6 tablets/day (3 tablets before lunch, 3 tablets before dinner) of Libramed for 30 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Each patient will be admistered 6 tablets/day (3 tablets before lunch, 3 tablets before dinner) of placebo for 30 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Libramed</intervention_name>
    <description>Policaptil Gel Retard</description>
    <arm_group_label>Libramed</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo-comparator</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female subjects 18 - 60 years old (18 and 60 included).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI ≥ 25 Kg/m2 and ≤ 34.9 Kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable body weight for the 3 months before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability of the participant (in the investigator's opinion) to comprehend the full&#xD;
             nature and purpose of the study including possible risks and side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who agree not to alter their diet in any way for the duration of the trial&#xD;
             and to maintain it at steady state (according to the forbidden food ingredients or&#xD;
             supplements, that have to be avoided, as outlined in the study protocol), apart from&#xD;
             the Treatment Period, during which they agree to follow the assigned diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who agree not to make any major lifestyle changes (e.g. changing their&#xD;
             exercise pattern, except as for what specified in the protocol for the Treatment&#xD;
             Period) during the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent to the study and willing to comply with all its procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postmenopausal women i.e. women who have not experienced a menstrual bleed for a&#xD;
             minimum of 12 months or women who have undergone surgical sterilization (tubal closure&#xD;
             or ovaries removal). Otherwise, necessity for women of childbearing potential to&#xD;
             follow a reliable contraceptive treatment.Contraceptive treatments deemed as reliable&#xD;
             for the study purposes are the following: hormonal contraceptives (pill, patch,&#xD;
             vaginal ring), intrauterine devices (IUD), subcutaneous implants; barrier systems as&#xD;
             condoms or diaphragm and methods based on the recognition of fertility from an&#xD;
             hormonal point of view.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastrointestinal disorders (i.e. gastric ulcer, Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) /&#xD;
             Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS)),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled hypertension (defined as systolic blood pressure ≥180mmHg and / or&#xD;
             diastolic blood pressure ≥100mmHg),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes as defined by international criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic liver disease with increased serum transaminase levels (SGOT and / or SGPT &gt; 2&#xD;
             UNL).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Thyroid disorders (i.e. hyperthyroidism or hypothyroidism).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired renal function defined as estimated glomerular filtration rate (e-GFR)&#xD;
             &lt;60mL/min/1.73m2 according to Modification of Diet in renal Disease (MDRD) formula due&#xD;
             to kidney failure or kidney disease / disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood disorders (i.e. anemia) or subjects who donated their blood within 1 month prior&#xD;
             to enrolment or had an important blood loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any chronic disorder or severe disease which, in the opinion of the investigator,&#xD;
             might jeopardise subject's safety, compliance with the protocol and/or ability to&#xD;
             complete the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous gastrointestinal surgery except for appendectomy, hernia surgery,&#xD;
             polypectomy, biopsies, colonic and gastric endoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of alcohol, drug or medication abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or intolerance to the ingredients contained in the test product&#xD;
             or the placebo; celiac subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects breastfeeding, pregnant, or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of eating disorder (anorexia, bulimia, binge eating disorder).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have taken anti-obesity medication (Orlistat) or food supplements or&#xD;
             natural health products taken with the aim to lose weight over the 2 months prior to&#xD;
             entry into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prokinetic drugs cannot be started during the study period (included the follow-up&#xD;
             period).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following treatments cannot be started during the study period (included the&#xD;
             follow-up period) and the treatment with one of these treatments should be started at&#xD;
             least 3 months prior to the beginning of the study at a stable dosage: -&#xD;
             pharmacological treatment for dyslipidemia [(3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A&#xD;
             (HMG-CoA) reductase inhibitors (the &quot;statins&quot;), fibrates (gemfibrozil, clofibrate and&#xD;
             fenofibrate), niacin/nicotinic acid, bile acid binding resins (colestipol and&#xD;
             cholestyramine)], antidepressant such as fluoxetine and bupropion, diuretics&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Padova</name>
      <address>
        <city>Padova</city>
        <zip>35128</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.aboca.com/it/i-nostri-prodotti/fitomagra-libramed</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 15, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 31, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 6, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 12, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 12, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 13, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Libramed</keyword>
  <keyword>Policaptil Gel Retard</keyword>
  <keyword>Overweight</keyword>
  <keyword>Obesity</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical Device</keyword>
  <keyword>glycemic profile</keyword>
  <keyword>lipid profile</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

