<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03421613</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3VM0416</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03421613</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>3VM1001 Cream for the Treatment of Pain Associated With Post Herpetic Neuralgia (PHN)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PHN</acronym>
  <official_title>A Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Crossover Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Tolerability of 3VM1001 Cream for the Treatment of Pain Associated With Post-Herpetic Neuralgia: A Proof of Concept Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>CDA Research Group, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>CDA Research Group, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Post-herpetic neuralgia (PHN) is pain following acute herpes zoster; defined as pain lasting&#xD;
      longer than 3 months. Current first line management consists of tricyclic anti-depressants&#xD;
      and anti-convulsants such as gabapentin and pregabalin. There is an unmet medical need for&#xD;
      treatments got topical therapies that demonstrate efficacy without serious side effects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Post-herpetic neuralgia (PHN) is defined as pain following acute herpes zoster (AHZ) lasting&#xD;
      &gt;3 months. PHN develops in about 10% of patients following an episode of AHZ. 95% of adults&#xD;
      ate seropositive for varicella zoster virus antibodies, and are, therefore, at risk for AHZ&#xD;
      and PHN. Wider use of AHZ vaccine approved in 2006 may reduce the incidence of PHN.&#xD;
      Nevertheless, PHN may be severe and frequently interferes with daily activities and with&#xD;
      sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
      First line management of PHN pain currently is tricyclic anti-depressants and&#xD;
      anti-convulsants such as gabapentin and pregabalin, and use of a 5% lidocaine patch. second&#xD;
      line therapies include opioid analgesia and topical capsaicin: combinations of topical and&#xD;
      systemic therapies may be used as well. These therapies have common side effects of dry&#xD;
      mouth, constipation, sedation, urinary retention, nausea, somnolence, dizziness, weight gain&#xD;
      and peripheral edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
      there is an unmet medial need for topical therapies that demonstrate efficacy without the&#xD;
      significant side effects o the therapies mentioned above. 3VM cream, a low concentration of&#xD;
      copper in a cream vehicle may b such a therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 6, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 4, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 30, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Crossover study to evaluate treatment and tolerability of the experimental product for treatment of post herpetic pain.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Subjects will be randomized to receive either treatment wih 3VM1001 cream or the comparator daily for 10 days followed by 5 day wash out period before 10 days of treatment with the comparator or investigational treatment, .</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The time averaged mean in a standard 100 mm visual analog scale (VAS).</measure>
    <time_frame>25 days total</time_frame>
    <description>The time averaged mean of all patient pain scores over each study period; trend over time for each treatment sill be assessed by day of therapy to evaluate any increase or decrease in effect for each study treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events, serious adverse events, and study discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>25 days total</time_frame>
    <description>Collection of adverse events and the number of subjects discontinuing he study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Global Expression of change Scale (PGIC) from baseline (day 0) to the end of each study period.</measure>
    <time_frame>25 days total</time_frame>
    <description>This measure is a single-item rating by participants of their improvement with treatment on a 7-point sale that ranges from &quot;very much improved&quot; to very much worse&quot; with &quot;no change &quot;the mid-midpoint&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Patient Global Assessment of Treatment Satisfaction from baseline to the end of each study phase.</measure>
    <time_frame>25 days total</time_frame>
    <description>Patient Global Assessment of Treatment Satisfaction from baseline to the end of each study phase. Patients will rate their overall satisfaction with study treatment using a 5-point categorical scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of Rescue medication</measure>
    <time_frame>25 days total</time_frame>
    <description>recording of the use of rescue mediation at each phase of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Treatment of PHN</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3VM1001 cream</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be randomized to self treat with 2 g of VM1001 cream times daily for ten days, have a five day wash out period and then 10 days of self treatment with the comparator.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be randomized to self treat with either active product or placebo comparator thrice daily for 10 days followed by a 5 day wash out period then 10 days of experimental treatment thrice daily for 20 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3VM1001</intervention_name>
    <description>Self treatment 3 times daily for 10 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>3VM1001 cream</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Cream without investigational drug. Self treatment 3 times daily for 10 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of PHN for &gt;3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent pain for more than 6 months from appearance of herpes zoster rash that is&#xD;
             not located above the scalp hairline, or in immediate proximity to mucous membranes&#xD;
             (given the low toxicity of copper, PHN affecting the face and neck will be included,&#xD;
             but subjects will be trained on avoidance of contact with the eyes or mouth);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years or older;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males or females of non-childbearing potential (i.e., 12 months or more of spontaneous&#xD;
             amenorrhea, bilateral oophorectomy at least 6 months prior to randomization,&#xD;
             hysterectomy with bilateral oophorectomy at least 6 months prior to randomization, or&#xD;
             for females over 50 years of age, hysterectomy without bilateral oophorectomy at least&#xD;
             6 months prior to randomization); female subjects of childbearing potential must agree&#xD;
             to use contraception (abstinence, birth control pills, rings or patches, diaphragm and&#xD;
             spermicide, intrauterine device, condom and vaginal spermicide, surgical&#xD;
             sterilization, vasectomy, progestin implant or injection); female partners of&#xD;
             childbearing potential of male subjects must agree to use contraception as defined&#xD;
             above;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent neuropathic pain that involves at least 1 dermatome and covering no more&#xD;
             than 400 cm2 (the target area);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain intensity in the target area of &gt; 40mm on a 100mm VAS at screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intact skin over the target area to be treated;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject agrees to take only the protocol-defined rescue medication as prescribed;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All concurrent medications taken for any reason except for the treatment of PHN must&#xD;
             be stable (dose, frequency) for 14 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to follow protocol with reference to cognitive and situational factors (eg.&#xD;
             stable housing, ability to attend visits);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to read and write English;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to apply cream without assistance;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with systemic disease that would put him/her at an additional risk or limit&#xD;
             his/her ability to participate in the study in the opinion of the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with known history of human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis C, or hepatitis&#xD;
             B;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignancy other than basal cell carcinoma and carcinoma in situ within the past 2&#xD;
             years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who has an active history of alcohol or drug abuse;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Wilson's disease or other known disorder of copper metabolism;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or allergy to any component of the product, or to acetaminophen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and breastfeeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with active herpes zoster lesions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with open skin lesions or skin infections in the target area, or conditions&#xD;
             over the target area such as eczema or psoriasis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mild pain in the target area, characterized by VAS score of &lt; 40 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain in any other part of the body that could interfere with the patient's assessment&#xD;
             of pain in the target area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who has taken concomitant medications for the treatment of PHN (except&#xD;
             acetaminophen or gabapentin) in the last four weeks. If taking gabapentin the dose&#xD;
             must have been stable for at least four weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with local anesthetic or steroids (including lidocaine patch, transcutaneous&#xD;
             electrical nerve stimulation, etc.) in the last 2 weeks or nerve blocks within the&#xD;
             last 30 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who has used capsaicin preparations on a regular basis in the 90 days prior to&#xD;
             screening and at all in the past two weeks;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of prohibited concomitant medications/therapies;&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Devices or therapeutic treatments for pain apart from acetaminophen as a rescue&#xD;
                  medication&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Systemic corticosteroids&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Other Investigational Drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Chemotherapeutic drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Immunotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Topical products applied to the target skin area&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject with history of serious mental illness or psychiatric illness such as&#xD;
             dementia, depression, or schizophrenia, that will limit his/her ability to comply with&#xD;
             study procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who is unable to apply, or have a care giver apply, study ointment to the area&#xD;
             of most painful skin segments, three times daily, once within 2 hours of waking, once&#xD;
             mid-afternoon, and once prior to bedtime;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who has participated in any other investigational study within 60 days prior&#xD;
             to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who is employed by the Sponsor, study staff, and their families; or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject who has any condition that would make him/her, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator or Sponsor, unsuitable for the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medex Healthcare Research, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60602</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medex Healthcare Reasearch, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10036</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 30, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 30, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 9, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 9, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 10, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>PHN, acute, herpes zoster</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia, Postherpetic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

