<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02851290</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-38540</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02851290</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Caudal and Penile Block on Hypospadias Repair Complications</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Caudal and Penile Block on Hypospadias Repair Complications</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Baylor College of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Baylor College of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Hypospadias is one of the most common genitourinary (GU) malformations, seen in approximately&#xD;
      1 of 250 male live births. Common methods of local anesthesia administration for hypospadias&#xD;
      surgery include caudal and dorsal penile nerve blocks. While both methods are known to be&#xD;
      effective with minimal risk, the effect on post-operative complications is not&#xD;
      well-established. The purpose of this randomized controlled trial is to evaluate if caudal&#xD;
      versus dorsal penile nerve block results in higher rates of post-operative complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hypospadias is a one of the most common genitourinary (GU) malformations, seen in&#xD;
      approximately 1 of 250 male live births, characterized by proximal location of the urethral&#xD;
      meatus, dorsal hooded foreskin with incomplete ventral fusion, and ventral curvature of the&#xD;
      penis. Hypospadias repair includes several standard steps including urethroplasty,&#xD;
      mobilization of adjacent flaps for urethroplasty coverage, rotation of penile skin flaps and&#xD;
      circumcision. In order for the surgeon to operate in a clean and relatively bloodless field,&#xD;
      tourniquets and local epinephrine injection have been used. In a rabbit hypospadias repair&#xD;
      model, the authors used both tourniquet and local epinephrine infiltration to maintain a&#xD;
      clear surgical field, and showed increased apoptotic urethral myocytes on TUNNEL assay and&#xD;
      collagen deposition in the epinephrine cohort. The study also showed structural changes in&#xD;
      the mitochondria on scanning electron microscopy in the epinephrine cohort. This is the only&#xD;
      hypospadias study demonstrating pathologic changes in the urethra after tourniquet or&#xD;
      epinephrine injection. While single stage hypospadias surgical techniques have standardized&#xD;
      significantly over the two decades, surgical complications can still occur in up to 28% of&#xD;
      patients. Complications include urethrocutaneous fistulas, meatal stenosis, glans dehiscence,&#xD;
      urethral strictures, and urethral diverticulum. Risk factors for hypospadias surgical&#xD;
      complications have been extensively published and include: proximal urethral location,&#xD;
      previous operation, glans width &lt;14 mm, no urethroplasty coverage layers, surgeon learning&#xD;
      curve, and age &lt;4 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The majority of hypospadias surgical complications need to be revised surgically and this&#xD;
      results in significant financial and emotional burden for the family. The financial impact of&#xD;
      hypospadias visits, repairs, and reoperations on society is largely unknown. A single study&#xD;
      in 2000 noted that $16.6 million was spent on operative and outpatient hypospadias care and&#xD;
      17,000 total outpatient hypospadias visits were made that year. No recent studies are&#xD;
      available and the cost to the patient per surgery and per surgical complication repair is&#xD;
      also unknown. Multiple objective hypospadias surgical questionnaires have been developed to&#xD;
      characterize postoperative appearance of the skin, meatus, urinary stream, and presence of&#xD;
      fistula. These studies have only been validated by the same institution and data correlating&#xD;
      questionnaire scores to complications is sparse.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Penile sensation is derived primarily from the dorsal nerve of the penis. Ventrally there is&#xD;
      some innervation to the frenulum that is derived from the perineal nerve branches. The dorsal&#xD;
      nerve of the penis is a branch of the pudendal nerve which is supplied from sacral nerves.&#xD;
      Common methods for penile block, which are performed by the hypospadias surgeon, include&#xD;
      dorsal nerve penile block (DNPB) or penile ring block. The DNPB involves infiltration of&#xD;
      local anesthetic using a short beveled needle in the subpubic location at the 10 and 2&#xD;
      o'clock positions such that the dorsal nerve of the penis is blocked as it enters the base of&#xD;
      the penis. The penile ring block is performed by infiltration of local anesthetic in the&#xD;
      subcutaneous tissue at the base of the penis. One prospective study showed that DNPB was&#xD;
      significantly better than ring block. Success rates of DNPB have been noted to be anywhere&#xD;
      from 90-100% in children undergoing circumcision. Complications from DNPB are exceptionally&#xD;
      rare at &lt;0.1% including hematoma and local tissue edema.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Caudal block is a commonly performed regional block by anesthesiologists for hypospadias&#xD;
      surgery. It involves blockade of the same nerve pathway described above, at a more proximal&#xD;
      location, by infiltration of the caudal epidural space through the sacral hiatus. The&#xD;
      procedure is performed usually in the lateral position. Anatomic landmarks are defined by an&#xD;
      equilateral triangle formed by the bilateral posterior superior iliac spines, and the sacral&#xD;
      hiatus. Initially a short beveled needle or small gauge angiocatheter is inserted into the&#xD;
      sacral hiatus at a 45 degree angle and then once a &quot;pop&quot; is heard, the angle is &quot;dropped&quot; to&#xD;
      0 degrees and the needle is advanced. Aspiration is performed and in the absence of&#xD;
      cerebrospinal fluid or blood, a local anesthetic is injected. Complications are exceptionally&#xD;
      rare at the rate of &lt;0.003% and include local anesthetic toxicity, neurological injury or&#xD;
      infection and success rates of up to 96% have been reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Penile physiology and blood flow parameters after DNPB and caudal block are largely unknown.&#xD;
      Very few studies show the effects of distal organ perfusion after regional blockade. One&#xD;
      study looking at children undergoing caudal block for urologic procedures found that caudal&#xD;
      block using 1.5 ml/kg of 0.15% ropivicaine increased the dorsalis pedis arterial parameters:&#xD;
      increased peak velocity 24%, volume flow 76%, arterial diameter 20%. The authors proposed a&#xD;
      sympatholytic mechanism as the reason for these physiologic changes. Another randomized&#xD;
      controlled trial primarily looking at post-operative pain outcomes in hypospadias repair&#xD;
      patients also found increased penile volumes of 27% in the caudal block arm, with the&#xD;
      proposed mechanism also being sympatholytic. Finally, there have been case reports in which&#xD;
      the sympatholytic effects of caudal blocks are used to treat glans ischemia after&#xD;
      circumcision.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Penile analgesia after caudal block is approximately equal to that of DNPB. A meta-analysis&#xD;
      of the circumcision analgesia literature, analyzing over 700 patients showed analgesic&#xD;
      equivalence of caudal versus parenteral analgesia. Also in the meta-analysis, caudal block&#xD;
      was found to be equivalent to DNPB with increased motor blockade found in the caudal block&#xD;
      arm. One randomized controlled trial assessing analgesia requirements in children undergoing&#xD;
      hypospadias repair after caudal block and penile block found that penile block resulted in&#xD;
      superior pain control. However, another randomized controlled trial found that caudal block&#xD;
      resulted in superior pain control as compared to penile block. After either bock, there are&#xD;
      usually no significant alterations in mean arterial pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, the association between caudal block and hypospadias surgical complications has&#xD;
      been theorized and has drawn international interest amongst pediatric urologists and&#xD;
      anesthesiologists. A randomized controlled trial of 54 distal hypospadias repair patients,&#xD;
      half assigned to caudal block and half to penile block, showed that all urethrocutaneous&#xD;
      fistulas were seen in the caudal block arm. Even though the primary outcome was&#xD;
      post-operative pain control between the groups, the authors theorized that caudal blocks lead&#xD;
      to sympathetic blockade, penile engorgement, tissue edema, and increased hypospadias surgical&#xD;
      complications. A nested case control series comparing 45 fistulas and 90 controls showed no&#xD;
      association between fistulas and caudal block. The authors found fistula to be associated&#xD;
      with proximal urethral location, penile epinephrine injection, and longer operative times.&#xD;
      Unpublished data presented at the 2015 American Urologic Association in New Orleans by Routh&#xD;
      et al. showed that in a retrospective single surgeon series of 452 primary hypospadias repair&#xD;
      patients, half which had caudal block and half which had penile block, caudal blockade was&#xD;
      highly associated with hypospadias surgical complications even after adjusting for operative&#xD;
      time (OR 3.9 (1.3-12.1)); p= 0.0008. This is the only study to date that has been powered&#xD;
      appropriately to assess the association between caudal block and hypospadias complications.&#xD;
      Thus, there is clinical equipoise regarding the utilization of caudal block versus penile&#xD;
      block for post-operative pain control and also in minimizing surgical complications in&#xD;
      hypospadias repair.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative hypospadias repair complications</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Post-operative follow-up to evaluate for post-operative complications including urethrocutaneous fistula, glans dehiscence, meatal stenosis, and urethral stricture</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-operative hypospadias repair pain</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Post-operative pain will be assessed using the FLACC scale (faces, legs, activity, cry and consolability scale)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Caudal block-related complications</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Complications related to caudal block</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dorsal penile nerve block-related complications</measure>
    <time_frame>1 hour post-operatively</time_frame>
    <description>Complications related to dorsal penile nerve block</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">66</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypospadias</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Caudal block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Local anesthetic will be administered into the caudal space</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dorsal penile nerve block</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Local anesthetic will be administered around the dorsal penile nerve</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Caudal block anesthesia</intervention_name>
    <description>After induction of general anesthesia, a caudal block will be performed using 0.75-1 mL/kg of 0.2% ropivacaine without epinephrine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Caudal block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dorsal penile nerve block anesthesia</intervention_name>
    <description>After induction of general anesthesia, a dorsal penile nerve block will be performed using 0.75-1 mL/kg of 0.2% ropivacaine without epinephrine</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dorsal penile nerve block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 4 months to 4 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA score I and II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary hypospadias repair in one stage including distal, midshaft, and proximal&#xD;
             repairs&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt;4 months or &gt;4 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA score &gt;II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Genetic syndromes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous hypospadias operations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staged hypospadias repair operations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Spinal dysraphism or other contraindications to caudal block&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infection at the block site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal of consent by the parents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness of the anesthesiologist or surgeon to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>4 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicolette K Janzen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Texas Children's Hospital/Baylor College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kara Toman, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Texas Children's Hospital/Baylor College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 28, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 1, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nicolette Janzen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor Pediatric Urology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hypospadias</keyword>
  <keyword>Caudal block</keyword>
  <keyword>Dorsal penile nerve block</keyword>
  <keyword>Anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>Urethrocutaneous fistula</keyword>
  <keyword>Urethral stricture</keyword>
  <keyword>Meatal stenosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Glanular dehiscence</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypospadias</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anesthetics</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

