<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02647073</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H15-02986</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02647073</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Mobile Monitoring of Vital Signs in Opioid Users</brief_title>
  <acronym>MOVE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Pilot Study to Evaluate the Feasibility of Mobile Monitoring of Vital Signs in Opioid Users</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Opioid dependence and its associated harms are becoming increasingly prevalent in North&#xD;
      America, with overdose now being the second leading cause of accidental death in the US. This&#xD;
      pilot study will investigate the feasibility of a novel mobile device to monitor vital signs&#xD;
      in both opioid-injecting individuals and hospital inpatients who are on high-dose oral&#xD;
      opioids. A secondary goal is to explore associations between consumption and changes in vital&#xD;
      signs post-injection with the long-term goal of developing a mobile system that will alert&#xD;
      clinicians when patients are at risk of overdose so that appropriate interventions can be&#xD;
      delivered in time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. PURPOSE The purpose of the pilot study is to assess feasibility of a novel device&#xD;
           (Canary 01 Mobile Vital Signs Monitoring Device) in individuals who inject opioids and&#xD;
           in hospital inpatients who are on high-dose oral opioid medications. The primary&#xD;
           objectives are to evaluate if the device can reliably and comfortably be worn for an&#xD;
           extended duration of time following opioid consumption and can accurately monitor&#xD;
           changes in vital signs (electrocardiogram (ECG), heart rate, respiratory rate) in this&#xD;
           clinical population and setting. A secondary purpose of the study is to enrich our&#xD;
           understanding of changes in vital signs that occur post-opioid-consumption. The&#xD;
           long-term goal of the study is to create a device that will allow clinicians and&#xD;
           patients to detect adverse effects of opioid consumption early (i.e. respiratory&#xD;
           depression), so that appropriate treatment interventions can be delivered to prevent&#xD;
           overdose-related morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. HYPOTHESES The team hypothesizes that the Canary 01 Mobile Vital Signs Monitoring Device&#xD;
           will prove to be a feasible and reliable device for monitoring vital signs before and&#xD;
           after consumption of opioids, among individuals who inject opioids and among individuals&#xD;
           who are on high doses of opioid medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. JUSTIFICATION Opioid medications are key agents for treating acute pain, cancer pain,&#xD;
           and are deemed to be essential medicines for pain care by the World Health Organization.&#xD;
           However, opioid medications have a serious side effect profile including contributing to&#xD;
           delirium, oversedation and respiratory depression in the event of overdose. Between 2005&#xD;
           and 2009, there were 815 deaths related to fentanyl, hydromorphone, morphine and&#xD;
           oxycodone in British Columbia. Opioid overdose is now the second leading cause of&#xD;
           accidental death in the United States.&#xD;
&#xD;
           In addition to adverse events, opioids are known to be highly addictive. In Canada,&#xD;
           there were an estimated 75,000-125,000 injection drug users (the vast majority of them&#xD;
           who injected opioids) as well as approximately 200,000 people with prescription opioid&#xD;
           dependence, as of 2012.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Knowledge gained in this innovative pilot study will inform development of a mobile&#xD;
           monitoring device designed to alert clinicians of cardiopulmonary changes indicating&#xD;
           opioid overdose in patients, allowing for rapid detection, intervention and&#xD;
           administration of potentially life-saving treatment. Ultimately, clinical implementation&#xD;
           of this device could lead to a reduction in the substantial morbidity and mortality&#xD;
           attributable to opioid-related overdoses.&#xD;
&#xD;
           In addition, through fulfillment of our secondary objective, this feasibility study will&#xD;
           contribute new knowledge regarding changes in cardiopulmonary status associated with use&#xD;
           of high opioid doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective To determine whether a mobile monitoring system for specific vital signs&#xD;
      (e.g., heart rate and respiratory rate) can be used successfully in the monitoring of opioid&#xD;
      dependent individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specifically, the study team will examine:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Participant compliance;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Feasibility of specific vital sign data collection, storage, and analysis for&#xD;
           participant status assessment; and&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Clinical utility and overall participant and provider acceptability of mobile monitoring&#xD;
           devices&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objective To document and characterize changes in cardiopulmonary status associated&#xD;
      with opioid consumption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5) RESEARCH METHOD The MOVE study is a single site, three-week feasibility study of&#xD;
      individuals who report ongoing/current injection opioid use. Potential study participants&#xD;
      will be recruited from the Providence Crosstown Clinic and St. Paul's Hospital. The target&#xD;
      enrolment goal is 25.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the study recruitment sites, potential study candidates will be invited to participate,&#xD;
      provide informed consent and complete the Screening Visit (Visit 1) in order to assess&#xD;
      eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once found to be eligible, individuals recruited at the Crosstown Clinic will complete all&#xD;
      other study visits (Visits 2, 3 &amp; 4) at Crosstown Clinic. At Crosstown Clinic, individuals&#xD;
      receive managed treatment for opioid dependence with known quantities of drug (e.g.&#xD;
      diacetylmorphine, hydromorphone). The clinic is staffed with clinicians who are trained and&#xD;
      equipped to deal with any potential opioid overdoses. For hospital inpatients recruited at&#xD;
      St. Paul's Hospital, all study visits will occur in hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be monitored on three separate study visits. At the start of each&#xD;
      session and prior to opioid consumption, the study coordinator will assist with placement of&#xD;
      two mobile monitoring devices on the study participant to measure specific vital signs:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Heart rate and ECG monitor: Heart rate and ECG data will be collected with a compact,&#xD;
           wireless device with 3 leads that are placed on the participant's chest. The leads are&#xD;
           connected to a processor/battery pack unit, approximately the size of a bar of soap.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Respiratory rate will be collected using Respiratory Inductance Plethysmography (RIP)&#xD;
           belts, fastened around the participant's abdomen.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Activity monitoring: An Inertial Measurement Unit (IMU) (gyro) is incorporated within&#xD;
           the device to measure the participant's activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Crosstown Clinic, the participant will receive their managed treatment via self-injection&#xD;
      and will be monitored for a total duration of 120 minutes in a clinic room/post-treatment&#xD;
      room.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At St. Paul's Hospital, the participant will be administered their dose of oral opioid&#xD;
      medications and will be monitored for a duration of 120 minutes ideally at their bedside in&#xD;
      their hospital room and always within their hospital ward.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring devices will be worn for a total duration of 120 minutes. The study coordinator&#xD;
      will remain with the participant throughout the observation period. In addition to vital&#xD;
      signs data, the study coordinator will complete a activity log documenting all activities&#xD;
      that occur during the time that the monitor is in place. In addition any, and all medical&#xD;
      treatments and/or interventions administered during this time will be recorded by members of&#xD;
      the study team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from the mobile monitors will be transmitted via Bluetooth to a smart phone, and then&#xD;
      securely transmitted to the study database. Transmitted data will be coded with the&#xD;
      participant's study identification code only and will not contain any protected health&#xD;
      information and will not be utilized for any clinical decision-making.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is important to highlight that data collected from the mobile monitoring device will&#xD;
      solely be used for research and will not serve any clinical decision-making purpose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be discharged from the study at Visit 4. Participants will be offered&#xD;
      addiction treatment referrals if requested.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety data will be collected up to 30 days following the last study visit and follow-up of&#xD;
      any serious adverse events will continue until resolution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      THE MOBILE VITAL SIGNS MONITORING DEVICE&#xD;
&#xD;
      The prototype has several main components, including several commercially available sensors&#xD;
      to measure heart rate, respiration, and motion data, an enclosed case containing circuitry&#xD;
      for processing and transmitting data, and a mobile phone/system interface to store and&#xD;
      transmit data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data is collected from respiratory bands, ECG electrodes, and an accelerometer. The safety of&#xD;
      individual sensor components has been evaluated previously by respective manufacturers and&#xD;
      all are currently available for commercial purposes. Two respiratory bands, worn on the&#xD;
      thorax and abdomen, will measure patterns and changes in participant breathing patterns.&#xD;
      Although not yet implemented, outputs such as breaths per minute could be extracted from the&#xD;
      data file by using peak finding or frequency analysis software in future. Four ECG electrodes&#xD;
      placed on the participant's thorax and abdomen will record analog voltage changes that&#xD;
      correspond to the electrical potential difference that occur during the cardiac cycle (i.e.&#xD;
      heartbeat). The electrodes are configured in a 3-lead setup, with three signal electrodes and&#xD;
      a driven electrode. In the unlikely event that the device malfunctions, Analog Devices ECG&#xD;
      chips with a current-limiting protection circuit have been used to optimize participant&#xD;
      safety, as per manufacturer specifications. The 3-axis analog accelerometer is sampled at 10&#xD;
      Hz, and used to denote activity and motion artefacts that may influence ECG and respiratory&#xD;
      data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These sensors are attached to a custom printed circuit board (PCB) and a Bluetooth module&#xD;
      inside a 3D printed case. The PCB holds two microprocessors needed for the system: the&#xD;
      PIC16LF1618 and the Broadcom Wireless Internet Connectivity for Embedded Devices (WICED)&#xD;
      Smart. The WICED Smart communicates sensor data to the mobile phone using Bluetooth Low&#xD;
      Energy (BLE). The case holds the circuit boards and a 3.7 V lithium-ion battery; the circuit&#xD;
      boards are screwed into a separate compartment inaccessible to patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The circuit board processes and sends the data to a phone application. Data is then&#xD;
      transferred wirelessly to a Standardized Query Language (SQL) database. Within this database,&#xD;
      each data point is associated with a timestamp and patient Identification (ID), allowing for&#xD;
      multiple patients' data to be stored in the same SQL database. Finally, the battery included&#xD;
      in the case has been tested to last for two days of continuous use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6) STATISTICAL ANALYSIS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Descriptive statistics, including the mean, standard deviation, median and 95% confidence&#xD;
      intervals of the mean for continuous variables, and frequency distribution for categorical&#xD;
      variables will be produced for participant demographics and baseline characteristics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STATISTICAL METHODS FOR PRIMARY AND SECONDARY OUTCOMES&#xD;
&#xD;
      As this is a feasibility study, more complex statistical analyses are not planned.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY ANALYSES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biometric data collected before and after opioid consumption will be compiled and used to&#xD;
      construct preliminary simulation models of average changes in heart rate and respiratory rate&#xD;
      following consumption of high dose opioids. Ultimately, the goal of these modeling exercises&#xD;
      will be to develop a clinical algorithm to be used with the mobile signs monitoring device to&#xD;
      determine thresholds of risk and levels of therapeutic intervention required at each&#xD;
      threshold.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Ongoing issues with the device and software that were provided by the sponsor.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 20, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 20, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Participant compliance: Proportion of participants who wear the device</measure>
    <time_frame>For Visit 2, Visit 3 and Visit 4 (&gt;100 minutes per 120minute session). Visits will take place over an average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants who wear the device for &gt;100 minutes per 120 minute session as reported by participants and observed by the study coordinator/nurse.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility: Proportion of participant sessions with continuous transmission of vital signs data</measure>
    <time_frame>For Visit 2, Visit 3 and Visit 4( &gt;100 minutes per 120 minute session). Visits will take place over an average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participant sessions with continuous transmission of vital signs data for &gt;100 minutes per 120 minute session</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical utility</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion</time_frame>
    <description>Compiled scores and summary data (means, medians, ranges) from participant &amp; clinician usability surveys.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Study retention and drop-out rates</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 3 weeks per participant</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Premature device removal event counts and rates (participant or clinician initiated);</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 3 weeks per participant.</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reliability of device as measured by artefact and transmission failure rates;</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 3 weeks per participant</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Characterization of physiological changes following opioid consumption;</measure>
    <time_frame>For Visit 2, Visit 3 and Visit 4 for 120 minutes. Visits will take place over an average of 3 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>For a subset of participants enrolled in the hospital, accuracy of data recorded by the device in comparison to data collected by bedside monitoring equipment</measure>
    <time_frame>For Visit 2, Visit 3 and Visit 4 at various time points per 120 minute session.Visits will take place over an average of 3 weeks per participant.</time_frame>
    <description>HR and RR</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Opioid Use Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mobile monitoring device arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Canary 01 Mobile Vital Signs Monitoring Device</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Canary 01 Mobile Vital Signs Monitoring Device</intervention_name>
    <description>The prototype has several main components, including several commercially available sensors to measure heart rate, respiration, and motion data, an enclosed case containing circuitry for processing and transmitting data, and a mobile phone/system interface to store and transmit data.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mobile monitoring device arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 19 to 64 years of age, inclusive;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current and ongoing injection drug use with opioids OR hospitalized inpatients under&#xD;
             the care of the St. Paul's Hospital Addiction Medicine Consult Team with current and&#xD;
             ongoing use of high dose oral opioid medications;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current and past history of an opioid use disorder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to communicate in English; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability to provide written informed consent and comply with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to understand study procedures due to changed health and/or mental status;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Chest circumference greater than 115 cm;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has a pacemaker or automatic cardioverter defibrillator (AICD) in situ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Diagnosed with atrial fibrillation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have other medical devices (i.e. insulin pump) that precludes the use of the device;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Allergies or skin conditions that preclude the use of adhesive electrodes; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any other condition that, in the judgment of the investigator, presents a&#xD;
             contraindication to study participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>64 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Keith Ahamad</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Crosstown Community Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V6B 1G8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Paul's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 22, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 4, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 6, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 20, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 20, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 24, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of British Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Keith Ahmad</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr Keith Ahmad</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Mobile Monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Post-Opioid Consumption</keyword>
  <keyword>Vital Signs</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

