<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02645162</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3450-PED-ERC-15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02645162</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Youth Leaders for Early Childhood Assuring Children Are Prepared for School</brief_title>
  <acronym>LEAPS</acronym>
  <official_title>A Cluster Randomized Control Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy and Feasibility of a Community-based Preschool Programme and Community Engagement Strategy Led by Community Youth Leaders in Rural Pakistan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aga Khan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Grand Challenges Canada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>UNICEF</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Aga Khan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Worldwide about 88 million children drop out of primary school annually. One of the&#xD;
      contributory factors is a lack of school readiness among young children, their families and&#xD;
      their teachers. To better prepare young children for school, investment in early childhood&#xD;
      interventions is necessary. Young children require good health, adequate nutrition and&#xD;
      social-emotional, cognitive and communication skills to succeed in school, which requires&#xD;
      both support in the family environment and a stable transition to the classroom environment.&#xD;
      Preschool programmes are designed to prepare children for formal learning. However, in many&#xD;
      low- and middle-income countries there is poor access to quality preschool programmes.&#xD;
      Further, the scale-up of early childhood interventions is challenged by a number of barriers&#xD;
      such as poor supply (e.g. policy provisions, financing, distance, early child development&#xD;
      workforce), inadequate cross-sector coordination, low demand (e.g. knowledge mobilization,&#xD;
      agency, community of purpose, opportunities to participate) and weak quality of services&#xD;
      (e.g. training, supervision and monitoring systems).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In partnership with the National Commission for Human Development, we propose to implement an&#xD;
      early childhood care and education programme in rural Sindh that is championed by Community&#xD;
      Youth Leaders. The Community Youth Leaders will run community preschools for children aged&#xD;
      3-6 years, and will also coordinate local community engagement and local stakeholder&#xD;
      strategies across sectors to leverage demand-side actions to promote ownership and scale-up&#xD;
      of early childhood interventions. The LEAPS Programme (Youth Leaders for Early Childhood&#xD;
      Assuring Children are Prepared for School) will be evaluated by a cluster randomized&#xD;
      controlled efficacy trial. The primary outcome will be children's school readiness, indexed&#xD;
      by both early academic and social emotional competencies assessed following 6-9 months of&#xD;
      intervention exposure. The compliance, fidelity and quality of the implementation process&#xD;
      will also be assessed in order to understand how these features moderate outcomes and whether&#xD;
      community-engagement strategies facilitate demand-side actions for scale-up. The expected&#xD;
      outcomes for this trial will include a model for quality preprimary education that addresses&#xD;
      a current supply-side gap, and will facilitate learning for demand-side actions to support&#xD;
      scale-up across a broad range of early childhood interventions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Trial Design The study is a cluster randomized controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims Aim 1: To evaluate the effectiveness of the LEAPS Programme on school readiness of&#xD;
      children, CYLs, families and services 1.1: To determine whether children who participate in&#xD;
      LEAPS preschools led by CYLs will achieve significantly better scores in assessments of&#xD;
      school readiness indexed by motor development, social-emotional development, emergent&#xD;
      literacy and language, emergent numeracy, approaches to learning and executive functions than&#xD;
      children in a control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.2: To identify the moderating and mediating variables (child, CYL, family and community&#xD;
      characteristics) for school readiness outcomes among children enrolled in LEAPS preschools.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.3: To describe the effects of intervention on CYLs' knowledge (ECD and education),&#xD;
      competencies (approaches to teaching) and personal/professional growth (executive&#xD;
      functioning, aspirations for parenting, family life and career, and autonomy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.4: To determine whether LEAPS community engagement strategies to address barriers to&#xD;
      scale-up of ECD programmes are effective with respect to family engagement with preschool,&#xD;
      support and intent for timely primary school enrolment, family utilization of child services,&#xD;
      service provider coordination, knowledge, participation in demand-side platforms and&#xD;
      demand-side creation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: To evaluate fidelity and compliance to the LEAPS Programme among community&#xD;
      stakeholders 2.1: To evaluate the fidelity of implementation and compliance to the LEAPS&#xD;
      preschool programme by the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2: To explore stakeholder experience of the preschool programme and community-based&#xD;
      strategies to understand facilitators, challenges and learn lessons for scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: To determine the cost effectiveness of the LEAPS Community-based preschool and&#xD;
      community engagement strategies on children's and community readiness for learning and&#xD;
      school.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clusters Ten clusters were randomly selected from a list of 20 clusters part of Responsive&#xD;
      Stimulation arm (Yousafzai, A. K., Rasheed, M. A., Rizvi, A., Armstrong, R., &amp; Bhutta, Z. A..&#xD;
      Effect of integrated responsive stimulation and nutrition interventions in the Lady Health&#xD;
      Worker programme in Pakistan on child development, growth, and health outcomes: a&#xD;
      cluster-randomised factorial effectiveness trial. The Lancet, 384(9950), 1282-1293. 2014)&#xD;
      using A-cluster software. Strata were rural/peri-urban. The inclusion criteria of including&#xD;
      the cluster in the randomization were: a functioning LHW and a functioning primary school in&#xD;
      the village. Five clusters were assigned each for intervention and control arms via simple&#xD;
      randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size The sample size has been estimated as 30 children per cluster with a total of 300&#xD;
      children, which will be adequate taking into account an estimated 10% attrition rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject Enrolment Control Arm: Children of age as defined by inclusion criteria will be&#xD;
      identified from a list of registered children with the Lady Health Worker (nearest record&#xD;
      possible). The sample will be stratified by the same age groups as described for the&#xD;
      intervention group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental Arm: A list of children meeting the inclusion criteria was available from the&#xD;
      LHW. Any additional child will be verified with the respective LHW prior to enrolment.&#xD;
      Enrolment for children in experimental group is defined as child having registered and&#xD;
      attended at least 3 days of preschool in week 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection Instruments All instruments were developed in English in the first instance&#xD;
      and then translated to Sindhi (with back translations) and piloted prior to use in the study.&#xD;
      A systematic adaptation protocol was followed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quality Assurance The following strategies are being used&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A 10% sample of assessments are being observed by the field supervisor and scored&#xD;
           simultaneously for inter-rater agreement. This shall be followed by a feedback session&#xD;
           with the assessor.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Daily debriefing meetings are held where challenges and solutions will be discussed and&#xD;
           will also be used as an opportunity for learning.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A 10% sample of classroom observations are being video recorded for coding by experts.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anthropometry equipment is calibrated daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Management Forms are being checked prior to entry. The data entry softwares include&#xD;
      checks to minimize errors. Data entry is being done at the data entry office located at the&#xD;
      field office. All forms are being data entered. A weekly report on status of data entry is&#xD;
      being shared by the data entry office.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis Plan: An intention to treat model.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>December 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>School readiness as defined by the percentage of items passed on a measure of school readiness.</measure>
    <time_frame>After a minimum of 6 months of intervention exposure.</time_frame>
    <description>Cognitive, social-emotional, motor, early literacy and early numeracy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Child executive functioning tasks composite score</measure>
    <time_frame>After a minimum of 6 months of intervention exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Inhibitory control, cognitive flexibility, working memory</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge and Practice for Health, Hygiene and Nutrition</measure>
    <time_frame>After a minimum of 6 months of intervention exposure</time_frame>
    <description>Child Report Questionnaire</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Child Development</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Preschool</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm will receive the community-based preschool intervention.&#xD;
The preschool sessions will include 2 groups per day (3 years 6months to 4 years 6 months in the morning session and 4 years 7 months to 5 year 6 months in the afternoon session at the time of enrolment)&#xD;
Each session will last 3 hours for 5 days per week.&#xD;
The expected CYL-to-child ratio will be 1:15; however, given the expected high level of local demand it may exceed to a maximum of 1:20 ratio.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will receive standard services available in the community.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Community-based Preschool</intervention_name>
    <description>Preschool sessions in community-based preschool&#xD;
Run by trained community youth leaders from the same village.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Preschool</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resident of study cluster&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not enrolled in a preschool&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Obvious disability&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>42 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>66 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aisha K Yousafzai, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Aga Khan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Muneera A Rasheed, MS</last_name>
    <phone>009234864334</phone>
    <phone_ext>4334</phone_ext>
    <email>muneera.rasheed@aku.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aga Khan University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karachi</city>
        <state>Sindh</state>
        <zip>74800</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Muneera A Rasheed, MS</last_name>
      <phone>00922134864334</phone>
      <phone_ext>4334</phone_ext>
      <email>muneera.rasheed@aku.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 31, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 31, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 1, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 31, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 31, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 1, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Aga Khan University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr Aisha Khizar Yousafzai</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pakistan</keyword>
  <keyword>Early Child Development, Care and Education</keyword>
  <keyword>Youth Leaders</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

