<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02645006</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SomamfycCTNF</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02645006</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Workshop for Primary Prevention of Falls. CHANGING TO NEVER FALL. CTNF</brief_title>
  <acronym>CTNF</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of an Intervention by a Health Education Workshop Compared With the Usual Advice to Reduce the Incidence of Falls in Independent 65 Years and Older Not Institutionalized. Primary Prevention.CHANGING TO NEVER FALL. CTNF</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sociedad Madrileña de Medicina de Familia y Comunitaria</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Comunidad de Madrid</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sociedad Madrileña de Medicina de Familia y Comunitaria</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether a primary prevention workshop is effective&#xD;
      decreasing at least 13% the annual incidence of falls in elderly compared to the habitual&#xD;
      counseling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before the first fall incident, the elderly aged 65 or more, living in community, are invited&#xD;
      to attend a workshop on fall preventing activities and factor risk detection. This activity&#xD;
      consists on four sessions (one session per week during three weeks and the fourth session one&#xD;
      year later) in which the elderly are expected to detect their own fall risk factors,&#xD;
      encouraged to introduce healthy habits and to increase physical activity in order to improve&#xD;
      strength and balance specifically.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This workshop has been prepared by family physicians following the latest scientific&#xD;
      recommendations, it will be lead by them on the first edition, but it has not been written in&#xD;
      formal language in order to be used by volunteers concerned about aging topics, independent&#xD;
      from the Health Service.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a Clinical Trial. The methodology is to compare the incidence of falls in two&#xD;
      groups. The intervention group will attend a three session workshop, will learn to recognize&#xD;
      their risk factors for fall, will be encouraged to adopt a healthy diet (vitamin D&#xD;
      consumption), modify home hazards , and increase physical activity (a strength and balance&#xD;
      program at home and a group walking route). After a monthly telephone follow-up they are&#xD;
      invited to attend a recall session, were they realize the change in the strength and balance&#xD;
      tests results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The control group will attend a single workshop session summarizing the major points of&#xD;
      prevention of falls ( risk factors of fall, healthy diet and vitamin D consumption, home&#xD;
      hazards, physical activity). After a monthly telephone follow-up they are invited to attend&#xD;
      the three session workshop for further prevention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GOALS&#xD;
&#xD;
      GENERAL Evaluate the effectiveness of an intervention program in the form of health education&#xD;
      workshop to reduce the incidence of falls in independent population aged 65 and older living&#xD;
      in the community.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SPECIFIC:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Estimate and compare the effectiveness of the intervention program in a workshop on&#xD;
           health education from a simple intervention with respect to:&#xD;
&#xD;
           • Final results: Principal: number and percentage of falls regular physical exercise 150&#xD;
           minutes a week of aerobic exercise and two times a week strength training.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Improvement of body mass index. Contribution supplement or vitamin D. Improved test&#xD;
           scores Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB or test Guralnik)&#xD;
&#xD;
           • Intermediate outcomes: Reduction in the number of risks identified in the home.&#xD;
           assistance to physical exercise as a group. Maintenance or support group for physical&#xD;
           exercise. Reduction of fear of falling (Fall Efficacy Scale abbreviate) Improved quality&#xD;
           of life (EuroQol 5) attendees know how to get up after a fall.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Select volunteers in the audience who wish to train to develop new editions of the&#xD;
           workshop as teachers, reaching the Community dimension of primary prevention, under the&#xD;
           supervision of the research group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Other:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Knowledge: Identify the general risk factors for falls. Identify personal risk&#xD;
                factors for falling. Identify the drugs associated with increased risk of falls.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Attitudes: Guide in avoiding risk factors and circumstantial household falls.&#xD;
                Recognize lifestyle that favor falls. Reinforce the practice of daily physical&#xD;
                activity. Encourage changes towards a balanced diet. Reviewing the reasons for fear&#xD;
                of falling. Support the creation of self-help groups that encourage physical&#xD;
                exercise daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Skills: Apply the advice received in the housing and clothing. Demonstrate that you&#xD;
                know develop a balanced and healthy menu daily. Demonstrate that you know off the&#xD;
                ground after a fall.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental study types randomized clinical trial, controlled, parallel with simultaneous&#xD;
      monitoring of both groups. The scope of the study is the community, the social network to&#xD;
      which they belong major centers of the Community of Madrid Random assignment of senior&#xD;
      centers where the intervention groups of intervention and control is performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Masking of participants on receiving the intervention is done, and there is masking the&#xD;
      analysis of statistical data by ignoring what group they belong results. The selection&#xD;
      criteria of the subjects are wide to allow extrapolation of results, increasing the external&#xD;
      validity of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention is a three-session workshop that explores the detection and correction of&#xD;
      risk factors for falls, changing working habits related to falls and applying interventions&#xD;
      that have been shown to be effective in the literature. Working knowledge, attitudes and&#xD;
      skills. It follows a period of one year follow up with monthly phone call to know the&#xD;
      existence of falls in that period and a session assessing memory with changes. The&#xD;
      intervention which is compared with the group counseling reporting the risk factors&#xD;
      associated with falls and the necessary interventions on the habits associated with them.&#xD;
      Working knowledge without delving into the changing attitudes. Follow up with the same&#xD;
      frequency call is performed that intervention to publicize the existence of the group falls&#xD;
      in that period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In terms of population, the selection will be made according to criteria of inclusion and&#xD;
      exclusion, but recruitment is voluntary type. The workshop will promote the community level&#xD;
      where the senior center selected as the site is located and workshop point to the interested&#xD;
      persons. The inclusion period covering the two weeks prior to the date set for the workshop&#xD;
      until the day before included. demographics (age, sex, cultural and socioeconomic status),&#xD;
      data related to falls (if you have had a fall or previously, current treatment with vitamin&#xD;
      D, concomitant diseases, associates, toxic drugs), accessibility data will be collected&#xD;
      (residence next to the workshop venue, existence of stairs at home, time availability to&#xD;
      attend all sessions, physical limitations to attend regardless).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Person 65 years or older, habitual residence (more than nine months per year) in the coverage&#xD;
      area of the senior center participants, independent ambulation by the field without help from&#xD;
      another person, able to attend: inclusion criteria defined all sessions, acceptance of&#xD;
      telephone follow-up, commitment to attend the final session, and given their informed consent&#xD;
      to participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Institutionalized person, moderate or severe cognitive impairment of any etiology, blindness,&#xD;
      total deafness, trouble reading, absolute contraindication for exercise or surgery in the&#xD;
      previous 6 months: exclusion criteria are defined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study variables are the following, in addition to the previously referred to as&#xD;
      demographic, related to falls or Accessibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous falls yes / no, Alcohol yes / no, grams of alcohol / week Group of neuroleptic&#xD;
      drugs, benzodiazepines, other. Number of drugs. Number of barriers identified as checklist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Corrected number of barriers. Reduce alcohol consumption, perform the homework, complete&#xD;
      their daily findings, conducted prior to the workshop activity (type of activity, minutes,&#xD;
      times a week), nutritional Journal: points. Weight, height, BMI, waist circumference. Fall&#xD;
      Efficacy Scale abbreviate - points, apply the advice received during the three sessions&#xD;
      (Diet- yes / no, Exercising-yes / no risk Home Improvement yes / no), the group is formed and&#xD;
      go during the three weeks of the workshop but. Make exercise properly off the ground yes /&#xD;
      no, number of attempts. Vit D treatment prior. Previous physical activity. Stairs at home.&#xD;
      Technical assistance to walk. Limitations to physical activity. Active disease. 5D EuroQol&#xD;
      quality of life: points. Health today points. Existence of hazards in home zones.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The assignment of participants in the control group or the intervention group may not be&#xD;
      random by the type of intervention proposed, but senior centers will be randomized to receive&#xD;
      the workshop with the sequence of intervention or monitoring sequence. It will be made, by an&#xD;
      outside professional to the research team, a random sampling of the list of the 32 Centres&#xD;
      for the Elderly in the Community of Madrid. As the intervention meets a priori criteria of&#xD;
      benefit in primary prevention, control group will receive three intervention sessions of the&#xD;
      workshop at the end of the follow-up period of 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participant will ignore the existence of the two kinds of workshop, so that masking is&#xD;
      achieved, however, not be possible to sign the informed consent prior to allocation to an&#xD;
      intervention or another. As the researcher who teaches the workshop will be impossible&#xD;
      masking since it will give the workshop in a sequence or another. It can be made in a&#xD;
      double-blind follow-up period to perform the same telephone survey in both groups by a&#xD;
      researcher other than educational workshop. Statistical analysis and evaluation of responses&#xD;
      for statistical development outside the study will be conducted, reaching a triple blind.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As for the follow-up period, it is known that primary prevention to evaluate this time has to&#xD;
      be very long. We have established a period of one year follow-up because it is the minimum&#xD;
      referred to in the literature to detect impact on reducing falls interventions regarding&#xD;
      physical activity and intake of vitamin D. However the aim of the researchers is to extend&#xD;
      monitoring phone in a second phase to complete the second year. Protocol ensures in a pattern&#xD;
      of telephone calls and data collected identical in both groups, scoring the reason for&#xD;
      stopping monitoring whenever possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The strategy of data analysis will take into account the exclusion of participants (such as&#xD;
      physical limitations) and causes of abandonment or follow-up workshop. An analysis was done&#xD;
      by intention to treat the participant maintaining the data in the group assigned regardless&#xD;
      of the end of the workshop or not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The calculated sample size is 316 participants, 158 participants in each arm. Comparison of&#xD;
      two proportions, unilateral test (the intervention is superior to standard treatment), 95%&#xD;
      confidence level, 80% statistical power, P1 (ratio -. Incidence of falls in the gr control or&#xD;
      usual care) 25%, P2 (expected incidence of falls in the intervention group) 12% (13%&#xD;
      reduction). Sample size (n) = 109, expected loss ratio 20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design effect (30 subjects per center. ICC 0.05). Design effect = 1+ (30.01) * 0.05 = about&#xD;
      1.15. Design effect 109 * 1.15 = 126. Adding 20% of losses = 158 participants per arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is designed as a pragmatic trial, evaluated the effectiveness of the workshop for&#xD;
      primary prevention of falls, with broad selection criteria and heterogeneous population, as&#xD;
      the reality that is to be applied, favoring the generalization of the results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As for the limitations provided for the study, one of which is the participation of healthy&#xD;
      individuals, and in the prevention field that requires a greater number of participants, a&#xD;
      longer follow-up and possible higher rate of default. Furthermore you risk to specific bias&#xD;
      as participation. You may only select those people who come to senior centers and premises&#xD;
      where cartels are exposed invitation, which will be a priori greatest assets and willing to&#xD;
      activities and social relationships. It is planned around this limitation in later editions&#xD;
      of the workshop, when the offer to other sensitized social partners on this issue expands.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another limitation is the supply of vitamin D, which has proven effective in those who&#xD;
      present higher deficits of this vitamin. However since it is an external study the health&#xD;
      system will not be available prior analytical determination, or it may decide to supplement&#xD;
      in 600 or 800 units a day but will opt to increase the level of contribution to the diet.&#xD;
      However, to have a letter to the family physician Participant is expected that a percentage&#xD;
      of the participants are evaluated for vitamin deficiencies or receive supplements of vitamin&#xD;
      D. These data will be recorded to be taken into account in the analysis phase.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>May 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>% incidence of falls in a year</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
    <description>% of incidence of falls in a year</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>score in Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB o Test de Guralnik)</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>dietary vitamin D intake</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>score in Mediterranean diet adherence test SEEDO (Sociedad Española para el Estudio de la Obesidad)</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of home hazards modification</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>% body mass index BMI</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>score FES-I test (Fall Efficacy Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Score short MNA_spanish (Mini Nutritional Assessment)</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Score EuroQol-5D (EQ-5D)</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">316</enrollment>
  <condition>Dietary Habits</condition>
  <condition>Accidental Falls</condition>
  <condition>Unspecified Fall, Occurrence at Home</condition>
  <condition>Physical Activity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm- 3 session workshop</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The intervention group will attend a three session workshop, will learn to recognize their risk factors for fall, will be encouraged to adopt a healthy diet (vitamin D consumption), modify home hazards , and increase physical activity (a strength and balance program at home and a group walking route). After a monthly telephone follow-up they are invited to attend a recall session, were they realize the change in the strength and balance tests results.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm- 1 session workshop</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will attend a single workshop session summarizing the major points of prevention of falls ( risk factors of fall, healthy diet and vitamin D consumption, home hazards, physical activity). After a monthly telephone follow-up they are invited to attend the three session workshop for further prevention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>3 session workshop</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention group will attend a three session workshop, will learn to recognize their risk factors for fall, will be encouraged to adopt a healthy diet (vitamin D consumption), modify home hazards , and increase physical activity (a strength and balance program at home and a group walking route). After a monthly telephone follow-up they are invited to attend a recall session, were they realize the change in the strength and balance tests results.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention arm- 3 session workshop</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>1 session workshop</intervention_name>
    <description>The control group will attend a single workshop session summarizing the major points of prevention of falls ( risk factors of fall, healthy diet and vitamin D consumption, home hazards, physical activity). After a monthly telephone follow-up they are invited to attend the three session workshop for further prevention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control arm- 1 session workshop</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  person 65 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  habitual residence (more than nine months per year) in the coverage area of the senior&#xD;
             center participants,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  walk independently without help from another person,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to attend all sessions,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acceptance telephone follow-up,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  commitment to attend the final session,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  and given their informed consent to participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  institutionalized person,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  moderate or severe cognitive impairment of any etiology,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  blindness,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  total deafness,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  trouble reading,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  absolute contraindication for exercise or surgery in the previous 6 months,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  engaged in other activities such muscle strengthening or tai chi balance.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>María Medina-Sampedro, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Somamfyc, Sociedad Madrileña de Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>María Medina-Sampedro, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+34617281028</phone>
    <email>mmedsam@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Somamfyc Sociedad Madrileña Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria</last_name>
    <phone>+34915229975</phone>
    <email>somamfyc@somamfyc.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Comunidad de Madrid, Centros de Mayores del SRBS</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>María Medina-Sampedro, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+34617281028</phone>
      <email>mmedsam@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Somamfyc Somamfyc</last_name>
      <phone>+34915229975</phone>
      <email>somamfyc@somamfyc.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 29, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 31, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 1, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 31, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 31, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 1, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sociedad Madrileña de Medicina de Familia y Comunitaria</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>MARIA MEDINA SAMPEDRO</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Especialista en Medicina Familiar y Comunitaria, Máster en Investigación en Atención Primaria, Coordinadora del Grupo de trabajo de Atención al Mayor de Somamfyc</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>falls</keyword>
  <keyword>elderly</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise,Physical</keyword>
  <keyword>vitamin d</keyword>
  <keyword>home hazards</keyword>
  <keyword>mediterranean diet</keyword>
  <keyword>body mass index</keyword>
  <keyword>lower extremity exercise movement technics</keyword>
  <keyword>vitamin D intake</keyword>
  <keyword>Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB o Test de Guralnik)</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

