<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02645487</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STU 022015-106</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02645487</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Stereotactic Radiosurgery (SRS) for Brain Metastasis</brief_title>
  <acronym>SRS</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase I Dose-Escalation Study of Stereotactic Radiosurgery (SRS) for Brain Metastasis Without Whole Brain Radiation (WBRT)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      SRS dose escalation for brain metastases in radiation-naïve patients will establish true&#xD;
      tolerable doses, which may exceed the current standard doses. This may lead to an improvement&#xD;
      in local control, patient survival, and/or quality-of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Recently, several large randomized studies have shown that in patients with limited brain&#xD;
      metastases, whole brain radiation can be safely deferred when treated with SRS and close&#xD;
      surveillance. In light of this, most of such patients are now treated with SRS alone without&#xD;
      WBRT. However, the SRS doses set by Radiation Therapy Oncology Group (RTOG) 90-05 continue to&#xD;
      be applied to patients without previous cranial irradiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The potential insufficiency of current SRS dose for long-term tumor control is of pressing&#xD;
      concern. The advances chemotherapy has led to an improvement in overall survival in many&#xD;
      patients with metastatic cancer, including malignancies often associated with brain&#xD;
      metastases, such as lung (40-50%) and breast (15%). As these patients survive longer, more&#xD;
      patients may develop brain metastases and the current dose of SRS may not be adequate to&#xD;
      control the brain metastases for the duration of their survival. In fact, there is evidence&#xD;
      that the control rate declines with time after SRS, and after 3 years, the local control rate&#xD;
      may be only about 60%. In the case of brain metastases from relatively radio-resistant&#xD;
      melanoma, the reported 12-months local control rates for SRS range from 52% to 75%. More&#xD;
      potent SRS doses could lead to improved long-term control of brain metastases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 18, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximal tolerated doses</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>To identify the maximal tolerated doses for single-fraction stereotactic radiosurgery, within 90 days from the date of procedure, in patients with brain metastases who have not undergone prior brain irradiation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the overall survival (OS), which is defined as the time between date of SRS and the date of death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate time to progression (TTP), which is defined as the time between date of SRS and date of documented progression. Specific TTP will be determined for the target lesion, non-target lesions, and elsewhere in brain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Local progression rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the local progression rate of the target lesion. Local progression will be defined by MRI (with or without contrast)/CT (with contrast) imaging according to the modified RECIST 1.1 criteria. Suspected radiation necrosis and/or pseudoprogression will be similarly evaluated</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the response rate, consisting of complete response (CR) and partial response according to the modified RECIST 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To measure the improvement in health-related quality of life (HRQoL).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>chronic toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days up to 2 years from the date of procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE version 5.0 to identify chronic toxicity for single-fraction stereotactic radiosurgery in patients with brain metastases who have not undergone prior brain irradiation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subgroup analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To perform subgroup analysis of the variables listed above. Subgroups may be defined by age, initial performance status, number of metastases, primary tumor histology, tumor volume, target volume receiving 12 Gy, and patients who are treated with whole brain radiotherapy after the protocol</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">135</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Neoplasms, Adult, Malignant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic Radiosurgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Radiation, Stereotactic Radiosurgery Dose-Escalation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stereotactic Radiosurgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Radiation, Stereotactic Radiosurgery Size &lt;= 1cm: 24 Gray (Gy); + 3 Gy incremental escalation up to 30 Gy &gt;1-2cm: 21 Gy; + 3 Gy incremental escalation up to 27 Gy &gt;2-3cm: 18 Gy; + 3 Gy incremental escalation up to 24 Gy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic Radiosurgery</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SRS</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Biopsy-proven non-hematopoietic malignancy, except for small cell lung cancer, germ&#xD;
             cell cancer, or unknown primary tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Radiographic evidence by MRI (or by CT scan with CT contrast if ineligible or&#xD;
             intolerant of MRI) of brain metastasis. (If patient is unable to tolerate MRI&#xD;
             contrast, an MRI without contrast is acceptable if lesions are visible)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. All brain metastases must be outside the brain stem (midbrain, pons and medulla).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient must have 10 or less brain metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The maximum diameter of any lesion must be less than or equal to 3.0 cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Previous treatment with surgery, radiation, chemotherapy, immunotherapy or any&#xD;
             targeted agents are allowed provided that:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiation was not to the brain.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Surgery to the brain was &gt; 7 days prior to SRS and there remains at least one&#xD;
                  additional brain metastasis that can be targeted with SRS&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. ECOG Performance Score of 2 or better/Karnofsky Performance Status score of 50-60 or&#xD;
             better.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. All men, as well as women of child-bearing potential must agree to use adequate&#xD;
             contraception (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study&#xD;
             entry and for the duration of study participation. Should a woman become pregnant or&#xD;
             suspect she is pregnant while participating in this study, she should inform her&#xD;
             treating physician immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. A female of child-bearing potential is any woman (regardless of sexual orientation,&#xD;
             marital status, having undergone a tubal ligation, or remaining celibate by choice)&#xD;
             who meets the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive months (i.e.,&#xD;
                  has had menses at any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months).&#xD;
&#xD;
             Medically acceptable birth control (contraceptives) includes:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Approved hormonal contraceptives (such as birth control pills, patch, or ring:&#xD;
                  Depo-Provera, Implanon), or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Barrier methods (such as a condom or diaphragm) used with a spermicide (a&#xD;
                  substance that kills sperm)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients had craniotomy and surgery to the brain within 7 days from the date of SRS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with leptomeningeal metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
             NOTE: For the purposes of exclusion, LMD is a clinical diagnosis, defined as positive&#xD;
             CSF cytology and/or equivocal radiologic or clinical evidence of leptomeningeal&#xD;
             involvement. Patients with leptomeningeal symptoms in the setting of leptomeningeal&#xD;
             enhancement by imaging (MRI) would be considered to have LMD even in the absence of&#xD;
             positive CSF cytology, unless a parenchymal lesion can adequately explain the&#xD;
             neurologic symptoms and/or signs. In contrast, an asymptomatic or minimally&#xD;
             symptomatic patient with mild or nonspecific leptomeningeal enhancement (MRI) would&#xD;
             not be considered to have LMD. In that patient, CSF sampling is not required to&#xD;
             formally exclude LMD, but can be performed at the investigator's discretion based on&#xD;
             level of clinical suspicion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with a contraindication to both MRI (with or without contrast) and CT scan&#xD;
             (with contrast)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with life expectancy &lt; 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects must not be pregnant or nursing at the time of SRS treatment due to the&#xD;
             potential for congenital abnormalities and the potential of this regimen to harm&#xD;
             nursing infants.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert Timmerman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UTSW</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah Hardee, MS</last_name>
    <phone>214-645-8525</phone>
    <email>sarah.hardee@UTSouthwestern.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kajal Desai, MS</last_name>
    <phone>2146458525</phone>
    <email>kajal.desai@utsouthwestern.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Timmerman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 30, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 30, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 1, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Robert Timmerman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

