<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02730364</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>205637</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02730364</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Efficacy and Safety Study of Theraflu Night Powder as Oral Solution for Cold and Flu</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Multicenter, Randomized, Parallel Group, Single-dose Study to Assess the Short Term Efficacy and Safety of Paracetamol 500 mg + Phenylephrine HCl 10 mg + Pheniramine Maleate 20 mg + Vitamin C 200 mg Powder for Oral Solution in Subjects With Symptoms of an Upper Respiratory Tract Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the study is to assess the short term efficacy of the Theraflu Night powder&#xD;
      for oral solution in the Russian population in &quot;Short term relief of the symptoms of colds,&#xD;
      chills and influenza, including mild to moderate pain, fever and nasal congestion&quot;.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The clinical phase of the study (from FSFV to LSLV) was never initiated due to the sponsor's&#xD;
    decision.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>This was an open label study.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy assessment Change from baseline, 3 hours after dosing in the Jackson Total Symptom Score (JTSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 3 hours post dosing</time_frame>
    <description>The severity of common cold symptoms will be self-assessed using the Jackson 8 items scale (questionnaire) by the participants on the site. This questionnaire measures the severity of 5 local symptoms (nasal congestion, rhinorrhea, sneezing, cough, and sore throat) and 3 systemic symptoms (chilliness, headache, malaise) each on a 4-point ordinal scale (0=not present, 1= mild, 2=moderate, 3= severe).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Infections, Respiratory Tract</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Theraflu night powder</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single dose (1 sachet) of Theraflu Night powder containing paracetamol, phenylephrine HCl, pheniramine maleate, and vitamin C as oral solution.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will not receive any medication</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paracetamol, phenylephrine HCl, pheniramine maleate, and vitamin C</intervention_name>
    <description>One sachet is provided for each participant randomized to the Theraflu Night powder containing paracetamol, phenylephrine HCl, pheniramine maleate, and vitamin C as oral solution.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Theraflu night powder</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Theraflu Night powder for oral solution</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must understand and provide written informed consent before any&#xD;
             assessment is performed, understand the study procedures, and be willing and able to&#xD;
             complete the required assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of a URTI as diagnosed by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mild to moderate sore throat, i.e. rated as 1 or 2 on a 4-point ordinal scale (0=not&#xD;
             present, 1= mild, 2=moderate, 3=severe), or headache (1, 2 or 3) or fever (less than&#xD;
             39°C ) or/and Nasal congestion (blocked nose): may be accompanied by rhinorrhea (runny&#xD;
             nose) and/or sneezing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Baseline Jackson TSS &gt; 8&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Common cold symptoms for less than 48 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of other investigational drugs within 30 days or 5 half-lives of enrollment,&#xD;
             whichever is longer. Investigational drug refers to any drug being evaluated in&#xD;
             clinical trials&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of or known hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs, excipients or to drugs&#xD;
             of similar chemical classes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing (lactating) women, where pregnancy is defined as the state of a&#xD;
             female after conception and until the termination of gestation, confirmed by a&#xD;
             positive hCG laboratory test (&gt; 5 mIU/mL) or urine dipstick at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of drug hypersensitivity, asthma, urticaria, or other significant allergic&#xD;
             diathesis. Participants with uncomplicated seasonal allergic rhinitis can be accepted&#xD;
             if expected allergy season is clearly one month outside enrollment/ treatment period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of brain diseases, liver diseases or epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any evidence of uncontrolled cardiovascular (including hypertension), pulmonary,&#xD;
             renal, hepatic, gastrointestinal, hematological, endocrinological, metabolic,&#xD;
             neurological or psychiatric diseases at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has closed angle glaucoma, urinary retention, prostatic hyperplasia,&#xD;
             pyloroduodenal obstruction, pheochromocytoma, diabetes mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A positive alcohol breath test or positive urine drug screen or a medical history data&#xD;
             indicative of alcoholism, drug addiction, or drug abuse within the preceding 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is current smoker of ≥10 cigarettes per day (or reports equivalent smoking&#xD;
             habits using other tobacco products) and is unwilling to refrain from smoking while at&#xD;
             the study site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is current smoker of ≥10 cigarettes per day (or reports equivalent smoking&#xD;
             habits using other tobacco products) and is unwilling to refrain from smoking while at&#xD;
             the study site&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is taking or has taken within the last two weeks of dosing monoamine oxidase&#xD;
             inhibitors, antidepressants, atropine, beta-blocking or sympathomimetic drugs&#xD;
             desferrioxamine, hepatotoxic drugs, drugs inducing liver microsomal enzyme, (such as&#xD;
             phenytoin, carbamazepine, isoniazid and rifampicin), neuroleptic drugs, chlorzoxazone,&#xD;
             CNS depressant drugs including barbiturates, hypnotics, opioid analgesics, anxiolytic&#xD;
             sedatives, antipsychotics or is anticipated to require any of these medications at any&#xD;
             time throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has used: Systemic or topical corticosteroids (with the exception of HRT and&#xD;
             contraceptive steroids for females), within 3 weeks prior to dosing or Slow-release&#xD;
             steroids (with the exception of HRT and contraceptive steroids for females) within 90&#xD;
             days prior to dosing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has used any of the following medications within 6 hours before first study&#xD;
             drug administration, or is anticipated to use any of these medications at any time&#xD;
             throughout the study: Any inhaler, medicated confectionary, throat lozenges, throat&#xD;
             pastilles, sprays, any products with demulcent properties such as chewing gums and&#xD;
             boiled sweets or mints, Any medication for sore throat containing a local anaesthetic,&#xD;
             Cold products and oral nasal decongestant products, Paracetamol or any NSAID&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has used substances of abuse, herbal medicines, antihistamines and homeopathic&#xD;
             medicine within 72 hours of dosing or is anticipated to require any of these drugs at&#xD;
             any time throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject was previously enrolled into the current study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persons directly or indirectly involved in the execution of this protocol, including&#xD;
             first degree relative of a study investigator, employees of the clinical study site,&#xD;
             employees of the CRO and persons related to them&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &quot;Vulnerable&quot; individual (as defined by the IRB e.g. incarcerated person)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>March 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 1, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 6, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetaminophen</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ascorbic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pheniramine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Phenylephrine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oxymetazoline</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

