<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04385719</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PK-24</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04385719</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Drug-drug Interactions Between Remdesivir and Commonly Used Antiretroviral Therapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>RemTLAR</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open-label, Randomized, Single Intravenous Dosing Study to Investigate the Effect of Fixed-dose Combinations of Tenofovir/Lamivudine or Atazanavir/Ritonavir on the Pharmacokinetics of Remdesivir in Ugandan Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Makerere University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Liverpool</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European and Developing Countries Clinical Trials Partnership (EDCTP)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Turin, Italy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Makerere University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ebola and HIV are found predominately in the same regions of the world and countries in&#xD;
      sub-Saharan Africa are most affected by both diseases. For Ebola, no approved therapies&#xD;
      exist. However, new investigational drugs are being evaluated to understand if they are&#xD;
      effective against the Ebola virus. Remdesivir is an anti-Ebola investigational drug for the&#xD;
      treatment of Ebola. Little is known about how the blood levels of remdesivir relate to how&#xD;
      effective it is in patients with HIV taking antiretroviral therapy. This study will explore&#xD;
      how commonly utilized ART (tenofovir/lamivudine and atazanavir/ritonavir) affect the drug&#xD;
      levels of remdesivir.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed as an open-label, randomized, fixed sequence, single intravenous dosing&#xD;
      study to assess the effects of antiretrovirals on remdesivir pharmacokinetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The selection of healthy volunteers, as opposed to patients with HIV, avoids the greatest&#xD;
      possible extent confounding factors, such as enzyme or transporter activity alteration in&#xD;
      inflammatory states, concomitant medications potentially impacting drug disposition and other&#xD;
      factors which are commonly present in a population of patients and cannot be easily&#xD;
      eliminated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess the safety and tolerability of single intravenous doses of remdesivir in adult&#xD;
           healthy volunteers&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To evaluate the intracellular pharmacokinetics of single dose intravenous remdesivir&#xD;
           with or without co-administration of oral fixed-dose combination tenofovir/lamivudine&#xD;
           with patients serving as their own controls&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To evaluate the difference in plasma and intracellular pharmacokinetics of intravenous&#xD;
           remdesivir among healthy volunteers receiving tenofovir/lamivudine versus healthy&#xD;
           volunteers receiving tenofovir/lamivudine plus atazanavir/ritonavir tablets.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To generate a population pharmacokinetic model to describe inter-individual variability&#xD;
           in intracellular pharmacokinetics of remdesivir&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. To describe polymorphic variants of relevant kinases that activate TFV and explore&#xD;
      possible consequences on remdesivir PK.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 16, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of adverse events categorised by body system</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>The number of adverse events will be tabulated by body system. All safety parameters will be listed by cohort, subject and visit/time and summarized by treatment and visit/time. No formal statistical hypotheses of the safety or tolerability are to be tested.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants with adverse events categorised by body system</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>The incidence of adverse events will be tabulated by body system. All safety parameters will be listed by cohort, subject and visit/time and summarized by treatment and visit/time. No formal statistical hypotheses of the safety or tolerability are to be tested.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak Concentration (CMax) of remdesivir in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>last measurable time-point (24 hours)</time_frame>
    <description>maximum plasma and intracellular concentration [Cmax] of remdesivir with or without co-administration of antiretroviral drugs.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to maximum concentration (TMax) of remdesivir in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>last measurable time-point (24 hours)</time_frame>
    <description>Time to maximum concentration of remdesivir in plasma and PBMCs with or without co-administration of antiretroviral therapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Terminal elimination half-life of remdesivir in plasma and PBMCs</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>terminal elimination half life of remdesivir in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and Plasma with or without co-administration of antiretroviral therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under concentration-time curve (AUC) of remdesivir</measure>
    <time_frame>last measurable time-point (24 hours)</time_frame>
    <description>Area under concentration-time curve of remdesivir in peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs) and Plasma with or without co-administration of antiretroviral therapy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean ratio and 90% confidence intervals of remdesivir CMax with and without antiretroviral therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>CMax of remdesivir in plasma and PBMCS will be compared with and without antiretroviral therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean ratio and 90% confidence intervals of remdesivir TMax with and without antiretroviral therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>TMax of remdesivir in plasma and PBMCS will be compared with and without antiretroviral therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean ratio and 90% confidence intervals of remdesivir terminal elimination half-life with and without antiretroviral therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>t 1/2 of remdesivir in plasma and PBMCS will be compared with and without antiretroviral therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric mean ratio and 90% confidence intervals of remdesivir area under concentration-time curve, with and without antiretroviral therapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>AUC (0-t) of remdesivir in plasma and PBMCS will be compared with and without antiretroviral therapy. t is the last measurable time-point</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Ebola</condition>
  <condition>HIV/AIDS</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study A Sequence 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose remdesivir 150mg IV on Day 1&#xD;
Wash out period Day 2-7&#xD;
TDF/3TC 300/300mg tablets OD from Day 8-14 single dose remdesivir 150mg IV on Day 14</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study A Sequence 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TDF/3TC 300/300mg tablets OD from Day 1-7 single dose remdesivir 150mg IV on Day 7&#xD;
Wash out period Day 8-14&#xD;
Single dose remdesivir 150mg IV on Day 15</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TDF/3TC/ATV/r 300/300/300/100mg tablets OD from Day 1-7 single dose remdesivir 150mg IV infusion on Day 7</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remdesivir</intervention_name>
    <description>Remdesivir (GS-5734) is a nucleoside analogue with in vitro activity against filoviruses EBOV, SUDV, BDBV and MARV, in addition to arenaviruses and coronaviruses</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study A Sequence 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Study A Sequence 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Study B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>GS-5734</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Evidence of a personally signed and dated informed consent document indicating that&#xD;
             the participant has been informed of all pertinent aspects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants who are willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan,&#xD;
             laboratory tests, and other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Healthy men and women aged 18 to 55 years of age, and in good health as determined by&#xD;
             past medical history, physical examination, vital signs, electrocardiogram, and&#xD;
             laboratory tests at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At screening, and all other visits, vital signs (systolic and diastolic blood pressure&#xD;
             and pulse rate) will be assessed in the sitting position and again (when required) in&#xD;
             the standing position. Sitting vital signs should be within the following ranges:&#xD;
&#xD;
             I. axillary body temperature between 35.5-37.0 °C II. systolic blood pressure, 90-139&#xD;
             mmHg III. diastolic blood pressure, 50-89 mmHg IV. Pulse rate, 50-90 bpm. If pulse&#xD;
             rate is between 40 and 50 bpm, the Investigator may decide to enroll the subject if&#xD;
             he/she has history of athletic practice or other regular high cardio-vascular activity&#xD;
             and ECG assessment is within normal range.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Subjects should be excluded if their standing vital signs (relative to sitting) show&#xD;
             findings which, in the opinion of the Investigator, are associated with clinical&#xD;
             manifestation of postural hypotension (i.e. absence of any other cause). The&#xD;
             Investigator should carefully consider enrolling subjects with either a &gt; 20 mmHg&#xD;
             decrease in systolic or a &gt;10 mm Hg decrease in diastolic blood pressure, accompanied&#xD;
             by a &gt; 20 bpm increase in heart-rate (from sitting to standing).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects must weigh at least 40 kg to participate in the study and must have a body&#xD;
             mass index (BMI) within the range 18-30 Kg/m2. BMI= Body weight (kg) / [Height (m)]2&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. HIV antibody negative at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Women of childbearing potential must be willing to use a highly effective&#xD;
             contraception method (eg. IUD or hormonal contraceptive implant, complete abstinence&#xD;
             (if genuinely followed)) or consistent use of a barrier method such as male or female&#xD;
             condoms plus oral progestin contraceptives for the duration of the study.&#xD;
             Non-surgically sterilized men must agree to abstain from sexual intercourse for the&#xD;
             duration of the study or use condoms for contraception for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Hemoglobin concentration equal or greater than 10 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Significant disease affecting cardiac, respiratory, gastrointestinal or neurological&#xD;
             symptoms which in the clinician's medical judgment could be worsened by participating&#xD;
             in this study or the presence of medical or surgical conditions which could prevent&#xD;
             the subject from complying with study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Serum alanine transaminase (ALT) levels above 2x upper limit of normal (ULN) or total&#xD;
             bilirubin &gt; 1.3x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Serum creatinine levels above 1.5x upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Evidence of QT prolongation on electrocardiogram (ECG) QTc (Rate adjusted QT interval)&#xD;
             &gt; 450ms (men) or 460ms (women)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnant women or female subjects who are unwilling to use a suitable contraceptive&#xD;
             method for the duration of the study (IUD or contraceptive implant)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Likely to be poorly adherent based on clinician's medical judgement&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Known to be current injection drug user&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohammed J Lamorde, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Infectious Diseases Institute, Uganda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Infectious Diseases Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Uganda</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ebola</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Remdesivir</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug Interactions</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Remdesivir</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

