<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04382898</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RN5609C00</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2018-004321-86</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04382898</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PRO-MERIT (Prostate Cancer Messenger RNA Immunotherapy)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRO-MERIT</acronym>
  <official_title>First-in-human, Dose Titration and Expansion Trial to Evaluate Safety, Immunogenicity and Preliminary Efficacy of W_pro1 (BNT112) Monotherapy and in Combination With Cemiplimab in Patients With Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>BioNTech SE</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>BioNTech SE</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Open-label, multicenter, dose titration and four-arm expansion trial to evaluate the safety,&#xD;
      tolerability, immunogenicity, and preliminary efficacy of W_pro1 cancer vaccine (W_pro1)&#xD;
      monotherapy or in combination with cemiplimab in patients with metastatic castration&#xD;
      resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC: Part 1 and Part 2 Arms 1A and 1B) and in patients with&#xD;
      high-risk, localized prostate cancer (LPC).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      -  W_pro1 consists of messenger ribonucleic acid (mRNA [or RNA]) targeting 5 antigens&#xD;
           expressed in de novo and metastatic prostate cancer that are separately complexed with&#xD;
           liposomes to form serum-stable RNA lipoplexes (RNA-LPX).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The RNA molecules are immune-pharmacologically optimized for high stability,&#xD;
           translational efficiency and presentation on major histocompatibility complex (MHC)&#xD;
           class I and II molecules. The vaccine is intended for intravenous (IV) bolus injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The RNA-LPX cancer vaccine induces activation of both the adaptive immune system&#xD;
           (vaccine antigen-specific CD8+/CD4+ T cell) as well as the innate immune system (TLR7&#xD;
           agonism of single-stranded RNA). The physiology of efficient induction, expansion and&#xD;
           differentiation of antigen-specific T cells is associated with programmed death&#xD;
           receptor-1 (PD-1) upregulation on these T cells. Thus, the cancer vaccine is expected to&#xD;
           have a synergistic mechanism of action with anti-PD-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In summary, the mechanism of action of W_pro1 both in monotherapy and in combination&#xD;
           with anti-PD-1 immune checkpoint inhibitor cemiplimab, together with carefully selected&#xD;
           and refined clinical setting presents a unique opportunity for patients with different&#xD;
           stages of prostate cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 19, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of dose limiting toxicities (DLTs)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of TEAEs reported by relationship, grade, and seriousness according to National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events, version 5.0 (NCI CTCAE v5.0).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) - Part 2 Arms 1A and 1B</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR, defined as the number of patients with a complete response (CR) or partial response (PR) per Prostate Cancer Working Group 3 (PCWG3).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of de novo induction or increase of W_pro1 antigen-specific T cells in peripheral blood compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in prostate-specific antigen (PSA) levels</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>PSA decline of 0 to 25%, &gt;25% to 50%, and &gt;50% compared to baseline, as well as PSA decline ≥ 50% according to PCWG3.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in PSA doubling time (PSADT)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>PSADT during treatment and end of treatment (EoT) compared to baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR - Part 1</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>ORR, defined as the number of patients with a CR or PR per PCWG3.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor response post-treatment compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate preliminary anti-tumor activity of W_pro1 monotherapy or in combination with cemiplimab in patients with newly diagnosed LPC.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">130</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1 (mCRPC) - dose titration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>W_pro1 monotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1A (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>W_pro1 in combination with cemiplimab</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1B [1] (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>W_pro1 monotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 2 (LPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>W_pro1 in combination with cemiplimab</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 3 (LPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>W_pro1 monotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1B [2] (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Following progression after W_pro1 monotherapy, patients in Arm 1b have the option to be treated with cemiplimab monotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>W_pro1</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous bolus injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 1 (mCRPC) - dose titration</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1A (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1B [1] (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 2 (LPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 3 (LPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cemiplimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Intravenous infusion</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1A (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 1B [2] (mCRPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part 2 Arm 2 (LPC) - expansion cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be male and aged ≥18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically confirmed prostate adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group Performance Status (ECOG PS)&#xD;
             score of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Specific key inclusion criteria for mCRPC patients (Part 1 and Part 2 Arms 1A and 1B):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have histologically confirmed mCRPC and have progressed after at least 2&#xD;
             but no more than 3 lines of life-prolonging systemic therapy (e.g., abiraterone or&#xD;
             enzalutamide, docetaxel, cabazitaxel) or cannot tolerate any of these therapies. These&#xD;
             lines of therapy include life-prolonging therapies administered in the metastatic&#xD;
             hormone-sensitive setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior surgical or chemical castration with a serum testosterone &lt;1.7 nmol/L (50&#xD;
             ng/dL). If the method of castration is luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone analogue&#xD;
             (LHRHa), there must be a plan to maintain effective LHRHa therapy for the duration of&#xD;
             the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have documented mCRPC progression within 6 months prior to screening&#xD;
             (assuming no subsequent change in treatments), as determined by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to provide an archival pre-treatment formalin-fixed,&#xD;
             paraffin-embedded tumor sample if available.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Specific key inclusion criteria for newly diagnosed LPC patients (Part 2 Arms 2 and 3):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment-naïve patients with LPC (i.e., N0, M0). According to risk levels of the&#xD;
             European Association of Urology Guidelines on Prostate Cancer (2018), and in line with&#xD;
             the U.S. National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN 2020), patients must have at&#xD;
             least 1 of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. PSA &gt;20 ng/mL or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Gleason Score &gt;7 or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Localized stage ≥cT2c, N0, M0 according to tumor, node, metastasis&#xD;
                  classification.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who intend to have and are suitable for a radical prostatectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must agree to provide tumor sample(s) from pre-treatment diagnostic biopsy&#xD;
             and planned post-treatment surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Main exclusion criteria for all patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a known history or current malignancy other than the inclusion&#xD;
             diagnosis. Note: Exceptions are patients with malignancies with a negligible risk of&#xD;
             metastasis or death, that have been adequately treated, such as non-invasive basal&#xD;
             cell or non-invasive squamous cell skin carcinoma, non-invasive, superficial bladder&#xD;
             cancer, and any cancer with a complete response (CR) that lasted more than 2 years may&#xD;
             be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had major surgery (e.g., requiring general anesthesia) within 4&#xD;
             weeks before screening, or have not fully recovered from surgery, or have a surgery&#xD;
             planned during the time of trial participation, except for the radical prostatectomy&#xD;
             planned for patients in Part 2 Arms 2 and 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have a known history of any of the following (testing not required):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) 1 or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Hepatitis B (carrier or active infection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hepatitis C (unless considered cured 5 years post curative anti-viral therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received or currently receive the following therapy/treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Chronic systemic immunosuppressive corticosteroid treatment (prednisone &gt;5 mg&#xD;
                  daily orally [PO] or IV, or equivalent) during the trial. Note: Replacement&#xD;
                  therapy (e.g., physiologic corticosteroid replacement therapy for adrenal or&#xD;
                  pituitary insufficiency) is not considered a form of systemic treatment and is&#xD;
                  permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Prior treatment with other immune modulating agents that was (a) within fewer&#xD;
                  than 4 weeks (28 days) or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer) prior to the first&#xD;
                  dose of cemiplimab, or (b) associated with immune-mediated AEs that were Grade ≥1&#xD;
                  within 90 days prior to the first dose of cemiplimab, or (c) associated with&#xD;
                  toxicity that resulted in discontinuation of the immune-modulating agent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Prior treatment with other immune modulating agents for any non-cancer disease&#xD;
                  within 4 weeks or 5 half-lives of the agent (whichever is longer) before the&#xD;
                  first dose of IMP.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Prior treatment with live-attenuated vaccines within 4 weeks before the first&#xD;
                  dose of IMP and during treatment with IMP.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Prior treatment with an investigational drug (including investigational vaccines)&#xD;
                  within 4 weeks or 5 half-lives of the agent (whichever is longer) before the&#xD;
                  planned first dose of IMP.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Therapeutic PO or IV antibiotics within 14 days prior to enrollment. Note:&#xD;
                  Patients receiving prophylactic antibiotics (e.g., for prevention of a urinary&#xD;
                  tract infection or chronic obstructive pulmonary disease) may be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Concurrent use of herbal products that may decrease PSA levels (e.g., saw&#xD;
                  palmetto).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Specific key exclusion criteria for mCRPC Patients (Part 1 and Part 2 Arms 1A and 1B):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Excluded medical conditions&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with toxicities from previous anti-cancer therapies that have not resolved to&#xD;
             baseline levels or to Grade ≤1 according to National Cancer Institute (NCI) CTCAE v5.0&#xD;
             with the exception of alopecia, anorexia, vitiligo, fatigue, hyperthyroidism,&#xD;
             hypothyroidism, and peripheral neuropathy. Anorexia, hyperthyroidism, hypothyroidism,&#xD;
             and peripheral neuropathy must have recovered to Grade ≤2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinically active brain metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with a history of symptomatic metastatic brain or meningeal tumors may&#xD;
                  be included, if the end of definitive therapy is &gt;3 months before the first dose&#xD;
                  of W_pro1 and the patients have no clinical or radiological evidence of tumor&#xD;
                  growth.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with brain metastases must not be undergoing acute or chronic&#xD;
                  corticosteroid therapy or steroid taper.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with central nervous system symptoms should undergo a computed&#xD;
                  tomography (CT) scan or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) of the brain to exclude&#xD;
                  new or progressive brain metastases. Spinal cord metastasis is acceptable.&#xD;
                  However, patients with spinal cord compression should be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Excluded prior or concomitant anti-cancer therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received or currently receive the following anti-cancer&#xD;
             therapy/agent:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Prior radiation therapy with curative intent within 14 days before the first dose&#xD;
                  of IMP. Note: Palliative radiotherapy is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Prior treatment with an anti-cancer agent (within 4 weeks or for systemic&#xD;
                  therapies after at least 5 half-lives of the drug [whichever is longer] before&#xD;
                  the first dose of IMP). Note: Prior treatment with bone resorptive therapy, such&#xD;
                  as bisphosphonates (e.g., pamidronate, zoledronic acid, etc.) and denosumab, is&#xD;
                  allowed assuming that the patients have been on stable doses for ≥4 weeks prior&#xD;
                  to first dose of trial treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Prior treatment with anti-cancer immunomodulating agents, such as blockers of&#xD;
                  programmed death receptor-1 PD-1, programmed cell death 1 ligand 1 (PD-L1), tumor&#xD;
                  necrosis factor receptor superfamily member 9 (TNRSF9, 4-1BB, CD137), OX-40,&#xD;
                  therapeutic vaccines, cytokine treatments, or any investigational agent within 4&#xD;
                  weeks or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer) before the first dose of IMP.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>BioNTech Responsible Person</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>BioNTech SE</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>BioNTech clinical trials patient information</last_name>
    <phone>+49 6131 9084</phone>
    <phone_ext>1919</phone_ext>
    <email>patients@biontech.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>BioNTech clinical trial information desk</last_name>
    <phone>+49 6131 9084</phone>
    <phone_ext>0</phone_ext>
    <email>info@biontech.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Arizona Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tucson</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85724</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Francisco</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94158</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale University</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06520</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Miami Hospital &amp; Clinics /Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33136</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Cancer Inst.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urology San Antonio P.A.</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Antonio</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78229</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virginia Cancer Specialists</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fairfax</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22031</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Bonn</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <zip>53105</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Klinikum der Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universität</name>
      <address>
        <city>Frankfurt</city>
        <zip>60590</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Martini-Klinik am UKE GmbH</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20246</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nationales Centrum für Tumorerkrankungen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <zip>69120</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Münster</name>
      <address>
        <city>Münster</city>
        <zip>48149</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Studienpraxis Urologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nürtingen</city>
        <zip>72622</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Urologische Klinik Planegg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Planegg</city>
        <zip>82152</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Tübingen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tübingen</city>
        <zip>72076</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Magyar Honvédség Egészségügyi Központ (MH EK Honvédkórház)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Budapest</city>
        <zip>1062</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Semmelweis Egyetem, Belgyógyászati Klinika</name>
      <address>
        <city>Budapest</city>
        <zip>1083</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Onkológiai Klinika</name>
      <address>
        <city>Debrecen</city>
        <zip>4032</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Szabolcs-Szatmár-Bereg Megyei Kórházak és Egyetemi Oktatókórház</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nyíregyháza</city>
        <zip>4400</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Szent Borbála Kórház</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tatabánya</city>
        <zip>2800</zip>
        <country>Hungary</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cancer Research UK Cambridge Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cambridge</city>
        <zip>CB2 0RE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Velindre Cancer Centre (VCC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cardiff</city>
        <zip>CF14 2TL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Glasgow, Beatson WoS Cancer Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glasgow</city>
        <zip>G12 0YN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University College London Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>NW1 2PG</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Royal Marsden Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SW3 6JJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Southampton - Southampton General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southampton</city>
        <zip>SO16 6YD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Hungary</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 11, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prostate cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>PRO-MERIT</keyword>
  <keyword>Cancer vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>W_pro1</keyword>
  <keyword>BioNTech SE</keyword>
  <keyword>RNA</keyword>
  <keyword>mCRPC</keyword>
  <keyword>LPC</keyword>
  <keyword>Cemiplimab</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cemiplimab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

