<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02650258</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1R01AG049024</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02650258</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cadence and Intensity Across the Adult Lifespan</brief_title>
  <acronym>CADENCE-Adults</acronym>
  <official_title>Cadence and Intensity Across the Adult Lifespan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Massachusetts, Amherst</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Massachusetts, Amherst</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine and link cadence (the number of steps taken in a&#xD;
      minute) to the intensity of physical activity (e.g. low-, moderate- and vigorous-intensity)&#xD;
      in adults (21-85 years old). The investigators anticipate that cadence will be a good&#xD;
      indicator of exercise intensity. Identifying how cadence relates to activity intensity will&#xD;
      allow for physical activity guidelines to be communicated to the public in a manner that is&#xD;
      more accessible to the lay person.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There will be up to two lab visits for CADENCE-ADULTS participants, all of which will be&#xD;
      completed in the Physical Activity and Health Lab at University of Massachusetts Amherst.&#xD;
      Participation will include: orientation to the experiment, consent, physical examination and&#xD;
      testing. The entire research protocol will last between 3.5-4.5 hrs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For all participants the first visit will consist of an orientation to the project,&#xD;
      screening, informed consent, physical exam and ECG (if necessary, see below), as well as the&#xD;
      graded treadmill walking protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to coming to the laboratory participants will undergo a phone screening in order to&#xD;
      identify interest, outline basic inclusion/exclusion criteria and give a brief description of&#xD;
      the study protocol. If interested participants will be scheduled for their first visit and be&#xD;
      given the instruction to arrive at the laboratory having observed at least a 4-hour fast.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The reason for required fast is that metabolic responses to exercise are affected by food&#xD;
      intake. By fasting for 4 hrs prior to the exercise testing window the investigators insure&#xD;
      standardization of metabolic responses to exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Orientation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be taken through a slide orientation session where all aspects of the study&#xD;
      will be covered. This slide set has both written and pictorial descriptions of the different&#xD;
      phases of the experiment, eligibility criteria, participant rights, compensation and&#xD;
      confidentially. At this time participants have the opportunity to ask any questions of the&#xD;
      experimenters that they would like.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Consent:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If after being presented with the orientation information a person would like to enroll in&#xD;
      the study they will be given the informed consent document. They will be given ample&#xD;
      opportunity to read through the document and decide if they would like to sign the paper and&#xD;
      enroll in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pre-testing screening:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the consent paperwork is signed participants will have their height, seating height,&#xD;
      body weight, body fat percentage, BMI, and waist circumference taken. Questions will also be&#xD;
      asked to ascertain date of birth, gender and race/ethnicity. Participants will then be taken&#xD;
      through a series of screening questionnaires to assess cardio-metabolic risk via the the most&#xD;
      recent edition of the American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) Resource for The Health&#xD;
      Fitness Specialist and also the American heart Association's (AHA) risk stratification&#xD;
      recommendations presented in the same ACSM resource. Risk will be assessed in the following&#xD;
      ways:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For participants considered low risk (men 21-44 years of age and women 21-54 years of age,&#xD;
      asymptomatic and with ≤ 1 risk factors) no physical examination and resting ECG is necessary&#xD;
      prior to enrolling in the study. Those considered at moderate risk (men 45-69 and women 55-69&#xD;
      years of age, asymptomatic with ≥ 2 risk factors) will require the physical examination and&#xD;
      resting ECG prior to enrolling in the study. Those considered to be high risk (symptomatic,&#xD;
      or with known cardiac, pulmonary or metabolic disease), or found to be at high risk following&#xD;
      risk stratification, will require medical supervision during the submaximal treadmill&#xD;
      exercise protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants who are 61-85 years of age will require a physical examination and resting&#xD;
      ECG prior to enrolling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical Exam and ECG:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A physical exam will be conducted by our study staff under the guidance of our medical&#xD;
      examiner (Dr. Chipkin) to assess for medical conditions that may interfere with exercise&#xD;
      protocol. In addition, this is being performed to ensure participant safety during exercise&#xD;
      protocol .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electrocardiogram (ECG). A 12-lead electrocardiogram will be performed by study staff and&#xD;
      reviewed by a clinical exercise specialist (e.g., clinical exercise physiologist) or MD prior&#xD;
      to exercise protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All testing will be overseen by trained study staff with an MS or PhD in Exercise&#xD;
      Science/Physiology or BS in Kinesiology. These accommodations meet the latest ACSM (10&#xD;
      Edition, Guidelines for Exercise Testing and Prescription) and AHA criteria for exercise&#xD;
      protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental Testing:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately prior to exercise testing participants will be outfitted with a number of&#xD;
      non-invasive devices to measure/monitor physical activity. Additionally they will be&#xD;
      outfitted with a wireless metabolic mask to measure gas exchange for a criterion measure of&#xD;
      energy expenditure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete both the treadmill testing and mock free-living activities while&#xD;
      physical activity and oxygen uptake are continually and concurrently measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each speed on the treadmill and each free-living activity will be performed for 5 minutes&#xD;
      with a 2 minute rest between each activity. Participants will complete each activity at their&#xD;
      preferred level of effort.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treadmill walking:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will then complete a series of walking bouts on a treadmill while their physical&#xD;
      activity and oxygen uptake are concurrently assessed. The walking bouts start at 0.5 miles&#xD;
      per hour and end at 6 miles per hour (0.5 miles per hour increments). Treadmill testing will&#xD;
      be terminated when any of the following criteria are attained: upon any natural tendency to&#xD;
      reach out to use the hand rails to steady and/or support themselves, following completion of&#xD;
      the fist bout when their heart rate attains 75% of age-predicted maximum heart&#xD;
      rate(indicative of having achieved vigorous intensity), participants identify as having a&#xD;
      14/20 or greater level of exertion on a Borg Rate of Perceived Exertion Scale, following&#xD;
      completion of first bout when the participant naturally selects to run instead of walk,&#xD;
      following completion of a bout at 6.0 mph, or before any of the above criteria, as the&#xD;
      participant prefers, reflecting their personal tolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Free-Living Activities:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will rest in chair, watch a portion of a movie while seated in a chair, complete&#xD;
      seated computer work, walk up and down a set of stairs, fold laundry while standing, and&#xD;
      vacuum the floor. Participant will then complete a continuous walk for 5 minutes at their&#xD;
      desired pace. This walk will be completed in a corridor with an electronic gait mat&#xD;
      (GaitRite, Inc., USA) covering a portion of the walking course.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following completion of the testing, participants will be given a small snack and drink and&#xD;
      will be monitored to ensure it is safe for them to return to their day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      NIH NIA supplement award R01AG049024-05S1, start date May 2018 -&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the above procedures related to the CADENCE-Adults parent award, participants&#xD;
      aged 61-85 may also participate in an optional component of the study related to the&#xD;
      supplement award. This will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 week of physical activity monitoring: An additional 7 consecutive days of physical activity&#xD;
      monitoring (ActiGraph GT9X and New Lifestyle DigiWalker SW-200). Participants will wear the&#xD;
      devices on their waist for 24 hours a day and maintain their usual physical activity levels.&#xD;
      They will also be asked to complete a daily physical activity log. Participants will be to&#xD;
      complete this within twelve weeks of their final visit to the physical activity and health&#xD;
      lab. In addition, they will also be asked a series questions regarding their physical&#xD;
      activity history over the past month (CHAMPS questionnaire).&#xD;
&#xD;
      AND Peak aerobic fitness treadmill protocol (modified Balke protocol). Participants will will&#xD;
      first walk for a warm-up period of 6 - 10 minutes at a comfortable walking speed. Treadmill&#xD;
      speed will then be set to elicit 70-80% of their age-predicted max heart-rate (HRmax), and&#xD;
      remain constant for the entirety of the protocol. This speed will be determined based on the&#xD;
      speed and heart rate relationship observed during the previous treadmill test (sub-maximal&#xD;
      treadmill protocol). Specifically, if 70% of HRmax was reached during the previous test, the&#xD;
      peak aerobic fitness test will start at the first speed at which this heart rate threshold&#xD;
      was first observed. If the previous test was terminated before 70% of HRmax (e.g., the&#xD;
      participant naturally chose to run or achieved a rating perceived exertion consistent with a&#xD;
      vigorous intensity), the speed for the peak protocol will be set at 0.5 mph faster than the&#xD;
      previous test's termination speed. If the previous test was terminated before 70% of HRmax&#xD;
      was reached because the participant: indicated they wished to stop the test, the researchers&#xD;
      stopped the test due to safety concerns, they reached for the handrail or became unsteady, or&#xD;
      they achieved a systolic blood pressure &gt;200 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure &gt;110 mmHg; then&#xD;
      the speed for the peak protocol will be set 0.5 mph slower than the previous termination&#xD;
      speed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant will first walk at the pre-determined testing speed for 2 minutes at a grade&#xD;
      (incline) of 0%. The grade will then be increased from 0% to 4% after 2-minutes, then to 6%&#xD;
      after 4 minutes, and then by 2% every minute thereafter until they indicate that they want to&#xD;
      stop (voluntary exhaustion), or earlier for any safety-related reasons. During this testing,&#xD;
      the participant will be outfitted with the Oxycon Mobile to assess peak aerobic fitness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For safety reasons, participants will be required to wear the ECG and BP equipment to monitor&#xD;
      their cardiovascular responses during this test. A trained staff member will be on hand to&#xD;
      operate this equipment, monitor responses and ensure safety procedures are followed. Our&#xD;
      medical investigator, Dr Stuart Chipkin will be on hand to supervise all peak treadmill&#xD;
      protocols.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be required to complete this a minimum of 7 days, and maximum of 12 weeks&#xD;
      from the the submaximal treadmil protocol in the parent award.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 5, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 5, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cadence (steps/min) as assessed by observation (hand tallied counts) of cadence</measure>
    <time_frame>Cross-sectional data; single time point, throughout study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>The identification of cadence value cut-points associated with low, moderate and vigorous activity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Monitor validation (difference in steps/min compared to observation/hand tallied counts)</measure>
    <time_frame>Cross-sectional data; single time point, throughout study, up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Compare the ability of different activity monitors to accurately measure cadence</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">260</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <condition>Walking</condition>
  <condition>Motor Activity</condition>
  <condition>Activities of Daily Living</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Young Adult</arm_group_label>
    <description>80 Adults 21-40 years of age: 10 Male and 10 Female in each 5 year increment (21-25, 26-30, 31-35, 36-40).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Middle Aged Adults</arm_group_label>
    <description>80 Adults 41-60 years of age: 10 Male and 10 Female in each 5 year increment (41-45, 46-50, 51-55, 56-60).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Older Adults</arm_group_label>
    <description>100 Adults 61-85 years of age: 10 Male and 10 Female in each 5 year increment (61-65, 66-69, 70-75, 76-80, 81-85).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>treadmill walking</intervention_name>
    <description>all participants walking at increasing speeds on a treadmill</description>
    <arm_group_label>Middle Aged Adults</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Older Adults</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Young Adult</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A convenience sample from the surrounding community of male and females 21-85 years will be&#xD;
        recruited as participants. Specifically, 10 men and 10 women for each 5-year age-group&#xD;
        category (21-25, 26-30, 31-35, etc.) will be collected.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults between ages 21-85 years, able to ambulate on a treadmill (self-report)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI less than 18.5 or more than 40kg/m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having smoked tobacco within the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  wheelchair bound, or conditions that prevent normal ambulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resting systolic blood pressure &gt; 159 mm HG, or diastolic blood pressure &gt; 99 mm HG&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalization for mental illness within the past 5 years (for the 41-60 and 61-85&#xD;
             year old cohorts this was change to &quot;within the past 1 year&quot;).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition/medication that may affect heart rate response to exercise testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of, or clinical symptoms or signs of, cardiovascular disease, stroke&#xD;
             or transient ischemic attacks, chest pain, unusual dyspnea during physical&#xD;
             activity/exercise, severe ankle swelling, or leg pain while walking.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any significant medical condition that may interfere with the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of musculoskeletal injuries or problems causing severe pain during&#xD;
             physical activity or exercise which interferes with daily activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a pacemaker or other implanted medical device (including metal joint&#xD;
             replacements).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is unable to complete all testing (1 or two sessions, based on risk&#xD;
             factors) within a maximal two week period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals wearing a full beard may need to be excluded from the study, as large&#xD;
             amounts of facial hair around the mouth and nose interfere with the seal of the device&#xD;
             that measures the air you breath. Because of this we are seeking participants that are&#xD;
             clean-shaven or with a beard where areas around the nose and mouth are clean-shaven&#xD;
             (e.g. goatee).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Catrine Tudor-Locke, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Carolina at Charlotte</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Walking Research Laboratory, University of North Carolina at Charlotte</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28223</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tudor-Locke C, Rowe DA. Using cadence to study free-living ambulatory behaviour. Sports Med. 2012 May 1;42(5):381-98. doi: 10.2165/11599170-000000000-00000. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22462794</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tudor-Locke C, Sisson SB, Collova T, Lee SM, Swan PD. Pedometer-determined step count guidelines for classifying walking intensity in a young ostensibly healthy population. Can J Appl Physiol. 2005 Dec;30(6):666-76.</citation>
    <PMID>16485518</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tudor-Locke C, Camhi SM, Leonardi C, Johnson WD, Katzmarzyk PT, Earnest CP, Church TS. Patterns of adult stepping cadence in the 2005-2006 NHANES. Prev Med. 2011 Sep;53(3):178-81. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2011.06.004. Epub 2011 Jun 25.</citation>
    <PMID>21708187</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tudor-Locke C, Han H, Aguiar EJ, Barreira TV, Schuna JM Jr, Kang M, Rowe DA. How fast is fast enough? Walking cadence (steps/min) as a practical estimate of intensity in adults: a narrative review. Br J Sports Med. 2018 Jun;52(12):776-788. doi: 10.1136/bjsports-2017-097628. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29858465</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moore CC, McCullough AK, Aguiar EJ, Ducharme SW, Tudor-Locke C. Toward Harmonized Treadmill-Based Validation of Step-Counting Wearable Technologies: A Scoping Review. J Phys Act Health. 2020 Jul 11:1-13. doi: 10.1123/jpah.2019-0205. [Epub ahead of print] Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32652514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tudor-Locke C, Aguiar EJ, Han H, Ducharme SW, Schuna JM Jr, Barreira TV, Moore CC, Busa MA, Lim J, Sirard JR, Chipkin SR, Staudenmayer J. Walking cadence (steps/min) and intensity in 21-40 year olds: CADENCE-adults. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2019 Jan 17;16(1):8. doi: 10.1186/s12966-019-0769-6.</citation>
    <PMID>30654810</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 24, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 6, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 8, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Requests for de-identified individual-level data (including descriptors) collected in CADENCE-Adults and used in publications will be considered and made available to qualified researchers within 2 years of publication of the associated paper. Data sharing agreements will be necessary for access.The CADENCE-Adults data base will be maintained and access ensured by the Physical Activity and Health Laboratory in the Department of Kinesiology at University of Massachusetts Amherst.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Researchers can request supporting information for two years post-publication</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Contact PI</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

