<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00847444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SUCCESS-C Trial</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00847444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Docetaxel Based Anthracycline Free Adjuvant Treatment Evaluation, as Well as Life Style Intervention</brief_title>
  <acronym>SUCCESS-C</acronym>
  <official_title>Simultaneous Study of Docetaxel Based Anthracycline Free Adjuvant Treatment Evaluation, as Well as Life Style Intervention Strategies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Philip Hepp</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ludwig-Maximilians - University of Munich</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, multicenter, 2x2 factorial design, randomized controlled, Phase III&#xD;
      study comparing the disease free survival after randomisation in patients treated with 3&#xD;
      cycles of Epirubicine-Fluorouracil-Cyclophosphamide(FEC)-chemotherapy, followed by 3 cycles&#xD;
      of Docetaxel(D)-chemotherapy, versus 6 cycles of Docetaxel- Cyclophosphamide&#xD;
      (DC)-chemotherapy, and to compare the disease free survival in patients with BMI of 24 - 40&#xD;
      kg/m² after randomisation with versus without the lifestyle intervention. Patients will be&#xD;
      required to have histopathological proof of a HER2/neu negative tumor and: axillary lymph&#xD;
      node metastases (pN1-3) or high risk node negative, defined as: 'pT ≥2 or histopathological&#xD;
      grade 3, or age ≤35 or negative hormone receptor status, but are not allowed to have evidence&#xD;
      of distant disease. Patients will have to be entered into the study no later than 6 weeks&#xD;
      after complete resection of the primary tumor. No other antineoplastic treatment other than&#xD;
      surgical treatment, the defined cytotoxic and endocrine treatment and radiotherapy will be&#xD;
      allowed prior to study entry and during the course of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Rationale:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Taxane based chemotherapy will be established as treatment standard in the adjuvant&#xD;
           setting of early breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  3xFEC100, followed by 3xDoc100 has been established as standard treatment option for&#xD;
           node-positive breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anthracycline based regimens do not seem to be superior in Her2/neu-negative patients&#xD;
           (Gennari et al., Slamon et al.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dietary intervention can improve outcome in patients with early breast cancer (WINS,&#xD;
           Chlebowski et al.)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The first primary objective of this study is to compare disease free survival after&#xD;
           randomisation in patients treated with a combination of&#xD;
           5-FU/Epirubicine/Cyclophosphamide followed by Docetaxel vs. Docetaxel/Cyclophosphamide&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The second primary objective of this study is to compare disease free survival after&#xD;
           randomisation in patients with vs. without lifestyle intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospectively randomized open label Phase III study with 2x2 factorial design&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The first primary objective of this study is to compare disease free survival after randomisation in patients treated with a combination of 5-FU/Epirubicine/Cyclophosphamide followed by Docetaxel vs. Docetaxel/Cyclophosphamide</measure>
    <time_frame>60 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The second primary objective of this study is to compare disease free survival after randomisation in patients with vs. without lifestyle intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>60 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3547</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lifestyle intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No individualized lifestyle intervention program.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Drug-based intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Randomization A AA: 3 cycles of 5-Fluorouracil 500 mg/m² i.v. body surface area and Epirubicine 100 mg/m² i.v. and Cyclophosphamide 500 mg/m² i.v., (FEC100), each administered on day 1, repeated on day 22, subsequently followed by 3 cycles of Docetaxel 100 mg/m² body surface area i.v. (D), administered on day 1, repeated on day 22 AB: 6 cycles of Docetaxel 75 mg/m² and Cyclophosphamide 600 mg/m² i.v. body surface area i.v. (DC), administered on day 1, repeated on day 22</description>
    <arm_group_label>AA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lifestyle-based Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>All Patients with a Body Mass Index (BMI) of 24 - 40 kg/m² at the time of enrollment will be subsequently randomized as follows:&#xD;
Second randomization B BA: Lifestyle intervention program to reduce body weight comprising individual weight loss, diet and physical activity goals in the framework of a 2-year standardized and structured telephone and mail-based intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Patients may be included in the study only if they meet all the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Primary epithelial invasive carcinoma of the breast pT1-4, pN0-3, pM0&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No evidence of HER2/neu overexpressing (IHC neg or +) or amplifying (FISH neg.) tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histopathological proof of axillary lymph node metastases (pN1-3) or high risk node&#xD;
             negative, defined as at least one criterion of the following: 'pT ≥2,&#xD;
             histopathological grade 3, age ≤35, negative hormone receptor'&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Complete resection of the primary tumor with margins of resection free of invasive&#xD;
             carcinoma not more than 6 weeks ago&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Females ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Performance status ≤ 2 on ECOG-Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate bone marrow reserve: leucocytes ≥ 3.0 x 109/l and platelets ≥ 100 x 109/l&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Bilirubin within the reference laboratory's normal range, ASAT (SGOT), ALAT (SGPT) and&#xD;
             AP within 1,5 fold of the reference laboratory's normal range for patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Willingness to participate in a telephone-based lifestyle intervention programme [10.]&#xD;
             Intention of regular follow up visits for the duration of the study [11.] Ability to&#xD;
             understand the nature of the study and to give written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients will be excluded from the study for any of the following reasons:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inflammatory breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Previous or concomitant cytotoxic or other systemic antineoplastic treatment which is&#xD;
             not part of this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A second primary malignancy (except in situ carcinoma of the cervix or adequately&#xD;
             treated basal cell carcinoma of the skin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Cardiomyopathy with impaired ventricular function (NYHA &gt; II), cardiac arrhythmias&#xD;
             influencing LVEF and requiring medication, history of myocardial infarction or angina&#xD;
             pectoris within the last 6 months, or arterial hypertension not being controlled by&#xD;
             medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any known hypersensitivity against Docetaxel, Epirubicine, Cyclophosphamide, or any&#xD;
             other medication included in the study protocol. The contraindication, warning notices&#xD;
             and measures of precaution of the products, as notified in the product infroamtion,&#xD;
             have to be respected&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Use of any investigational agent within 3 weeks prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients in pregnancy or breast feeding (in premenopausal women anticonception has to&#xD;
             be assured)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Insulin-requiring diabetes mellitus (non-insulin requiring patients with type 2&#xD;
             diabetes are eligible for the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Serious digestive and/or absorptive problems that exclude adherence to the study diet&#xD;
             [10.] Self-reported inability to walk at least one kilometer (at any pace) [11.]&#xD;
             Cardiovascular, respiratory or musculoskeletal disease or joint problems that preclude&#xD;
             moderate physical activity. Moderate arthritis that does not preclude physical&#xD;
             activity is not a reason for exclusion [12.] Psychiatric disorders or conditions that&#xD;
             would preclude participation in the study intervention [13.] Patients not sufficiently&#xD;
             fluent in German language to understand the nature of this study and any of the&#xD;
             interventional measures&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Wolfgang Janni, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Klinikum der Heinrich-Heine-Universität Düsseldorf</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Frauenklinik der Heinrich Heine Universität</name>
      <address>
        <city>Düsseldorf</city>
        <zip>40225</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.success-studie.de</url>
    <description>SUCCESS-Trial homepage</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 17, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 17, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 19, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 17, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 17, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">April 19, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ludwig-Maximilians - University of Munich</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Philip Hepp</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Sponsors Representant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

