<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00849849</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RO-08-11</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00849849</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comprehensive Postpartum Screening Strategies for Women With Gestational Diabetes Mellitus (GDM)</brief_title>
  <acronym>COPSS-GDM</acronym>
  <official_title>Comprehensive Postpartum Screening Strategies for Women With Prior Gestational Diabetes (COPSS - GDM): Now is the Time for a Paradigm Shift in Clinical Practice</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Woman's</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Woman's</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Previous gestational diabetes (GDM) predisposes affected women to diabetes. Pregnancy, in&#xD;
      essence, serves as a metabolic stress test and uncovers underlying insulin resistance and&#xD;
      ß-cell dysfunction. Cumulative incidence rates of type 2 diabetes (DM2) among women with a&#xD;
      history of GDM vary widely depending on the length of follow up and the underlying risk of&#xD;
      diabetes in the population. Like DM2, the incidence of postpartum diabetes appears to be&#xD;
      increasing The cumulative incidence of DM2 varied from 2.6 to &gt; 70% in studies with&#xD;
      postpartum follow-up ranging from 6 weeks to 28 years. Among women with a history of&#xD;
      gestational diabetes, it is generally accepted that race, age, parity, family history of&#xD;
      diabetes, pre-pregnancy weight, postpartum obesity, and weight gain are risk factors for&#xD;
      developing DM2. Other suspected risk factors include smoking, physical inactivity, diet, and&#xD;
      drugs that adversely affect glucose metabolism. Despite the high and increasing rate of DM2&#xD;
      in Louisiana, the medical community does not have reliable estimates of the number of woman&#xD;
      living in southern Louisiana who develop diabetes subsequent to GDM. At Woman's Hospital, the&#xD;
      investigators had 8246 deliveries in 2007; 7873 mothers (95% of deliveries) were either&#xD;
      African American or Caucasian. Of this group of women, 665 were diagnosed with gestational&#xD;
      diabetes mellitus. Thus, around 8.5% of the African American and Caucasian women delivering&#xD;
      babies at Woman's Hospital in 2007 had a glucose abnormality. The incidence of diabetes and&#xD;
      impaired glucose metabolism in the immediate postpartum period and within 12 months after&#xD;
      delivery in this population is unknown. There are no long-term studies performed in Louisiana&#xD;
      that have compared the benefits of different screening strategies or evaluated an optimum&#xD;
      testing frequency after GDM to reduce the rate of DM2 and cardiovascular disease (CVD) in&#xD;
      these high-risk women. The investigators plan to use this study as an outreach effort to&#xD;
      provide screening for previous gestational diabetic mothers without adequate medical coverage&#xD;
      following delivery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Women with previous gestational diabetes constitute an ideal group for the development,&#xD;
      testing, and implementation of clinical strategies for primary diabetes prevention. One-third&#xD;
      to one-half of women with a history of GDM will develop type 2 (DM2) within 3-5 years and 70%&#xD;
      will develop DM2 if followed &gt;10 years. Studies have shown that measuring only the fasting&#xD;
      glucose level postpartum is not sufficiently sensitive to identify all women who have&#xD;
      impaired glucose tolerance (IGT) or DM2. Data presented at the Fifth International&#xD;
      Workshop-Conference on GDM indicated that, postpartum, only 34% of the women with IGT or DM2&#xD;
      had impaired fasting glucose and that 44% of those with DM2 had fasting levels below 100&#xD;
      mg/dl (&lt;5.5 mmol/l). The recommended process to detect permanent diabetes in women who have&#xD;
      had GDM and who might become pregnant again is a 75-g 2-h oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT)&#xD;
      6-12 weeks post partum and every year thereafter. Postpartum management of women with GDM is&#xD;
      critical because of their markedly increased risk of DM2 and its comorbidities in the future&#xD;
      Follow-up studies of women with GDM are necessary to establish the most efficient and&#xD;
      most-effective approach to postpartum screening for type 2 diabetes. This study will examine&#xD;
      the diagnostic effectiveness of OGTT-derived glucose tolerance, insulin secretion and insulin&#xD;
      sensitivity indices compared with indices derived from fasting values of glucose and insulin&#xD;
      in subjects with GDM performed post-partum. We will establish whether post-partum fasting&#xD;
      and/or glucose-stimulated indices of insulin sensitivity and secretion most accurately&#xD;
      estimate the degree of insulin resistance relative to ß-cell function in all race/ethnicity&#xD;
      groups of women after delivery of a pregnancy complicated by gestational diabetes and predict&#xD;
      their risk for development of diabetes and CVD. .Primary Objective1) We will identify,&#xD;
      recruit and test 100 individuals with prior GDM in order to:§ Determine the best way to&#xD;
      assess glucose tolerance disorders' prevalence after pregnancy complicated by GDM in southern&#xD;
      Louisiana.§ Determine the most effective screening strategy to identify those women with&#xD;
      prior GDM who develop or are at high risk for developing DM2 and comorbidities postpartum.A 2&#xD;
      hr, 75-gram OGTT with measurements of insulin and glucose will be performed at their 6-12&#xD;
      week and 1-year post-delivery check-up; this will be compared with the results of their&#xD;
      single fasting glucose and insulin value.Secondary Objectives1) We will measure&#xD;
      cardiometabolic markers (lipids, blood pressure) in the COPS-GDM study in order to:§ Identify&#xD;
      the frequency and value of CVD risk markers in women with glucose abnormalities persisting&#xD;
      after pregnancies with GDMGlucometabolic perturbations carry a particularly high risk for&#xD;
      metabolic syndrome in women with prior GDM. Woman with prior GDM shown to have higher blood&#xD;
      pressure and an altered lipid profile with increased LDL cholesterol and triglyceride levels&#xD;
      and decreased HDL cholesterol levels that correlate with cardiovascular disease (CVD) risk&#xD;
      factors2) We will measure anthropometric measures (body weight, BMI, abdominal girth) and&#xD;
      liver aminotransferase levels (ALT, AST) in order to:§ Determine if there is a higher&#xD;
      prevalence of postpartum glucose abnormalities in women with prior GDM predicted by BMI&#xD;
      category and/or abdominal adiposity § Determine if elevated abnormal aminotransferase&#xD;
      activity is more prominent in prior GDM women and the relationship to subsequent diabetes&#xD;
      Former gestational diabetic mothers when compared with women with no history of GDM are found&#xD;
      to have higher body mass index (BMI) and visceral adiposity. The distribution of postpartum&#xD;
      glucose abnormalities by BMI category was found to be more common with increased BMI.3) We&#xD;
      will investigate the impact of breastfeeding in women with a prior GDM on glucose tolerance&#xD;
      and CVD risk factors to:§ Determine if lactation has immediate and long-term favorable&#xD;
      effects in this patient population postpartum.Breast-feeding has been associated with&#xD;
      significantly lower triglyceride level, higher HDL cholesterol, lower total cholesterol/HDL&#xD;
      ratio, lower mean fasting glucose, and lower prevalence of any postpartum abnormality of&#xD;
      glucose tolerance, including diabetes. Breastfeeding has also been reported to lower the rate&#xD;
      of overt diabetes developing later in life in women with a history of gestational diabetes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine best way to assess glucose disorder prevalence in women with prior GDM</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>A 2 hr, 75-gram OGTT with measurements of insulin and glucose will be performed at their 6-12 week and 1-year post-delivery check-up; this will be compared with the results of their single fasting glucose and insulin value.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Investigate if cardiometabolic markers-lipid profile and blood pressure anthropometric markers such as BMI [BMI, absolute body weight]; visceral adiposity as assessed by abdominal girth are associated with an increased diabetes risk</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">214</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Postpartum GDM OGTT</arm_group_label>
    <description>200 women with prior GDM in their index pregnancies will undergo postpartum screening assessment. This program will follow these women who are at a high risk of developing DM2 after delivery for 1 year.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood samples for diabetes testing&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Postpartum women with GDM (before 12 weeks postpartum)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postpartum Women (6-12 weeks)who experienced GDM during index pregnancy 18 years to 42&#xD;
             years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written consent for participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (Medical):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cholestasis during the past pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum AST and/or ALT level exceeding more than twice normal laboratory values&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical manifestation of cardiovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical manifestation of diabetes or use of anti-diabetic drugs before&#xD;
             pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical manifestation of any other significant metabolic, hematologic,&#xD;
             pulmonary, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, neurologic, immune, hepatic, renal,&#xD;
             urologic disorders, or cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular use of medications for weight control, psychosis and hormonal birth control&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of medication to treat diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria (Psychiatric and Behavioral):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or clinical manifestation of any eating disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who smoke&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of drug or alcohol abuse (up to 14 drinks a week are allowed) within the past&#xD;
             two years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or pregnancy planned during the coming year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing or unable to adhere to the clinical evaluation schedule over the twelve&#xD;
             -month study period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karen E Elkind-Hirsch, MSc,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Woman's Health Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Woman's Hospital Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baton Rouge</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70815</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2014</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 23, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 24, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 17, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 17, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 18, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Woman's</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Karen Elkind-Hirsch</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Scientific Director of Research</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>postgestational diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>diabetes mellitus</keyword>
  <keyword>OGTT</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin secretion</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes, Gestational</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

