<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00841581</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R-08-410</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15392</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00841581</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lucentis to Treat Pigment Epithelial Detachment</brief_title>
  <official_title>Intravitreal Lucentis (iL) (Ranibizumab) for the Treatment of AMD Related Pigment Epithelial Detachment (PED)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lawson Health Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lawson Health Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with Pigment Epithelial Detachments secondary to Age-Related Macular Degeneration&#xD;
      (AMD) will receive intravitreal Lucentis monthly for 6 months in the hope of improving visual&#xD;
      acuity from a baseline evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exudative Age Related Macular Degeneration (AMD) results in a significant and severe visual&#xD;
      loss if left untreated as documented in natural history and observational arms of studies&#xD;
      such as the macular photocoagulation study (MPS) and the Tap and VIP study with Visudyne. It&#xD;
      is also clear however, that the different lesion types (classified by intravenous fluorescein&#xD;
      angiography ((IVFA)) as occult, minimally classic or predominately classic) have both a&#xD;
      different natural history and a different response to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The recent introduction of the anti-VEGF agents such as Macugen and Lucentis have&#xD;
      significantly advanced our ability to treat AMD as both agents show clear efficacy across all&#xD;
      lesion subtypes regardless of lesion composition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A clear absence of literature on clinical outcomes exist however for fibrovascular pigment&#xD;
      epithelial detachments (PED). PED represents a form of exudative AMD which clearly behaves in&#xD;
      a unique and distinctive manner when compared to the lesion(s) described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As standard exclusion criteria within most of the major AMD trials, lesion composition of any&#xD;
      IVFA subtype is acceptable as long as less then 50% of the lesion is composed of blood or&#xD;
      pigment epithelial detachment. This has resulted in a notable absence of clinical literature&#xD;
      on the response of predominately PED type lesions to current standard of care anti-VEGF&#xD;
      agents. In an effort to address this absence, a prospective evaluation of the response of&#xD;
      predominately PED type lesions to Lucentis, the current gold standard therapy is needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thirty two patients will be recruited to participate based on the Inclusion / Exclusion&#xD;
      Criteria described in a later paragraph.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive monthly intravitreal Lucentis injections every 33 days (+/- 4 days) for&#xD;
      6 months. At 6 months, patients will be evaluated based on ETDRS Visual Acuity and OCT to&#xD;
      determine response to Lucentis therapy. Patients not experiencing a visual improvement from&#xD;
      baseline ETDRS acuity (defined as a net gain from baseline of 10 or more letters) or showing&#xD;
      a reduction in the height of the fibrovascular PED lesion on OCT of greater than 30% from&#xD;
      baseline OCT will be deemed Lucentis non-responders. These patients will receive no further&#xD;
      intravitreal Lucentis injections, but will undergo re-evaluation at 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients deemed responders, will continue with an OCT-guided 6 months active treatment&#xD;
      period. In these patients, iL will be administered if evidence of visual loss of 1 or more&#xD;
      lines (Snellen) from 6-month visit values, evidence of intraretinal or subretinal fluid on&#xD;
      OCT, or growth of PED by greater than 50 microns from the 6-month visit OCT values.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-responders will be evaluated only at the 12-month final visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline IVFA, OCT, Snellen Visual Acuity, ETDRS refraction and contrast sensitivity will be&#xD;
      obtained along with a comprehensive ophthalmological examination. Complete diagnostic&#xD;
      assessments including fluorescein angiography, OCT and visual function testing will be&#xD;
      repeated at 3, 6 and 12 months after baseline treatment. In addition, patients who will&#xD;
      continue on active intravitreal Lucentis therapy beyond 6 months (responders), will undergo&#xD;
      monthly OCT examinations (months 6 through 11) and ophthalmic safety examinations in order to&#xD;
      determine the need for Lucentis administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the final, Month 12 visit, all patients will undergo ophthalmic examination, OCT, ETDRS&#xD;
      refraction, Snellen Visual Acuity and contrast sensitivity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To investigate whether iL given monthly for 6 months in patients with Predominantly PED lesions (secondary to AMD) will significantly improve mean visual acuity from baseline on a standardized ETDRS chart.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of iL given monthly for 6 months in patients with Predominantly PED lesions on lesion growth and activity over the study period.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of iL given monthly for 6 months in patients with Predominantly PED lesions alone on contrast sensitivity.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of iL given monthly for 6 months in patients with Predominantly PED lesions on central retinal thickness via Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT).</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of iL given for up to 12 months in patients with Predominantly PED lesions on lesion growth and activity over the study period.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the effect of iL given for up to 12 months in patients with Predominantly PED lesions on central retinal thickness via Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT).</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Pigment Epithelial Detachment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lucentis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>All patients receive iL for for first 6 months of study. At 6 months - patients are classified as &quot;responders&quot; or &quot;non-responders&quot;. &quot;Responders&quot; receive iL PRN based on OCT,clinical exam etc. &quot;Non-responders&quot; are seen again at 12 months for repeat investigations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ranibizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Ranibizumab 0.5 mgs. (0.05 mls.) intravitreally for 6 months then as needed prn for 6 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lucentis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lucentis</other_name>
    <other_name>DIN 02296810</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Predominantly PED type lesions as classified on IVFA and OCT secondary to AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. PED under the geometric center of the foveal avascular zone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Evidence of recent disease progression as suggested by one or more of the following:&#xD;
             sub-retinal lipid or cystic macular edema, sub-retinal hemorrhage, vision loss within&#xD;
             the last 3 months or documented lesion growth on FA over previous 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Visual acuity of between 20/40 and 20/800 in the study eye - Equivalent to Early&#xD;
             Treatment of Diabetic Retinopathy Study (ETDRS) eye chart score of 5 to 75 letters at&#xD;
             2 meters.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ambulatory Vision in the fellow eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willingness and ability to participate and provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals with choroidal neovascularization from causes other than AMD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients physically unable to tolerate intravenous fluorescein angiography&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any intraocular surgery within 2 months in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior retinal or vitreous surgery including vitrectomy or scleral buckling in the&#xD;
             study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any significant ocular disease that has compromised or could compromise vision in the&#xD;
             study eye and confound analysis of the primary outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Individuals with physical or mental disabilities that prevent accurate vision testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of treatment of CNVM in the study eyes other than extrafoveal confluent laser&#xD;
             photocoagulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Prior photodynamic therapy for CNV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any patient with recent history of new onset cardiac disease or thromboembolic CNS&#xD;
             event in the past.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Women of childbearing potential who are not on two forms of effective contraception&#xD;
             during the trial and for at least 60 days following the last dose of study medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas G Sheidow, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ivey Eye Institute, LOndon, Ontario, Canada</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ivey Eye Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>N6A 4G5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 9, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 9, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 11, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 7, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 7, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 8, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Lawson Health Research Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thomas G. Sheidow</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Vitreoretinal Surgeon, Associate professor of Ophthalmology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Age Related Macular Degeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Pigment Epithelial Detachment</keyword>
  <keyword>Intravitreal Detachment</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-VEGF</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Retinal Detachment</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dissociative Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ranibizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

