<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03251885</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0188-16-NHR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03251885</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Extended-spectrum β-lactamase -Producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBL) Vertical Transmission in Women With Preterm Labor Versus Those in Term Pregnancy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Extended-spectrum β-lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBL) Vertical Carriage and Transmission Rates in Women With Preterm Labor Versus Women With Term Pregnancy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Western Galilee Hospital-Nahariya</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Western Galilee Hospital-Nahariya</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aims of the study are to evaluate the rate of ESBL-producing Enterobacteriaceae&#xD;
      colonization among women in preterm labor and term labor, the incidence of maternal vertical&#xD;
      transmission of ESBL, and the clinical significance of ESBL in preterm infants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Preterm delivery occurs before 37 weeks of gestation. Worldwide the preterm birth rate is&#xD;
      estimated to be about 11% and in Israel the preterm birth rate is approximately 7% (1, 2).&#xD;
      Preterm birth is the leading direct cause of neonatal death (death in the first 28 days of&#xD;
      life), and is responsible for 27% of neonatal deaths worldwide. Preterm births are divided to&#xD;
      spontaneous, due to preterm labor or preterm premature rupture of membrane, or iatrogenic&#xD;
      with labor induction due to maternal or fetal complications. The major risk factors for&#xD;
      spontaneous preterm birth include previous preterm delivery, multiple gestation, uterine&#xD;
      anomaly, systemic infection, history of cervical surgery and short cervical length. The&#xD;
      clinical findings of true labor (contractions plus cervical changes) are the same whether&#xD;
      labor occurs preterm or at term (3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment of women &lt;34 weeks of gestation with suspected preterm labor consist of a course of&#xD;
      betamethasone to reduce neonatal morbidity and mortality associated with preterm birth,&#xD;
      tocolytic drugs for up to 48 hours to delay delivery, antibiotics for Group B Streptococcus&#xD;
      (GBS) chemoprophylaxis and magnesium sulfate for pregnancies at 24 to 32 weeks of gestation&#xD;
      to provide neuroprotection against cerebral palsy and other types of severe motor dysfunction&#xD;
      (4). A 2014 Cochrane review of randomized trials of intrapartum antibiotic treatment of women&#xD;
      colonized with GBS found that intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis resulted in a significant&#xD;
      reduction in early-onset neonatal GBS infection and a non-significant reduction in neonatal&#xD;
      mortality (5). Intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis is given in cases of positive screening&#xD;
      culture for GBS from either vagina or rectum, positive history of birth of an infant with&#xD;
      early-onset GBS disease or GBS bacteriuria during the current pregnancy (6, 7, 8). Other risk&#xD;
      factors of developing early-onset sepsis include Intrapartum fever ≥38ºC, preterm labor (&lt;37&#xD;
      weeks of gestation) and prolonged rupture of membranes (≥18 hours); women who have these risk&#xD;
      factors should receive antibiotic prophylaxis in labor (9).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Israeli Center for Disease Control report concerning early-onset neonatal invasive GBS&#xD;
      disease showed a relatively similar incidence of invasive disease over the years 2006-2015&#xD;
      (10). In contrast, a recent report showed a marked increase in Gram-negative early-onset&#xD;
      sepsis. The incidence of early-onset Gram-negative sepsis in Israel during the years&#xD;
      2008-2014 was 0.49 for 1000 live births and increased from 0.16 per 1000 in 2008 to 0.32 in&#xD;
      2014 (11). The incidence of E.coli early-neonatal sepsis rises significantly in preterm&#xD;
      births (55 in preterm births vs. 26 in term) and in 2014 the burden of disease caused by&#xD;
      E.coli was higher than GBS.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most Gram-negative pathogens are resistant to ampicillin. Resistance of isolated E.coli to&#xD;
      second and third generation cephalosporins was noted in 8.3% of early-onset infections,&#xD;
      particularly in preterm and low-birth weight neonates and imply transmission of resistant&#xD;
      strains during labor. Extended-spectrum β- lactamase-producing Enterobacteriaceae (ESBL) are&#xD;
      pathogens which are practically resistant to all penicillins and cephalosporines. ESBL-&#xD;
      producing Enterobacteriaceae may also harbor additional antibiotic-resistant genes against&#xD;
      aminoglycosides, trimethoprim-sulfamethoxazole, ciprofloxacin and other agents (12). Although&#xD;
      the prevalence of ESBL carriage is unknown, it is clearly increasing in the community and in&#xD;
      many parts of the world 10-40% of strains of E.coli and Klebsiella pneumoniae express ESBL.&#xD;
      However, there are no guidelines concerning surveillance cultures of pregnant women both in&#xD;
      term or preterm labor for ESBL colonization although neonatal screening in neonatal intensive&#xD;
      care units (NICU), on admission and periodically after, is accepted in order to prevent ESBL&#xD;
      transmission in the NICU. In addition, we would like to compare the rate of ESBL carriage&#xD;
      rate in women in preterm versus term labor.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 12, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maternal rectal and vaginal specimens will be compared to assess influence of culturing site and admission and labor specimens will be compared for possible influence of hospitalization on ESBL carriage</measure>
    <time_frame>two years</time_frame>
    <description>positive ESBL vs. negative ESBL</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Preterm Labor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>women with preterm labor</arm_group_label>
    <description>pregnant women &lt; 37 weeks of gestations with regular uterine contractions and &gt; 3 cm dilation, &gt; 80% effacement</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>women with term pregnancy</arm_group_label>
    <description>pregnant women &gt; 37 weeks of gestation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>swabs</intervention_name>
    <description>Two swabs will be taken at each screen: one from the vagina and the other from the rectum for vaginal and rectal assessment of maternal colonization</description>
    <arm_group_label>women with preterm labor</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>women with term pregnancy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Two swabs will be taken at each screen: one from the vagina and the other from the rectum for&#xD;
      vaginal and rectal assessment of maternal colonization. Maternal colonizing ESBL strain will&#xD;
      be compared with infant's strain, if detected by the routine weekly NICU rectal surveillance&#xD;
      for ESBL carriage.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        women in preterm labor women in term labor&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm delivery &lt;37 weeks of gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  term delivery &gt; 37 weeks of gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unknown gestational age&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>female only</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Maya Wolf, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Galilee Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maya Wolf, MD</last_name>
    <phone>972--507887800</phone>
    <email>mayaw@gmc.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Galil Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nahariyya</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maya Wolf, MD</last_name>
      <phone>972-507887800</phone>
      <email>homesickid@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 14, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Western Galilee Hospital-Nahariya</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Maya Wolf</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obstetric Labor, Premature</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

