<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03255252</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ICM-URC 2015/27</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03255252</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment Study to Evaluate Specific Immune Response in Locally Advanced Cervix Cancer After Radio-chemotherapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>IMMUVIX</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment Study to Evaluate Specific Immune Response in Locally Advanced Cervix Cancer After Radio-chemotherapy (IMMUVIX)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institut du Cancer de Montpellier - Val d'Aurelle</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institut du Cancer de Montpellier - Val d'Aurelle</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Perspectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To set-up another clinical trial with this specific phenotype as the main stratification&#xD;
           factor. Therefore a more aggressive or a more specific systemic treatment (with or&#xD;
           without an immunomodulator) could be proposed to those selected patients in the field of&#xD;
           personalized medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the use of the smear as a surrogate non-invasive technique to biopsy for&#xD;
           immunomonitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To use the CTC/PD-L1 assay as a liquid biopsy in future clinical trials for&#xD;
           stratification and monitoring of cancer patients undergoing immune checkpoint&#xD;
           treatments. This specific subset of CTCs might represent metastatic cells with a high&#xD;
           potential to escape T cell-mediated lysis and might therefore be the actual targets of&#xD;
           immunotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cervical cancer is a real worldwide health care issue. High-risk human papillomavirus&#xD;
      (HR-HPV) chronic infection is a co-factor in the development of the cervical cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HR-HPV genome encodes two oncoproteins (E6 and E7) which are required to sustain the&#xD;
      malignant phenotype of pre-neoplastic lesions and are considered as foreign antigens&#xD;
      recognized by the immune system, Many studies have suggested that local immunologic escape&#xD;
      can cause the emergence of HPV-induced cervical cancer Radio-chemotherapy is the gold&#xD;
      standard treatment for locally advanced cervical cancer, resulting in 2 year-control rates of&#xD;
      about 70 to 85 %. A better and earlier understanding of the reasons for tumor escape may&#xD;
      hopefully help to improve these outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both radiation and chemotherapy are myelosuppressive treatments, but new treatment modalities&#xD;
      such as Intensity-Modulated Radiation Therapy (IMRT) may allow a more rapid hematologic&#xD;
      recovery. In addition to this immunosuppressive microenvironment, a significant number of&#xD;
      tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs) are detected in cervical cancer tissue, highlighting&#xD;
      interactions between tumor and immune cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Another issue is the fact that cancer cells develop different strategies to bypass the immune&#xD;
      surveillance, such as a down-regulation of class I human leucocyte antigen (HLA) on tumor&#xD;
      cells surface.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, there is growing evidence of the importance of immune cells in response to&#xD;
      cervical cancer treatment. TILs have been correlated with cervical cancer patients' outcome.&#xD;
      More precisely, the location and type of these immune cells seem to be of great importance&#xD;
      for the tumor response to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Receptors with negative regulatory function have been identified on the surface of those T&#xD;
      cells, including CTLA4 and PD1 and seem to play a great role in tumor escape to treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The presence of circulating tumor cells (CTCs) was shown to be correlated with a poor&#xD;
      patient's prognosis in many cancers. A recent study suggested a potential mechanism of immune&#xD;
      escape of these CTCs resulting in metastasis spreading.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis of this study is that the frequency of PD1+,CD39+, specific phenotype of the&#xD;
      non-regulatory CD4+ and CD8+ T cells among TILs is involved with the lack of response to the&#xD;
      treatment and correlates with an early relapse after the treatment (i.e. patients with a very&#xD;
      poor prognosis).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Perspectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To set-up another clinical trial with this specific phenotype as the main stratification&#xD;
           factor. Therefore a more aggressive or a more specific systemic treatment (with or&#xD;
           without an immunomodulator) could be proposed to those selected patients in the field of&#xD;
           personalized medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the use of the smear as a surrogate non-invasive technique to biopsy for&#xD;
           immunomonitoring.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To use the CTC/PD-L1 assay as a liquid biopsy in future clinical trials for&#xD;
           stratification and monitoring of cancer patients undergoing immune checkpoint&#xD;
           treatments. This specific subset of CTCs might represent metastatic cells with a high&#xD;
           potential to escape T cell-mediated lysis and might therefore be the actual targets of&#xD;
           immunotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 15, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>radiothérapy with concomittant chemotherapy</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Expression of CD8+CD39+PD1+ lymphocytes infiltrate on cervix biopsies</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year disease free survival</time_frame>
    <description>Cervix biopsies analysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect on 1-year DFS of other putative biomarkers (CD73, CD39, PD1 and Tim3) on the non-regulatory CD4+ and CD8+ lymphocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year disease free survival</time_frame>
    <description>Cervix biopsies and blood samples analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">29</enrollment>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cisplatin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Weekly cisplatin (40 mg/m²) will be administered during radiotherapy. At least 3 cycles of cisplatin should be performed according to the hematological and renal functions but not mandatory.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cisplatin injection</intervention_name>
    <description>Weekly cisplatin (40 mg/m²) will be administered during radiotherapy. At least 3 cycles of cisplatin should be performed according to the hematological and renal functions but not mandatory.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cisplatin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>radiotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>A total dose of 45Gy in 25 fractions to the PTV is considered standard but simultaneous integrated boost or two steps boost to specific volumes (positive lymph nodes for example) are accepted and left to the investigator's discretion).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cisplatin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HPV-positive cervical cancer proven* by biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All FIGO stages cervical cancers which are the matter for radio-chemotherapy and&#xD;
             exclusive brachytherapy indications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status ≤2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be affiliated to a Social Security System.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient information and written informed consent form signed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adenocarcinoma of cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known autoimmune disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV and/ or hepatitis infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pelvic radiation or radio-chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent or metastatic cervical cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contra-indication for cisplatin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient pregnant and/or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other malignancy within the previous 5 years (except for appropriately&#xD;
             treated melanoma skin carcinoma).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition&#xD;
             potentially hampering compliance with the study protocol and follow-up schedule&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean-Pierre BLEUSE, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>ICM Val d'Aurelle</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinique Beausoleil</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34070</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU Montpellier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34295</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ICM Val d'Aurelle</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montpellier</city>
        <zip>34298</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Dikshit R, Eser S, Mathers C, Rebelo M, Parkin DM, Forman D, Bray F. Cancer incidence and mortality worldwide: sources, methods and major patterns in GLOBOCAN 2012. Int J Cancer. 2015 Mar 1;136(5):E359-86. doi: 10.1002/ijc.29210. Epub 2014 Oct 9.</citation>
    <PMID>25220842</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Vuyst H, Clifford G, Li N, Franceschi S. HPV infection in Europe. Eur J Cancer. 2009 Oct;45(15):2632-9. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2009.07.019. Epub 2009 Aug 24.</citation>
    <PMID>19709878</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>zur Hausen H. Papillomavirus infections--a major cause of human cancers. Biochim Biophys Acta. 1996 Oct 9;1288(2):F55-78. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>8876633</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mauch P, Constine L, Greenberger J, Knospe W, Sullivan J, Liesveld JL, Deeg HJ. Hematopoietic stem cell compartment: acute and late effects of radiation therapy and chemotherapy. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 1995 Mar 30;31(5):1319-39. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>7713791</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mell LK, Tiryaki H, Ahn KH, Mundt AJ, Roeske JC, Aydogan B. Dosimetric comparison of bone marrow-sparing intensity-modulated radiotherapy versus conventional techniques for treatment of cervical cancer. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2008 Aug 1;71(5):1504-10. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrobp.2008.04.046.</citation>
    <PMID>18640499</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kobayashi A, Weinberg V, Darragh T, Smith-McCune K. Evolving immunosuppressive microenvironment during human cervical carcinogenesis. Mucosal Immunol. 2008 Sep;1(5):412-20. doi: 10.1038/mi.2008.33. Epub 2008 Jul 2.</citation>
    <PMID>19079205</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jordanova ES, Gorter A, Ayachi O, Prins F, Durrant LG, Kenter GG, van der Burg SH, Fleuren GJ. Human leukocyte antigen class I, MHC class I chain-related molecule A, and CD8+/regulatory T-cell ratio: which variable determines survival of cervical cancer patients? Clin Cancer Res. 2008 Apr 1;14(7):2028-35. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-07-4554.</citation>
    <PMID>18381941</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hasim A, Abudula M, Aimiduo R, Ma JQ, Jiao Z, Akula G, Wang T, Abudula A. Post-transcriptional and epigenetic regulation of antigen processing machinery (APM) components and HLA-I in cervical cancers from Uighur women. PLoS One. 2012;7(9):e44952. Epub 2012 Sep 14.</citation>
    <PMID>23024775</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gadducci A, Guerrieri ME, Greco C. Tissue biomarkers as prognostic variables of cervical cancer. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2013 May;86(2):104-29. doi: 10.1016/j.critrevonc.2012.09.003. Epub 2012 Sep 30. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23031678</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bell MC, Edwards RP, Partridge EE, Kuykendall K, Conner W, Gore H, Turbat-Herrara E, Crowley-Nowick PA. CD8+ T lymphocytes are recruited to neoplastic cervix. J Clin Immunol. 1995 May;15(3):130-6.</citation>
    <PMID>7559915</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yamazawa K, Matsui H, Ishikura H, Seki K, Mitsuhashi A, Sekiya S. Significance of perivascular lymphocytic infiltrates on survival of patients with invasive cervical cancer. J Immunother. 2003 Mar-Apr;26(2):149-55.</citation>
    <PMID>12616106</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Piersma SJ, Jordanova ES, van Poelgeest MI, Kwappenberg KM, van der Hulst JM, Drijfhout JW, Melief CJ, Kenter GG, Fleuren GJ, Offringa R, van der Burg SH. High number of intraepithelial CD8+ tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes is associated with the absence of lymph node metastases in patients with large early-stage cervical cancer. Cancer Res. 2007 Jan 1;67(1):354-61.</citation>
    <PMID>17210718</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Vos van Steenwijk PJ, Ramwadhdoebe TH, Goedemans R, Doorduijn EM, van Ham JJ, Gorter A, van Hall T, Kuijjer ML, van Poelgeest MI, van der Burg SH, Jordanova ES. Tumor-infiltrating CD14-positive myeloid cells and CD8-positive T-cells prolong survival in patients with cervical carcinoma. Int J Cancer. 2013 Dec 15;133(12):2884-94. doi: 10.1002/ijc.28309. Epub 2013 Jul 5.</citation>
    <PMID>23740735</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sznol M, Chen L. Antagonist antibodies to PD-1 and B7-H1 (PD-L1) in the treatment of advanced human cancer. Clin Cancer Res. 2013 Mar 1;19(5):1021-34. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-12-2063.</citation>
    <PMID>23460533</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Karim R, Jordanova ES, Piersma SJ, Kenter GG, Chen L, Boer JM, Melief CJ, van der Burg SH. Tumor-expressed B7-H1 and B7-DC in relation to PD-1+ T-cell infiltration and survival of patients with cervical carcinoma. Clin Cancer Res. 2009 Oct 15;15(20):6341-7. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-09-1652. Epub 2009 Oct 13.</citation>
    <PMID>19825956</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yan J, Zhang Y, Zhang JP, Liang J, Li L, Zheng L. Tim-3 expression defines regulatory T cells in human tumors. PLoS One. 2013;8(3):e58006. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0058006. Epub 2013 Mar 5.</citation>
    <PMID>23526963</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bastid J, Cottalorda-Regairaz A, Alberici G, Bonnefoy N, Eliaou JF, Bensussan A. ENTPD1/CD39 is a promising therapeutic target in oncology. Oncogene. 2013 Apr 4;32(14):1743-51. doi: 10.1038/onc.2012.269. Epub 2012 Jul 2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22751118</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bastid J, Regairaz A, Bonnefoy N, Déjou C, Giustiniani J, Laheurte C, Cochaud S, Laprevotte E, Funck-Brentano E, Hemon P, Gros L, Bec N, Larroque C, Alberici G, Bensussan A, Eliaou JF. Inhibition of CD39 enzymatic function at the surface of tumor cells alleviates their immunosuppressive activity. Cancer Immunol Res. 2015 Mar;3(3):254-65. doi: 10.1158/2326-6066.CIR-14-0018. Epub 2014 Nov 17.</citation>
    <PMID>25403716</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bonnefoy N, Bastid J, Alberici G, Bensussan A, Eliaou JF. CD39: A complementary target to immune checkpoints to counteract tumor-mediated immunosuppression. Oncoimmunology. 2015 Feb 3;4(5):e1003015. eCollection 2015 May.</citation>
    <PMID>26155397</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ma Y, Adjemian S, Mattarollo SR, Yamazaki T, Aymeric L, Yang H, Portela Catani JP, Hannani D, Duret H, Steegh K, Martins I, Schlemmer F, Michaud M, Kepp O, Sukkurwala AQ, Menger L, Vacchelli E, Droin N, Galluzzi L, Krzysiek R, Gordon S, Taylor PR, Van Endert P, Solary E, Smyth MJ, Zitvogel L, Kroemer G. Anticancer chemotherapy-induced intratumoral recruitment and differentiation of antigen-presenting cells. Immunity. 2013 Apr 18;38(4):729-41. doi: 10.1016/j.immuni.2013.03.003. Epub 2013 Apr 4.</citation>
    <PMID>23562161</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ko A, Kanehisa A, Martins I, Senovilla L, Chargari C, Dugue D, Mariño G, Kepp O, Michaud M, Perfettini JL, Kroemer G, Deutsch E. Autophagy inhibition radiosensitizes in vitro, yet reduces radioresponses in vivo due to deficient immunogenic signalling. Cell Death Differ. 2014 Jan;21(1):92-9. doi: 10.1038/cdd.2013.124. Epub 2013 Sep 13.</citation>
    <PMID>24037090</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Evans EM, Man S, Evans AS, Borysiewicz LK. Infiltration of cervical cancer tissue with human papillomavirus-specific cytotoxic T-lymphocytes. Cancer Res. 1997 Jul 15;57(14):2943-50.</citation>
    <PMID>9230206</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Höhn H, Pilch H, Günzel S, Neukirch C, Freitag K, Necker A, Maeurer MJ. Human papillomavirus type 33 E7 peptides presented by HLA-DR*0402 to tumor-infiltrating T cells in cervical cancer. J Virol. 2000 Jul;74(14):6632-6.</citation>
    <PMID>10864677</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Höhn H, Pilch H, Günzel S, Neukirch C, Hilmes C, Kaufmann A, Seliger B, Maeurer MJ. CD4+ tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes in cervical cancer recognize HLA-DR-restricted peptides provided by human papillomavirus-E7. J Immunol. 1999 Nov 15;163(10):5715-22.</citation>
    <PMID>10553103</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hilders CG, Ras L, van Eendenburg JD, Nooyen Y, Fleuren GJ. Isolation and characterization of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes from cervical carcinoma. Int J Cancer. 1994 Jun 15;57(6):805-13.</citation>
    <PMID>8206676</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Santin AD, Bellone S, Palmieri M, Bossini B, Roman JJ, Cannon MJ, Bignotti E, Canè S, Pecorelli S. Induction of tumor-specific cytotoxicity in tumor infiltrating lymphocytes by HPV16 and HPV18 E7-pulsed autologous dendritic cells in patients with cancer of the uterine cervix. Gynecol Oncol. 2003 May;89(2):271-80.</citation>
    <PMID>12713991</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Jong A, van Poelgeest MI, van der Hulst JM, Drijfhout JW, Fleuren GJ, Melief CJ, Kenter G, Offringa R, van der Burg SH. Human papillomavirus type 16-positive cervical cancer is associated with impaired CD4+ T-cell immunity against early antigens E2 and E6. Cancer Res. 2004 Aug 1;64(15):5449-55.</citation>
    <PMID>15289354</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kenter GG, Welters MJ, Valentijn AR, Lowik MJ, Berends-van der Meer DM, Vloon AP, Essahsah F, Fathers LM, Offringa R, Drijfhout JW, Wafelman AR, Oostendorp J, Fleuren GJ, van der Burg SH, Melief CJ. Vaccination against HPV-16 oncoproteins for vulvar intraepithelial neoplasia. N Engl J Med. 2009 Nov 5;361(19):1838-47. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa0810097.</citation>
    <PMID>19890126</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Heusinkveld M, Welters MJ, van Poelgeest MI, van der Hulst JM, Melief CJ, Fleuren GJ, Kenter GG, van der Burg SH. The detection of circulating human papillomavirus-specific T cells is associated with improved survival of patients with deeply infiltrating tumors. Int J Cancer. 2011 Jan 15;128(2):379-89. doi: 10.1002/ijc.25361. Epub 2010 Apr 5.</citation>
    <PMID>20473854</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>van der Burg SH, Ressing ME, Kwappenberg KM, de Jong A, Straathof K, de Jong J, Geluk A, van Meijgaarden KE, Franken KL, Ottenhoff TH, Fleuren GJ, Kenter G, Melief CJ, Offringa R. Natural T-helper immunity against human papillomavirus type 16 (HPV16) E7-derived peptide epitopes in patients with HPV16-positive cervical lesions: identification of 3 human leukocyte antigen class II-restricted epitopes. Int J Cancer. 2001 Mar 1;91(5):612-8.</citation>
    <PMID>11267969</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Welters MJ, de Jong A, van den Eeden SJ, van der Hulst JM, Kwappenberg KM, Hassane S, Franken KL, Drijfhout JW, Fleuren GJ, Kenter G, Melief CJ, Offringa R, van der Burg SH. Frequent display of human papillomavirus type 16 E6-specific memory t-Helper cells in the healthy population as witness of previous viral encounter. Cancer Res. 2003 Feb 1;63(3):636-41.</citation>
    <PMID>12566307</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Welters MJ, van der Logt P, van den Eeden SJ, Kwappenberg KM, Drijfhout JW, Fleuren GJ, Kenter GG, Melief CJ, van der Burg SH, Offringa R. Detection of human papillomavirus type 18 E6 and E7-specific CD4+ T-helper 1 immunity in relation to health versus disease. Int J Cancer. 2006 Feb 15;118(4):950-6.</citation>
    <PMID>16152582</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ressing ME, van Driel WJ, Celis E, Sette A, Brandt MP, Hartman M, Anholts JD, Schreuder GM, ter Harmsel WB, Fleuren GJ, Trimbos BJ, Kast WM, Melief CJ. Occasional memory cytotoxic T-cell responses of patients with human papillomavirus type 16-positive cervical lesions against a human leukocyte antigen-A *0201-restricted E7-encoded epitope. Cancer Res. 1996 Feb 1;56(3):582-8.</citation>
    <PMID>8564975</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bontkes HJ, de Gruijl TD, van den Muysenberg AJ, Verheijen RH, Stukart MJ, Meijer CJ, Scheper RJ, Stacey SN, Duggan-Keen MF, Stern PL, Man S, Borysiewicz LK, Walboomers JM. Human papillomavirus type 16 E6/E7-specific cytotoxic T lymphocytes in women with cervical neoplasia. Int J Cancer. 2000 Oct 1;88(1):92-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10962445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Luxton JC, Rowe AJ, Cridland JC, Coletart T, Wilson P, Shepherd PS. Proliferative T cell responses to the human papillomavirus type 16 E7 protein in women with cervical dysplasia and cervical carcinoma and in healthy individuals. J Gen Virol. 1996 Jul;77 ( Pt 7):1585-93.</citation>
    <PMID>8758003</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Steinert G, Schölch S, Niemietz T, Iwata N, García SA, Behrens B, Voigt A, Kloor M, Benner A, Bork U, Rahbari NN, Büchler MW, Stoecklein NH, Weitz J, Koch M. Immune escape and survival mechanisms in circulating tumor cells of colorectal cancer. Cancer Res. 2014 Mar 15;74(6):1694-704. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-13-1885. Epub 2014 Mar 5.</citation>
    <PMID>24599131</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mazel M, Jacot W, Pantel K, Bartkowiak K, Topart D, Cayrefourcq L, Rossille D, Maudelonde T, Fest T, Alix-Panabières C. Frequent expression of PD-L1 on circulating breast cancer cells. Mol Oncol. 2015 Nov;9(9):1773-82. doi: 10.1016/j.molonc.2015.05.009. Epub 2015 Jun 9.</citation>
    <PMID>26093818</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Golden EB, Apetoh L. Radiotherapy and immunogenic cell death. Semin Radiat Oncol. 2015 Jan;25(1):11-7. doi: 10.1016/j.semradonc.2014.07.005. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25481261</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Delgado FG, Martínez E, Céspedes MA, Bravo MM, Navas MC, Cómbita Rojas AL. Increase of human papillomavirus-16 E7-specific T helper type 1 response in peripheral blood of cervical cancer patients after radiotherapy. Immunology. 2009 Apr;126(4):523-34. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2567.2008.02912.x. Epub 2008 Sep 5.</citation>
    <PMID>18778290</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lim K, Small W Jr, Portelance L, Creutzberg C, Jürgenliemk-Schulz IM, Mundt A, Mell LK, Mayr N, Viswanathan A, Jhingran A, Erickson B, De los Santos J, Gaffney D, Yashar C, Beriwal S, Wolfson A, Taylor A, Bosch W, El Naqa I, Fyles A; Gyn IMRT Consortium. Consensus guidelines for delineation of clinical target volume for intensity-modulated pelvic radiotherapy for the definitive treatment of cervix cancer. Int J Radiat Oncol Biol Phys. 2011 Feb 1;79(2):348-55. doi: 10.1016/j.ijrobp.2009.10.075. Epub 2010 May 14.</citation>
    <PMID>20472347</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 10, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 18, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cisplatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

