<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03250702</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB13-0852</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03250702</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DUCS-DHD Determinants of Hypertension in Tanzania</brief_title>
  <acronym>DUCS-HTN</acronym>
  <official_title>Dar es Salaam Urban Cohort Hypertension Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Harvard School of Public Health (HSPH)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Harvard School of Public Health (HSPH)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the Dar es Salaam Urban Cohort Hypertension Study (DUCS-HTN) was to determine the&#xD;
      current prevalence, risk factors, and barriers to diagnosis and treatment for hypertension in&#xD;
      Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. Few previous studies in Tanzania have analyzed the modifiable&#xD;
      determinants of high BP as well as barriers to diagnosis and treatment of hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DUCS-HTN is a cohort of adults living in the Ukonga ward of Dar es Salaam who had been&#xD;
      registered in the Dar es Salaam Health and Demographic Surveillance System (HDSS) in 2011.&#xD;
      Due to the large size of Ukonga, the investigators chose to randomly sample two of the seven&#xD;
      neighborhoods that compose Ukonga and then conducted a census of these two randomly selected&#xD;
      neighborhoods, Mwembe Madafu and Markazi. The investigators attempted to contact all 4896&#xD;
      HDSS participants who were at least 40 years of age and lived in one of these neighborhoods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trained interviewers conducted face-to-face interviews and physical examinations in&#xD;
      participants' homes from March to June 2014. Follow-up visits were conducted from April to&#xD;
      June 2015.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among 4896 potentially eligible participants from the HDSS baseline survey, 3604 (74%) were&#xD;
      still living at the same address in 2014. Of these, 2290 (64%) enrolled in the DUCS-HTN&#xD;
      study. Of the participants enrolled at baseline, 1752 (77%) participated in the follow-up&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood pressure measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
      Trained interviewers measured blood pressure with digital blood pressure monitors (15 Omron&#xD;
      M2 and 5 Beurer BM 40 monitors). Standard, large, and extra-large cuff sizes were used&#xD;
      according to the size of a participant's arm. Blood pressure was measured three times with at&#xD;
      least a 5-minute rest before the first measurement and 3-minute rests between each subsequent&#xD;
      measurement. Blood pressure was taken on the left arm with the participant seated and the arm&#xD;
      straight at heart level. Usual blood pressure values were calculated as the mean of the&#xD;
      second and third readings. If a second visit was conducted, usual blood pressure values were&#xD;
      defined as the mean of the second and third readings at both the first and second visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypertension was defined as SBP≥140 mmHg or DBP≥90 mmHg, or self-reported use of&#xD;
      anti-hypertensive medication. Grade I hypertension was defined as SBP of 140 to 159 or DBP of&#xD;
      90 to 99 mmHg; grade II hypertension was defined as SBP of 160 to 179 or DBP of 100 to 109&#xD;
      mmHg; and grade III hypertension was defined as SBP≥180 or DBP≥110 mmHg. Hypertension control&#xD;
      was defined as current antihypertensive use and blood pressure of less than 140/90 mmHg. If a&#xD;
      participant was found to have grade I or II hypertension, a second visit was scheduled, at&#xD;
      least three days later. Those with grade III hypertension at the last reading of the first&#xD;
      visit or grade I or II hypertension at the last reading of the second visit were told that&#xD;
      they had high blood pressure, advised to see a health professional and were given a referral&#xD;
      letter. In addition, a second visit and blood pressure reading was scheduled for a random&#xD;
      sample of one-fifth of participants, who were selected for additional blood, urinary, and&#xD;
      dietary measurements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of covariates&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants were administered a socio-demographic and lifestyle questionnaire and had&#xD;
      their height, weight, and waist and hip circumference measured. Some demographic information&#xD;
      (age, sex, neighborhood, religion, and assets used to create a household wealth index) was&#xD;
      previously recorded during the HDSS baseline. Information on household health insurance&#xD;
      coverage was collected in 2015 as part of routine HDSS updates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Standard protocols were used to take anthropometric measurements. Participants were weighed&#xD;
      with minimal clothing using a digital scale (Seca, Germany) to the nearest 0.1kg and height&#xD;
      was measured, with participants not wearing shoes, to the nearest 1cm. Body mass index (BMI)&#xD;
      was calculated as the ratio of weight in kilograms to height in meters squared (kg/m2) and&#xD;
      categorized according to WHO categories.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Global Physical Activity Questionnaire (GPAQ) was used to assess physical activity for&#xD;
      work, transportation, and leisure. The investigators defined physical inactivity according to&#xD;
      WHO guidelines. Number of servings of alcoholic beverages consumed was reported over the past&#xD;
      30 days. The investigators assumed 14 grams of alcohol as a standard drink portion size. A&#xD;
      household wealth index was created through a principal component analysis of household&#xD;
      characteristics and assets, and was categorized into quintiles. In the follow-up visit,&#xD;
      participants were asked about their health over the past year and the reasons for not seeking&#xD;
      hypertension care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A subsample of ~ one fifth of the participants completed a food frequency questionnaire, two&#xD;
      24-hour dietary recalls, a 24-hour urine collection for sodium, creatinine, protein, and&#xD;
      potassium, and had capillary total cholesterol and blood glucose measurements taken.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Continuous variable</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Visited health professional for hypertension care</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Self report of visiting health professional for hypertension care between baseline and follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Taking antihypertensive medication</measure>
    <time_frame>1-year follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Self report of taking antihypertensive treatment at time of follow-up</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypertension</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>SBP &gt;=140 or DBP &gt;=90 or using antihypertensive medication</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2290</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertension</condition>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        DUCS-HTN is a cohort of adults living in the Ukonga ward of Dar es Salaam who had been&#xD;
        registered in the Dar es Salaam Health and Demographic Surveillance System (HDSS) in 2011.&#xD;
        Due to the large size of Ukonga, we chose to randomly sample two of the seven neighborhoods&#xD;
        that compose Ukonga and then conducted a census of these two randomly selected&#xD;
        neighborhoods, Mwembe Madafu and Markazi. We attempted to contact all 4896 HDSS&#xD;
        participants who were at least 40 years of age and lived in one of these neighborhoods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Trained interviewers conducted face-to-face interviews and physical examinations in&#xD;
        participants' homes from March to June 2014. Follow-up visits were conducted from April to&#xD;
        June 2015.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Among 4896 potentially eligible participants from the HDSS baseline survey, 3604 (74%) were&#xD;
        still living at the same address in 2014. Of these, 2290 (64%) enrolled in the DUCS-HTN&#xD;
        study. Of the participants enrolled at baseline, 1752 (77%) participated in the follow-up&#xD;
        study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lived in Madafu or Markazi neighborhoods of Ukonga Ward in Tanzania&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mentally or physically disabled&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>August 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 11, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 11, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 15, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 15, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Harvard School of Public Health (HSPH)</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Goodarz Danaei</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Global Health</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tanzania</keyword>
  <keyword>Observational</keyword>
  <keyword>Sub-Saharan Africa</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

