<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04307121</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>108058</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04307121</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Association of Constipation Inflammatory and Microbial Translocation Markers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Association of Constipation Inflammatory and Microbial Translocation Markers as Well as Markers of Microbial Translocation Including Endotoxin and Its Antibodies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tungs' Taichung Metroharbour Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tungs' Taichung Metroharbour Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Growing evidences showed that patients with chronic constipation accompanied with intestinal&#xD;
      dysbiosis. Gut dysbiosis is a harbinger of chronic inflammation, yet the underlying basis is&#xD;
      unclear. Plasma level of microbial translocation is a marker of mucosal permeability.&#xD;
      Increased mucosal permeability ignites elevated microbial translocation and is a source of&#xD;
      systemic immune activation in CKD patients. The passage of microbial components from the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal tract into the systemic circulation may be an important contributor to the&#xD;
      chronic inflammatory process and subsequent atherosclerosis development. We plan to determine&#xD;
      the association constipation with biomarkers of inflammation such monocyte activation and&#xD;
      associated cytokines as well as markers of microbial translocation including endotoxin and&#xD;
      its antibodies, intestinal barrier proteins of 200 hemodialysis patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design and Population&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients and methods 2.1. Patient selection Two hundred hemodialysis patients are recruited.&#xD;
      Functional constipation will be diagnosed according to the Rome IV criteria. Organic lesions&#xD;
      of the abdominal cavity and the pelvic floor are excluded in all patients by endoscopic&#xD;
      (sigmoidoscopy, colonoscopy, gastroduodenoscopy), radiologic and ultrasonographic evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be carried out in accordance with the Declaration of Helsinki as revised in&#xD;
      2008. All patients will give written informed consent to participate in the study. All&#xD;
      patients in the renal division of Tungs Taichung Metroharbour Hospital were prospectively and&#xD;
      consecutively included. The inclusion criteria are&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Hemodialysis for more than 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Age older than 20 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exclusion criteria are a history of chronic inflammatory disease, the presence of current&#xD;
      infection, collagen vascular disease or immuno-modulatory or immuno-suppressive treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurements of inflammatory cytokines, etotaxin-1, and amyloid A&#xD;
&#xD;
      The plasma levels of MCP-1, IL-6, CRP, IL-17A and calprotectin are tested by commercially&#xD;
      available human ELISA kit respectively, according to the manufacturer's instruction. Human&#xD;
      serum eotaxin1 levels are determined using a commercial ELISA kit (R&amp;D systems, Minneapolis,&#xD;
      MN, USA) according to the manufacturer's protocol. The commercially available ELISA procedure&#xD;
      is used to measure serum amyloid A concentration in serum,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endotoxin and Endotoxin Ig M as well as IgG core antibody&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endotoxin is measured in serum by Limulus Amebocyte Lysate QCL-1000 from Lonza (catalogue #&#xD;
      50-647U)(EU/ml). Serum or plasma samples are diluted at 1∶5 ratio with LAL reagent water.&#xD;
      Endotoxin IgG core antibodies are measured in plasma using an ELISA kit from Cell Sciences&#xD;
      Inc (catalogue # HK504). Units are expressed as GMU/ml which are IgG standard median units&#xD;
      based on medians of ranges of 1000 healthy adults by the manufacturer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Determination of CD14 and CD16 Mononuclear Phenotype&#xD;
&#xD;
      Peripheral blood will be collected by venipuncture using ethylenedi- aminetetraacetic acid&#xD;
      (EDTA) as an anticoagulant. For cytometric analysis, monoclonal antibodies against CD14&#xD;
      (fluorescein isothiocyanate (FITC) conjugated; clone RMO52; Beckman Coulter, Miami, FL, USA),&#xD;
      CD16 (phycoerythrin (PE) conjugated; clone 3G8; Beckman Coulter, Miami, FL, USA), CD45&#xD;
      (phycoerythrin cyanin-5 (PC5); clone J33; Beckman Coulter, Miami, FL, USA), and CD56 (clone&#xD;
      IM2073; Beckman Coulter, Miami, FL, USA) are used. Briefly, 100 l of the whole blood is&#xD;
      stained with saturating amounts of the above mentioned monoclonal antibodies and&#xD;
      corresponding isotype controls. After incubation for 15 min at room temperature in the dark&#xD;
      according to the manufacturer's recommendations, OptiLyse C (Beckman Coulter, Miami, FL) is&#xD;
      added to lyse RBC and the samples are fixed. Fixed cells are analyzed by flow cytometry&#xD;
      within 6 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Determination of leukocyte and monocyte subset distribution is performed using a&#xD;
      FC500-Cytometer (Beckman Coulter), and CXP analysis software (version 2.2) is used (Schroers&#xD;
      et al., 2005). Monocytes are identified as CD45 positive and CD56 negative cells exhibiting a&#xD;
      specific forward and sideward scatter profile. Monocytes are then gated in an SSC/CD dot&#xD;
      plot, identifying monocytes as CD86 cells with monocyte scatter properties. Subsets of CD14&#xD;
      monocytes with and without CD16 are defined according to the surface expression pattern of&#xD;
      the lipopolysaccharide receptor CD14 and the CD16 (Fcgamma receptor III). One million cells&#xD;
      are analyzed from each sample, and the percentage of CD16 positive mononuclear cells&#xD;
      (CD14+/CD16+ and CD14++/CD16+) and the number of cells out of the total monocytes are&#xD;
      compared using fluorescent microbeads (Flow-Count, Beckman Coulter). The CD86 antibody (clone&#xD;
      HA5.2B7; Beckman Coulter, Miami, FL, USA) is used in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      sCD14, LBP, zonulin and I-FABP assays&#xD;
&#xD;
      LBP and sCD14 markers are used to monitor the microbial translocation while Zonulin and&#xD;
      I-FABP are measured to explore intestinal permeability: LBP plasma levels are measured using&#xD;
      Enzyme Immunoassay for Quantification of free human LBP ELISA kit, according to the&#xD;
      manufacturer's recommendations. Dilution factor is 1:800. Plasma level of sCD14 is measured&#xD;
      using Human sCD14 kit, according to the manufacturer's specifications. Dilution factor is&#xD;
      1:200. Zonulin serum levels are measured using Human zonulin ELISA kit. I-FABP plasma levels&#xD;
      are measured by ELISA kit according to the manufacturer's recommendations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Crossover</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbial Translocation Markers</measure>
    <time_frame>1 years</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma level of microbial translocation is a marker of mucosal permeability. Increased mucosal permeability ignites elevated microbial translocation and is a source of systemic immune activation in CKD patients. microbial translocation including endotoxin and its antibodies, intestinal barrier proteins</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Constipation</condition>
  <condition>Inflammation</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      plasma&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        hemodialysis (HD) patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemodialysis for more than 3 months and Age older than 20 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  he exclusion criteria are a history of chronic inflammatory disease, the presence of&#xD;
             current infection, collagen vascular disease or immuno-modulatory or&#xD;
             immuno-suppressive treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Paik Seong Lim, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Tungs' Taichung Metroharbour Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tungs' Taichung MetroHarbour Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 13, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>constipation</keyword>
  <keyword>microbial translocation</keyword>
  <keyword>inflammatory markers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Inflammation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Constipation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

