<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04305431</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200036</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>20-CC-0036</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04305431</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dietary Behavior Intervention in African Americans at Risk for Cardiovascular Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Exploring a Dietary Behavior Intervention in African-Americans at Risk for Cardiovascular Disease: A Community Acceptability and Feasibility Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The risk of heart disease among African Americans is still common despite a greater&#xD;
      understanding of the disease and better approaches to managing it. Healthy cooking and eating&#xD;
      patterns can help reduce the risk of heart disease. But things like access to grocery stores&#xD;
      and knowledge of good nutrition can affect these healthy patterns. Researchers want to see if&#xD;
      community-based programs can help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn about the cooking behaviors of African American adults at risk for heart disease.&#xD;
      Also, to see if a community-based cooking intervention will affect home-cooking behaviors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      African American adults 18 and older who live in Wards 7 and 8 of Washington, D.C., and have&#xD;
      at least one self-reported risk factor for heart disease&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase I participants will complete a survey. It asks about their medical history, lifestyle,&#xD;
      stress level, and eating habits. They will take part in a focus group. During this, they will&#xD;
      talk about what they eat and what foods are available to them. Participation lasts 1 day for&#xD;
      3 hours at Pennsylvania Avenue Baptist Church in Washington, D.C.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase II participants will go to shared cooking events at Pennsylvania Avenue Baptist Church.&#xD;
      These will be held once a week for 6 weeks. They will be led by a trained chef. Participants&#xD;
      will visit the NIH Clinical Center 3 times. Transportation will be provided if they need it.&#xD;
      They will have physical exams and have blood drawn. They will be interviewed and complete&#xD;
      questionnaires. A dietician will review the food they eat. An occupational therapist will&#xD;
      assess their cooking skills. They will keep a daily cooking journal. Participation lasts 18&#xD;
      weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Disparities in cardiovascular disease (CVD) morbidity and mortality among African-Americans&#xD;
      (AAs) persist despite advances in risk factor identification and evidence-based management&#xD;
      strategies. Studies suggest risk factor reduction, such as obesity treatment, positively&#xD;
      attenuates the mortality disparity between AAs and other racial/ethnic groups. Closing the&#xD;
      CVD disparity gap may require attention to more proximal causes of CVD that lower risk&#xD;
      factors, including cardiovascular health behaviors such as dietary intake and physical&#xD;
      activity. Cardiovascular-related health behaviors are directly correlated with socioeconomic&#xD;
      status, and thus, populations with lower socioeconomic status are more likely to experience&#xD;
      disparate health outcomes. One particularly important health behavior known to reduce CVD&#xD;
      risk, but also with culturally specific influences and dynamics, is dietary behavior. Factors&#xD;
      such as food access, decreased nutritional awareness, and cultural preference are significant&#xD;
      contributors to dietary behaviors and lower dietary quality. Given that lower dietary quality&#xD;
      is reported among AAs, it is important to understand how these other factors may influence AA&#xD;
      dietary behaviors and decisions. Among dietary behaviors, cooking behavior is identified as&#xD;
      an important way to lower sodium intake and daily calories as well as to improve fiber&#xD;
      intake. Cooking activity among AAs has been reported as lower than other racial/ethnic&#xD;
      groups. Determinants of cooking among AAs have not been fully explored in the literature.&#xD;
      Qualitative studies suggest demographic variables related to employment, number of family&#xD;
      members, as well as psychosocial variables related to social support and norms may have a&#xD;
      role. Limited cooking intervention studies, which have included AAs, suggest improved&#xD;
      outcomes related to diet, including DASH scores, but impact on home cooking behavior during&#xD;
      or after a cooking intervention is not known, because self-reported confidence and/or dietary&#xD;
      quality variables have been the primary outcomes reported. Furthermore, outcomes of these&#xD;
      studies and suggested related factors to home cooking have not been measured against&#xD;
      feasibility measures for delivering the intervention in a community setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will occur in two phases: First phase consists of a focus group discussion on&#xD;
      dietary behaviors with community members and the second phase consists of the dietary&#xD;
      behavior intervention delivered in a community setting, clinical examination, survey and&#xD;
      biomarker data collection.The primary objective of this study is to explore feasibility&#xD;
      measures, facilitators and barriers related to cooking and cooking frequency among an AA&#xD;
      adult population at risk for CVD following participation in a cooking intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are to explore relationships between feasibility measures, especially in&#xD;
      relation to participant burden, cooking frequency, facilitators and barriers suggested from&#xD;
      current literature as related to cooking at home. These include 1) psychosocial factors,&#xD;
      social support, social network diversity, perceived stress of cooking behaviors, 2) lifestyle&#xD;
      behaviors: sleep, physical activity, 3) built environment factors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 5, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility Measures</measure>
    <time_frame>26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Recruitment and retention/attrition Attendance/Dosage Participant burden Implementation- treatment fidelity; measures of home cooking behavior</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Facilitators and Barriers</measure>
    <time_frame>26 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Cooking diaries Cooking Self-Efficacy Scale D.C. CHOC Cooking Survey Cooking and Food Provisioning Action Scale AMPS (cooking skill) score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Second Phase Secondary Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>18 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Social Network Index HPLP-II Perceived Stress Scale MESA Neighborhood Healthy Food Availability Scale Perceptions of Neighborhood Food Retail Outlets Neighborhood Satisfaction Food purchasing practices Self-rated Health Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Assessment International Physical Activity Questionnaire-Short Form Food Away from Home Purchasing Frequency Family Meals Eaten Together Grocery receipts CVD related laboratory biomarkers Antropometric mesurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Diet</condition>
  <condition>Cooking</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1/All Subjects</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Second phase participants</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cooking Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>90-minute culinary education sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1/All Subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  FIRST PHASE:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A sample of AA adults (n= 20) living in Wards 7 or 8 of Washington, D.C. will be recruited&#xD;
        for this phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Self-identified AA adults (defined as age greater than or equal to 18)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Live in Wards 7 or 8 in Washington, D.C.&#xD;
&#xD;
        At least one self-reported risk factor for CV disease known by participant or told to&#xD;
        participant by a clinician within the last 12 months. Specific risk factors are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  overweight or obese (self-reported height and weight compute to BMI if needed greater&#xD;
             than or equal to 25)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated waist to hip ratio&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated cholesterol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical hypertension or prehypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prediabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated fasting glucose level on laboratory report&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  current smoker or prior (within the past 12 months) smoker.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Under the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
        Do not live in Wards 7 or 8 in Washington, D.C.No risk factors for CVD&#xD;
&#xD;
        Or adults not of AA descent (self-identified)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Non-English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        SECOND PHASE:&#xD;
&#xD;
        A sample of AA adults (n= 30) living in Wards 7 or 8 of Washington, D.C. will be recruited&#xD;
        for this phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        English-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Self-identified AA adults (defined as age greater than or equal to 18)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Who live in Wards 7 or 8 in Washington, D.C.&#xD;
&#xD;
        At least one self-reported risk factor for CV disease known by participant or told to&#xD;
        participant by a clinician within the last 12 months. Specific risk factors are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  overweight or obese (BMI greater than or equal to 25 )&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated waist to hip ratio&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated cholesterol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinical hypertension or prehypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prediabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  elevated fasting glucose level on laboratory report&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  current smoker or prior (within the past 12 months) smoker.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Willing to not attend or enroll in another cooking/culinary education program or class&#xD;
        during participation in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Not enrolled currently or in the prior 12 months (at time of recruitment) in another&#xD;
        ongoing cooking/culinary education program or class&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        AAs who are not age greater than or equal to 18&#xD;
&#xD;
        AA Adults not living in Wards 7 or 8 in Washington, D.C.&#xD;
&#xD;
        AA adults without at least one risk factor for CVD&#xD;
&#xD;
        Or adults not of AA descent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Non-English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
        Those enrolled currently or in the prior 12 months at time of recruitment in another&#xD;
        ongoing cooking/culinary education program or class&#xD;
&#xD;
        Those not willing to not attend or enroll in another cooking/culinary education program or&#xD;
        class during participation in this study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nicole M Farmer, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ralph T Tuason, R.N.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 594-2212</phone>
    <email>ralph.tuason@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Brenda Roberson, RN</last_name>
      <phone>(301) 594-5321</phone>
      <email>broberson@mail.nih.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2020-CC-0036.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 28, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>Heart Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Dietary Behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>Nutrition</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

