<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04583215</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>050/2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04583215</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Enhancing Frontal Lobes Plasticity in Mild Cognitive Impairment</brief_title>
  <acronym>PAS-MCI</acronym>
  <official_title>Enhancing Frontal Lobes Plasticity and Function in Patients With Mild Cognitive Impairment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      More than 5 million people live with Alzheimer's dementia (AD) in North America. No effective&#xD;
      treatment exists yet probably because by the time AD has developed it is too late to&#xD;
      intervene. Mild Cognitive Impairment (MCI) is a clinical state that typically precedes AD. In&#xD;
      MCI, the prefrontal cortex supports compensatory mechanisms that depend on robust synaptic&#xD;
      plasticity and that delay progression to AD. Using a neurostimulation approach that enhances&#xD;
      prefrontal cortical plasticity in vivo, this project aims to enhance prefrontal cortical&#xD;
      plasticity and function in patients with MCI. If successful, this project would discover a&#xD;
      treatment modality that enhances compensation in MCI and ultimately, prevents progression to&#xD;
      AD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Paired Associative Stimulation (PAS) is a neurostimulation approach that induces cortical&#xD;
      plasticity by simulating spike-timing-dependent plasticity. Combining PAS with&#xD;
      electroencephalography (EEG) (PAS-EEG), we can assess dorsolateral prefrontal cortex (DLPFC)&#xD;
      plasticity in vivo. Using PAS-EEG, we have demonstrated that patients with AD are impaired on&#xD;
      DLPFC plasticity compared to healthy control (HC) individuals and that DLPFC plasticity is&#xD;
      associated with working memory in AD and HC individuals. We have also shown that a 2-week&#xD;
      course of daily PAS to the left DLPFC restores DLPFC plasticity in patients with AD and&#xD;
      enhances their working memory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, we propose to study DLPFC plasticity and its relationship to executive function in MCI&#xD;
      and then assess the efficacy of a 2-week course of PAS in enhancing DLPFC plasticity and&#xD;
      executive function in this population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If successful, this project will identify a novel neurostimulation intervention (PAS) to&#xD;
      enhance prefrontal cortical function in MCI patients. This enhancement could result in&#xD;
      modifying the trajectory of Alzheimer's disease by delaying the progression from MCI to&#xD;
      clinical AD. This project will also identify a mechanism (neuroplasticity) that underlies&#xD;
      enhanced prefrontal cortical function. Other interventions (e.g. behavioral,&#xD;
      neurostimulation, pharmacological) could then be tested whether they engage neuroplasticity&#xD;
      to enhance prefrontal cortical function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objectives and hypotheses of the study are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective 1: To compare baseline DLPFC plasticity and its relationship to executive function&#xD;
      in MCI vs. HC participants. Hypothesis 1a: MCI participants will be impaired on PAS-LTP&#xD;
      (TMS-induced cortical evoked activity) in the left DLPFC compared to HC participants.&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1b: MCI participants will be impaired on 2-back d' and a composite executive&#xD;
      function measure compared to HC participants. Hypothesis 1c: PAS-LTP will be associated with&#xD;
      2-back d' and composite executive function measure in MCI and HC participants after&#xD;
      controlling for age, sex, and education.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective 2: To assess the efficacy of a 10-session course of bilateral PAS in enhancing&#xD;
      DLPFC plasticity and executive function in MCI participants. Hypothesis 2a: MCI participants&#xD;
      randomized to 10-session course of active PAS will experience higher PAS-LTP in the left&#xD;
      DLPFC immediately and 1 and 4 weeks after the course compared to MCI participants randomized&#xD;
      to a 10-session course of a sham control PAS condition (PAS-C). Hypothesis 2b: MCI&#xD;
      participants randomized to a 10-session course of active PAS will experience better 2-back&#xD;
      performance and higher composite executive function immediately and 1 and 4 weeks following&#xD;
      the 10-session course compared to MCI participants randomized to the course of PAS-C.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective 3: To assess whether changes in DLPFC plasticity mediate changes in executive&#xD;
      function in MCI participants following the 10-session course. Hypothesis 3: Changes in&#xD;
      PAS-LTP immediately and 1 and 4 weeks following the 10-session course will mediate changes in&#xD;
      2-back d' and composite executive function measure at all three follow-up time points.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 12, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>At screening 100 MCI and 50 HC participants will undergo clinical and cognitive assessments and a brain MRI to localize the DLPFC. If eligible, at baseline, all participants will undergo N-back and PAS-EEG to assess baseline DLPFC plasticity. Following baseline procedures, MCI participants will be randomized (1:1) to the study intervention consisting of 10 sessions of either bilateral PAS or PAS-C to the right and left DLPFC, 1 session/day, for 10 days. On the last day of the intervention, participants will repeat the cognitive assessments and on the following day they will repeat N-back and PAS-EEG to assess the effect of daily PAS on executive function and DLPFC plasticity. Finally, on the 7th day following the intervention, MCI participants will repeat N-back and PAS-EEG, and on the 28th and 29th day following the intervention, MCI participants will repeat the cognitive assessments, N-back and PAS-EEG to evaluate the sustainability of effects.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>A unique advantage of Paired Associative Stimulation (PAS) over other TMS-based interventions is that its control condition (PAS-C) is almost impossible to distinguish from active PAS. Thus, the RCT phase of the study will be completed under triple-blind conditions. First, participants will be blind to whether they are randomized to PAS or PAS-C. Second, the investigator team (investigators and interventionists delivering the 10-session course) will be blind to group assignment. Third, the outcomes assessors conducting the clinical, cognitive and PAS-EEG assessments at baseline and follow-ups will be blind to group assignment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PAS-Long-term-potentiation (PAS-LTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>PAS-LTP is measured as the ratio of TMS-induced cortical evoked activity (CEA) post-PAS to TMS-induced CEA pre-PAS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in PAS-Long-term-potentiation (PAS-LTP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately and 1 and 4 weeks following the 10-session course</time_frame>
    <description>PAS-LTP is measured as the ratio of TMS-induced cortical evoked activity (CEA) post-PAS to TMS-induced CEA pre-PAS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>N-Back Performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure will be based on the 2-back condition of the N-Back. N-back accuracy will be assessed using d', which is a sensitivity index based on the z scores of hit rates (H- correctly responding to target trials as target trials) and false alarm rates (F- incorrectly responding to non-target trials as target trials) using the following formula: d' = z(H) - z(F).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in N-Back Performance</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately and 1 and 4 weeks following the 10-session course</time_frame>
    <description>The primary outcome measure will be based on the 2-back condition of the N-Back. N-back accuracy will be assessed using d', which is a sensitivity index based on the z scores of hit rates (H- correctly responding to target trials as target trials) and false alarm rates (F- incorrectly responding to non-target trials as target trials) using the following formula: d' = z(H) - z(F).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Executive Function Composite Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The executive function composite measure will be calculated using established and well validated tests from a comprehensive neuropsychological battery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Executive Function Composite Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, immediately and 4 weeks following the 10-session course</time_frame>
    <description>The executive function composite measure will be calculated using established and well validated tests from a comprehensive neuropsychological battery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Mild Cognitive Impairment</condition>
  <condition>Memory Impairment</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active PAS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>After completing the N-back and PAS-EEG at Visit 3, MCI participants randomized to the active condition will receive a 10-session course of PAS (Visits 4-13), followed by the three follow-up assessments at 0 days, 7 days, and 28 days post intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PAS-Control (PAS-C)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>After completing the N-back and PAS-EEG at Visit 3, MCI participants randomized to the sham condition will receive a 10-session course of PAS-C (Visits 4-13), followed by the three follow-up assessments at 0 days, 7 days, and 28 days post intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy Controls will complete screening and baseline N-Back and PAS-EEG. They will not complete the 10-session course of PAS or follow-up assessments.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paired Associative Stimulation (PAS)</intervention_name>
    <description>On each of the 10 days of the intervention, participants will receive PAS (or PAS-C) to the left DLPFC by delivering peripheral nerve stimulation (PNS) to the right median nerve and TMS to the left DLPFC, followed immediately by PAS (or PAS-C) to the right DLPFC by delivering PNS to the left median nerve and TMS to the right DLPFC. PAS-C differs from PAS only by including an interstimulus interval of 100 ms between PNS and TMS to the DLPFC, compared to 25 ms in the active PAS condition. Using 100 ms interval, we have previously demonstrated that PAS-C does not induce PAS-LTP in the DLPFC. If a participant cannot attend one or more of the 10 consecutive PAS or PAS-C treatment sessions, we will allow up to four extra treatment days to make up for missed sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active PAS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>PAS-Control (PAS-C)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (TMS)</other_name>
    <other_name>Peripheral Nerve Stimulation (PNS)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        MCI Group:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 60 years or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Right-handed (to minimize heterogeneity with respect to cognitive reserve and&#xD;
             plasticity) and as determined by the Edinburgh Handedness Questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of MCI due to AD using the core clinical criteria by the National Institute&#xD;
             on Aging and Alzheimer's Association for MCI participants (NIA-AA) and ascertained by&#xD;
             a study investigator. The following checklist will be used to ascertain the MCI&#xD;
             diagnosis:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Cognitive concern reflecting a change in cognition reported by patient or&#xD;
                  informant or clinician (i.e., historical or observed evidence of decline over&#xD;
                  time)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Not demented ascertained using the study investigator opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. No vascular, traumatic, or medical causes of cognitive decline ascertained using&#xD;
                  the study investigator opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Evidence of longitudinal decline in cognition, when feasible, and ascertained&#xD;
                  using the study investigator opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. History consistent with AD genetic factors, where relevant, and ascertained using&#xD;
                  the study investigator opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Objective evidence of single or multi domain amnestic MCI, where single domain&#xD;
             includes only amnestic MCI; and multi domain includes amnestic MCI and the presence of&#xD;
             mild impairment in one or more additional cognitive domains. The rationale for&#xD;
             participants being required to have at least single domain amnestic MCI is that&#xD;
             patients with amnestic MCI are considered to have prodromal AD and therefore would be&#xD;
             a target for future AD prevention studies. To determine impairment in memory or other&#xD;
             domains, the participant has to be at least -1.0 standard deviation below the mean of&#xD;
             test norms, on two or more tests assessing the same cognitive domain. For example, two&#xD;
             or more tests assessing memory, for amnestic MCI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willingness to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Ability to read and communicate in English (with corrected vision and hearing, if&#xD;
             needed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current use of an acetylcholine esterase inhibitor or memantine ascertained using a&#xD;
             Medication List.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Major Depressive Disorder with active symptoms in the last 3 months ascertained using&#xD;
             the Structured Clinical Interview for DSM 5 (SCID-5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A lifetime diagnosis of bipolar disorder; intellectual disability; or a psychotic&#xD;
             disorder ascertained using the SCID-5&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Substance use disorder active in the last 3 months ascertained using the SCID-5&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any other DSM-5 diagnosis ascertained using the SCID-5 that may be associated with&#xD;
             prefrontal cortical dysfunction as ascertained using a study investigator opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Current anticonvulsant use due to its impact on TMS induced activity and ascertained&#xD;
             using a Medication List. An exception will be made if they are taking gabapentin or&#xD;
             pregabalin AND if the dose had been stable for at least 4 weeks prior to study entry&#xD;
             AND if prescribed for chronic pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Current benzodiazepine use of more than what is equivalent to lorazepam 2 mg/day as&#xD;
             ascertained using a Medication List. This is due to their known pro-GABAergic activity&#xD;
             and the suppressive effect of GABAergic agents on cortical plasticity&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any contraindication to MRI or contraindication to TMS (e.g., cardiac pacemaker,&#xD;
             acoustic device, history of seizures) ascertained using the TMS Adult Safety Screen&#xD;
             (TASS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy Controls&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 60 years or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Right-handed (to minimize heterogeneity with respect to cognitive reserve and&#xD;
             plasticity) and as determined by the Edinburgh Handedness Inventory&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. MoCA score &gt; 26&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to read and communicate in English (with corrected vision and hearing, if&#xD;
             needed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willingness to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Diagnosis of MCI due to AD using the core clinical criteria by the National Institute&#xD;
             on Aging and Alzheimer's Association for MCI participants and ascertained by a study&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any lifetime DSM-5 diagnosis ascertained using the SCID-5 (except for simple/specific&#xD;
             phobias) or diagnosis that may be associated with prefrontal cortical dysfunction as&#xD;
             ascertained using a study investigator opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any current use of a psychotropic medication for a CNS condition as ascertained using&#xD;
             the Medication List.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Current anticonvulsant use due to its impact on TMS induced activity and ascertained&#xD;
             using a Medication List. An exception will be made if they are taking gabapentin or&#xD;
             pregabalin AND if the dose had been stable for at least 4 weeks prior to study entry&#xD;
             AND if prescribed for chronic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Current benzodiazepine use of more than what is equivalent to lorazepam 2 mg/day as&#xD;
             ascertained using a Medication List. This is due to their known pro-GABAergic activity&#xD;
             and the suppressive effect of GABAergic agents on cortical plasticity&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any contraindication to MRI or contraindication to TMS (e.g., cardiac pacemaker,&#xD;
             acoustic device, history of seizures) ascertained using the TMS Adult Safety Screen&#xD;
             (TASS)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tarek Rajji, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tarek Rajji, MD</last_name>
    <phone>416-535-8501</phone>
    <phone_ext>33661</phone_ext>
    <email>tarek.rajji@camh.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shima Ovaysikia, MA</last_name>
    <phone>416-535-8501</phone>
    <phone_ext>32589</phone_ext>
    <email>pasmci@camh.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M6J 1H4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shima Ovaysikia</last_name>
      <phone>647-939-5368</phone>
      <email>shima.ovaysikia@camh.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Nicole Ledwos</last_name>
      <phone>416-705-6562</phone>
      <email>nicole.ledwos@camh.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tarek K Rajji, MD.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel M Blumberger, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sanjeev Kumar, MD,</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rajji TK, Sun Y, Zomorrodi-Moghaddam R, Farzan F, Blumberger DM, Mulsant BH, Fitzgerald PB, Daskalakis ZJ. PAS-induced potentiation of cortical-evoked activity in the dorsolateral prefrontal cortex. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2013 Nov;38(12):2545-52. doi: 10.1038/npp.2013.161. Epub 2013 Jul 3.</citation>
    <PMID>23820586</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kumar S, Zomorrodi R, Ghazala Z, Goodman MS, Blumberger DM, Cheam A, Fischer C, Daskalakis ZJ, Mulsant BH, Pollock BG, Rajji TK. Extent of Dorsolateral Prefrontal Cortex Plasticity and Its Association With Working Memory in Patients With Alzheimer Disease. JAMA Psychiatry. 2017 Dec 1;74(12):1266-1274. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2017.3292.</citation>
    <PMID>29071355</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Centre for Addiction and Mental Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tarek Rajji</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief of the Adult Neurodevelopment and Geriatric Psychiatry Division</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Memory Impairment</keyword>
  <keyword>Executive Function</keyword>
  <keyword>Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Paired Associative Stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuroplasticity</keyword>
  <keyword>Electroencephalography</keyword>
  <keyword>Working Memory</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognition</keyword>
  <keyword>Prefrontal Cortex</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cognitive Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

