<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04589312</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>17.0019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04589312</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Maternal Pertussis Wholecell Responses</brief_title>
  <acronym>WoMANPOWER</acronym>
  <official_title>The Safety and imMunogeNicity of Combined Pertussis-cOntaining Vaccine (Tdap) for HIV-infected Pregnant WomEn and Their newboRns - A Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St George's, University of London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Medical Research Council</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Public Health England</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>MU-JHU CARE</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>BioNet-Asia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St George's, University of London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Pertussis is resurging worldwide. In Africa alone it is estimated that there are 2.1 million&#xD;
      cases and 542,000 deaths from pertussis in infants under 1 year with the highest rates of&#xD;
      morbidity and mortality in infants &lt;3 months old, before possible prevention via the infant&#xD;
      immunization programme1. To protect these most vulnerable infants, the World Health&#xD;
      Organisation (WHO) recommends Tdap vaccination as safe in pregnancy and recommends the use of&#xD;
      wP vaccines within the EPI. Maternal antibody following aP vaccination can interfere with&#xD;
      infant anti-pertussis antibody responses post infant EPI vaccination, which is of concern in&#xD;
      high burden settings such as Uganda. There are therefore multiple factors in this population&#xD;
      which may influence the effect of pertussis immunization in pregnancy, and which have not&#xD;
      been studied, most notably HIV infection and interference with wP vaccines in infants. The&#xD;
      immunogenicity of Tdap in HIV-infected pregnant women has not yet been examined. In addition,&#xD;
      to date, the effect of maternal vaccination, placental transfer and infant antibody responses&#xD;
      in HEU infants have not been studied at all. There are no studies examining the immune&#xD;
      response to wP vaccine administered to infants (EPI recommendation) whose mothers received aP&#xD;
      in pregnancy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The study will take a 2x2 formation, with four groups:&#xD;
HIV-uninfected women, standard of care vaccines in pregnancy;&#xD;
HIV-uninfected women, Tdap vaccine in pregnancy;&#xD;
HIV-infected women, standard of care vaccines in pregnancy;&#xD;
HIV-infected women, Tdap vaccine in pregnancy.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Study nursing staff and participants will be blinded to the vaccine given and vaccine syringes will be covered with an opaque label, obscuring the vaccine. Only the preparing pharmacist will be aware of the vaccine used. A study nurse who is blinded to the vaccine given will observe for immediate reactions to the vaccine in a separate room from where the woman will receive her vaccination. This room will have an emergency trolley with appropriate drugs available should these be required.&#xD;
The laboratory-based research team conducting the assays will be blinded to subject allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-pertussis toxin (PT) and anti-FHA IgG concentrations in cord blood of Tdap-vaccinated HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women.</measure>
    <time_frame>At delivery</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-pertussis toxin (PT) and anti-FHA IgG concentrations in cord blood of Tdap -vaccinated vs Tdap -unvaccinated pregnant women and whether this differs by maternal HIV status.</measure>
    <time_frame>At delivery</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-PT and anti-FHA IgG concentrations in infants born to Tdap vaccinated vs Tdap -unvaccinated pregnant women 4 weeks after the completion of a series of primary vaccination with 3 doses of wP vaccine, and whether this differs by maternal HIV status.</measure>
    <time_frame>18 weeks of pregnancy</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Pregnant Women</measure>
    <time_frame>First vaccination visits</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of maternal Subjects With Solicited Local and Solicited Systemic AEs and percentage with any Unsolocited AEs; Percentage of Maternal Subjects With Serious Adverse Events (SAEs), Unsolicited Medically Attended AEs (MAEs) and Unsolicited AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Pregnant Women</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 months of age of infants</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of maternal Subjects With Solicited Local and Solicited Systemic AEs and percentage with any Unsolocited AEs; Percentage of Maternal Subjects With Serious Adverse Events (SAEs), Unsolicited Medically Attended AEs (MAEs) and Unsolicited AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Infants</measure>
    <time_frame>At birth</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of Infants With SAEs, Unsolicited AEs and AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal by a clinical examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Infants</measure>
    <time_frame>At 18 weeks of age</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of Infants With SAEs, Unsolicited AEs and AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal by a clinical examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Infants</measure>
    <time_frame>At 6 months of age to assess health of the infant (phone call)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of Infants With SAEs, Unsolicited AEs and AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal by a clinical examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Infants</measure>
    <time_frame>At 9 months of age to assess health of the infant (phone call)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of Infants With SAEs, Unsolicited AEs and AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal by a clinical examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety Outcome: Safety assessment of Tdap vaccine vs Td vaccine in HIV-infected vs HIV-uninfected pregnant women - Infants</measure>
    <time_frame>At 12 months of age to assess health of the infant (phone call)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of Infants With SAEs, Unsolicited AEs and AEs Leading to Study Withdrawal by a clinical examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-PT and anti-FHA IgG concentrations in HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected pregnant women following Tdap vs Td vaccination during pregnancy (4 weeks post-vaccine &amp; at delivery)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks post-vaccine &amp; at delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-PT IgG antibody avidity in HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected pregnant women following Tdap vs Td vaccination during pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 weeks of pregnancy, 4 weeks post-vaccine, at delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum bactericidal activity in HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected pregnant women following Tdap vs Td vaccination during pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 weeks of pregnancy, 4 weeks post-vaccine, at delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-PT IgG and anti-FHA placental transfer ratios in HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected pregnant women following Tdap vs Td vaccination during pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 weeks of pregnancy, 4 weeks post-vaccine, at delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tetanus Toxoid antibody responses in HIV-infected and HIV-uninfected pregnant women following Tdap vs Td vaccination during pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 weeks of pregnancy, 4 weeks post-vaccine, at delivery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Pertussis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women not living with HIV, Td vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women not living with HIV, Tdap vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women living with HIV, Td vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women living with HIV, Tdap vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of care vaccines</intervention_name>
    <description>Visit 1: Check tetanus immunisation status. Vaccination up to 25+ 6 weeks of pregnancy with Td; Visit 2: vaccination at least 4 weeks after visit 2 with either Tdap or Td (per randomisation and according to WHO guidance)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women living with HIV, Td vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women not living with HIV, Td vaccine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Boostagen, (BioNet-Asia)</intervention_name>
    <description>Visit 1: Check tetanus immunisation status. Vaccination up to 25+ 6 weeks of pregnancy with Td; Visit 2: vaccination at least 4 weeks after visit 2 with either Tdap or Td (per randomisation and according to WHO guidance);</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women living with HIV, Tdap vaccine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Pregnant women not living with HIV, Tdap vaccine</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be a woman aged 18 years or older, inclusive at day of signing the&#xD;
             ICF;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant woman at &gt;16 and &lt;26 weeks gestation, verified by ultrasound scan;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented HIV test during pregnancy taken by rapid test at the screening visit;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low risk, singleton pregnancy, as assessed by the study physician based on ultrasound&#xD;
             scan and previous obstetric history; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The woman is willing to comply with the study procedures, including giving birth at&#xD;
             Kawempe National Referral Hospital, remaining in the study area until the infant is 1&#xD;
             year old and is able to provide informed consent for herself and on behalf of the&#xD;
             infant&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous anaphylaxis to any component of Td or Tdap vaccines;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  vaccination is otherwise contraindicated (per product monographs);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented to have received four or more previous tetanus toxoid vaccine doses (as&#xD;
             this would prevent randomisation to Tdap group and receipt of two additional tetanus&#xD;
             toxoid containing vaccines);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of pre-eclampsia or eclampsia in previous pregnancies;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gestational diabetes in current pregnancy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Rhesus negative mothers;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multigravida;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous late stillbirth (defined as loss of pregnancy at any time after 28 weeks&#xD;
             gestation);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous low birth weight baby of less than 2.0 kilograms or premature delivery&#xD;
             (defined as a delivery before 37 weeks gestation);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous neonatal death (defined as death of an infant within the first 28 days of&#xD;
             life);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous delivery of an infant with a known or suspected genetic or chromosomal&#xD;
             abnormality;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other significant pregnancy related complications judged likely to affect&#xD;
             the safety of the mother or infant or to significantly compromise the endpoint data&#xD;
             collected;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other significant neonatal complications judged likely to affect the safety&#xD;
             of the mother or infant or to significantly compromise the endpoint data collected;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant maternal chronic illness including but not limited to hypertension&#xD;
             requiring treatment, heart disease, lung disease, neurological disorders including a&#xD;
             history of epilepsy or recurrent afebrile seizures, kidney disease, liver disease,&#xD;
             anaemia and other haematological disorders (including sickle cell), endocrine&#xD;
             disorders including known diabetes mellitus, autoimmunity;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe anaemia (less than 7.0g/dL);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known Syphilis or hepatitis B (HBV) virus positive or found to be Syphilis or HBV&#xD;
             positive during screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other condition judged to significantly increase the risks to either the mother or&#xD;
             the infant within the current pregnancy (including relevant history from previous&#xD;
             pregnancies);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any blood product including human immunoglobulins at any stage during the&#xD;
             current pregnancy or plan to receive any blood products during the period or trial&#xD;
             participation (receipt of blood products in an emergency or for obstetric reasons will&#xD;
             not represent a protocol deviation given such situations are unplanned);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically suspected or confirmed congenital or acquired clotting or bleeding&#xD;
             disorders or the current receipt of medications known to alter clotting or bleeding;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant signs or symptoms of acute illness, significant&#xD;
             abnormalities in vital signs, an axillary temperature of greater than 38.0°C or any&#xD;
             recorded fever (greater than 38.0°C) in the preceding 24 hours;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Two or more symptoms (nausea/vomiting, diarrhoea, headaches, fatigue and myalgia)&#xD;
             rated as grade 2 and clinically significant on the maternal systemic reactogenicity&#xD;
             scale present at baseline on the day of vaccination;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Deprived of freedom by an administrative or court order, or in an emergency setting,&#xD;
             or hospitalized involuntarily;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in the 4 weeks preceding the trial vaccination or planned participation&#xD;
             during the present trial period in another clinical trial investigating a vaccine,&#xD;
             drug, medical device, or medical procedure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of being treated for pertussis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kirsty Le Doare, MBBS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>St George's, University of London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manish Sadarangani, MRCPCH, DPHIL, BM.BCh, MA</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>BC Children's Hospital Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eve Nakabembe, MBChB,M.Med</last_name>
    <phone>+256 772 914 240</phone>
    <email>drevena@yahoo.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Madeleine Cochet, MPH</last_name>
    <email>mcochet@sgul.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MUJHU Care Ltd</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mary Kyohere, Dr.</last_name>
      <email>mkyohere@mujhu.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eve Nakabembe, Dr</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Uganda</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Whooping Cough</keyword>
  <keyword>Pertussis</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccination</keyword>
  <keyword>Pregnancy</keyword>
  <keyword>Infant</keyword>
  <keyword>Newborn</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Whooping Cough</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

