<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04585984</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1905-FIVI-063-NG</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04585984</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Antioxidant Probiotic Administration on Seminal Quality and Reproductive Outcomes.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Antioxidant Probiotic Administration on Seminal Quality and Reproductive Outcomes.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fundación IVI</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>ADM Protexin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Biopolis S.L.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Instituto Valenciano de Infertilidad, IVI VALENCIA</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fundación IVI</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The quality of semen plays a fundamental role in correct fertilization and development of&#xD;
      normal embryos that result in a live birth. Unfortunately, semen quality has declined during&#xD;
      the last decades, and reduced more and more. The cases of male factor infertility currently&#xD;
      correspond to 30% of the reported cases of infertility. The parameters that are directly&#xD;
      affected in infertile men reflecting an impaired spermatogenesis are sperm concentration,&#xD;
      motility, morphology, ejaculate volume and DNA damage, in addition to various alterations at&#xD;
      the molecular level that often go unnoticed and are related to the physiological capacity of&#xD;
      the sperm. These alterations result in a decrease in reproductive capacity, which leads to&#xD;
      the need for assisted reproduction techniques (ART). The identification of new ways to&#xD;
      increase the quality of sperm could be very useful to improve the reproductive performance of&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Probiotics are defined as 'living microorganisms, which, when administered in adequate&#xD;
      amounts, confer benefits for the health of the host'. The consumption of probiotics is&#xD;
      increasing worldwide as therapy for many different diseases and disorders. In the field of&#xD;
      assisted reproduction, the microbiome has been extensively studied with respect to the female&#xD;
      endometrium to assess endometrial receptivity. However, there is little evidence about the&#xD;
      role of the microbiome in semen. Previous studies demonstrated a moderate improvement on some&#xD;
      sperm parameters, but still there is a need to confirm its translation into a clinical&#xD;
      contribution to reproductive success.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the effect of these strains, Lactobacillus rhamnosus&#xD;
      CECT8361 and Bifidobacterium longum CECT7347, on the seminal quality of infertile patients&#xD;
      coming to IVIRMA clinics to undergo their first IVF/ICSI cycle by means of determining direct&#xD;
      improvement on the basic sperm analysis results, on sperm DNA integrity and on the seminal&#xD;
      microbiome profile, to ultimately evaluate the effect that it may have on the embryo quality&#xD;
      and reproductive results of the cycles of these patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective randomized, unicentric, intervention study aimed at evaluating the&#xD;
      effect of the combination of two probiotics on seminal quality and subsequent reproductive&#xD;
      outcomes of infertile patients. As it is a food supplement, we will be subject to the&#xD;
      Biomedicine Regulation and not to the Clinical Trials Regulation, as already classified by&#xD;
      the Spanish Drug Agency. The study will be conducted on infertile patients at the IVIRMA&#xD;
      Valencia clinic for two years to complete planned interventions and data collection and&#xD;
      analysis. The reference population includes infertile patients coming to the clinic for&#xD;
      IVF/ICSI assisted reproduction treatment with own or donated oocytes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will come to the clinic to undergo the treatment. If their characteristics are in&#xD;
      accord with the inclusion criteria, the study will be presented and explained to them and&#xD;
      their partners so they can evaluate their participation in it. If they wish to participate,&#xD;
      they will sign an informed consent form, and they will be randomized using a&#xD;
      computer-generated randomisation list into the control group (who will receive placebo) or&#xD;
      the treatment group (who will receive the probiotic compound).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The success rate in patients with these characteristics, confirmed by the evaluation of&#xD;
      historical information from the clinic's own database, is approximately 35% of the cycles&#xD;
      using own oocytes, which can be used as a valid approximation. In a unilateral contrast test,&#xD;
      assuming a risk of an alpha error of 0.05 and a beta (statistical power) of 80%, to&#xD;
      demonstrate a difference of 15% thanks to the intervention, we need a number of 134 cases per&#xD;
      arm and, assuming losses of 5% during the follow-up, this number would be rounded to 140&#xD;
      cases per study group, which makes a total of 280 couples to be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial is double-blind: the patient, the investigator and all site personnel (with the&#xD;
      exception of the trial nurse/coordinator and/or pharmacy assistant) will remain blinded&#xD;
      throughout the course of the trial as to which treatment each subject received, including the&#xD;
      assessing physician, the embryologist and other auxiliary members of the team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The male assigned to the experimental group will start taking a 50% combination of the two&#xD;
      probiotics (Lactobacillus rhamnosus CECT8361 and Bifidobacterium longum CECT7347) at a dose&#xD;
      of 109 CFU/day on the same day of the first visit. The probiotics will be supplied by the&#xD;
      company ADM Biopolis S.L. (Valencia, Spain). The carrier of lyophilized probiotics is&#xD;
      maltodextrin and the mixture is encapsulated in hypromellose capsules. The patient will take&#xD;
      one capsule daily corresponding to the administration of 109 cfu/day. The patient should take&#xD;
      these probiotics for at least 21 days before undergoing an assisted reproduction cycle.&#xD;
      Patients receiving the placebo will be following the same instructions. For both groups of&#xD;
      patients, a seminal sample will be collected on their first visit to evaluate the baseline&#xD;
      quality of the semen, as well as a microbiome analysis will be carried out using 16S rRNA&#xD;
      sequencing (by ADM Biopolis) to determine the status of the semen at the starting point of&#xD;
      the study. After 21 days, the patients will be appointed to deposit a second semen sample in&#xD;
      order to perform the IVF/ICSI cycle. This sample will also be analysed, both for semen&#xD;
      parameters and microbiome. Values obtained from both of the samples collected will be&#xD;
      compared to observe the effect of the administration of the probiotic on the quality of sperm&#xD;
      and its microbial population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fresh semen samples will be evaluated by means of a spermiogram following the standard&#xD;
      operating procedures, in which data will be collected on volume, pH, sperm concentration,&#xD;
      sperm mobility, cell viability and morphology. In addition, a DNA fragmentation analysis will&#xD;
      be carried out using the Halosperm G2 kit (Halotech) based on the sperm chromatin dispersion&#xD;
      technique. A part of the fresh sample will be frozen by submersion into liquid nitrogen and&#xD;
      then storage in a -80ºC freezer, and sent to ADM Biopolis to perform the taxonomical&#xD;
      identification of the bacterial populations in the semen samples using 16S rRNA sequencing&#xD;
      with the Ion Torrent platform (Lifetechnologies).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the IVF/ICSI has been performed and oocytes have been correctly fertilised, embryo&#xD;
      selection and blastocyst transfer will be carried out according to the usual medical practice&#xD;
      to the woman's uterus, so that they can continue their development in the womb.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During recruitment, the couple will also sign a consent form allowing the team to collect&#xD;
      data from the results of the cycle, both during embryo development and during the pregnancy&#xD;
      and the delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A database will be defined with the variables destined to be analysed according to the&#xD;
      objectives set: semen quality analysis, sperm DNA fragmentation, microbial analysis, embryo&#xD;
      development, gestation and delivery. The exported data will be duly codified in order to&#xD;
      protect the clinical and personal information of the patients according to the Spanish data&#xD;
      protection law. Finally, and prior to the statistical study, an exploratory data analysis&#xD;
      will be carried out to review the quality of the information extracted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main variable of the study is the live birth rate per cycle defined as the percentage of&#xD;
      cases in which a complete treatment of assisted reproduction is carried out with control or&#xD;
      experimental semen, which manage to obtain offspring for each cycle of ovarian stimulation&#xD;
      included in the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The patient, investigator, assessing physician, embryologist and all site personnel with the exception of the trial nurse/coordinator and/or pharmacy assistant will remain blinded throughout the course of the trial as to which treatment each subject received.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Live birth rate per cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of cases in which a complete treatment of assisted reproduction is carried out with control or experimental semen, which manage to obtain offspring for each cycle of ovarian stimulation included in the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">280</enrollment>
  <condition>Male Infertility</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>140 men will be taking a placebo once a day during 21 days prior to the start of the IVF/ICSI cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>140 men will be taking the probiotic compound (50% of each probiotic: Lactobacillus rhamnosus and Bifidobacterium longum at a dose of 10^9 cfu/day) once a day for 21 days prior to the start of the IVF/ICSI cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experimental - Probiotic</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in the experimental group will take one compound (pill) a day for 21 days, containing a 50% combination of two probiotics: Lactobacillus rhamnosus and Bifidobacterium longum, at a dose of 10^9 cfu/day. The carrier of lyophilized probiotics is maltodextrin and the mixture is encapsulated in hypromellose capsules.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Lactobacillus rhamnosus</other_name>
    <other_name>Bifidobacterium longum</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in the control group will take one unit of placebo a day for 21 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Control</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men aged 18-45 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men with more than 5 million progressive mobile spermatozoa in the ejaculate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women aged 18-37 using their own oocytes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women aged &gt;37 using donated oocytes where the donor is &lt;36 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with AMH values between 1-5 ng/ml or 5-35 pmol/l&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female BMI &gt;30kg/m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known female history of thrombophilia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of endometriosis stages III-IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of severe adenomyosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Repeated implantation failures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recurrent miscarriages, Mullerian abnormalities or hydrosalpinx&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any other probiotics by the male partner within the previous 3 months (to take&#xD;
             account of a full spermatogenic cycle)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of antibiotics by the male partner within the previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known use of corticosteroids&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of sexually transmitted diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Semen analysis and seminal microbiota analysis.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IVIRMA Valencia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <zip>46015</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>María Gil Juliá, MSc</last_name>
      <phone>+34699712040</phone>
      <email>maria.gil@ivirma.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>María Gil Juliá, MSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicolás Garrido Puchalt, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan Giles Jiménez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carmina Vidal Martínez, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rocío Rivera Egea, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Probiotic</keyword>
  <keyword>Lactobacillus rhamnosus</keyword>
  <keyword>Bifidobacterium longum</keyword>
  <keyword>Sperm DNA fragmentation</keyword>
  <keyword>Seminal microbiota</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infertility</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infertility, Male</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

