<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04583540</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>QOL placenta accrete</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04583540</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Quality of Life in Postpartum Women With Placenta Accrete Spectrum.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Health Status and Quality of Life in Postpartum Women With Placenta Accrete Spectrum.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      1. The objective of this study is to provide an overview of the core domains&#xD;
           (physical,psychological,social) of quality of life and health state in postpartum women&#xD;
           after the placenta accrete spectrum.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. to assess which factors are associated with quality of life and health state domains&#xD;
           postpartum.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The morbidly adherent placenta is abnormally adherent placenta to myometrium due to the&#xD;
      absence of decidua basalis partially or totally in a way that prevents normal placental&#xD;
      separation after delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MAP includes a spectrum classified according to the extend of trophoblastic invasion to&#xD;
      myometrium into (accrete, increta, percreta).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The greatest risk factor is previous uterine surgery mostly previous caesarian sections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the last decade incidence of placenta accrete spectrum has increased in direct proportion&#xD;
      with increased rates of cesarean sections up to 1 per 500 pregnancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This rising incidence makes placenta accrete spectrum (PAS)one of the most serious problems&#xD;
      in obstetrics with a high rate of complications peripartum and postpartum as well like&#xD;
      (peripartum hysterectomy - intestinal injure- bladder injure - ureteral injure - ICU&#xD;
      admission- massive blood transfusion) that may affect patients health outcome and their&#xD;
      quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diagnosis of PAS depends mainly on the history of antepartum hemorrhage and confirmed by the&#xD;
      grayscale US with high sensitivity and specificity reaching up to 90%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Medical service is no longer one-sided evaluated. Patient-centered care is a core in medical&#xD;
      service.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quality of life (QOL) and health status (HS) are important categories of patient-reported&#xD;
      outcomes (PROs), in which the patient's perspective is key, and that can be used to assess&#xD;
      the impact of current HS and to assess the efficiency of interventions. The difference&#xD;
      between these PROs is that where HS refers to self-perceived physical, psychological, and&#xD;
      social functioning, QOL also incorporates patients' evaluation of functioning, i.e.&#xD;
      (dis)satisfaction with the aspects of life. Since health care is becoming more and more&#xD;
      patient-centered, the assessment of the patient's subjective experience is considered to be&#xD;
      essential for informed clinical decision-making and health policy. Therefore, research on QOL&#xD;
      and HS in postpartum women is increasing, in which multiple contributing factors and&#xD;
      interventions are examined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The WHOQOL is a quality of life assessment developed by the WHOQOL Group with fifteen&#xD;
      international field centers, simultaneously, in an attempt to develop a quality of life&#xD;
      assessment that would be applicable cross-culturally.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The WHOQOL-Bref scoring assesses four domains of quality of life with 26 items 1_physical&#xD;
      health, 2-psychological health, 3- social relationships, 4- environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The short form 36 ( SF-36) score is validated quality of life survey with 36 items to assess&#xD;
      health outcome and quality of life through eight domains 1- physical functioning (PF), 2-role&#xD;
      limitation due to the physical problem ( RP), 3-bodily pain (BP), 4- general health (GH), 5-&#xD;
      vitality (VT), 6- social functioning (SF), 7- role limitation due to emotional problem (RE),&#xD;
      8- mental health (MH).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this research is to assess the quality of life in patients who had placenta&#xD;
      accreta spectrum using WHOQOL-BREF scoring and SF-36 quality of life survey&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess quality of life in patients had placenta accrete spectrum 6-8 weeks postpartum</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Use of SF-36 survey to assess quality of life in women had placenta accrete spectrum 6-8 weeks postpartum</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>patients had placenta accrete spectrum 6-8 weeks postpartum</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Use of WHOQOL-bref scoring to assess quality of life in women had placenta accrete spectrum 6-8 weeks postpartum</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Placenta Accrete Spectrum</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All women have confirmed diagnosis of placenta accrete spectrum by Doppler abdominal&#xD;
        ultrasound termination of pregnancy by elective cs after fullterm.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1-Confirmed diagnosis of MAP. 2-Termination of pregnancy after 36 weeks gestation&#xD;
             3-Peripartum hysterectomy for MAP. 4- Complicated CS without hysterectomy 5-Maternal&#xD;
             age between 18 and 45 yrs 6-No other medical diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Emergency CS before confirming MAP diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Preterm delivery (before 36 weeks in case of MAP)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. .peripartum hysterectomy for any cause other than MAP&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Other medical diseases that affect the quality of life&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Postpartum depression.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Beshoy Atef Mounir</last_name>
    <phone>01285836093</phone>
    <email>batef0270@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sherif Mohammed Abdel-Mageed Badran</last_name>
    <phone>01009536255</phone>
    <email>doctorbadran1@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of medicine Assiut university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Beshoy Atef Mounir</last_name>
      <phone>01285836093</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 12, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Beshoy Atef Mounir Rizk</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

