<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04580979</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00004513-FDXR</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04580979</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Natural History Study of FDXR Mutation-related Mitochondriopathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Natural History Study of Neurodegeneration and Optic Atrophy Caused by Ferredoxin Reductase Mutations in Pediatric and Adult Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>State University of New York at Buffalo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Callum McKeefery and Nikki Albano McKeefery Pediatric Division of Genetics Fund</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>State University of New York at Buffalo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the study is to systematically characterize the clinical course of the&#xD;
      progressive neuropathy and optic atrophy observe in pediatric and adult patients with&#xD;
      biallelic mutations in the ferredoxin reductase gene.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The mitochondrial membrane-associated ferredoxin reductase (FDXR) is a flavoprotein that&#xD;
      initiates the mitochondrial electron transport chain by transferring electrons from NADPH to&#xD;
      the mitochondrial cytochrome P450 system via the ferredoxins FDX1 or FDX2. In addition to&#xD;
      essential roles in Fe-S cluster biogenesis, this pathway is also central to the biosynthesis&#xD;
      of steroid hormones. Previously, Dr. Taosheng Huang's research group has identified mutations&#xD;
      in the FDXR gene in many individuals who share clinical presentations consistent with a&#xD;
      mitochondrial disorder-including ataxia, hypotonia and optic atrophy-and obtained a&#xD;
      naturally-occurring Fdxr mutant mouse model from Jackson Lab that corroborated these results&#xD;
      (PMID: 29040572 and PMID: 30250212). In particular, FDXR enzyme activity, mitochondrial&#xD;
      complex activities and ATP production were all significantly reduced in their patient&#xD;
      samples. Their studies further indicated that Fdxr mutation leads to neurodegeneration that&#xD;
      is associated with both inflammation as well as the abnormal accumulation of iron in the&#xD;
      mitochondria, likely as a result of disrupted Fe-S cluster synthesis. More recently, his&#xD;
      group has used the CRISPR-Cas9 system to generate a mouse line with a p.R389W amino acid&#xD;
      change, which more precisely matches the most common human variant observed in their patients&#xD;
      and shows a much more severe phenotype than their previous, naturally occurring Fdxr mouse&#xD;
      model. They have also show that AAV-based gene therapy can significantly improve the&#xD;
      condition of Fdxr mutant mice (DOI:https://doi.org/10.1016/j.omtm.2020.05.021), providing&#xD;
      valuable preclinical data that may open the door for adapting such gene therapy treatments&#xD;
      for use in human clinical trials. Given the recent regulatory approval granted to gene&#xD;
      therapy treatments for LCA2, SMA1, and β-thalassemia, there is strong possibility that such&#xD;
      an approach will ultimately produce a viable clinical treatment for FDXR patients as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      FDXR is required for Iron-sulfur (Fe-S) clusters synthesis which is essential for multiple&#xD;
      important biological processes, including electron transfer, cofactor synthesis, and gene&#xD;
      regulation. Fe-S cluster biosynthesis is a tightly regulated process that requires&#xD;
      coordinated delivery of both iron and sulfur and is a cofactor of many proteins. A variety of&#xD;
      human disorders have been associated with impaired Fe-S cluster synthesis, including&#xD;
      neurodegenerative disorders (e.g. Friedreich's ataxia) and myopathy with lactic acidosis.&#xD;
      Iron homeostasis, which requires precise synthesis and localization of Fe-S clusters in&#xD;
      mitochondria, is critical to ensure that there is sufficient iron for cellular functions,&#xD;
      without reaching toxic levels of iron. Excessive levels of iron favor the formation of excess&#xD;
      oxygen free radicals and consequent mitochondrial dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Rare Disease Act and Rare Disease Orphan Product Development Act highlight the importance&#xD;
      of rare disease research and the obstacles to developing effective treatments for these&#xD;
      diseases. However, the study of rare diseases may open a window to studying other human&#xD;
      conditions. For example, Iron-sulfur biosynthesis abnormalities have been observed in more&#xD;
      common human diseases such as Friedreich's ataxia. This relationship highlights the&#xD;
      importance of human disease research by multiple approaches to understand biological&#xD;
      mechanisms and for general application to human health. For these reasons, a better&#xD;
      understanding of the pathogenesis of FDXR deficiency may help facilitate our knowledge of&#xD;
      disease biology, neurodevelopment, brain function, and other organ abnormalities. Thus, in&#xD;
      order to better understand the function of FDXR and to help lay the groundwork for eventual&#xD;
      clinical trials of gene therapy or drug-based treatments for FDXR-related disease, the&#xD;
      investigators propose this natural history study of both pediatric as well as adult patients&#xD;
      with biallelic mutations in the ferredoxin reductase gene.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 3, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Custom Medical History Questionnaire for Patients with FDXR Mutation-related Mitochondriopathy</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>In addition to a standard medical history, patients or their legal guardians will be asked to complete a custom medical history questionnaire tailored toward conditions commonly observed in patients with biallelic FDXR mutations. The items that will be asked about in this questionnaire are as follows:&#xD;
Known mutations in FDXR&#xD;
Any family history of illness&#xD;
Complications of pregnancy&#xD;
Premature birth&#xD;
Complications with birth&#xD;
Developmental delay&#xD;
Developmental regression&#xD;
Abnormal size of brain&#xD;
Movement disorders (ataxia, dystonia, etc.)&#xD;
Seizures&#xD;
Optic atrophy in eye exam&#xD;
Vision loss&#xD;
Other vision problems (color, eye movement)&#xD;
Hypotonia (muscle weakness or lack of tone)&#xD;
Electromyogram (EMG)&#xD;
Muscle biopsy&#xD;
Spasticity (muscle stiffness or tightness)&#xD;
Brain MRI performed?&#xD;
Electroencephalogram (EEG)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Retrospective examination of the medical records of patients with FDXR Mutation-related Mitochondriopathy</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>With the informed consent of the patients or their parent(s) and/or legal guardian(s), the investigators will perform a retrospective examination of the medical records of both living and deceased patients with confirmed biallelic FDXR mutations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Scale for the Assessment and Rating of Ataxia (SARA)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>SARA is a clinical scale developed by the Ataxia Study Group that is based on a semiquantitative assessment of cerebellar ataxia on an impairment level. SARA measures the following 8 items, which are used to determine the relative severity of the ataxia phenotype: gait, stance, sitting, speech, finger-chase test, nose-finger test, fast alternating movements and heel-shin test. Each item is rated on a numerical scale (as indicated below), with &quot;0&quot; indicating a normal phenotype and higher scores indicating worse outcomes:&#xD;
Gait: 0 to 8&#xD;
Stance: 0 to 6&#xD;
Sittings: 0 to 4&#xD;
Speech: 0 to 6&#xD;
Finger-chase test: 0 to 4&#xD;
Nose-finger test: 0 to 4&#xD;
Fast alternating movements: 0 to 4&#xD;
Heel-shin test: 0 to 4</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>National Institutes of Health (NIH) Toolbox for the Assessment of Neurological and Behavioral Function</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>The National Institutes of Health (NIH) Toolbox is a composite of existing neuropsychological instruments that assesses cognitive, motor, emotional, and sensory function across all stages of life. It consists of a combination of tests that can be administered to patients via computer or tablet in two hours or less, and delivers a variety of individual and composite measures that can provide information on key aspects of neurological and behavioral function in patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQol-5 Dimension (EQ-5D) instrument, a questionnaire to measure health and quality-of-life</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>EQ-5D is a two-part, standardized questionnaire based on the subjective judgement of the patients. The two sections are as follows:&#xD;
An assessment of five dimensions of quality of life: mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort and anxiety/depression. Five possible answers are provided for each dimension: no problems, slight problems, moderate problems, severe problems and extreme problems. For children and youths, 3 options are provided: no problems, some problems, and a lot of problems.&#xD;
A self-report of the patient's perceived health status, based on a visual analogue scale (VAS) with a scale ranging from 0 (worst) to 100 (best).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Eye assessments to evaluate ocular health</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Visual acuity examination will be performed to determine the patient's clarity or sharpness of vision.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth and development (height)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>World Health Organization (WHO) growth charts will be used to document height in centimeters (cm) for patients ranging from ages 5 to 19 years old. Routine methods will be used to document height for all other age groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth and development (weight)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>World Health Organization (WHO) growth charts will be used to document weight in kilograms (kg) for pediatric patients age 5 to 10 years old. Routine methods will be used to document weight for all other age groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Growth and development (BMI)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>World Health Organization (WHO) growth charts will be used to document Body Mass Index (BMI) in kilograms per meter square for patients age 5 to 19 years old. Routine methods will be used to document BMI for all other age groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Inventory of Non-Ataxia Signs (INAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>INAS is an instrument developed by the Ataxia Study Group to provide structured information on non-ataxia signs in ataxia patients. INAS consists of 30 items, each of which is related to one of the following 16 signs or syndromes: areflexia, hyperreflexia, extensor plantar response, spasticity, paresis, amyotrophy, fasciculations, myoclonus, rigidity, chorea, dystonia, resting tremor, sensory symptoms, brainstem oculomotor signs (horizontal and vertical ophthalmoparesis, slowing of saccades), urinary dysfunction and cognitive impairment. For a semiquantitative assessement of non-ataxia signs, the number of non-ataxia signs is counted, yielding the INAS count, a dimensionless value with a range from 0 to 16. A sign is recorded as present if at least one item related to this sign is positive.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Neurodegenerative Disease, Hereditary</condition>
  <condition>Mitochondrial Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Optic Atrophy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with ferredoxin reductase deficiency</arm_group_label>
    <description>Male and female patients from age 2 to age 65 with clinically confirmed FDXR mutations. Both living and deceased patients will be included, if eligible. For deceased patients, the patient's medical history records will be reviewed, and an interview of the parent(s) or caregiver(s) will be performed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mutation analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>The investigators will sequence DNA samples from the patients or their families.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with ferredoxin reductase deficiency</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      The medical records will be retained for all patients. For select patients, blood, DNA, skin&#xD;
      punch biopsies will also be obtained for the purpose of genetic and biochemical analysis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Primary care clinic&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are clinically diagnosed with biallelic mutations in the ferredoxin&#xD;
             reductase gene&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and female patients from 2 to 65 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have consented to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the case of a deceased patient whose parent(s) and/or legal guardian(s) have&#xD;
             provided informed consent for study participation, the investigators will review the&#xD;
             patient's medical records to determine study eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant postnatal complications or congenital anomalies that are not known to be&#xD;
             associated with ferredoxin reductase deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received any experimental treatment for ferredoxin reductase deficiency&#xD;
             within the 6 months prior to enrollment, or is expected to receive any such therapy&#xD;
             during the study period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Taosheng Huang</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>State University of New York at Buffalo</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Taosheng Huang, MD, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>716-323-0041</phone>
    <email>thuang29@buffalo.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UBMD Pediatrics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buffalo</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Taosheng Huang</last_name>
      <phone>716-323-0041</phone>
      <email>thuang29@buffalo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Taosheng Huang, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Slone J, Peng Y, Chamberlin A, Harris B, Kaylor J, McDonald MT, Lemmon M, El-Dairi MA, Tchapyjnikov D, Gonzalez-Krellwitz LA, Sellars EA, McConkie-Rosell A, Reinholdt LG, Huang T. Biallelic mutations in FDXR cause neurodegeneration associated with inflammation. J Hum Genet. 2018 Dec;63(12):1211-1222. doi: 10.1038/s10038-018-0515-y. Epub 2018 Sep 25.</citation>
    <PMID>30250212</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Slone JD, Yang L, Peng Y, Queme LF, Harris B, Rizzo SJS, Green T, Ryan JL, Jankowski MP, Reinholdt LG, Huang T. Integrated analysis of the molecular pathogenesis of FDXR-associated disease. Cell Death Dis. 2020 Jun 4;11(6):423. doi: 10.1038/s41419-020-2637-3.</citation>
    <PMID>32499495</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Peng Y, Shinde DN, Valencia CA, Mo JS, Rosenfeld J, Truitt Cho M, Chamberlin A, Li Z, Liu J, Gui B, Brockhage R, Basinger A, Alvarez-Leon B, Heydemann P, Magoulas PL, Lewis AM, Scaglia F, Gril S, Chong SC, Bower M, Monaghan KG, Willaert R, Plona MR, Dineen R, Milan F, Hoganson G, Powis Z, Helbig KL, Keller-Ramey J, Harris B, Anderson LC, Green T, Sukoff Rizzo SJ, Kaylor J, Chen J, Guan MX, Sellars E, Sparagana SP, Gibson JB, Reinholdt LG, Tang S, Huang T. Biallelic mutations in the ferredoxin reductase gene cause novel mitochondriopathy with optic atrophy. Hum Mol Genet. 2017 Dec 15;26(24):4937-4950. doi: 10.1093/hmg/ddx377. Erratum in: Hum Mol Genet. 2018 Jun 15;27(12):2224.</citation>
    <PMID>29040572</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yang L, Slone J, Zou W, Queme LF, Jankowski MP, Yin F, Huang T. Systemic Delivery of AAV-Fdxr Mitigates the Phenotypes of Mitochondrial Disorders in Fdxr Mutant Mice. Mol Ther Methods Clin Dev. 2020 May 22;18:84-97. doi: 10.1016/j.omtm.2020.05.021. eCollection 2020 Sep 11.</citation>
    <PMID>32995353</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 2, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 9, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>State University of New York at Buffalo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Taosheng Huang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Neurodegeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Mitochondrial disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Optic atrophy</keyword>
  <keyword>Ferredoxin reductase</keyword>
  <keyword>Iron-sulfur cluster biogenesis</keyword>
  <keyword>Iron overload</keyword>
  <keyword>Iron homeostasis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neurodegenerative Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Optic Atrophy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heredodegenerative Disorders, Nervous System</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Genetic Diseases, Inborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mitochondrial Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atrophy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

