<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04587284</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHUBX 2018/72</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04587284</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Economic Evaluation of Robot-assisted Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy vs Conventional Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy and Open Retropubic Radical Prostatectomy in Prostate Cancer: a Real-life Study Based on the French National Healthcare Data System (SNDS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ECOREPAR</acronym>
  <official_title>Economic Evaluation of Robot-assisted Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy vs Conventional Laparoscopic Radical Prostatectomy and Open Retropubic Radical Prostatectomy in Prostate Cancer: a Real-life Study Based on the French National Healthcare Data System (SNDS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Bordeaux</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bordeaux PharmacoEpi</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Bordeaux</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to assess the cost-effectiveness ratio and the clinical benefit (survival,&#xD;
      disease recurrence, functional results) of the robot-assisted laparoscopic radical&#xD;
      prostatectomy compared with other procedures using real-life data from SNDS. The population&#xD;
      of patients who benefited from robot-assisted surgery will be identified in the SNDS through&#xD;
      a practices survey, allowing the identification of centres fully converted to robotics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Over the last 15 years, robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy surgery has seen a&#xD;
      considerable rise in France. To date, it represents the most common surgical technique for&#xD;
      radical prostatectomies, compared with standard procedure such as open retropubic radical&#xD;
      prostatectomy or laparoscopic radical prostatectomy (8000 procedures/year, 40% of surgeries).&#xD;
      In 2016, the French Health Authority (HAS) published a report on the robot-assisted&#xD;
      laparoscopic radical prostatectomy practice that highlighted the small amount of available&#xD;
      convincing data to provide evidence for a significant clinical benefit. There were no&#xD;
      published data on overall or progression-free survival compared with other surgical&#xD;
      procedures, with an important organizational and financial impact for healthcare institutions&#xD;
      and patients. The question of the clinical benefit and the cost-effectiveness ratio of this&#xD;
      surgical procedure is still relevant taking into account that randomized studies are&#xD;
      difficult to carry out and that results of prospective registers will be available in many&#xD;
      years. In this context, the use of the French National Claims Database (SNDS) appears to be&#xD;
      the best short-term and reduced-cost solution to identify patients who benefited from the&#xD;
      three surgical procedures since the rise of robotics. It would provide real-life data to&#xD;
      national institutions in order to conclude on the opportunity to set a specific hospital&#xD;
      tariff for the robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy. This study aims to assess&#xD;
      the cost-effectiveness ratio and the clinical benefit (survival, disease recurrence,&#xD;
      functional results) of the robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy compared with&#xD;
      other procedures using real-life data from SNDS. The population of patients who benefited&#xD;
      from robot-assisted surgery will be identified in the SNDS through a practices survey,&#xD;
      allowing the identification of centres fully converted to robotics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incremental cost / progression-free (without additional treatment) life-year saved 5 years after initial surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years after initial surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival requiring new treatment at 5 years will be calculated from :&#xD;
Death within 5 years of surgery&#xD;
Occurrence, over the period (5 years), of recurrences / progressions requiring additional treatment by radiotherapy and / or hormone therapy.&#xD;
A sensitivity analysis will be carried out after 1: 1 matching between subjects in each prostatectomy group.&#xD;
Estimation of the probability of event-free survival using the Kaplan-Meier estimator; Comparison of the risk of occurrence of each event between groups using a Cox proportional hazards model (after checking the underlying assumptions). The risk comparison will be measured using an hazard ratio, its 95% confidence interval and the p-value associated with the Wald test&#xD;
without adjustment, from the overall population;&#xD;
after adjustment for the propensity score, from the overall population;&#xD;
from matched groups 1: 1.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incremental cost / life-year saved at 8 years.</measure>
    <time_frame>8 years after initial surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival requiring new treatment at 5 years will be calculated from :&#xD;
Death within 8 years of surgery&#xD;
Occurrence, over the period (8 years), of recurrences / progressions requiring additional treatment by radiotherapy and / or hormone therapy.&#xD;
A sensitivity analysis will be carried out after 1: 1 matching between subjects in each prostatectomy group.&#xD;
Estimation of the probability of event-free survival using the Kaplan-Meier estimator; Comparison of the risk of occurrence of each event between groups using a Cox proportional hazards model (after checking the underlying assumptions). The risk comparison will be measured using an hazard ratio, its 95% confidence interval and the p-value associated with the Wald test&#xD;
without adjustment, from the overall population;&#xD;
after adjustment for the propensity score, from the overall population;&#xD;
from matched groups 1: 1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cost of robotic surgery.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years after initial surgery;8 years after initial surgery</time_frame>
    <description>None-adjusted estimation of cost-effectiveness ratios (95% confidence interval estimated by bootstrap) Net Monetary Benefit estimation of each surgical procedure (NMB = E x λ - C) with λ = differential cost-effectiveness threshold.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Urological hospitalizations within 90 days following the initial surgery.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days following the initial surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The initial hospital stay will be compared between the prostatectomy groups using standardized differences:&#xD;
without adjustment, from the overall population;&#xD;
after adjustment for the propensity score, from the overall population; from the matched groups 1: 1.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">84667</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with open retropubic radical prostatectomy</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with laparoscopic radical prostatectomy</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Three groups will be constituted according to surgical procedure: robot-assisted&#xD;
        laparoscopic radical prostatectomy, open retropubic radical prostatectomy, and laparoscopic&#xD;
        radical prostatectomy. All patients will be followed for at least 5 years and up to 8 years&#xD;
        from the index date. Index date will be defined as the initial radical prostatectomy&#xD;
        surgery performed between 2012-2015.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Total retro-pubic prostatectomy (PTRP) identified in the SNDS by the standard,&#xD;
        Classification of Medical Acts &quot;JGFA006&quot; act&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laparoscopic total prostatectomy (PTL) identified in the SNDS by the CCAM &quot;JGFC001&quot;&#xD;
             act and the health and social establishment files number of centers not equipped with&#xD;
             a surgical robot&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Robot-assisted total prostatectomy (PTRA) identified in the SNDS by the CCAM &quot;JGFC001&quot;&#xD;
             act and the health and social establishment files number of centers equipped with a&#xD;
             surgical robot for more than 12 months and having a rate of use of this technique for&#xD;
             more than 95% minimally invasive prostatectomies. The number of PTRA will be&#xD;
             identified by a survey in each center and the manufacturer's data as explained above&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient who has not received previous treatment for this cancer by hormone therapy,&#xD;
        radiotherapy, brachytherapy or HiFU (treatments sought in the SNDS prior to surgery by the&#xD;
        prescription of pharmaceutical specialties or the presence of CCAM procedures)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient operated for laparoscopic radical prostatectomy or robot-assisted laparoscopic&#xD;
             radical prostatectomy in a center equipped with a surgical robot but with a rate of&#xD;
             use of this technique less than 95% (centers offering different minimally invasive&#xD;
             approaches that do not allow to define if the intervention was performed in robotic&#xD;
             surgery or in open surgery)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient operated for a robot-assisted laparoscopic radical prostatectomy in a center&#xD;
             having started a robotic activity for less than 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient previously treated with another therapeutic modality for his prostate cancer&#xD;
        (salvage prostatectomies after hormone therapy, radiotherapy, brachytherapy or HiFU)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nathalie PREAUBERT</last_name>
    <phone>05 57 82 01 59</phone>
    <email>nathalie.hayes@chu-bordeaux.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laurent PIAZZA</last_name>
    <phone>05 57 82 08 22</phone>
    <email>laurent.piazza@chu-bordeaux.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier Universitaire de Bordeaux</name>
      <address>
        <city>Talence</city>
        <zip>33400</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>PREAUBERT Nathalie</last_name>
      <phone>05 57 82 01 59</phone>
      <email>nathalie.hayes@chu-bordeaux.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>PIAZZA Laurent</last_name>
      <phone>05 57 82 08 22</phone>
      <email>laurent.piazza@chu-bordeaux.fr</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

