<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04585516</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>274964</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04585516</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Diagnostic Usefulness of Different Types of Gastrointestinal Endoscopic Investigations.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Diagnostic Usefulness of Different Types of Gastrointestinal Endoscopic Investigations.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Region Örebro County</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Region Örebro County</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The number of endoscopies performed varies greatly between different countries and does not&#xD;
      reflect variations in disease incidents. The costs of unnecessary endoscopies are significant&#xD;
      and with a better selection of which patients need to be examined with endoscopy, resources&#xD;
      could be saved in healthcare, and a better triage would mean that malignancies and other more&#xD;
      serious conditions do not have to wait. An example of unnecessary endoscopy is a colonoscopy&#xD;
      in patients with irritable bowel syndrome or gastroscopy in patients with functional&#xD;
      dyspepsia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the project is, among other things:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What diagnostic benefit have gastroscopy, colonoscopy, capsule endoscopy and double&#xD;
           balloon enteroscopy for different indications in different age groups?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  What are the risks of this type of examination?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can patients be better selected based on symptoms, psychometric data or laboratory&#xD;
           findings to reduce the number of unnecessary examinations and prioritize those that&#xD;
           should be scooped up first?&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Can changed calling methods reduce the number of late cancellations and rebookings and&#xD;
           missed patients?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1: Identification of colorectal cancer in Örebro Region - Effectiveness of Standardised&#xD;
      Course of Care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Introduction: To shorten time to diagnosis of suspected colorectal cancer (CRC) in Sweden,&#xD;
      CRC was included in the &quot;standardised course of care&quot; (SCC) in 2016. However, not all&#xD;
      patients with CRC are referred via the SCC, and CRC is also found in patients undergoing a&#xD;
      routine colonoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To identify CRC cases in the Örebro Region and how they were identified.&#xD;
      Furthermore, to investigate the reasons for and possible effect of not being included in the&#xD;
      SCC-CRC for cases found via colonoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: Reviewing medical records of patients with CRC referred to the Clinic of Surgery in&#xD;
      the Örebro Region in 2016-2018 (n=459).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The information recalled from the journals includes diagnostic pathway of CRC discovery, age,&#xD;
      gender, Body Mass Index (BMI), Hb-value, date of referral to colonoscopy, date of preformed&#xD;
      colonoscopy, referral route (SCC-CRC or non-CRC-SCC), reasons for referral (including SCC-CRC&#xD;
      criteria) and patient symptoms. Furthermore, we will gather data of tumor localization&#xD;
      (caecum; ascending colon; splenic flexure; transverse colon; hepatic flexure; descending&#xD;
      colon; sigmoid and rectum), TNM-stage of the tumor, [11] tumor differentiation (high grade or&#xD;
      low grade tumor), and source of referral (referral by general practitioner or referral by&#xD;
      hospital physician).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Age is determined at the time of referral. BMI is defined as the most recent BMI value at&#xD;
      time of referral within six months prior or six months after referral date. Hb-value will be&#xD;
      defined as the most recent Hb-value within a month prior of the time of referral. Diagnostic&#xD;
      interval is defined as the number of days days between the referral and the colonoscopy. When&#xD;
      the tumor localization is described as in between two locations of the colon (e.g. descendent&#xD;
      colon and sigmoid colon) the most proximal location is chosen for statistical analysis.&#xD;
      Patients with two or more synchronous cancers are registered as more than one incident per&#xD;
      case. When the tumor localization is described as being present in the rectosigmoid&#xD;
      transition, the sigmoid is used as the tumor localization in the analysis. When patients have&#xD;
      two or more symptoms and reasons for referral, data are registered as more than one incident&#xD;
      per case. TNM stage is converted to tumor stage I-IV. [1] When patients have one or more&#xD;
      synchronic cancer with different TNM stages, the highest cancer stage is chosen for analysis.&#xD;
      If the TNM stage is not fully known (e.g. information about lymph nodes and metastases are&#xD;
      missing) the stage is set as no lymph node engagement or metastases, If the original referral&#xD;
      cannot be found, date and reasons for referral are collected from journal entries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2: The Swedish standardized course of care for colorectal cancer - cancer prevalence and&#xD;
      predictive values of entry criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Introduction: To shorten waiting times for cancer treatment and to reduce national&#xD;
      inequalities in cancer care, the standardized course of care (SCC) was implemented in Sweden.&#xD;
      The SCC for colorectal cancer (CRC-SCC) was implemented in 2016. Since then, about 46.000&#xD;
      patients have been examined according to a CRC-SCC. However, few studies have been conducted&#xD;
      to evaluate the CRC-SCC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim: To identify the prevalence of colorectal cancer (CRC) in patients referred to Örebro&#xD;
      University Hospital (USÖ) according to a CRC-SCC. We also aimed to investigate the positive&#xD;
      predicting values (PPVs) and odds ratios (ORs) of different SCC-criteria with respect to CRC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method: Medical record review including all patients examined by colonoscopy as part of a&#xD;
      CRC-SCC-referral to USÖ between September, 2016 and December 2018 (n=1271).The parameters of&#xD;
      interest include; patient characteristics such as sex and age, the SCC-criteria for&#xD;
      reasonable suspicion of cancer. If the patient has an altered bowel function it is registered&#xD;
      whether the patient has loose stool, constipation, a combination of the two, or not specified&#xD;
      in the referral. Rectal bleeding is defined as fresh rectal bleeding, excluding melaena.&#xD;
      Patients who fulfill multiple criteria are registered as more than one incidence case.&#xD;
      Laboratory values such as fecal occult blood, plasma-hemoglobin, and fecal-calprotectin&#xD;
      (F-calprotectin) are registered. The most resent value at the time of referral is used. If&#xD;
      there is no value within a month of the referral, no value was registered. A patient is&#xD;
      regarded to have a positive fecal occult blood test (FOBT) if at least one out of three tests&#xD;
      is positive. A f-calprotectin &lt;50mg/kg is considered negative. Findings from the colonoscopy&#xD;
      such as CRC, polyps, inflammation of the colon, diverticulosis, hemorrhoids, angiodysplasia&#xD;
      or no finding are registered. All findings with colonoscopy are, if possible, histologically&#xD;
      verified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3: Why do we perform gastroscopy in younger patients?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background: Esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) is the golden standard diagnostic method in&#xD;
      upper GI pathologies. The current guidelines indicate that patients with alarm symptoms&#xD;
      and/or dyspeptic patients over 50 years of age should be readily investigated with&#xD;
      gastroscopy. However, EGD is also frequently performed in the younger population, where it&#xD;
      often results in absence of pathological findings. In Örebro approximately 4000 EGD are&#xD;
      completed yearly, approximately 40% of the EGD's are performed in patients &gt;50 years,&#xD;
      requiring extensive resources.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim: to identify factors in the EGD referrals of patients under 50 years of age without alarm&#xD;
      symptoms, in order to minimize the number of unnecessary EGD's in this age group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method and material: The study will be conducted as a retrospective database study. We will&#xD;
      process the EGD referrals and diagnostic findings of young patients (age 18-50 y) performed&#xD;
      during 2017-2019 at Örebro University Hospital. Statistical analysis will be performed to&#xD;
      identify which signs and symptoms are associated with a pathological finding during EGD and&#xD;
      which signs and symptoms are associated with a negative finding. The parameters of interest&#xD;
      include; patient characteristics such as sex and age will separately analyze the groups&#xD;
      18-29y, 30-39y, and 40-49 y. Other parameters include: BMI, ethnicity, use of NSAID/ASA, h.&#xD;
      pylori analysis, eventual treatment for h. pylori, smoking, alcohol consumption,presence of&#xD;
      GI disease before gastroscopy, previously done gastroscopy, source of referral (primary&#xD;
      health care or in-hospital patients), if present: fulfillment of Rome IV criteria for&#xD;
      functional dyspepsia, symptoms such as anemia, fecal occult blood, palpable mass in abdomen,&#xD;
      weight loss, loss of appetite, dysphagia, vomiting, jaundice, waiting time between referral&#xD;
      and gastroscopy, as well as the findings under gastroscopy; GERD/oesofagitis, peptic ulcus,&#xD;
      gastritis, dysplasia/cancer, IBD, celiac disease, hiatal hernia&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Year</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>All confirmed colorectal cancer cases that were diagnosed via colonoscopy.</measure>
    <time_frame>between September 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of patients that was admitted to the department of surgery with confirmed colorectal cancer, diagnosed according to the standardized course of care for colorectal cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients that was diagnosed with colorectal cancer. with colorectal cancer</measure>
    <time_frame>between September 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>All patients that were admitted to the endoscopy unit according to the standardized course of care for colorectal cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of upper GI pathology</measure>
    <time_frame>between Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of upper GI pathology in all patients &lt;50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>route of colorectal cancer diagnosis 1</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of patients with confirmed colorectal cancer that was diagnosed with colonoscopy according to the standardized chain of care for colorectal cancer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>route of colorectal cancer diagnosis 2</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of patients with confirmed colorectal cancer that was diagnosed with routine colonoscopy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Localization of colorectal cancer</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The site of the tumor in confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tumor characteristics of colorectal cancer 1</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The stage of the tumor in confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tumor characteristics of colorectal cancer 2</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The histology of the tumor in confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 1</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with changes in bowel habits &gt;4 weeks in patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 2</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with radiology in patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 3</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with abnormal rectal finding via palpation or rectoscopy in patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 4</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with rectal bleeding without obvious source in patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 5</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with rectal bleeding despite adequate treatment of bleeding source in patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 6</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with rectal bleeding in high-risk patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics of colorectal cancer 7</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with bleeding anemia of unknown source in patients with confirmed colorectal cancer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 1</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>male/female</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 2</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>age</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 3</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>hemoglobine value</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 4</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>calprotectin value</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 5</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Days between referral and colonoscopy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 6</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 and December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>referral from primary health care yes/no</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>patient characteristics of colorectal cancer 7</measure>
    <time_frame>January 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>referral year: 2017/2017/2018</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 1</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with weight loss &gt;10%</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 2</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>age</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 3</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018 0</time_frame>
    <description>male/female</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 1</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with loose stools</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 2</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with constipation</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 3</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with altered bowel function specified</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 4</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with abnormal radiology</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 5</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with abnormal rectal examination</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 6</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with rectal bleeding without obvious source</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 7</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with rectal bleeding despite adequate treatment</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 8</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of high-risk patients with rectal bleeding</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 9</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with anemia of unknown cause</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 10</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with positive fecal occult blood test</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>symptom characteristics in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 11</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with increased fecal calprotectin</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 1</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with polyps high-grade/low grade dysplasia</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 2</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with diverticulosis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 3</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with inflammation unspecified</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 4</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with IBD</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 5</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with infectious colitis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 6</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with microscopic colitis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 7</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with diverticulitis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 8</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with hemorrhoids</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 9</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with angiodysplasia</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Endoscopic finding in patients who were admitted for colonoscopy 10</measure>
    <time_frame>September 2016 - December 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with no findings.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with weight loss &gt;10%</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with loss of appetite</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 3</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with dysphagia</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 4</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with vomiting</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 5</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with jaundice</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 6</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with GERD/oesofagitis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with gastritis</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 8</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with peptic ulcer disease</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 9</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with dysplasia/cancer</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 10</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with IBD</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 11</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with celiac disease</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients who meet Rome IV criteria for functional dyspepsia.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 13</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with other unspecified pathology</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 1</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>male/female</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients who smoke</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 3</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with age 18-29, age 30-39, age 40-49.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 4</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients using NSAIDs/ASA</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 5</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients who had done a h. pylori test</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 6</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients with a positive h. pylori test</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of patients who were eradicated after a positive h. pylori test</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 8</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>ethnicity of patients (proportion caucasian origin, African origin, arabic origin, asian origin)</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patients characteristics in patients &lt; 50 years who were admitted for a gastroscopy 9</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 2019-April 2020</time_frame>
    <description>days between referral and gastroscopy</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>Colo-rectal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Gastrointestinal Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with suspected colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients that were admitted to the department of surgery with suspected colorectal cancer between January 2016 and December 2018 (n=459).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients admitted according to the standardized course of care for colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients that were admitted to the endoscopy department according to the standardized course of care for colorectal cancer between September 2016 and December 2018 (n=1271).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &lt; 50 years that were admitted for gastroscopy</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients younger than 50 years that were admitted to the endoscopy department for a gastroscopy between jan 2018 and April 2019 (n= 1915)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &gt;80 years that were admitted for colonoscopy</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients older than 80 years that were admitted to the endoscopy department for a colonoscopy between Sept 2016 and Jan 2019 (n= 981)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>endoscopy</intervention_name>
    <description>Colonoscopy or gastroscopy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with suspected colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &lt; 50 years that were admitted for gastroscopy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &gt;80 years that were admitted for colonoscopy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients admitted according to the standardized course of care for colorectal cancer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who underwent an endoscopic diagnostic procedure.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        All patients who underwent a diagnostic diagnostic procedure at the endoscopy unit at the&#xD;
        University Hospital Örebro.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients &lt;18 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Örebro</city>
        <state>Egion Rebro Ounty</state>
        <zip>70185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 7, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 12, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Region Örebro County</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michiel van Nieuwenhoven</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Md, MSc, associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>colonoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>gastroscopy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Digestive System Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

