<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04588142</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>L-020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04588142</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Probiotic Supplementation on Exercise Endurance Among Non-elite Athletes</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of Probiotic Supplementation on Exercise Endurance Among Non-elite Athletes: A Randomized, Placebo-controlled, Double-blind, Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lallemand Health Solutions</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lallemand Health Solutions</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this trial is to evaluate the effects of 6-week administration of probiotics on&#xD;
      running performance among non-elite athletes. It is hypothesized that participants receiving&#xD;
      probiotics may improve their running performance at an endurance test compared to their&#xD;
      placebo-receiving counterparts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants recruited from the university community in the Southeast U.S. will participate&#xD;
      in a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled interventional study for approximately 9&#xD;
      weeks following obtainment of informed consent. Two weeks prior to randomization participants&#xD;
      will begin the pre-baseline period and complete daily and weekly questionnaires (physical&#xD;
      activity and muscle soreness, bowel movements and gastrointestinal health, flu and cold&#xD;
      symptoms). Visit 2 will occur during the pre-baseline period and participants will complete a&#xD;
      VO2 max fitness assessment, which will be used during the endurance testing. Participants&#xD;
      will also receive the SenseWear Armdand Mini®, a wearable device that will record their&#xD;
      physical activity, sleeping patterns and energy expenditure for one week prior to visits 3&#xD;
      and 4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be randomized at visit 3. Prior to this visit, participants will consume a&#xD;
      standardized breakfast, collect a stool sample and a saliva sample that will be brought to&#xD;
      site. During this visit participants will have a body composition and perform the Submaximal&#xD;
      Treadmill Test. During the treadmill test, participants will provide finger prick samples for&#xD;
      subsequent analysis of blood metabolites (glucose and lactate) and perceived exhaustion&#xD;
      subjectively. Lastly, participants will complete several nutrition and motivation-related&#xD;
      questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One week prior to the final visit (V4), participants will be asked to wear the SenseWear&#xD;
      Armband Mini® again for one week, which they will return at the final visit. Participants&#xD;
      will eat another standardized breakfast prior to the final visit, visit 4. They will bring a&#xD;
      stool and saliva sample to the site. During visit 4, participants will complete the&#xD;
      submaximal treadmill test, while providing finger prick samples for analysis of blood and&#xD;
      lactate levels. In addition, body composition will be assessed, as well as nutrition and&#xD;
      motivation (subjectively). Visit 4 will be followed by a washout week, during which&#xD;
      participants will not intake the study supplement but they will complete daily, weekly, and&#xD;
      the final questionnaire.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time-to exhaustion during submaximal treadmill test</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of time-to exhaustion during submaximal treadmill test at the end of intervention from those that received probiotic versus placebo.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in perceived exertion</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in the Borg Rating of Perceived Exertion among probiotics versus placebo (score range = 9, very light effort to 20, extremely strenuous exercise)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in blood glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in capillary blood glucose among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in blood lactate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in capillary blood lactate among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in salivary stress and immune biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the difference in salivary cortisol, alpha-amylase and sIgA at the end of intervention among probiotics versus placebo</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in cold/flu episodes</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare severity, duration and number of cold/flu episodes throughout the intervention among probiotics versus placebo, as assessed by a Visual Analogue Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in gastrointestinal function and discomfort</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare GI function during the intervention and change in GI function from baseline among probiotics versus placebo assessed by the Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale (GSRS) and the Digestion-Associated Quality of Life (DQLQ).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Difference in bowel habits</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To compare bowel habits during the intervention, frequency and consistency, among probiotics versus placebo assessed by the Bristol Stool Form Scale (BSFS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Exercise Endurance</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants are randomized to receive probiotics for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants are randomized to receive placebo for 6 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Probiotic</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-elite athletes receive probiotic for 6 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Non-elite athletes receive placebo for 6 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy adults between 18-45 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Regularly participate in running and cross-training, and willing to maintain this&#xD;
             level of training throughout the study. Participant must satisfy all three&#xD;
             sub-criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. 3-5 days per week of running or cross-training AND&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. 45 minutes - 1.5 hours per activity session AND&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Run ≥15 miles per week&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. VO2 max values that in the 60-85th percentile (good-excellent health) range according&#xD;
             to ACSM guidelines [1].&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any physician-diagnosed diseases that would impact exercise performance or&#xD;
             participation, including gastrointestinal disease, heart/cardiopulmonary disease,&#xD;
             diabetes, thyroid disease, hypogonadism, hepatorenal disease, musculoskeletal&#xD;
             disorder, neuromuscular/neurological disease, autoimmune disease, cancer, peptic&#xD;
             ulcers or anemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Professional or elite athletes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Use of any antibiotic drug within 4 weeks of randomization. Volunteer could be&#xD;
             eligible to participate after a 2-week washout period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Currently smoking (including vaping)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnant, planning to get pregnant, or currently breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Lactose intolerance and/or milk, soy or yeast allergy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bobbi Langkamp-Henken, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Florida</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Caitlin McDermont, M.Sc.</last_name>
    <phone>352-682-4882</phone>
    <email>nutrition-study@ufl.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UF Health Sports Performance Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32607</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Caitlin McDermont</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ergogenic effects</keyword>
  <keyword>Probiotics</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-elite athletes</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>After publications of the results, de-identified data will be shared with qualified researchers and scientists upon reasonable request to the sponsor including a detailed proposal of the intended use of the data, as per the Lallemand Health Solutions Inc. Policy on Clinical Trial Transparency and Data Sharing (available upon request).</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

