<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04580160</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>V-CA-0001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04580160</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Venous Stent for the Iliofemoral Vein Investigational Clinical Trial Using the DUO Venous Stent System</brief_title>
  <acronym>VIVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Venous Stent for the Iliofemoral Vein Investigational Clinical Trial Using the DUO Venous Stent System</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vesper Medical, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vesper Medical, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, multi-center, single-arm, non-blinded clinical trial designed to&#xD;
      investigate the safety and efficacy of the Vesper DUO Venous Stent System as compared to a&#xD;
      pre-defined performance goal (PG) established from published, peer reviewed scientific&#xD;
      literature related to stenting of iliofemoral venous outflow obstructions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 30, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety - Freedom from major adverse events (MAEs) at 30 days</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Freedom from major adverse events (MAEs) at 30 days post index procedure, as adjudicated by the Clinical Events Committee (CEC) or Core Laboratory, including:&#xD;
Device or procedure-related death&#xD;
Device or procedure-related bleed at the target vessel and/or the target lesion or at the access site requiring surgical or endovascular intervention or blood transfusion of ≥2 units&#xD;
Device or procedure-related venous injury occurring in the target vessel and/or the target lesion or at the access site requiring surgical or endovascular intervention&#xD;
Major amputation of the target limb&#xD;
Clinically significant pulmonary embolism (PE), confirmed by CT angiography&#xD;
Stent embolization outside of the target vessel&#xD;
Presence of new thrombus within the stented segment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy - Primary patency of stented segment at 12 months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Primary patency of stented segment at 12 months defined as freedom from:&#xD;
Duplex Ultrasound (DUS) core laboratory adjudicated occlusion or stenosis &gt;50% within the stented segment. If DUS shows &gt;50% stenosis or occlusion, confirmation by diagnostic intravascular ultrasound (IVUS) is required.&#xD;
CEC adjudicated clinically driven target lesion reintervention (CD-TLR) defined as endovascular or surgical procedure for new, recurrent, or worsening symptoms and core lab adjudicated &gt;50% stenosis or occlusion within the stented segment confirmed by diagnostic IVUS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>May-Thurner Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Deep Vein Thrombosis</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Venous Insufficiency</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Duo Venous Stent System Implantation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Duo Venous Stent System</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects with nonmalignant iliofemoral venous outflow obstruction presenting with nonthrombotic (NT), acute thrombotic (AT) or chronic postthrombotic (CPT) disease pathogenesis will be selected for study participation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Duo Venous Stent System Implantation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or non-pregnant, non-breastfeeding females ≥18 years of age at the time of&#xD;
             consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject is able and willing to provide written informed consent prior to receiving any&#xD;
             non-standard of care, protocol specific procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Female subjects of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
             days prior to treatment and must use some form of contraception (abstinence is&#xD;
             acceptable) throughout the time of clinical trial exit&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Willing and capable of complying with all required follow-up visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Estimated life expectancy ≥1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject is ambulatory (use of assistive walking device such as a cane or walker is&#xD;
             acceptable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Body mass index (BMI) &lt;40&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Clinically significant symptomatic venous outflow obstruction in one iliofemoral&#xD;
             venous segment (one limb) per subject, is indicated for venoplasty and stenting, and&#xD;
             meets at least one of the following clinical indicators:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. CEAP score ≥3&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. VCSS pain score ≥2&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Suspected deep vein thrombosis (DVT) with symptoms occurring prior to receiving a&#xD;
                  DUO Stent&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Subject is willing and able to comply with PI recommendation for compression therapy,&#xD;
             if required&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Presence of unilateral, non-malignant venous obstruction of the common femoral vein&#xD;
             (CFV), external iliac vein (EIV), common iliac vein (CIV), or any combination thereof,&#xD;
             defined as a ≥50% reduction in target vessel lumen diameter and confirmed by&#xD;
             venographic or IVUS imaging. The cranial point of the obstruction may extend to the&#xD;
             iliac vein confluence of the inferior vena cava (IVC) and the caudal point may be 2mm&#xD;
             above either the inflow of the deep femoral (or profunda) or the lesser trochanter,&#xD;
             whichever is most cranial&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Obstructive lesion(s) able to be treated with continuous stent coverage&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Adequate inflow to the target lesion(s) involving at least a patent femoral or deep&#xD;
             femoral vein and a landing zone in the CFV free from significant disease requiring&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Reference vessel diameter is of adequate size to accommodate the appropriate size&#xD;
             stent as measured by IVUS&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. All vessels from insertion site through target vessel can accommodate a 9F or 10F&#xD;
             sheath, depending on the stent size used&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Ability to cross interventional devices through target lesion(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. In DVT subjects, successful treatment of acute thrombus must have occurred prior to&#xD;
             receiving any DUO Stents for an underlying obstructive lesion. Successful treatment of&#xD;
             acute thrombus is defined as reestablishment of antegrade flow with ≤30% residual&#xD;
             thrombus (confirmed by venogram or IVUS) and freedom from bleeding and symptomatic&#xD;
             pulmonary embolism (confirmed by imaging). After successful treatment of thrombus is&#xD;
             confirmed, eligible obstructive lesion(s) can be treated with a DUO Stent during the&#xD;
             same procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. All subjects must undergo a SARS-CoV-2 test and have a negative test result within 8&#xD;
             days of the index procedure. If a SARS-CoV-2 test is unavailable due to institution&#xD;
             policy, a test shortage, or if there is a delay in test results, the subject must&#xD;
             complete the COVID-19 questionnaire and must have answered NO to all questions to be&#xD;
             eligible for enrollment. A SARS-CoV-2 test will not be required for enrollment if a&#xD;
             subject has received a complete cycle of an authorized COVID-19 vaccine or has&#xD;
             documented evidence of a positive COVID-19 antibody test and is asymptomatic and has&#xD;
             no long-lasting effects (per PI discretion) from a prior COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. A measured temperature less than 99.5°F (37.5°C) on the day of the index procedure and&#xD;
             no history of fever or feeling feverish within 14 days of the index procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. No prior history, within 60 days of the index procedure, of a SARS-CoV-2 positive&#xD;
             test, or COVID-19 symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Target limb symptoms caused by peripheral arterial disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presence of unresolved significant pulmonary embolism prior to use of the DUO Venous&#xD;
             Stent System confirmed by chest CT. If subject has documented history of significant&#xD;
             pulmonary embolism within the last 6 months, a chest CT is required to confirm&#xD;
             significant pulmonary embolism is not currently present.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Presence of IVC obstruction or target venous obstruction that extends into the IVC&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of acute DVT located outside target limb&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Contralateral venous occlusive disease of the CFV, EIV, and/or CIV, with planned&#xD;
             treatment ≤390 days after the index procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Uncontrolled or active coagulopathy or known, uncorrectable bleeding diathesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Coagulopathy causing INR &gt;2 which is not amenable to medical treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Platelet count &lt;50,000 cells/mm3 or &gt;1,000,000 cells/mm3 and/or White blood cell (WBC)&#xD;
             &lt;3,000 cells/mm3 or &gt;12,500 cells/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Uncorrected hemoglobin of ≤9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subject is on dialysis or has an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt;30&#xD;
             mL/min. In subjects with diabetes mellitus, eGFR &lt;45 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of Heparin Induced Thrombocytopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Presence of known aggressive clotting disorders such as Lupus Anticoagulant Disorder,&#xD;
             Antiphospholipid antibody syndrome, homozygous gene Factor V Leiden or Prothrombin&#xD;
             gene abnormalities, Protein C and S deficiency or Antithrombin deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known hypersensitivity or contraindication to antiplatelet therapy or anticoagulation,&#xD;
             nickel, or titanium&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Contrast agent allergy that cannot be managed adequately with pre-medication&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Intended concurrent adjuvant procedure (except for venoplasty) such as creation of&#xD;
             temporary arteriovenous fistula, femoral endovenectomy or saphenous vein ablation&#xD;
             and/or saphenous vein stripping during the index procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subjects who have had any prior surgical or endovascular procedures to the target&#xD;
             vessel. Note that subjects who have had successful catheter-directed or mechanical&#xD;
             thrombolysis in the target vessel for DVT at least 90 days prior to the index&#xD;
             procedure may be included&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Planned surgical or interventional procedures of the target limb (except thrombolysis&#xD;
             and/or thrombectomy in preparation for the procedure or vena cava filter placement&#xD;
             prior to stent implantation in subjects at high risk for pulmonary embolism) within 30&#xD;
             days prior to or 30 days after the index procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Planned surgical or interventional procedures for other medical conditions (i.e., not&#xD;
             associated with the target limb) 30 days prior to or 30 days after the index procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Previous venous stenting of the target limb, the IVC, or contralateral limb if stents&#xD;
             extend into the IVC&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Iliofemoral venous segment unsuitable for treatment with available sizes of DUO Stent&#xD;
             implants&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Lesions with intended treatment lengths extending into the IVC&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. No safe landing zone at or above the profunda femoral confluence&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Participating in another investigational study in which the subject has not completed&#xD;
             the primary endpoint(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Has other comorbidities that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would preclude them&#xD;
             from receiving this treatment and/or participating in study-required follow-up&#xD;
             assessments&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Joseph C Griffin</last_name>
    <phone>14848926340</phone>
    <email>jgriffin@vespermedical.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Joseph Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sandy Chung</last_name>
      <phone>714-744-8795</phone>
      <email>Sandy.chung@stjoe.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bhavraj Khalsa, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Risa Jiron</last_name>
      <phone>650-736-1598</phone>
      <email>rjiron@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>William Kuo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Vascular Experts</name>
      <address>
        <city>Darien</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06820</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria Myslinski</last_name>
      <phone>201-956-6834</phone>
      <email>mmyslinski@thevascularexperts.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Paul Gagne, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hartford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hartford</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alison Champagne</last_name>
      <phone>860-972-6049</phone>
      <email>Alison.champagne@hhchealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edward Gifford, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MedStar Washington Hospital Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kassaye Sesaba</last_name>
      <phone>202-877-7452</phone>
      <email>kassaye.t.sesaba@medstar.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steven Abramowitz, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Clinical Research-Deland LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lake Mary</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32746</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michelle Jones</last_name>
      <phone>386-785-2400</phone>
      <phone_ext>396</phone_ext>
      <email>mjones@accelclinical.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ashish Gupta, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Palm Vascular Centers</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami Beach</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33140</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Gimeno</last_name>
      <phone>305-763-8734</phone>
      <email>jennifer@palmvascular.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Beasley, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai Medical Center of Florida</name>
      <address>
        <city>Miami</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33140</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yoselin Lugo</last_name>
      <phone>305-674-2121</phone>
      <phone_ext>59162</phone_ext>
      <email>Yoselin.Lugo@msmc.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Ayad, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Piedmont Atlanta Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30309</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Fatina Ashley</last_name>
      <phone>404-450-0825</phone>
      <email>FaTina.Ashley@piedmont.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Charles Ross, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Karp</last_name>
      <phone>312-926-5289</phone>
      <email>jkarp@nm.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kush Desai, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Midwest Cardiovascular Research Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Davenport</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lori Christensen, RN, BSN</last_name>
      <phone>563-324-2828</phone>
      <email>christensen.@mcrfmd.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicholas Shammas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiovascular Institute of the South</name>
      <address>
        <city>Opelousas</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zip>70570</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Victoria Smith</last_name>
      <phone>337-942-3006</phone>
      <email>victoria.smith@cardio.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kaylan Veerina, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Michigan Outpatient Vascular Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dearborn</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48126</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nathalia Clark</last_name>
      <phone>201-894-3163</phone>
      <email>Nathalia.Clark@EHMCHealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elias Kassab, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Edgewood Hospital and Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Englewood</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07631</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aaron Chang</last_name>
      <phone>201-408-5645</phone>
      <email>Sungrok.chang@EHMCHealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Steve Elias, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Holy Name Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Teaneck</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07666</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Angelee Butters</last_name>
      <phone>201-541-6312</phone>
      <email>abutters@holyname.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>John Rundback, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aaron Greenberg</last_name>
      <phone>212-214-3666</phone>
      <email>Aaron.Greenberg@mountsinai.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Lookstein, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Irving Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christa Lei Sonido</last_name>
      <phone>212-305-1694</phone>
      <email>cms2392@cumc.columbia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Edvard Skripochnik, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stony Brook Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stony Brook</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11790</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andrew Bryan</last_name>
      <phone>631-444-8156</phone>
      <email>Andrew.bryan@stonybrookmedicine.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Antonios Gasparis, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Atrium Health</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlotte</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>28204</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kathryn Pool</last_name>
      <email>Kathryn.pool@atriumhealth.org</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Office: 704-373-0212 Fax:704-468-3393</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erin Murphy</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NC Heart and Vascular</name>
      <address>
        <city>Raleigh</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27607</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Junette Yu</last_name>
      <phone>919-784-6564</phone>
      <email>Junette.Yu@unchealth.unc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dorian Defreitas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ohio Health Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Johnna Booker</last_name>
      <phone>614-566-1272</phone>
      <email>Johnna.Booker@ohiohealth.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Jolly, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Judith Brimmeier</last_name>
      <phone>412-235-1304</phone>
      <email>brimmeierja@upmc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rabih Chaer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Miriam Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02906</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lina Felix</last_name>
      <phone>401-793-4105</phone>
      <email>lfelix@lifespan.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Peter Soukas, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Houston Healthcare Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77090</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Joan Morrison</last_name>
      <phone>832-633-5463</phone>
      <email>Joan.Morrison@HCAHealthCare.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Eric Trestman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Dallas Research Associates</name>
      <address>
        <city>McKinney</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75069</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Maria Yusuf</last_name>
      <phone>972-529-6939</phone>
      <email>maria@ndresearch.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Muhammad A Khan, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hurricane Cardiology Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Braunfels</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kristen Hlozek</last_name>
      <phone>857-334-0851</phone>
      <email>kristen@hurricanecardiology.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jason Yoho, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sentara Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Norfolk</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23507</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sarah Havert</last_name>
      <phone>757-388-2991</phone>
      <email>sshavert@sentara.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David Dexter, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lake Washington Vascular, PPLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bellevue</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98004</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kimberly Glorieux</last_name>
      <phone>425-453-1772</phone>
      <email>kimg@lkwv.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kathleen Gibson, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical College of Wisconsin, Vascular &amp; Interventional Radiology, Froedtert Hospital Radiology, Rm 2803</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milwaukee</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53226</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elizabeth Weil</last_name>
      <phone>414-805-3125</phone>
      <email>eweil@mcw.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Parag Patel, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Independent Public Clinical Hospital No 1 in Lublin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lublin</city>
        <zip>20-081</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anna Niedzialek</last_name>
      <phone>+48 601 804 310</phone>
      <email>anianiedzialek@interia.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Radoslaw Pietura, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital in Opole</name>
      <address>
        <city>Opole</city>
        <zip>45-401</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Malgorzata Ziólkowska</last_name>
      <phone>+48 77 45520642</phone>
      <email>ziolkowskamalgorzata@interia.pl</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Grzegorz Oszkinis, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medical University of Karol Marcinkowski</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poznań</city>
        <zip>61-484</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jolanta Tomczak</last_name>
      <phone>+48 618549141</phone>
      <email>jolantatomczak.pte@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Zbigniew Krasinski, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venous Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venous Insufficiency</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>May-Thurner Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

