<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03114462</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016-1023</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-01164</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03114462</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial of Stereotactic HYpofractionateD RadioAblative (HYDRA) Treatment of Laryngeal Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Trial of Stereotactic HYpofractionateD RadioAblative (HYDRA) Treatment of Laryngeal Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Cancer Prevention Research Institute of Texas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical research study is to find the highest tolerable dose of&#xD;
      stereotactic hypofractionated radioablation (HYDRA) radiation that can be given to patients&#xD;
      with laryngeal cancer. The safety of this radiation will also be studied.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If participant is found to be eligible to take part in this study, participant will be&#xD;
      assigned to a radiation level of HYDRA radiation based on when participant joins this study.&#xD;
      Up to 5 dose levels of HYDRA radiation will be tested. Up to 10 participants will be enrolled&#xD;
      at each dose level. The first group of participants will receive the lowest dose level. Each&#xD;
      new group will receive a higher dose than the group before it, if no intolerable side effects&#xD;
      were seen. This will continue until the highest tolerable dose of HYDRA radiation is found.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HYDRA Radiation Administration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If participant is found to be eligible to take part in this study, participant will receive&#xD;
      HYDRA radiation on up to 5 days over the course of about 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During radiation, participant will be asked to lie still for about 30-45 minutes. To help&#xD;
      make sure that participant's head and neck do not move, participant will wear a head and neck&#xD;
      mask. Participant will then have CT or PET-CT scans to make sure that participant is in the&#xD;
      right position before participant begins HYDRA radiation. The actual HYDRA radiation&#xD;
      treatment will take about 5-10 minutes to complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Length of Study Participation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant may continue receiving HYDRA radiation for up to 2 weeks and for a total of 5&#xD;
      times. Participant will no longer be able to receive the study radiation if the disease gets&#xD;
      worse, if intolerable side effects occur, or if participant is unable to follow study&#xD;
      directions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation on this study will be over after Long-Term Follow-Up. Long-Term Follow-Up may&#xD;
      take up to 10 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Days that participant receives HYDRA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a speech pathology exam to check participant's voice, swallowing,&#xD;
           and breathing function.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will complete the same 5 questionnaires that participant did at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-Up Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      About 6 weeks after participant's last dose of HYDRA radiation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a videostroboscopy to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a speech pathology exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a CT or PET-CT scan to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will complete the same 5 questionnaires that participant did at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a laryngoscopy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease. A laryngoscopy is a standard procedure in which a tube with a&#xD;
           lighted camera is inserted through participant's mouth and into participant's throat.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a core biopsy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease. To perform a core biopsy, a sample of tissue is removed using a&#xD;
           hollow core needle that has a cutting edge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      About 3 months after participant's last dose of HYDRA radiation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a modified barium swallow to test participant's swallowing&#xD;
           function and to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a CT or PET-CT scan to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will complete the same 5 questionnaires that participant did at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a laryngoscopy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a core biopsy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      About 6 months after participant's last dose of HYDRA radiation:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a videostroboscopy to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will complete the same 5 questionnaires that participant did at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a CT or PET-CT scan to check&#xD;
           the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a speech pathology exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a laryngoscopy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a core biopsy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Long-Term Follow-Up:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After participant's 6 month follow-up visit, every 3 months for the first 2 years, and then&#xD;
      every 6 months after that for up to 5 years:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a videostroboscopy to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a speech pathology exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a modified barium swallow to test participant's swallowing&#xD;
           function and to check the status of the disease. This will only be done between 3-6&#xD;
           months and then 18-24 months after the first HYDRA dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will complete the same 5 questionnaires that participant did at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a CT or PET-CT scan to check&#xD;
           the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a laryngoscopy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If the doctor thinks it is needed, participant will have a core biopsy to check the&#xD;
           status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an investigational study. HYDRA radiation is delivered using methods that are not&#xD;
      FDA-approved or commercially available. It is currently being used for research purposes&#xD;
      only. The study doctor can explain how the radiation is designed to work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 50 participants will be enrolled in this study. All will take part at MD Anderson.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 9, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2027</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) of Stereotactic Hypofractionated RadioAblative (HYDRA) Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days</time_frame>
    <description>Toxicity graded using the NCI Common Toxicity Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) v. 4.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Complete Response Rate of Stereotactic Hypofractionated RadioAblative (HYDRA) Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Overall complete response rate with laryngeal HYDRA measured from duration of time from start of treatment to primary disease relapse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Respiratory and Intrathoracic Organs</condition>
  <condition>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of the Larynx</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic Hypofractionated Radioablation (HYDRA)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive HYDRA radiation on up to 5 days over the course of about 2 weeks, and for a total of 5 times.&#xD;
Questionnaires completed at Baseline, on days receiving HYDRA, 6 weeks after last dose of HYDRA, 3 months after last dose of HYDRA, and 6 months after last dose of HYDRA. Also after the 6 month follow-up visit, every 3 months for the first 2 years, and then every 6 months after that for up to 5 years.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stereotactic Hypofractionated Radioablation</intervention_name>
    <description>Starting dose is 8.0 Gy per fraction for 5 fractions (total dose = 40.0 Gy). Subsequent cohorts of participants receive an additional 0.5 Gy per fraction.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic Hypofractionated Radioablation (HYDRA)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HYDRA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>Quality of life and symptom questionnaires completed at: Baseline, on days receiving HYDRA, 6 weeks after last dose of HYDRA, 3 months after last dose of HYDRA, and 6 months after last dose of HYDRA. Also after the 6 month follow-up visit, every 3 months for the first 2 years, and then every 6 months after that for up to 5 years.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic Hypofractionated Radioablation (HYDRA)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Surveys</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients older than 18 years of age with histologically proven squamous cell carcinoma&#xD;
             of the larynx.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Stage T1N1/T2-4aN0-1 disease, as defined by American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC)&#xD;
             criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ECOG (Zubrod) performance status 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Must be functionally and technically fit for partial laryngectomy. Subsite study&#xD;
             candidates will be evaluated by enrolling physician. The assessment checklist will be&#xD;
             submitted at time of enrollment and evaluated by Dr. Gross or Dr. Phan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception&#xD;
             (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry, for&#xD;
             the duration of study participation, and for 90 days following completion of therapy.&#xD;
             Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while participating in this&#xD;
             study, she should inform her treating physician immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. A female of child-bearing potential is any woman (regardless of sexual orientation,&#xD;
             having undergone a tubal ligation, or remaining celibate by choice) who meets the&#xD;
             following criteria: *Has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy; or&#xD;
             *Has not been naturally postmenopausal for at least 12 consecutive months (i.e., has&#xD;
             had menses at any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Ability to understand English language and the willingness to sign a written informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have undergone resection of primary disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have received induction chemotherapy for their cancer diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who have undergone a diverting tracheostomy which is either a) traversing&#xD;
             directly through tumor, b) has been placed for true airway insufficiency. Patients&#xD;
             with a tracheostomy placed preemptively for impending airway compromise remain&#xD;
             eligible for enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior cancer diagnosis, except appropriately treated localized epithelial skin cancer&#xD;
             or cervical cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Prior radiation therapy to the head and neck region.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women of childbearing potential (a woman of child-bearing potential is a&#xD;
             reproductively mature woman who has not undergone a hysterectomy or who has not been&#xD;
             naturally postmenopausal for at least 24 consecutive months [i.e., who has had menses&#xD;
             at any time in the preceding 24 consecutive months]) and male participants must&#xD;
             practice effective contraception (oral, injectable, or implantable hormonal&#xD;
             contraceptive; tubal ligation; intra-uterine device; barrier contraceptive with&#xD;
             spermicide; or vasectomized partner) throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients unable or unwilling to give written, informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Severe, active co-morbidity, defined as follows: a. Unstable angina and/or congestive&#xD;
             heart failure requiring hospitalization within the last 6 months. b. Transmural&#xD;
             myocardial infarction within the last 6 months. c. Acute bacterial or fungal infection&#xD;
             requiring intravenous antibiotics at the time of registration. d. Chronic Obstructive&#xD;
             Pulmonary Disease exacerbation or other respiratory illness requiring hospitalization&#xD;
             or precluding study therapy within 30 days before registration. e. Hepatic&#xD;
             insufficiency resulting in clinical jaundice and/or coagulation defects; note,&#xD;
             however, that laboratory tests for liver function and f. Acquired Immune Deficiency&#xD;
             Syndrome (AIDS) based upon current CDC definition; note, however, that HIV testing is&#xD;
             not required for entry into this protocol. Protocol-specific requirements may also&#xD;
             exclude immuno-compromised patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Exclusion #8 continued: g. History of treatment with potent immunosuppressive drugs&#xD;
             for such conditions as post organ transplant, severe rheumatoid arthritis, etc. within&#xD;
             the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects must not be pregnant or nursing due to the potential for congenital&#xD;
             abnormalities and the potential of this regimen to harm nursing infants&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Evidence of metastatic disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jack Phan, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jack Phan, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <phone>713-563-2300</phone>
    <email>jphan@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jack Phan, MD,PHD</last_name>
      <email>jphan@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>May 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 15, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 15, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 16, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of respiratory and intrathoracic organs</keyword>
  <keyword>Squamous cell carcinoma of the larynx</keyword>
  <keyword>Stereotactic hypofractionated radioablation</keyword>
  <keyword>HYDRA</keyword>
  <keyword>Questionnaires</keyword>
  <keyword>Surveys</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Squamous Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Laryngeal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Squamous Cell Carcinoma of Head and Neck</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

