<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01544036</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15591</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>K23DK074616</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01544036</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Monitoring Renal Blood Flow With Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound During Coronary Angiogram</brief_title>
  <official_title>Monitoring Renal Blood Flow Using Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound in Predicting Acute Kidney Injury After Exposure to Iodinated Contrast Agent</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Virginia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Virginia</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Contrast induced nephropathy (CN) is a common cause of acute kidney injury and is associated&#xD;
      with increased morbidity and mortality and healthcare cost. Iodinated contrast media (ICM)&#xD;
      induce kidney injury through vasoconstriction and ischemia as well as direct tubular&#xD;
      toxicity. Older subjects, individuals with preexisting kidney disease, diabetes, hypotension,&#xD;
      and those exposed to higher volumes of ICM are at higher risks for CN. Within the last&#xD;
      several years, multiple strategies have been used in clinical studies to reduce the risk of&#xD;
      CN in high risk individuals with inconsistent results. In general, it is agreed that volume&#xD;
      expansion is effective in reducing the risk. However, no study has looked at changes in renal&#xD;
      blood flow (RBF) in response to volume expansion or after exposure to ICM to investigate its&#xD;
      relationship with occurrence of CN.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this proposal, up to 125 individuals with preexisting kidney disease as evidenced by an&#xD;
      estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) between 30 - 60 ml/min/1.73 m2 and up to 25&#xD;
      individuals with normal renal function (total of up to 150 individuals) who are scheduled for&#xD;
      coronary angiography will be studied. Each individual will have serial measurements of RBF;&#xD;
      at baseline, after volume expansion with normal saline, and after exposure to ICM, using the&#xD;
      novel technique of contrast enhanced ultrasound (CEU). The investigators will investigate the&#xD;
      utility of monitoring RBF with CEU in predicting the occurrence of CN (a rise of &gt; 0.3 mg/dL&#xD;
      or 25% in baseline serum creatinine 48 hours after exposure to ICM) after adjusting for other&#xD;
      known risk factors in the group of subjects with reduced GFR. The investigators will also&#xD;
      examine the correlation between RBF changes and other urinary and serum biomarkers of kidney&#xD;
      injury in this group. Up to 25 individuals with a normal kidney function will be studied in a&#xD;
      separate part of the study in which the accuracy of CEU based measurements of RBF will be&#xD;
      compared to the RBF and blood flow velocity obtained simultaneously using a Doppler flow&#xD;
      probe placed directly inside the main renal artery during coronary angiogram procedure. Total&#xD;
      to enroll = 150.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      What will be done in this protocol? Specific to Aim 1: To investigate the correlation between&#xD;
      changes in RBF after exposure to iodinated contrast agent, measured by CEU, on occurrence of&#xD;
      acute kidney injury (AKI) in a population of subjects at risk for CN.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures: Subjects with an estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR), measured by the&#xD;
      Modification of Diet in Renal Disease (MDRD) formula, between 30 - 60 ml/min/1.73 m2 who are&#xD;
      scheduled for a coronary angiogram will be enrolled in this study. These subjects are&#xD;
      considered to be at higher risks of CN. It is important to clarify that all subjects are&#xD;
      scheduled for a coronary angiography for clinical reasons before enrollment in this study.&#xD;
      Coronary angiography is not a part of interventions of this protocol. The decision regarding&#xD;
      the need for coronary angiography and the strategies for its prevention are made by the&#xD;
      subjects' healthcare providers and not the research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The details of protocol will be discussed with all interventional cardiologists and&#xD;
      permission will be obtained to discuss study details with potential subjects. Eligible&#xD;
      subjects will be identified by searching the electronic medical record of individuals who are&#xD;
      listed in the cardiac catheterization laboratory schedule for inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria. Subjects who appear to qualify for study participation based on medical record&#xD;
      review the inclusion and exclusion criteria will be approached. The details of the study&#xD;
      goals, procedures and risks will be discussed with each individual and questions will be&#xD;
      answered. The subjects will then be asked to sign the informed consent form. They will then&#xD;
      be enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since undergoing an X-ray examination or exposure to iodinated contrast media are&#xD;
      contraindicated in pregnancy, we assume all women of child bearing age having a test to rule&#xD;
      out pregnancy before enrolling in the study. If this test is not done, we will contact the&#xD;
      subject's cardiologist and arrange for it as a part of clinical care and not a research&#xD;
      related procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the time of enrollment data on subjects' age, race, gender, ethnicity, history of coronary&#xD;
      artery disease, diabetes and congestive heart failure will be collected. Subjects with a&#xD;
      history of heart failure will be asked about presence of symptoms of heart failure such as&#xD;
      shortness of breath at rest or with activities, fatigue, palpitation and dyspnea. This&#xD;
      information will be used to identify the New York Heart Association (NYHA) class of heart&#xD;
      failure which is considered a risk factor for CN. List of medications used by subjects will&#xD;
      also be recorded. Vital signs will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples for basic metabolic panel and urine samples for urinalysis will be collected&#xD;
      and sent to the University of Virginia lab. More blood and urine samples will be collected&#xD;
      for measurement of the concentrations of biomarkers of kidney injury neutrophil&#xD;
      gelatinase-associated lipocalin (NGAL), cystatin C, beta 2 microglobulin, epithelial growth&#xD;
      factor (EGF), uromodulin, osteopontin, albumin and creatinine. These samples will be sent to&#xD;
      the the O'Brien Center at the University of San Diego, California for analysis..&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline 2-dimensional kidney ultrasound images will be obtained. All study subjects will&#xD;
      undergo baseline contrast enhanced ultrasound imaging of the kidneys using Definity&#xD;
      intravenous infusion as described in details below. They will then receive intravenous&#xD;
      infusion of normal saline for prevention of CN. Please see &quot;hydration protocol&quot; below.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately before transfer to the cardiac catheterization lab and after volume expansion&#xD;
      with i.v. normal saline, CEU imaging of the kidneys using Definity will be repeated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will undergo coronary angiogram procedure as planned by their interventional&#xD;
      cardiologists. Immediately after this procedure, CEU imaging of the kidneys using Definity&#xD;
      will be repeated. Subjects will be monitored for a minimum of 30 minutes after completion of&#xD;
      Definity infusion. Blood samples for basic metabolic panel and urine samples for urinalysis&#xD;
      will be collected and sent to the UVA lab. The research study procedures for this visit will&#xD;
      end at this time. Routine cardiac catheterization lab procedures will be followed at this&#xD;
      time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on the volume and type of ICM will be recorded. Subjects will be discharged as&#xD;
      scheduled by the cardiology team. One to three days (24 - 72 hours) later the subjects will&#xD;
      return for a follow up visit. During the follow up visit, questions will be asked to assess&#xD;
      for potential adverse events. Vital signs will be obtained (blood pressure and heart rate).&#xD;
      Blood samples for basic metabolic panel and urine samples for urinalysis will be collected&#xD;
      and sent to the UVA lab. More blood and urine samples will be collected for measurement of&#xD;
      the concentrations of biomarkers of kidney injury NGAL, cystatin C, beta 2 microglobulin,&#xD;
      EGF, uromodulin, osteopontin, albumin and creatinine. These samples will be sent to the&#xD;
      O'Brien Center at the University of San Diego in California.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The outcome of the study, AKI, will be defined as a rise of greater than 0.3 mg/dL or 25% in&#xD;
      the baseline serum creatinine concentration 48 hours after exposure to ICM.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 2: To validate the RBF data obtained by CEU by comparing it to measurements&#xD;
      obtained by a Doppler ultrasound probe placed inside the main renal artery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures: Up to 25 subjects with normal renal functions who are scheduled for a coronary&#xD;
      angiography will be studied in this part of the proposed study. Blood samples for basic&#xD;
      metabolic panel and urine samples for urinalysis will be collected and sent to the UVA lab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Immediately before undergoing coronary angiography, each subject will undergo CEU study using&#xD;
      Definity to measure baseline RBF. Femoral or radial access has already been obtained to&#xD;
      perform the coronary angiogram. A guide catheter is used to selectively engage the renal&#xD;
      artery and 5 cc of contrast will be injected to perform renal angiography. If the renal&#xD;
      artery appears angiographically normal and is without evidence of any degree of&#xD;
      atherosclerotic renal artery stenosis, then a Doppler flow wire (0.014&quot;) will be advanced&#xD;
      into the main renal artery. If the patient is not already systemically anticoagulated for the&#xD;
      coronary angiogram or coronary intervention, then heparin is administered (50 U/kg) to&#xD;
      prevent clotting on the Doppler wire. Proper positioning of the Doppler wire will be&#xD;
      confirmed by injecting 1-2 cc of contrast. Velocity of the blood flow within the main renal&#xD;
      artery will be measured directly using this Doppler wire. After completion of these&#xD;
      measurements, coronary angiography procedures will be performed as scheduled. Measurement of&#xD;
      blood velocity in the main renal artery with the Doppler probe will be repeated before&#xD;
      removal of the arterial catheter. CEU using Definity for measurement of RBF will be repeated&#xD;
      at this point. Subjects will be monitored for a minimum of 30 minutes after completion of&#xD;
      Definity infusion and a urine sample will be obtained and sent to the UVA lab for urinalysis.&#xD;
      Blood samples for basic metabolic panel will be collected and sent to the UVA lab. The&#xD;
      changes from baseline in the velocity of blood after exposure to ICM obtained by Doppler&#xD;
      probe will be compared to the values obtained by CEU. Multiple measurements (at least three)&#xD;
      using each method will be performed at each time point and the mean of these measurements&#xD;
      will be compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound Subjects will be connected to a continuous pulse oximeter and&#xD;
      heart monitor. The Definity vial will be placed at room temperature before being used. It&#xD;
      will be activated after shaking the vial using Vialmix for 45 seconds. It will be used&#xD;
      immediately after activation. 1.3 mL of Definity will be mixed in 30 ml of preservative free&#xD;
      saline. Infusion of Definity into a peripheral vein will be started at 2 ml/min and titrated&#xD;
      for optimal image quality (not to exceed 10 ml/min at any time). After reaching steady state&#xD;
      (2 -3 minutes) baseline contrast ultrasound imaging of right kidney will be performed with&#xD;
      low mechanical index (MI) of 0.1. High MI (1.0) impulse will be used to disrupt Definity&#xD;
      microbubbles within the kidney tissue. This would result in a very brief time period during&#xD;
      which renal cortex is free of microbubbles and appears completely anechoic (time zero). As&#xD;
      continuous infusion of microbubbles continues, during the wash-in period renal tissue is&#xD;
      replenished with microbubbles. Time-intensity curve after disruption of tissue microbubbles&#xD;
      will be fitted to a rising exponential function: intensity (y) = basic intensity (BI) + A&#xD;
      [1-exp(-beta.t) using specialized software. The slope of this curve or beta is related to the&#xD;
      velocity of microbubbles (or blood) that enter the tissue and the plateau of the curve or A&#xD;
      is related to the relative blood volume within the tissue. Since blood flow is the movement&#xD;
      of a certain volume of blood at a certain speed, the product of the two (A.beta) would&#xD;
      represent tissue blood flow. After disruption of microbubbles within the kidney tissue with a&#xD;
      high MI pulse, continuous imaging of the kidney with low MI (0.1) will continue for about 15-&#xD;
      30 seconds to generate the time-intensity graph. The high MI pulse and replenishment sequence&#xD;
      will be repeated two more times. An average of the three parameters obtained at each time&#xD;
      period will be used for the final analysis. Infusion of Definity will stop at this point. A&#xD;
      urine sample will be collected for urinalysis after 30 minutes of stopping Definity to assess&#xD;
      for potential renal related adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hydration Protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      0.9% sodium chloride (normal saline) solution will be infused intravenously at a rate of 3&#xD;
      mL/kg/hr for one hour. This will be followed by normal saline given at a rate of 1 ml/kg/hr&#xD;
      for the remainder of the time before and also during and at least for one hour after coronary&#xD;
      angiogram. Patients with heart failure and documented ejection fraction of &lt; 30% will receive&#xD;
      normal saline infusion at a reduced rate of 1.5 ml/kg/hr for the 1st hour followed by 0.5&#xD;
      mL/kg/hr after that for the same time periods as for other subjects. At any point, if a&#xD;
      subject experiences shortness of breath, oxygen saturation will be measured and intravenous&#xD;
      hydration protocol will be stopped.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2012</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute Kidney Injury</measure>
    <time_frame>24 - 72 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between changes in renal blood flow measured by contrast ultrasound and occurrence of AKI.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in novel biomarkers of AKI</measure>
    <time_frame>24 - 72 hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Contrast Induced Acute Kidney Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Renal blood flow before and after exposure to iodinated contrast agent (perflutren) also known as Definity will be measured using contrast enhanced ultrasound (CEUS).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>perflutren</intervention_name>
    <description>Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound is performed during continuous intravenous infusion of Definity (drug) to assess changes in renal blood flow during the study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Contrast Enhanced Ultrasound</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Definity</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion For specific aim 1 - Subjects with reduced kidney function&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult (&gt;18 years of age) men and women&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. All races and ethnicities&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Chronic kidney disease stage 3 with an estimated GFR by MDRD formula between 30 - 59&#xD;
             ml/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Being scheduled for a coronary angiography study as part of their clinical care&#xD;
&#xD;
        For specific aim 2 - Subjects with normal kidney function&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Adult (&gt;18 years of age) men and women&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. All races and ethnicities&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Being scheduled for a coronary angiography study&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Estimated GFR greater than or equal to 60 ml/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion For specific aim 1 - Subjects with reduced kidney function&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Estimated GFR greater than 60 or below 30 ml/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of kidney transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known history of a right to left intracardiac shunt&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of allergies to Definity®&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of Pulmonary Hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
        For specific aim 2 - Subjects with normal kidney function&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Estimated GFR less than 60 ml/min/1.73 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of kidney transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of a right to left intracardiac shunt&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy or lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of allergies to Definity®&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of recent major bleeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of allergy to heparin or heparin-induced thrombocytopenia&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of renal artery stenosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Evidence of renal artery stenosis during the placement of Doppler wire in the renal&#xD;
             artery&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of Pulmonary Hypertension&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kambiz Kalantari, MD, MS</last_name>
    <phone>434-924-5125</phone>
    <email>kk6c@virginia.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kambiz Kalantari, MD</last_name>
      <phone>434-924-5820</phone>
      <email>kk6c@virginia.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Sharon L Johnson, CRC</last_name>
      <phone>434-924-5802</phone>
      <email>slj3b@virginia.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kambiz Kalantari, MD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michael Ragosta, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia Health System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 27, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 2, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 5, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 18, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 18, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 19, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>AKI</keyword>
  <keyword>contrast nephropathy</keyword>
  <keyword>renal blood flow</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

