<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01549132</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EKHT RETINAL RESEARCH UNIT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01549132</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Retinal Oximtery Following Treatment for Diabetic Maculopathy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Non-invasive Retinal Oximetry Using Oxymap in Patients With Diabetic Maculopathy Receiving Laser/Intravitreal Anti-VEGF Therapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>East Kent Hospitals University NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>East Kent Hospitals University NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators believe that oxygen saturation measurements in the retina may provide more&#xD;
      information on how well the retina is working and may detect problems in the retina earlier&#xD;
      than the fundus fluorescein angiography (FFA). This may be useful to an ophthalmologist so&#xD;
      that they may identify abnormal areas of the retina and commence or change the treatment so&#xD;
      that they may prevent irreversible blindness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most patients with clinically significant macular oedema and/or ischaemic diabetic&#xD;
      retinopathy could have either laser or Intravitreal Anti-VEGF injection treatment provided&#xD;
      they are counseled about the risks. It is known the Anti-VEGF injections reduce oedema and it&#xD;
      is believed that laser treatment of the retina in this condition improves the oxygen supply&#xD;
      to the retina and sometimes reverses the damage. It will be useful to take pictures of these&#xD;
      treated eyes using the Oxymap spectral retinal camera(s) to see whether the investigators can&#xD;
      detect a change in the oxygen saturation in the retina before and after treatment using our&#xD;
      oxygen saturation methods.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      WHAT IS SPECTRAL IMAGING?&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a way of studying in detail an area that is being imaged. This can be done because&#xD;
      each picture of the same area is taken using different colours of light (wavelength).&#xD;
      Different materials in the picture will absorb and reflect the different wavelengths of light&#xD;
      from a hyperspectral camera differently. It is then possible to look at each point in the&#xD;
      picture and work out what is in the picture. This has been used in satellites and aeroplanes&#xD;
      to identify what is on the ground. For example, it can distinguish the different types of&#xD;
      trees on the ground based on the different way they absorb and reflect different wavelengths&#xD;
      of light.&#xD;
&#xD;
      USING SPECTRAL IMAGING IN MEDICINE. Spectral imaging was found to have uses in medicine&#xD;
      because of its ability to distinguish one thing from another. A lot of Spectral imaging&#xD;
      research has been done to measure the amount of oxygen in the blood. This is because oxygen&#xD;
      is important to all living cells in the human body - without it cells would die or stop&#xD;
      working. Oxygen is carried to living cells by blood in blood vessels known as arteries and&#xD;
      the left over is carried away by veins. Most of the oxygen in the blood is transported by&#xD;
      cells in the blood containing a chemical called haemoglobin. There are two main forms of&#xD;
      haemoglobin called oxyhaemoglobin (haemoglobin binds to oxygen) and deoxyhaemoglobin&#xD;
      (haemoglobin that is not bound to oxygen). The proportion of oxyhaemoglobin to the total&#xD;
      amount of haemoglobin (both oxyhaemoglobin and deoxyhaemoglobin) is called the oxygen&#xD;
      saturation and is presented as a percentage. The normal saturation in the artery is about 97%&#xD;
      because it contains more oxyhaemoglobin and in the vein it is about 75% because it contains&#xD;
      less oxyhaemoglobin. Importantly oxyhaemoglobin (HbO2) and deoxyhaemoglobin (Hb) have&#xD;
      different spectral characteristics - i.e they absorb light differently at various wavelengths&#xD;
      of light. This has been extensively documented in various publications using samples of&#xD;
      blood. This property is the basis of pulse oximetry which is the measurement of the oxygen&#xD;
      saturation (OS) in the finger tip using a saturation probe which is commonly used in the&#xD;
      hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The different spectral characteristics of Hb and HbO2 can also be used in spectral imaging to&#xD;
      calculate the amount of each in the blood to perform oxygen saturation measurements in&#xD;
      certain parts of the body. This has previously been used to study the oxygen supply in the&#xD;
      skin and also to look at the oxygen supply in patients with diabetes which is a condition&#xD;
      that is caused by a lack of a hormone called insulin causing high amount of sugar in the&#xD;
      blood resulting in damage to the blood vessels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Spectral imaging has only recently started to be used in imaging the eye. The main emphasis&#xD;
      of Spectral imaging in ophthalmology has been on measuring the oxygen saturations in the&#xD;
      retina (the layer at the back of the eye that allows us to see). This is called retinal&#xD;
      oximetry. In essence, the principles of retinal oximetry are similar to that of pulse&#xD;
      oximetry, i.e using the different spectral characteristics of Hb and HbO2 to calculate the&#xD;
      oxygen saturation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In diabetic retinopathy, the only way the investigators can study the blood supply is by&#xD;
      performing a Fundus Fluorescein Angiogram (FFA). This is an invasive test which involves the&#xD;
      injection of a dye into the arm, this dye is transported by blood to the eye and pictures of&#xD;
      the blood vessels are taken with the dye in it. Also, importantly, there are side effects&#xD;
      (sometimes life-threatening) to injecting this dye into the arm. If there is a problem with&#xD;
      the blood supply in the retina then the dye will not fill up in the blood vessel and is seen&#xD;
      in the pictures as a black area. The FFA provides information on the blood supply but not&#xD;
      directly on the amount of oxygen in it. Loss of sight from diabetic retinopathy and&#xD;
      age-related macular degeneration is believed to be caused by a reduction in the amount oxygen&#xD;
      being supplied to the retina by the blood vessels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators believe that oxygen saturation measurements in the retina using spectral&#xD;
      imaging could be a more useful test for an ophthalmologist because it may provide more&#xD;
      information on how well the retina is working and may detect problems in the retina earlier&#xD;
      than the FFA. This may be useful to an ophthalmologist so that they may identify abnormal&#xD;
      areas of the retina and commence or change the treatment so that they may prevent&#xD;
      irreversible blindness.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>April 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">45</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetic Maculopathy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        • Patients will be selected from the Ophthalmology clinics with all sites at East Kent&#xD;
        Hospitals University Foundation NHS Trust. These patients will be selected non-randomly by&#xD;
        the ophthalmology clinician involved in their care based whether their clinical diagnosis&#xD;
        fulfils the inclusion criteria. The ophthalmologists who are seeing patients in the&#xD;
        ophthalmology clinics will identify the patients fulfilling the inclusion criteria for this&#xD;
        study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetic Retinopathy affecting the central retina (designated maculopathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No contraindications to pupil dilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ocular media sufficiently clear to enable retinal imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pupils which can be dilated (i.e not using miotic medication)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to participate with the research study and formal consent obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Narrow drainage angles or any other contraindication to being dilated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dense cataracts or other ocular media opacities inhibiting a good view of the retina&#xD;
             on fundoscopy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>NISHAL PATEL, MD FRCOPHTH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CONSULTANT OPHTHALMOLOGIST</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>NISHAL PATEL, MD FRCOPHTH</last_name>
    <phone>PATEL</phone>
    <email>nishal.patel@ekht.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>ART ATIONU</last_name>
    <email>ART.ATIONU@ekht.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 6, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 8, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 9, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 8, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 8, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">March 9, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>East Kent Hospitals University NHS Foundation Trust</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>NISHAL PATEL</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Consultant Ophthalmologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Clinically significant macular oedema</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinal Oximetry</keyword>
  <keyword>Spectral imaging</keyword>
  <keyword>Retinal Laser therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Intravitreal Anti-VEGF Injection therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

