<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01192646</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HBLSS TRIAL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01192646</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Home Based Life Saving Skills Training in a Rural Area in Tanzania</brief_title>
  <acronym>HBLSS</acronym>
  <official_title>IMPACT OF HOME BASED LIFE SAVING SKILLS TRAINING IN A RURAL AREA IN TANZANIA IN FACILITY DELIVERY, PREPARATION OF BIRTH PLANS AND COST-EFFECTIVENESS. AN INTERVENTION CLUSTER RANDOMIZED TRIAL.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Uppsala University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Swedish International Development Cooperation Agency (SIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      The maternal mortality ratio in Tanzania has been persistently high for ten years with no&#xD;
      signs of the ratio going down.The Tanzania Demographic and Health Survey (TDHS) of 1999 and&#xD;
      2005 estimate the maternal mortality ratio to be 528 and 578 per 100,000 live births&#xD;
      respectively (TDHS 1999, TDHS 2004/05).The major direct causes include obstetric haemorrhage,&#xD;
      obstructed labour, pregnancy induced hypertension, sepsis and abortion complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Most deliveries (53%) in Tanzania occur outside the health facilities. Of these 53% of births&#xD;
      that occur outside the health facilities 31% are attended by relatives, 19% by traditional&#xD;
      births attendants (TBA) while 3% have no assistance at all. Though, the proportional of&#xD;
      mothers delivering in health facilities (47%) and receiving skilled attendance at birth (46%)&#xD;
      is low but more than 94 percent of women attend antenatal care (ANC) in health facilities at&#xD;
      least once. This indicates that there are factors that impede these women delivering in the&#xD;
      health facilities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Low awareness of obstetric danger signs may be one of the contributing factors for delay to&#xD;
      decide to seek care when a complication occur thus contributing the first phase of delay.&#xD;
      Studies in Tanzania show that most women are not aware of danger signs of obstetric&#xD;
      complications during pregnancy, delivery and after delivery. A study conducted in Mtwara&#xD;
      rural to assess the use and determinants of skilled attendants at delivery showed that&#xD;
      proportional of women delivered with skilled care increases with increasing knowledge of&#xD;
      pregnancy danger signs, but it also showed that few women have knowledge of pregnancy danger&#xD;
      signs&#xD;
&#xD;
      An increasing body of evidence supports the importance of community participation in maternal&#xD;
      and infant health programs for establishing ownership, identifying problems effectively,&#xD;
      achieving equity and helping to institutionalize health programs. To mount an effective&#xD;
      maternal health effort aimed at reducing maternal and infant mortality, multiple levels of&#xD;
      program and policies need to be in place and functioning. In addition, linkages, from the&#xD;
      communities, local dispensaries and health centres to first referral hospitals that are&#xD;
      adequately equipped, need to be developed and sustained&#xD;
&#xD;
      A home based life saving skills (HBLSS) is a strategy that intends to educate pregnant women&#xD;
      and their primary family caregivers and home birth attendants on critical knowledge and&#xD;
      skills to keep a pregnant woman healthy, to recognize life-threatening maternal and newborn&#xD;
      complications and promote the adoption of health care and health-seeking behaviours at the&#xD;
      individual and community levels. The aim of this strategy is to prevent maternal and neonatal&#xD;
      morbidity and mortality through creating awareness on women's birth preparedness and access&#xD;
      to emergency obstetric care services&#xD;
&#xD;
      RESEARCH QUESTIONS&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Can HBLSS increase women empowerment and male involvement in the decisions relating to&#xD;
           access of emergency obstetric and newborn cares?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Can the HBLSS increase hospital deliveries, increase awareness of obstetric and neonatal&#xD;
           danger signs, birth preparedness and emergency readiness in a rural community?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      Broad Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To investigate social-cultural, community and traditional practices that impact on&#xD;
           women's birth preparedness and access and utilization of emergency obstetric care&#xD;
           services in rural district.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess the impact of home based life saving skills (HBLSS) on hospital delivery&#xD;
           awareness of obstetric and neonatal danger signs, birth preparedness&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To explore customs, taboos and practices including herbal remedies during pregnancy and&#xD;
           labour that influence birth preparedness and utilization of emergency obstetric care&#xD;
           services.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess perception, attitude and health seeking behaviour when a complication occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To determine the effect of HBLSS educational programme on hospital delivery, birth&#xD;
           preparedness, emergency readiness and utilization of emergency obstetric care services&#xD;
           among women in Rufiji district.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To assess the impact of HBLSS educational programme on male awareness and involvement in&#xD;
           assisting women on birth preparedness and access to emergency obstetric care services.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. To determine the cost-effectiveness of HBLSS educational programme&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Cluster Randomized Trial&#xD;
&#xD;
      28 clusters will be randomly selected, 14 clusters will receive HBLSS training and the other&#xD;
      14 clusters will not receive HBLSS training.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      STATEMENT OF THE PROBLEM AND RATIONALE&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite several interventions to address the unacceptably high rates of maternal and neonatal&#xD;
      mortality, the problem still persists. Maternal Mortality ratio in Tanzania has been&#xD;
      persistently high without signs of declining. Currently it stands between 578 and 950 per&#xD;
      100,000 live births (TDHS 2005, WHO 2007). The neonatal mortality rate as well in the country&#xD;
      is 32 per 1,000 live births (TDHS 2005).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Almost 94% of pregnant women attend antenatal care in health facilities at least once, but&#xD;
      only 47% deliver in these facilities and skilled attendance at birth is 46% (TDHS 2005,&#xD;
      Mpembeni et al 2007). Births that occur outside the health facilities are assisted by&#xD;
      relatives, TBA and some women do not have assistance at all (Kayombo 1995, Kayombo 2008,&#xD;
      Comonsky 1983 ). Studies in Tanzania have shown that home birth with unskilled attendants is&#xD;
      often the norm (TDHS 1999, TDHS 2005, Mpembeni 2007). This indicates that there are factors&#xD;
      that impede these women delivering in the health facilities. Among the factors may include&#xD;
      socio-cultural, economic activities, family, community factors. If these factors are&#xD;
      compounded by low awareness of danger signs of obstetric complication then these women and&#xD;
      neonates are more at risk of death when a complication occurs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous studies in Rufiji district showed that community has low acceptance of facility&#xD;
      delivery and referral to hospitals when advised (Pembe 2008b). Furthermore, like in other&#xD;
      parts of Tanzania women have low knowledge of danger signs of complications during pregnancy,&#xD;
      delivery and after delivery despite attending antenatal care (Mpembeni 2007, Pembe 2008a). In&#xD;
      another study on the use of essential obstetric care facilities, a quarter (60/232) of women&#xD;
      with complications were referred to the hospital level but less than half (48%) arrived at&#xD;
      their referral points. Out of 60 referred cases 31 (52%) did not arrive in any of the two&#xD;
      hospitals of the district. Nineteen were traced for their outcome and it was found that three&#xD;
      died on the way to the hospital (Urassa 2005). Consequently, there is a great need for an&#xD;
      innovative and empowering community-based intervention whose characteristics address this&#xD;
      problem.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODOLOGY&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a cluster randomized trial. The cluster has been chosen because the intervention&#xD;
      is done in the community in groups rather than individuals. The unit of randomization will be&#xD;
      the health care facility. Randomly selected facility clusters will receive HBLSS in addition&#xD;
      to the antenatal care received and the in the control group only routine ANC will be done.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study area&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will be conducted in Rufiji district. Rufiji district is one of the six districts&#xD;
      of the Coastal Region in Tanzania. It is situated about 300 km in Southern of the capital&#xD;
      city Dar es Salaam. The district is more rural with few suburban areas. The district has an&#xD;
      estimated population of 203,102 according to census results 2002 with a male population being&#xD;
      98,398 and female 104,704 (BoS 2002). Geographically the Rufiji river divides the district&#xD;
      into two halves Northern and Southern parts with the formation of flood plain, coastal-delta,&#xD;
      and plateau zones. Since inauguration of the &quot;Mkapa&quot; bridge in 2003 across the Rufiji river,&#xD;
      transport between northern and the southern part of the district as well as to the southern&#xD;
      regions has improved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Only the main road from Dar es Salaam to the Southern regions is passable in all seasons,&#xD;
      while other roads in the district are difficult to pass especially during the rainy season.&#xD;
      The limited transport system makes people dependent more on the health services available&#xD;
      within the district.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to the administrative structure in Tanzania, the district is divided into five&#xD;
      divisions, which are further divided into 19 wards. There are eight wards in the flood plain,&#xD;
      four in the coastal-delta, and seven in the plateau zone. There are 128 villages in the&#xD;
      district. Each village has 2 to 4 hamlets (Vitongoji) under the leadership of a hamlet&#xD;
      chairperson. The average population in a village is 1600, therefore with an annual population&#xD;
      growth rate of 4% it is estimated that 64 women will become pregnant in a year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The district has two hospitals, Utete a government district hospital and Mchukwi a private&#xD;
      not for profit hospital owned by the Pentecostal church. Both hospitals have doctors, nurses&#xD;
      and midwives providing medical care and surgical care including comprehensive emergency&#xD;
      obstetric care. There are four rural health centres (RHCs) and 52 dispensaries two of which&#xD;
      are private not for profit and another two are private for profit. Antenatal care (ANC) is&#xD;
      provided in hospitals, all RHCs and all dispensaries. The normal practice is for the pregnant&#xD;
      woman to register for antenatal care at the nearest health facility. Dispensaries and RHCs&#xD;
      have guidelines for referring women with risks or complications to hospitals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants Randomly selected facility clusters will receive HBLSS in addition to the&#xD;
      antenatal care received or only routine antenatal care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The unit of randomization is health facility. 28 health facilities will be selected and&#xD;
      randomised into two groups each with 14 facilities. One group will be provided with HBLSS&#xD;
      educational programme through their VHW while another group will be monitored for the purpose&#xD;
      of comparison&#xD;
&#xD;
      Key participants will be pregnant women together with their immediate relatives such as aunt&#xD;
      and the husband. They will receive the HBLSS training. Village health workers who will be&#xD;
      trained by HBLSS trainers, will be used to provide the training in the community Intervention&#xD;
      The selected clusters will receive HBLSS training. This training is being conducted in some&#xD;
      other parts of Tanzania.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HBLSS procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HBLSS was conceived as a component of the Community Partnership for Safe Motherhood&#xD;
      Model. It targets a homebirth team consisting of all of those who can be expected to be&#xD;
      present at a birth, namely, the pregnant woman, her family caregivers, and the birth&#xD;
      attendant. The education, motivation, cohesion and mobilization of pregnant women, families&#xD;
      and communities are seen necessary to improve pregnancy outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HBLSS training was designed by the American College of Nurse-midwives has been successfully&#xD;
      implemented in other developing countries including India and Ethiopia (Sibley et al 2001).&#xD;
      In Tanzania it was adopted and adapted for use and was launched by Honourable Mohamed Shein&#xD;
      the Vice President of the United Republic of Tanzania on the 25th of March 2007 in Morogoro.&#xD;
      The White Ribbon Alliance (WRA) adapted the HBLLS training curriculum taking into&#xD;
      consideration the major causes of maternal mortality in the region and the Tanzanian context,&#xD;
      and translated it into Swahili. The training and materials have been field tested and the&#xD;
      first Training of trainers (TOTs) and the training of community was done in Manyara region.&#xD;
      Other trainings are ongoing. Recently WRA conducted training in Rukwa rural district that&#xD;
      involved district health providers, 20 primary health care providers and 500 community&#xD;
      members from 20 villages. HIV awareness and prevention of mother-to-child HIV transmission&#xD;
      are integrated into the training manual. The strategy is to build on existing practices and&#xD;
      to negotiate acceptable and feasible safe practices with the homebirth team members to&#xD;
      develop both a consensus on the appropriate action and a capacity to take that action when&#xD;
      needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HBLSS training manual has a flexible, modular design comprised of 12 preventive and life&#xD;
      saving skill topics. Drawing on best practices and current research, to maximize effective&#xD;
      communication and learning among community members who may be unable to read, essential&#xD;
      content is reinforced through pictorial Take Action Cards that are taken home for reference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trainer uses various teaching methods to maximize effective communication and learning&#xD;
      among participants including:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Stories and case histories&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Discussion and demonstrations&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Identification of complications using picture cards&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Take Action Cards.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  There will be one Take Action Card for each topic or problem. These cards will be used&#xD;
           during training and a booklet made of these cards will be left at woman's home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HBLSS sensitization and training&#xD;
&#xD;
      The HBLSS training in the district will start with ten (10) TOTs training at the district&#xD;
      level. These will train the research assistants (RAs) preferably community health worker&#xD;
      (VHW) or health assistants, one from each selected village. The RAs will train the community&#xD;
      on HBLSS. All pregnant mothers will be identified by the RA. The RA will make appointment to&#xD;
      the family according to their convenience. The RA will visit the family every month to&#xD;
      discuss the danger signs, decision making, and birth preparedness and emergency readiness&#xD;
      with the family. The RA will keep all the records of training each family, the number visits&#xD;
      made and whether the woman attended antenatal care or develop any complication. When the&#xD;
      woman delivers the RA will record the place of delivery and whether there was any referral&#xD;
      given.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: Baseline study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Since the study will employ cluster-sampling, technique, a design effect was taken into&#xD;
      consideration when calculating the sample size. We used a design effect of 2 a value which&#xD;
      have been reported in the most recent Demographic and Health Surveys as a design effect of&#xD;
      the variable &quot;Mothers received medical assistance at delivery&quot; in the Coastal Zone where this&#xD;
      study will be conducted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore using the above formula and taking into consideration the design effect, a minimum&#xD;
      of 766 women is required for the baseline survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size for Cluster Randomized control trial&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size for the intervention study which is a cluster randomized trial was calculated&#xD;
      using the Acluster programme methods described by Donner and Klar, 2000. We estimated the&#xD;
      mean cluster size of 100 pregnant women, an intracluster correlation coefficient of 0.05. We&#xD;
      further assume that a power of 90% to detect an increase of 15% in the rate of hospital&#xD;
      delivery. In this case we will need 28 clusters, 14 for intervention group and 14 as control.&#xD;
      We will need to have 1347 women in intervention group and 1347 in the control group. A 20% in&#xD;
      increase will be done so as to offset the loss of follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sequence generation&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be done by including all women who book for antenatal care during the time of the&#xD;
      study, both in the control and intervention clusters.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Allocation concealment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Four health centers will be chosen randomly for intervention and control (2 each). Then&#xD;
      random selection of 24 dispensaries will be done by using random number tables. Allocation to&#xD;
      intervention and control will be done randomly by lottery method.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis will be done taking consideration on clustering. Primary analysis will be undertaken&#xD;
      as intention to treat at cluster level and individual level. Pearson Chi-square test will&#xD;
      used to compare variables. The result will be deemed significant if p value &lt; 0.05. Multiple&#xD;
      logistical regression methods will also be used to see the predictor variables on the use of&#xD;
      health facility for delivery. This will be done for both cluster and at individual level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA COLLECTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline information&#xD;
&#xD;
      The provision of emergency obstetric care services using United Nations (UN) signal functions&#xD;
      and Safe motherhood Initiative (SMI) assessment tool in all the facilities will be done.&#xD;
      Health workers will be interviewed to determine their capabilities to undertake emergency&#xD;
      obstetric care in their facilities. Birth preparedness, emergency readiness including&#xD;
      awareness of danger signs of obstetric and neonatal complications among women, their spouses,&#xD;
      head of the households and other family members will be done. Information on male involvement&#xD;
      will also be sought. A structured questionnaire will be used to gather the information.&#xD;
      Information relating to traditionally preferred and/or recommended discouraged foods during&#xD;
      pregnancy will also be collected. In addition, information on other traditional practices&#xD;
      including rituals for the first or the last born child and or twins will be documented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative interviews including focus group discussions (FGDs) and in-depth interviews will&#xD;
      be conducted. FGDs will be done in the community on perceptions, attitudes, male involvement&#xD;
      and health seeking behaviour on the use of emergency obstetric care services. In-depth&#xD;
      interview will be conducted with key informants such as religious leaders and other opinion&#xD;
      people in the community to compliment the data on perceptions of place of delivery and of&#xD;
      obstetric and neonatal danger signs. In-depth interviews will also be conducted to health&#xD;
      care providers to supplements the documentation with focus on factors which make many women&#xD;
      deliver outside health facilities and efforts made to make them deliver in health facilities.&#xD;
      In addition review reports of ward health committee to see if maternal and newborn features&#xD;
      out in the report as a sign of awareness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on traditional pregnancy management practices, including use of herbal plants and&#xD;
      their preparation in facilitating child delivery and their perceived safety will be&#xD;
      collected. Plants used will be collected and botanic identification will be done by a&#xD;
      botanist for scientific names and for literature review for their safety. In addition where&#xD;
      possible concoctions used for facilitating child delivery and for managing pregnancy and&#xD;
      infant health problems will be collected for laboratory screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information from the qualitative studies will also help in preparing instruments for&#xD;
      quantitative studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Topic guides will be used during the FGDs and in-depth interviews. We will also conduct an&#xD;
      economic valuation of the training so as to obtain a cost-effectiveness analysis of this type&#xD;
      of educational program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA PROCESSING AND ANALYSIS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      When data collection will be completed, serial numbers will be assigned to the questionnaires&#xD;
      to facilitate identification of the different patient data. Thereafter responses for the&#xD;
      open-ended questions will be reviewed, categorized and coded for the computer data entry.&#xD;
      Data entry into the computer will be done by the principal investigator with the help of an&#xD;
      assistant using the statistical package for social sciences (SPSS) and EPI INFO6 computer&#xD;
      programmes. Data cleaning will be done. Chi- squared test will be used to determine&#xD;
      association between variables. Where the chi-square test will not be valid the Yates&#xD;
      corrected Chi square test will be used. The results will be deemed significant if p-value&#xD;
      will be less than 0.05.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Qualitative data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The audio-taped information will be transcribed and then back translated from Swahili to&#xD;
      English to Swahili. A qualitative content analysis method as described by Graneheim and&#xD;
      Lundman will be used for analysis (Graneheim 2004). All texts will be read several times to&#xD;
      identify meaning units, that is, statements that relate to the topic of analysis. The meaning&#xD;
      units will then be condensed. The condensed meaning units will be coded then the codes will&#xD;
      be categorized according to similarities and differences in content.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>August 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of women delivering in a health facility</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of community members pregnant mothers involved in birth preparedness and complication readiness</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of men involved in birth preparedness and assisting in women seeking care for complications.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of pregnant women with birth plans</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of pregnant women using herbal remedies during pregnancy and labour</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The cost-effectiveness of HBLSS training</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Home based life saving skills training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Home based life saving skills will done in one the study group and in the control group no training will be done</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NO HBLSS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>No intervention will be given to the control clusters</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HBLSS</intervention_name>
    <description>Home Based life saving skills training will be done in the intervention cluster while in the control group no training</description>
    <arm_group_label>Home based life saving skills training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>NO HBLSS</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women in the community&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Relatives of the pregnant women including aunts, husbands and in-laws&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Furaha August, MD,M.Med</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrea Pembe, MD, M.Med, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Siriel Massawe, MD, M.Med, M.Ed, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elisabeth Darj, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Upssala University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Furaha August, MD, M.Med</last_name>
    <phone>255754304250</phone>
    <email>drfuraha@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Andrea Pembe, MD,M.Med, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>255754262483</phone>
    <email>drfuraha@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rufiji District</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rufiji</city>
        <state>Pwani Region</state>
        <zip>00000</zip>
        <country>Tanzania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Tanzania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sibley L, Buffington ST, Beck D, Armbruster D. Home based life saving skills: promoting safe motherhood through innovative community-based interventions. J Midwifery Womens Health. 2001 Jul-Aug;46(4):258-66.</citation>
    <PMID>11603641</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mpembeni RN, Killewo JZ, Leshabari MT, Massawe SN, Jahn A, Mushi D, Mwakipa H. Use pattern of maternal health services and determinants of skilled care during delivery in Southern Tanzania: implications for achievement of MDG-5 targets. BMC Pregnancy Childbirth. 2007 Dec 6;7:29.</citation>
    <PMID>18053268</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahluwalia I, Kouletio M, Curtis K, Schmid T. Observations from the CDC: community empowerment: CDC collaboration with the CARE Community-Based Reproductive Health Project in two districts in Tanzania. J Womens Health Gend Based Med. 1999 Oct;8(8):1015-9.</citation>
    <PMID>10565658</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahluwalia IB, Schmid T, Kouletio M, Kanenda O. An evaluation of a community-based approach to safe motherhood in northwestern Tanzania. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2003 Aug;82(2):231-40.</citation>
    <PMID>12873791</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berer M. Maternal mortality and morbidity: is pregnancy getting safer for women? Reprod Health Matters. 2007 Nov;15(30):6-16.</citation>
    <PMID>17938066</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Donner A and Klar N. Design and Analysis of Cluster Ramdomization Trial In Health Research. Arnold-Hooder Headline Group. 2000. ISBN 0 340 69153 0</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goodburn E, Campbell O. Reducing maternal mortality in the developing world: sector-wide approaches may be the key. BMJ. 2001 Apr 14;322(7291):917-20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11302911</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Graneheim UH, Lundman B. Qualitative content analysis in nursing research: concepts, procedures and measures to achieve trustworthiness. Nurse Educ Today. 2004 Feb;24(2):105-12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>14769454</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>National Bureau of Statistics (NBS) and ORC Macro. Tanzania Demographic and Health Survey 2004-5. Dar es salaam, Tanzania: National Bureau of statistics and ORC Macro. 2005</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 31, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 1, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 1, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Dr Furaha August</name_title>
    <organization>Muhimbili University of Health and Allied Sciences</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>maternal health</keyword>
  <keyword>birth preparedness</keyword>
  <keyword>cost effectiveness</keyword>
  <keyword>male involvement</keyword>
  <keyword>delivery at hospital</keyword>
  <keyword>complication readiness</keyword>
  <keyword>Health seeking behavior in pregnancy, labour and pregnancy complication</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

