<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02278250</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MS201922-0001</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>VX14-803-001</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2014-003838-86</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02278250</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>First in Human Study of M4344 in Participants With Advanced Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-Label Study of the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetic/Pharmacodynamic Profile of M4344 (Formerly VX-803) as a Single Agent and in Combination With Cytotoxic Chemotherapy in Participants With Advanced Solid Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>EMD Serono Research &amp; Development Institute, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck KGaA, Darmstadt, Germany</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>EMD Serono</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and tolerability of multiple ascending&#xD;
      doses of single-agent M4344 administered twice-weekly (BIW), twice daily (BID) or once daily&#xD;
      dose schedule in participants with advanced solid tumors. This investigation is a three part&#xD;
      study examining M4344 alone and in combination with carboplatin to determine the safety and&#xD;
      maximum tolerated dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 26, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 24, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 16, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts A, A2, A3, B1, C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Number of Participants with Treatment Emergent Adverse Events and Serious Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Part A, A2, A3, B1: From baseline until 14 days after discontinuation of study treatment (assessed up to approximately 6 years); Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5, C6: up to 30 days after discontinuation of study treatment (assessed up to approximately 6 years)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts A, A2, A3, B1, C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Number of Participants with Clinically Significant Changes in Clinical Laboratory Values (Serum Chemistry and Hematology), Vital Signs, and Electrocardiogram (ECG) Assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>Part A, A2, A3, B1: From baseline until 14 days after discontinuation of study treatment (assessed up to approximately 6 years); Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5, C6: up to 30 days after discontinuation of study treatment (assessed up to approximately 6 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with clinically significant changes in clinical laboratory values (serum chemistry and hematology), vital signs, and ECG assessments were assessed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A, A2 and A3: Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) and/or Recommended Phase 2 (RP2D) of Single-Agent M4344 Administered BIW or BID or Once Daily or Drug Holiday Schedule</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluation for dose-limiting toxicity will be during Cycle 1 (each cycle is of 21 days) for each participant</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part B1: Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) and/or Recommended Phase 2 (RP2D) of M4344 Administered in Combination with Carboplatin</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluation for dose-limiting toxicity will be during Cycle 1 (each cycle is of 21 days) for each participant</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Proportion of Participants With Objective Response according to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) Version 1.1 Assessed by the Investigator</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline until disease progression or start of new anti-cancer treatment line (approximately up to 6 years)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A: Area Under the Concentration Curve (AUC) of M4344</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 1, Day 15 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A: Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of M4344</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 1, Day 15 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A: Time to Reach Maximum Plasma Concentration (tmax) of M4344</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 1, Day 15 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A2 and A3: Area Under the Concentration Curve (AUC) of M4344 and Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 1, Day 15 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A2 and A3: Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of M4344 and Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 1, Day 15 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part A2 and A3: Time to Reach Maximum Plasma Concentration (tmax) of M4344 and Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 1, Day 15 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parts A, A2, A3 and B1: Objective Tumor Response (OR) and Disease Stabilization (SD) as Evaluated by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 2 Cycles (each cycle is of 21 days) until tumor progression (approximately up to 6 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part B1: Area Under the Concentration Curve (AUC) of M4344</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 2 up to Cycle 1, Day 9 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part B1: Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of M4344</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 2 up to Cycle 1, Day 9 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part B1: Time to Reach Maximum Plasma Concentration (tmax) of M4344</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 2 up to Cycle 1, Day 9 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Confirmed Best Overall Response (BOR) According to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST Version 1.1) as Assessed by Investigator</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, until disease progression or start of new anti-cancer treatment line (approximately up to 6 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Duration of Response Assessed From Complete Response (CR) or Partial Response (PR) According to Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) Version 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline until PD, death, or last adequate tumor assessment (approximately up to 6 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Progression Free Survival (PFS) as Evaluated by RECIST Version 1.1</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline until tumor progression (approximately up to 6 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed every 3 months for up to 1 year or more or until study closure, whichever comes first (approximately up to 6 years)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Area Under the Concentration Curve (AUC) of M4344 and Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 12, Day 1 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Maximum Observed Plasma Concentration (Cmax) of M4344 and Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 12, Day 1 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Part C1, C2, C3, C4, C5 and C6: Time to Reach Maximum Plasma Concentration (tmax) of M4344 and Metabolites</measure>
    <time_frame>Cycle 1, Day 1 up to Cycle 12, Day 1 (each cycle is of 21 days)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>10</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">98</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A: M4344 BIW</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of M4344 administered BIW as a single agent.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A2: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of M4344 administered BID or once daily as a single agent.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part A3: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of M4344 administered in a drug holiday schedule (different schedule with either 3 days once daily (QD) or BID followed by 4 days of pausing, 5 days of QD or BID followed by 2 days of pausing, 7 days of QD or BID dosing followed by 7 days of pausing or 14 days of QD or BID dosing followed by 7 days of pausing may be explored. Other dosing holiday schedules may be explored if agreed by the sponsor and Investigators).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part B1: M4344 + Carboplatin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of M4344 in combination with carboplatin.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C1: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An expanded cohort study to confirm the potential effect of M4344 in participants whose tumor carry a loss-of-function mutation in the gene ARID1A.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C2: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An expanded cohort study to confirm the potential effect of M4344 in participants whose tumor carry a loss-of-function mutation in the genes ATRX and/or DAXX.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C3: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An expanded cohort study to confirm the potential effect of M4344 in participants whose tumor carry a loss-of-function mutation in the gene ataxia telangiectasia mutated (ATM).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C4: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An expanded cohort study to confirm the potential effect of M4344 in participants whose tumor carry a loss-of-function mutation in the gene ARID1A.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C5: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An expanded cohort study to confirm the potential effect of M4344 in participants whose tumor carry a loss-of-function mutation in the genes ATRX and/or DAXX.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Part C6: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>An expanded cohort study to confirm the potential effect of M4344 in participants whose tumor carry a loss-of-function mutation in the gene ataxia telangiectasia mutated (ATM).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>M4344</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose escalation of M4344 administered as a single agent.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part A2: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part A: M4344 BIW</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part B1: M4344 + Carboplatin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part C1: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part C2: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part C3: M4344 BID or once daily</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>VX-803</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carboplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>Carboplatin will be administered in combination with escalated dose of M4344.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part B1: M4344 + Carboplatin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>M4344</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose escalation of M4344 administered in a drug holiday schedule (different schedule with either 3 days once daily (QD) or BID followed by 4 days of pausing, 5 days of QD or BID followed by 2 days of pausing, 7 days of QD or BID dosing followed by 7 days of pausing or 14 days of QD or BID dosing followed by 7 days of pausing may be explored. Other dosing holiday schedules may be explored if agreed by the sponsor and Investigators) applies to A3.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part A3: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>VX-803</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>M4344</intervention_name>
    <description>M4344 at the Recommended Phase 2 dose (RP2D) from Part A3 in expansion cohorts.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Part C4: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part C5: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Part C6: M4344 Drug holiday schedule</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>VX-803</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part A, A2 and A3: Participants with one histologically or cytologically confirmed&#xD;
             malignant advanced solid tumor, for which no standard therapy is available which may&#xD;
             convey clinical benefit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part B1: Participants with one histologically or cytologically confirmed malignant&#xD;
             advanced solid tumor, for which no standard therapy is available which may convey&#xD;
             clinical benefit and/or participants must have progressed after at least 1 prior&#xD;
             chemotherapy regimen in the metastatic setting, and for which carboplatin would be&#xD;
             considered standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part C: Participants with 1 histologically or cytologically confirmed malignant&#xD;
             advanced solid tumors for which no recommended standard therapy is available (that is,&#xD;
             participants who have exhausted all standard of care options according to National&#xD;
             Comprehensive Cancer Network [NCCN] Guidance) which may convey clinical benefit, and&#xD;
             whose tumor has at least 1 of the following biomarkers as determined by a central&#xD;
             trial assay or by an assay with appropriate regulatory status: - C1 or C4:&#xD;
             loss-of-function mutations in the gene ARID1A - C2 or C5: loss-of-function mutations&#xD;
             in the genes ATRX and/or DAXX - C3 or C6: loss-of-function mutation in the gene ataxia&#xD;
             telangiectasia mutated (ATM) - This mandatory biomarker assessment must be conducted&#xD;
             during screening on a fresh tumor biopsy (or a biopsy obtained after the end of the&#xD;
             previous treatment regimen). If this is not possible for medical reason(s), available&#xD;
             archival tumor material can be used (historical data should not be used to confirm&#xD;
             biomarker status)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease either according to RECIST criteria (Version 1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WHO performance status of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of greater than or equal to (&gt;=)12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematological and biochemical indices within acceptable ranges at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other protocol defined inclusion criteria could apply&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy, unless brief course for palliative therapy, endocrine therapy,&#xD;
             target-specific therapy, immunotherapy, or chemotherapy during the 4 weeks (6 weeks&#xD;
             for nitrosoureas and Mitomycin-C, and 4 weeks for investigational medicinal products)&#xD;
             or 4 drug half-lives before first dose of study drug, whichever is greater&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part B1: More than 6 cycles of prior therapy with carboplatin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing toxic manifestations of previous treatments. Exceptions to this are alopecia&#xD;
             or certain Grade 1 toxicities, which in the opinion of the investigator should not&#xD;
             exclude the participant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Part B1: Any known history of Grade 4 thrombocytopenia with any prior chemotherapy&#xD;
             regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brain metastases unless asymptomatic, treated, stable, and not requiring steroids for&#xD;
             at least 4 weeks before first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants who are already pregnant or lactating, or plan to become pregnant&#xD;
             within 6 months of the last dose of study drug are excluded. Female participants of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must adhere to contraception guidelines. Female participants&#xD;
             will be considered to be of nonchildbearing potential if they have undergone surgical&#xD;
             hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy or have been amenorrheic for over 2 years with&#xD;
             a screening serum follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH) level within the laboratory's&#xD;
             reference range for postmenopausal females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants with partners of childbearing potential must agree to adhere to&#xD;
             contraception guidelines. Men with pregnant or lactating partners or partners who plan&#xD;
             to become pregnant during the study or within 6 months of the last dose of study drug&#xD;
             are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery less than or equal to (&lt;=) 4 weeks before first dose of study drug or&#xD;
             incomplete recovery from a prior major surgical procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious co-morbid medical conditions, including clinically-significant cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other protocol defined exclusion criteria could apply&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Responsible</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>EMD Serono Research &amp; Development Institute, Inc., a subsidiary of Merck KGaA, Darmstadt, Germany</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Michigan Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ann Arbor</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48109-5901</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington University in St. Louis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Louis</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>63110</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rutgers Cancer Institute of New Jersey</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Brunswick</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>8903</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC)</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10065</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tennessee Oncology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Froedtert &amp; The Medical College of Wisconsin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wauwatosa</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53226</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus Medisch Centrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <zip>3075 EA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinic de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>&quot;Fundacion Jimenez Diaz START Madrid. Oncology Phase I&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>START Madrid. Fundacion Jimenez Diaz- Oncologia-Fase I</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>&quot;Hospital Clinico Universitario de Valencia Servicio de Hematologia y Oncologia Medica&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sarah Cannon Research Institute UK</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <state>Greater London</state>
        <zip>W1G 6AD</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Marsden Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sutton</city>
        <state>Surrey</state>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.emdgroup.com/en/trial-details/?id=MS201922-0001</url>
    <description>Trial Awareness and Transparency website</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://medical.emdserono.com/en_US/home.html</url>
    <description>US Medical Information website, Medical Resources</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 27, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 27, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 29, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>VX14-803-001</keyword>
  <keyword>VX-803</keyword>
  <keyword>M4344</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced Solid Tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Cytotoxic Chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Carboplatin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We are committed to enhancing public health through responsible sharing of clinical trial data. Following approval of a new product or a new indication for an approved product in both the US and the European Union, the study sponsor and/or its affiliated companies will share study protocols, anonymized patient data and study level data, and redacted clinical study reports with qualified scientific and medical researchers, upon request, as necessary for conducting legitimate research. Further information on how to request data can be found on our website bit.ly/IPD21</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

