<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02280837</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>262-83</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02280837</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Is Glucagon-like Peptide-1 Insufficiency a Residual Risk in Coronary Artery Disease?</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Observational Study to Examine the Relationship Between GLP-1 Insufficiency and Severity of Coronary Artery Disease in Patients Enrolled in BOREAS Registry, a Prospective Registry of Cardiovascular and Renal Diseases. : Is GLP-1 Insufficiency a Residual Risk in Coronary Artery Disease?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sapporo Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sapporo Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the investigators hypothesized that significant proportion of patients with&#xD;
      coronary artery disease (CAD) has reduced capacity of glucagon-like peptide-1 (GLP-1)&#xD;
      secretion, which is detectable as blunted response of plasma active GLP-1 level to oral&#xD;
      glucose loading and that reduced GLP-1 secretory function is associated with increased&#xD;
      severity of coronary artery stenosis but not with classic risk factors for CAD. To test this&#xD;
      hypothesis, the investigators will analyze correlation between GLP-1 secretory capacity and&#xD;
      severity of coronary artery stenosis determined by Gensini Score (GS), an established score&#xD;
      system for coronary artery stenoses. Additionally, the investigators will analyze&#xD;
      relationship between level of &quot;total&quot; GLP-1 and severity of coronary artery stenosis to&#xD;
      determine how it is different from the active GLP-1 - coronary stenosis relationship.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Recently, the investigators found that a significant proportion of subjects in a general&#xD;
      population shows attenuated secretion of active GLP-1 in response to oral glucose loading and&#xD;
      that the insufficient secretion of GLP-1 was independently associated with elevation of blood&#xD;
      pressure (BP) (Yoshihara et al. PLoS One 2013;8:e67578). In that study, it was also found&#xD;
      that the amount of GLP-1 secreted after glucose loading was not correlated with any of&#xD;
      conventional serum lipid parameters (i.e., triglyceride, LDL-cholesterol and HDL-cholesterol)&#xD;
      or plasma insulin level. These findings suggest that insufficiency of GLP-1 secretion may&#xD;
      promote atherosclerosis and formation of coronary plaques. Furthermore, lack of correlation&#xD;
      between response of active GLP-1 secretion and serum lipids or plasma insulin indicates that&#xD;
      insufficient secretion of active GLP-1 may be a hidden risk factor of atherosclerotic&#xD;
      vascular disease. Based on those results in a previous study, the investigators designed the&#xD;
      present study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present study is a single-centered (Sapporo Medical University Hospital), observational&#xD;
      study enrolling patients who will be admitted to our institute for coronary angiogram.&#xD;
      Written informed consent will be obtained from patients on admission. Patients will receive&#xD;
      demographic measurements, blood sampling for routine serum biochemistry and detailed analyses&#xD;
      of serum lipids (such as apolipoproteins, remnant-like lipoprotein particle and&#xD;
      oxidized-LDL-cholesterol) after overnight fast and oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT). In&#xD;
      OGTT, blood will be sampled for assay of glucose, insulin, active GLP-1 and total GLP-1&#xD;
      before, 30 min, 60 min, and 120 min after oral 75 g-glucose loading. Capacity of GLP-1&#xD;
      secretion will be determined as area under the curve of plasma GLP-1 level (AUC-GLP-1). All&#xD;
      study subjects will undergo coronary angiogram and severity of coronary artery stenosis will&#xD;
      be quantified by Gensini score (GS). Relationship between GS, AUC-active-GLP-1 or&#xD;
      AUC-total-GLP-1, blood pressure, serum lipid parameters, and indices of insulin resistance&#xD;
      (homeostasis model assessment as an index of insulin resistance and Matsuda-Defronzo index)&#xD;
      will be examined by use of univariate and multivariate regression analyses to determine&#xD;
      whether AUC-active-GLP-1 or AUC-total-GLP-1 is an independent determinant of coronary artery&#xD;
      stenosis. This study will be conducted as one of projects in BOREAS registry, a&#xD;
      non-interventional, multicenter registry of cardiovascular and/or renal diseases conducted by&#xD;
      our institute and affiliated hospitals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The time frame for which the outcome measures is assessed: Informed consent on Hospital day&#xD;
      1, Demographic examinations and blood and urine tests on Hospital day 1 and day 2, OGTT on&#xD;
      Hospital day 2 or day 3, Coronary angiogram and scoring coronary stenoses on Hospital day 3&#xD;
      or a later day within 14 days after admission (patients who could not undergo angiogram&#xD;
      within 14 days after admission by incidental causes will be excluded), Acquisition of data&#xD;
      necessary for analyses on Day 9-17 (Data set of each patients, including remnant-like protein&#xD;
      particle, ApoA1, ApoB, and ApoE, will be mostly completed within approximately 9-17 days&#xD;
      after admission. Samples for determination of GLP-1 will be stored at -80 C until assay).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 27, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 29, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 27, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Severity of coronary artery stenosis expressed as Gensini Score determined by coronary angiography</measure>
    <time_frame>at the time of coronary angiogram: Coronary angiogram will be performed on Hospital day 3 or a later day within 14 days after admission.</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">190</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with suspected or diagnosed coronary artery disease</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Determination of plasma GLP-1 level</intervention_name>
    <description>Determination of GLP-1 level in samples of oral glucose tolerance tests</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with suspected or diagnosed coronary artery disease</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Non-diabetic patients with suspected or diagnosed CAD who are hospitalized for coronary&#xD;
        angiogram will be enrolled in this study. The patients are expected to be similar to those&#xD;
        who have visited our institute recently; approximately 28% of patients with CAD are&#xD;
        diabetics, and one third of them are medically untreated at the time of their first visit.&#xD;
        In recent years, 500-600 patients have undergone coronary angiography per year in this&#xD;
        institute, and approximately 50% of them were without history of percutaneous coronary&#xD;
        interventions (PCI) or coronary bypass surgery. Hence, approximately 180-210 patients per&#xD;
        year will be candidates for the present project.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-diabetic patients (HbA1c &lt;6.5%) with suspected or diagnosed CAD at ages of 35-80&#xD;
             years who are hospitalized for coronary angiogram will included in this study. - No&#xD;
             change in medications (if any) for dyslipidemia within 3 month prior to admission is&#xD;
             also a criterion for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetic patients whose HbA1c is higher than 6.5% or who have received insulin or&#xD;
             hypoglycemic agents and those who need immediate pharmacological treatments after&#xD;
             admission will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of PCI also will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tetsuji Miura, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sapporo Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sapporo Medical University, School of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sapporo</city>
        <state>Hokkaido</state>
        <zip>0608556</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 26, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 31, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 2, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>GLP-1</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>February 10, 2021</submitted>
    <returned>March 2, 2021</returned>
    <submitted>March 5, 2021</submitted>
    <returned>March 31, 2021</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

