<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03637842</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>7662</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03637842</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lorcaserin for Cannabis Use Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Trial of Lorcaserin for Cannabis Use Disorder</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>New York State Psychiatric Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Drug Abuse (NIDA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>New York State Psychiatric Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to investigate the effect of lorcaserin on reductions in&#xD;
      cannabis use and multiple constructs of impulsivity in outpatient treatment-seeking&#xD;
      individuals with cannabis use disorder (CUD). Additionally, the investigators will make use&#xD;
      of the technological application of ecological momentary assessments (EMA), to collect&#xD;
      real-time data at key time intervals during the study on participants' use of cannabis and&#xD;
      other substances in addition to measuring impulsive traits through self-initiated, fixed and&#xD;
      random phone prompts. This will be a 13-week randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled&#xD;
      trial, with week 1 focused on baseline assessments of impulsivity (through EMA in vivo and at&#xD;
      study visits), weeks 2- 3 of medication lead-in, and week 4 targeting a reduced cannabis&#xD;
      use/quit day through week 13. The primary aims are to (1) Examine the effect of lorcaserin&#xD;
      compared to placebo, on reductions in cannabis use among treatment-seeking outpatients with&#xD;
      CUD, (2) Examine the effect of lorcaserin compared to placebo on behavioral and self-report&#xD;
      measures of impulsivity among individuals with CUD during the medication lead-in phase (weeks&#xD;
      2-3). The secondary aim is to examine whether reductions in impulsivity (during weeks 2-3)&#xD;
      mediates the effect of lorcaserin on cannabis use (during weeks 8-13), if the primary&#xD;
      hypotheses are supported. Finally, the investigators will explore the effect of lorcaserin&#xD;
      compared to placebo on (1) drop-out rates, (2) time to discontinuation from study, (3)&#xD;
      treatment adherence, and (4) nicotine use.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cannabis use disorder (CUD) is a major public health problem associated with significant&#xD;
      psychiatric and medical morbidity, poor performance, and legal consequences.4 4.2 million&#xD;
      people in the United States meet criteria for CUD.5 15% of all admissions for substance abuse&#xD;
      treatment were related to cannabis as the primary, presenting problem in 2014 and 86% of&#xD;
      those admissions were referred for ambulatory care.6 Despite the large number of patients&#xD;
      with CUD seeking outpatient treatment, the investigators have limited options available.&#xD;
      While evidence-based practices (EBP), and specifically psychotherapies, have been studied to&#xD;
      treat CUD and various approaches have been shown to have clinical utility,7-9 many patients&#xD;
      have difficulty achieving significant reductions in their use or sustained abstinence.10 This&#xD;
      is further complicated by patients' limited access to EBPs,11 frequent poor adherence by&#xD;
      therapists in the community to EBP interventions,12-14 and challenges in treating CUD with&#xD;
      EBPs when available in community settings.10 Finding effective medications for the treatment&#xD;
      of CUD is essential. There are no FDA approved medications for CUD. A number of&#xD;
      pharmacological treatment trials for CUD have been performed.1* While some agents have shown&#xD;
      promise,15-17 no medication strategy has emerged as clearly efficacious in producing&#xD;
      abstinence.1,18 As the changing legal landscape influences patients' goals for reductions in&#xD;
      cannabis use as compared to abstinence only, and with increasing support from the research&#xD;
      community, future studies need to identify medications that lead to reductions in cannabis&#xD;
      use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Impulsivity has been linked to the predisposition,19 severity,20 and poor treatment&#xD;
      outcomes21, 22 in cannabis users and CUD, making it a prime pharmacology target. Notably,&#xD;
      there is an entwined relationship between cannabis and impulsivity. Impulsivity as a&#xD;
      neurobehavioral trait is associated with cannabis use,and acute and chronic use of cannabis&#xD;
      has been shown to exacerbate impulsivity, with some mixed evidence likely attributable to&#xD;
      diverse constructs of impulsivity used across studies. While the investigators may not be&#xD;
      able to fully determine which came first-the impulsivity or the cannabis use, further&#xD;
      research is needed to demonstrate whether reductions across constructs of impulsivity can&#xD;
      lead to improvements in CUD, and vice versa. Over the last two decades, 5HT2C receptor&#xD;
      agonists have been shown to alter neurobiological systems of addiction and relevant drug use&#xD;
      behavior in the preclinical literature by increasing inhibitory control on mesolimibic&#xD;
      dopamine processes and resultant incentive motivation based behaviors,23 both directly and&#xD;
      indirectly, particularly with regards to their impact on reducing impulsivity.24 In 2012,&#xD;
      lorcaserin, a selective 5HT2C receptor agonist, was approved by the FDA, allowing for&#xD;
      clinical exploration of its role in the treatment of substance use disorders, including&#xD;
      CUD.25 Recently, a fully powered clinical trial of lorcaserin for tobacco smoking cessation&#xD;
      was positive.26 The primary purpose of this study is therefore to investigate the effect of&#xD;
      lorcaserin on reductions in cannabis use and multiple constructs of impulsivity in outpatient&#xD;
      treatment-seeking individuals with CUD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, the investigators will make use of the technological application of ecological&#xD;
      momentary assessments (EMA), to collect real-time data at key time intervals during the study&#xD;
      on participants' use of cannabis and other substances in addition to measuring impulsive&#xD;
      traits through self-initiated, fixed and random phone prompts. This will be a 13-week&#xD;
      randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial, with week 1 focused on baseline&#xD;
      assessments of impulsivity (through EMA in vivo and at study visits), weeks 2-3 of medication&#xD;
      lead-in, and week 4 targeting a reduced cannabis use/quit day through week 13. This &quot;proof of&#xD;
      concept&quot; study will provide Dr. Brezing with training in randomized controlled trial&#xD;
      operations, multiple constructs to measure impulsivity, utilization of technology as a&#xD;
      measurement tool, and identification of outcomes that may prove important to reductions in&#xD;
      cannabis use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (Aim 1) Examine the effect of lorcaserin compared to placebo, on reductions in cannabis use&#xD;
      among treatment-seeking outpatients with CUD, with the primary outcome measured by average&#xD;
      weekly mean episodes of any cannabis use (including edibles, vaping, and other variable&#xD;
      potency cannabinoid products) per day. (Aim 2) Examine the effect of lorcaserin compared to&#xD;
      placebo on behavioral and self-report measures of impulsivity among individuals with CUD&#xD;
      during the medication lead-in phase (weeks 2-3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Aim: If the hypotheses of the Primary Aims are supported, the investigators will&#xD;
      examine whether reductions in impulsivity (during weeks 2-3) mediates the effect of&#xD;
      lorcaserin on cannabis use (during weeks 8-13).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Aims: To explore the effect of lorcaserin compared to placebo on (1) drop-out&#xD;
      rates, (2) time to discontinuation from study, (3) treatment adherence, and (4) nicotine use.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    terminated due to lorcaserin recall&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 29, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 29, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double Blind Randomized Controlled Trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Encapsulated medication</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Who Achieved a Reduction in Cannabis Use Per Daily Quartiles</measure>
    <time_frame>13 weeks of study or participants length of participation</time_frame>
    <description>descriptive of cannabis use per day captured in daily quartiles based on self report as collected by the Time Line Follow back. The quartiles defined as follows: 12AM-6AM; 6AM-12PM; 12PM-6PM;6PM-12AM. Participants would report if they used during each of these times.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Cannabis Use Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lorcaserin XR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lorcaserin XR 20mg daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo Oral Capsule</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lorcaserin</intervention_name>
    <description>Lorcaserin XR 20mg per day</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lorcaserin XR</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Belviq</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo oral capsule</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals between the ages of 18-70&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Meets DSM-V criteria for a current cannabis use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Seeking treatment for cannabis use disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. THC-positive urine drug screen&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Capable of giving informed consent and complying with study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Has regular access to the internet by any means&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Not underweight (Defined as BMI ≥18.5)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Lifetime history of DSM-V diagnosis of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current DSM-V criteria for a psychiatric disorder supported by the MINI that in the&#xD;
             investigator's judgment is unstable, would be disrupted by the study medication, or is&#xD;
             likely to require new pharmacotherapy or psychotherapy during the study period.&#xD;
             Individuals who are currently stable on psychotropic medication for at least 3months&#xD;
             may be included if in the investigator's opinion the psychotropic medication is&#xD;
             compatible with the study medication (lorcaserin).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals who meet DSM-V criteria for any moderate to severe substance use disorder&#xD;
             other an cannabis, caffeine or nicotine use disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnancy, lactation, or failure to use adequate contraceptive method in female&#xD;
             patients who are currently engaging in sexual activity with men&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Unstable medical conditions, such as AIDS, cancer, uncontrolled hypertension,&#xD;
             uncontrolled diabetes, pulmonary hypertension or heart disease; or individuals with a&#xD;
             history of serotonin syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Legally mandated to participate in a substance use disorder treatment program&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Current or recent history of significant violent or suicidal behavior, risk for&#xD;
             suicide or homicide&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Currently meets DSM-V diagnosis for an eating disorder or is underweight (BMI &lt;18.5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Elevated liver function tests (AST and ALT &gt; 3 times the upper limit of normal) or&#xD;
             impaired renal function&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known history of allergy, intolerance, or hypersensitivity to lorcaserin&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Concurrent use of migraine medications ergotamine (Cafergot, Ergomar) or&#xD;
             dihydroergotamine (Migranal), 5HT2B receptor agonists like cabergoline, medications&#xD;
             metabolized by CYP2D6 (thioridazine, tamoxifen, metoprolol, aripiprazole, codeine,,&#xD;
             MAOIs, or St. John's Wort&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christina Brezing, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CUMC/NYSPI</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia Substance Treatment and Research Service</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10019</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 19, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 16, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>New York State Psychiatric Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christina Ann Brezing</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Psychiatrist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cannabis</keyword>
  <keyword>impulsivity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Marijuana Abuse</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 21, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/42/NCT03637842/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 21, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/42/NCT03637842/SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <pre_assignment_details>1 person who was enrolled dropped out of the study prior to randomization. 4 people were randomized in total.</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Lorcaserin XR</title>
          <description>Lorcaserin XR 20mg daily&#xD;
Lorcaserin: Lorcaserin XR 20mg per day</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>Placebo</title>
          <description>Placebo Oral Capsule&#xD;
Placebo oral capsule: Placebo</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="2"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="2"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="2"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Lorcaserin XR</title>
          <description>Lorcaserin XR 20mg daily&#xD;
Lorcaserin: Lorcaserin XR 20mg per day</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>Placebo</title>
          <description>Placebo Oral Capsule&#xD;
Placebo oral capsule: Placebo</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="2"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="2"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="4"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Mean</param>
          <dispersion>Standard Deviation</dispersion>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="24.0" spread="1.4"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="33.5" spread="16.3"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="28.8" spread="10.9"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Sex: Female, Male</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Female</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Male</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Ethnicity (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Not Hispanic or Latino</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Race (NIH/OMB)</title>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <param>Count of Participants</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <title>American Indian or Alaska Native</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Asian</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Black or African American</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="2"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>White</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>More than one race</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
                <category>
                  <title>Unknown or Not Reported</title>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B2" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="4"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Number of Participants Who Achieved a Reduction in Cannabis Use Per Daily Quartiles</title>
        <description>descriptive of cannabis use per day captured in daily quartiles based on self report as collected by the Time Line Follow back. The quartiles defined as follows: 12AM-6AM; 6AM-12PM; 12PM-6PM;6PM-12AM. Participants would report if they used during each of these times.</description>
        <time_frame>13 weeks of study or participants length of participation</time_frame>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Lorcaserin XR</title>
            <description>Lorcaserin XR 20mg daily&#xD;
Lorcaserin: Lorcaserin XR 20mg per day</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>Placebo</title>
            <description>Placebo Oral Capsule&#xD;
Placebo oral capsule: Placebo</description>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Number of Participants Who Achieved a Reduction in Cannabis Use Per Daily Quartiles</title>
          <description>descriptive of cannabis use per day captured in daily quartiles based on self report as collected by the Time Line Follow back. The quartiles defined as follows: 12AM-6AM; 6AM-12PM; 12PM-6PM;6PM-12AM. Participants would report if they used during each of these times.</description>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="2"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="2"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="O1" value="2"/>
                    <measurement group_id="O2" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>Up to 13 weeks</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Lorcaserin XR</title>
          <description>Lorcaserin XR 20mg daily&#xD;
Lorcaserin: Lorcaserin XR 20mg per day</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>Placebo</title>
          <description>Placebo Oral Capsule&#xD;
Placebo oral capsule: Placebo</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, all-cause mortality</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="2"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="2"/>
              </event>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="2"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="2"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>0</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="2"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="2"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <limitations_and_caveats>Study was prematurely terminated due to FDA recall of Lorcaserin.</limitations_and_caveats>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Christina Brezing, MD</name_or_title>
      <organization>New York State Psychiatric Institute</organization>
      <phone>6467748181</phone>
      <email>christina.brezing@nyspi.columbia.edu</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

