<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03638791</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Microbiome in OCD</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03638791</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Microbiome in Obsessive-compulsive Disorder</brief_title>
  <acronym>MIO</acronym>
  <official_title>Skin and Gut Microbiome Impact on Obsessive Compulsive Disorder (OCD) Symptoms and Treatment Effect</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Karolinska Institutet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Karolinska Institutet</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Humans live in symbiosis with microbes and their implication for health and&#xD;
      disease is evident. The importance of microbiome-gut-brain axis in psychiatric disorders is&#xD;
      an area of increasing research interest. OCD is a promising target for microbiome research as&#xD;
      Pediatric Acute-onset Neuropsychiatric Syndrome (PANS)/ Pediatric autoimmune neuropsychiatric&#xD;
      disorders associated with streptococcal infections (PANDAS) are reactions to infectious&#xD;
      agents precipitating acute onset of severe OCD symptoms. Furthermore, preliminary evidence&#xD;
      has associated probiotic treatment with alleviation of OCD symptoms. We propose the first&#xD;
      clinical study on the microbiome and its effects on OCD patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim: To analyze the gut microbiota in patients with OCD compared with healthy matched&#xD;
      controls and assess changes in microbial composition following treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measures: Differences in alpha diversity (number of observed species and Chao-1&#xD;
      estimator), beta diversity (UniFrac distances), and taxa abundance of bacterial groups (at&#xD;
      the phylum, class, order, family, and genus levels) and severity of OCD symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: Our aim is to enroll 30 OCD patients and 30 matched controls. Shotgun metagenomic&#xD;
      sequencing will be used. Sequenced data will be processed followed by non-parametric&#xD;
      statistical testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance: gut microbiome in patients with OCD beofre and after ERP treatment has never&#xD;
      been done before. The microbial composition may impact on OCD symptoms, severity, and&#xD;
      chronicity and could inform future therapeutic possibilities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Obsessive-compulsive disorder (OCD) is a highly debilitating disorder with a lifetime&#xD;
      prevalence of approximately 2% is equally distributed among men and women. OCD generally&#xD;
      starts at an early age and usually develops a chronic course if left untreated. Many patients&#xD;
      with OCD receive treatment after years of delay due to both patient and health care factors;&#xD;
      therefore, OCD affects educational achievement, ability to work and interpersonal&#xD;
      relationships. Moreover, it poses a considerable burden and distress to family caregivers&#xD;
      [1], and accounts for one of the ten most disabling mental health conditions worldwide [2].&#xD;
&#xD;
      The role of the microbial community in health and disease has been a neglected subject in&#xD;
      human research until recently, despite the fact that human microbes comprise about 1-3 % of&#xD;
      our body mass [3]. Gut microbes play important roles in nutrient metabolism, production of&#xD;
      vitamins, and prevention of pathogens from colonizing our intestine [4]. Recently, microbiota&#xD;
      in the gut has gained increasing interest due the extensive connection between the gut and&#xD;
      the brain [5]. The bidirectional communication through neural, hormonal, and immunological&#xD;
      signaling involving the central, autonomic, and enteric nervous systems forms the&#xD;
      microbiome-gut-brain axis [6]. In psychiatry, dysbioses have been reported in anorexia&#xD;
      nervosa, major depression, autism, and other major psychiatric disorders [9, 10].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Association between OCD onset and infection has long been known. PANS/PANDAS are acute-onset&#xD;
      forms of OCD associated with autoimmune reactions from pathogens such as streptococcus&#xD;
      infection [11, 12]. The connection between bacterial pathogen and immunological response,&#xD;
      which generates OCD symptoms, is further evidence for the importance of the&#xD;
      microbiome-gut-brain axis in OCD. Lately, there have been numerous hypotheses regarding the&#xD;
      importance of gut microbiome and OCD symptoms [13, 14].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims: Characterize composition and diversity of the gut microbiome in individuals with OCD&#xD;
      compared with healthy controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  We hypothesize that patients with OCD will show evidence of gut dysbiosis (imbalance)&#xD;
           marked by lower microbial diversity and specific taxonomic and gene content differences&#xD;
           compared to healthy controls. Primary outcome is α-diversity, which refers to the number&#xD;
           of species (richness) at one site, β-diversity, which refers to the differences in&#xD;
           species composition between participants, and taxonomic abundance of bacterial groups&#xD;
           (at the phylum, class, order, family, and genus levels). These measures yield&#xD;
           information about individual microbial composition at each site and homogeneity in a&#xD;
           group of people.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  We hypothesize that reduced α and β diversity in gut microbiome correlate with severity&#xD;
           of obsessive-compulsive symptoms measured by Yale-Brown Obsessive-Compulsive Scale&#xD;
           (Y-BOCS), and Obsessive-Compulsive Inventory Revised (OCI-R). We predict that greater&#xD;
           symptom severity is associated with lower diversity. A significant negative correlation&#xD;
           will be supportive evidence for the microbiome-gut-brain axis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  We hypothesize that there will be significant richer α diversity in gut microbiome&#xD;
           composition after successful psychotherapy (change in Y-BOCS score).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment: Healthy controls will be recruited through advertisement or included from&#xD;
      previous studies with their consent. Male and female patients between 18-45 years of age from&#xD;
      the OCD-clinic at Huddinge Hospital with a DSM-5 diagnosis of OCD and fear of contamination&#xD;
      will be invited to participate. Age matched controls will be recruited who have no personal&#xD;
      or family history of OCD. Exclusion criteria for all groups include history of GI tract&#xD;
      surgery (other than appendectomy or cholecystectomy); history of inflammatory bowel disease,&#xD;
      irritable bowel syndrome, celiac disease, or any other diagnosis that could explain chronic&#xD;
      or recurring bowel symptoms, antibiotic use in the past 3 months; pro-biotic use in the past&#xD;
      4 weeks; pregnantcy. Intellectual disability, autism spectrum disorder and psychosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment: All participants will meet an experienced psychiatrist for diagnostic assessments&#xD;
      including M.I.N.I. interview. Participants will be asked to complete self-assessment forms on&#xD;
      the Internet and answer questions about their dietary habits for the last three months.&#xD;
      Weight and height for body mass index (BMI) calculation will be measured. All assessment&#xD;
      forms, information from interviews and medical examination will be documented in their&#xD;
      medical record. Further information (e.g. antibiotics and previous therapies) will be&#xD;
      collected from their medical records with the participants' consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators chose the following questionnaire battery to capture all relevant outcome&#xD;
      variables (OCD-symptoms), nutrition, and stool characteristics and frequency.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Yale-Brown Obsessive Compulsive Scale (Y-BOCS): A commonly used clinical,&#xD;
           semi-structured interview assessing severity of OCD symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obsessive-Compulsive Inventory Revised (OCI-R -): An18 item self-report questionnaire&#xD;
           estimating OCD symptom dimensions.The OCI-R yields a total score and 5 subscales:&#xD;
           checking, hoarding, neutralizing, obsessing, ordering and washing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Meal Q questionnaire: A web-based food frequency questionnaire normed in Sweden will&#xD;
           validate energy and macronutrient intake, which affects the microbial composition.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bristol Stool Scale: A medical diagnostic scale designed to classify the form of human&#xD;
           faeces into seven categories.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, the investigators will collect demographic information of all patients: age,&#xD;
      sex, age at onset, occupation status, somatic health, and psychiatric comorbidities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stool sampling procedure: Patients and controls will be provided with clear instructions for&#xD;
      home fecal sample collection. Patients will collect two stool samples at the beginning of&#xD;
      treatment and two at the end of treatment. Controls will collect two samples at one time&#xD;
      point only. Participants will collect stool at home using convenient kits that will be sent&#xD;
      to the KI biobank. Fecal microbial DNA will be isolated using a phenol chloroform extraction&#xD;
      method combined with physical disruption of bacterial cells and a DNA clean-up kit (QiaAmp&#xD;
      DNAstool minikit, Qiagen, CA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exposure and Respons Prevention therapy (ERP): an evidence-based psychotherapy administered&#xD;
      by experienced psychologists, either individually, in groups, face-to-face or through&#xD;
      internet. A minimum of five exposure and respons prevention sessions is required in order for&#xD;
      it to be considered an ERP treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample storage in biobank: All samples will be stored at Karolinska Institutets (KI) biobank.&#xD;
      Application for biobank storage of samples is in progress according to rules and regulations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metagenomic sequencing: The investigators will use shotgun metagenomics [21]. Whole-genome&#xD;
      metagenome shotgun sequencing can provide functional information on which genes are present&#xD;
      in the microbiota of patients. This method can also provide a more detailed taxonomical&#xD;
      resolution that 16S rRNA sequencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data generated will be processed by the Quantitative Insights Into Microbial Ecology (QIIME2)&#xD;
      pipeline. Sequences are clustered into Operational Taxonomic Units (OTUs; similar to species&#xD;
      level) based on their sequence similarity at a 97% threshold using BLAST and assigned&#xD;
      taxonomy using the Greengenes database. Principal coordinates (PCs) will be generated using&#xD;
      unweighted and weighted UniFrac distances.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Metagenomic shotgun sequencing: will be prepared and sequenced. To efficiently utilize the&#xD;
      flow cells, about ten samples will be multiplexed, with dual indices, per lane of the flow&#xD;
      cell. Prior to downstream bioinformatics analysis, raw sequence data will be quality filtered&#xD;
      and trimmed to remove bases with Phred quality scores less than 20.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis: Downstream bioinformatics analysis will consist of: i) taxonomic&#xD;
      composition estimation to identify what microorganisms are present in the samples at&#xD;
      strain-level resolution [ConStrains, kraken, metaphlan2]; ii) functional annotation and&#xD;
      profiling using both reference gene catalog-based methods and hidden Markov model-based gene&#xD;
      family approaches to determine microbial gene content and abundances [concoct, mocat2],&#xD;
      including determination of the antibiotic resistance potential (antibiotic resistome); and&#xD;
      iii) computing descriptive statistics and identifying groups within the data, as well as&#xD;
      performing statistical analyses between subgroups using additional metadata, where available&#xD;
      [hirbin, stats]. Bioinformatics analyses will be performed on the Swedish National&#xD;
      Infrastructure for Computing's (SNIC) cluster computing resources at UPPMAX. Differences in&#xD;
      alpha diversity (expressed as number of observed species and Chao-1 estimator), beta&#xD;
      diversity (UniFrac distances), and taxa abundance of bacterial groups (at the phylum, class,&#xD;
      order, family, and genus levels) will be analyzed. Since response variables are not predicted&#xD;
      to be normally distributed, non-parametric testing will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Determination of sample size: As no previous studies have been conducted on OCD, the&#xD;
      investigators consulted similar studies conducted on patients with depression and anorexia&#xD;
      nervosa. All have included between 20-30 patients which was sufficiently large to detect&#xD;
      significant differences in alpha and beta diversity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Timeline: Ethical application has been approved and all samples have been collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 5, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 4, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>4 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Alpha diversity</measure>
    <time_frame>2018-09-01</time_frame>
    <description>expressed as number of observed species and Chao-1 estimator</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beta diversity</measure>
    <time_frame>2018-09-01</time_frame>
    <description>UniFrac distances</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between microbiota diversity and symptom severity</measure>
    <time_frame>2018-09-01</time_frame>
    <description>correlation between alpha diversity and Y-BOCS score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in microtioba diversity before and after ERP treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>2018-09-01</time_frame>
    <description>Change in alpha diversity before and after treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Microbiota</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Matched Controls without treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OCD</arm_group_label>
    <description>Exposure and response inhibition</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exposure and response inhibition</intervention_name>
    <description>Cognitive behavioural therapy designed for treatment of Obsessive-compulsive disorder</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>OCD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Stool samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Recruitment of participants from Karolinska Hospital in Solna and Huddinge. Healthy&#xD;
        Controls are recruited from Sweden from advertisements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DSM-5 diagnosis of OCD. Age matched controls will be recruited who have no personal or&#xD;
             family history of OCD.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of GI tract surgery (other than appendectomy or cholecystectomy); history of&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, irritable bowel syndrome, celiac disease, or any other&#xD;
             diagnosis that could explain chronic or recurring bowel symptoms, antibiotic use in&#xD;
             the past 3 months; pro-biotic use in the past 4 weeks; pregnancy. Intellectual&#xD;
             disability, autism spectrum disorder and psychotic disorders.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christian Rück, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Diana Radu Djurfeldt, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Long Chen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+46725670088</phone>
    <email>long.chen@ki.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M46: Karolinska Universitetssjukhuset, Psykiatri Sydväst</name>
      <address>
        <city>Stockholm</city>
        <state>Huddinge</state>
        <zip>141 86</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christian Rück, M.D., Ph.D</last_name>
      <phone>+46(0)70484 33 92</phone>
      <email>christian.ruck@ki.se</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christian Rück, M.D., Ph.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 16, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 16, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Karolinska Institutet</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Christian Rück</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Rucklab, affiliate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Compulsive Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

