<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03636958</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2018-13</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03636958</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Safety of Perampanel in Combination in Glioma-refractory Epilepsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Study of the Efficacy and Safety of Perampanel in Combination in Glioma-refractory Epilepsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique Hopitaux De Marseille</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique Hopitaux De Marseille</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Gliomas are primitive brain tumors frequently associated with epilepsy. In a significant&#xD;
      number of these patients epilepsy is resistant to antiepileptic drugs. There are currently no&#xD;
      recommendations for the management of these drug-resistant epilepsies associated with glioma.&#xD;
      In addition, few studies have addressed the subject and no treatment appears to be superior&#xD;
      to others in the literature for this indication. In addition, many antiepileptic drugs pose&#xD;
      problems of tolerance or interaction with chemotherapy in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fundamental studies on glioma-associated epilepsies have shown that there is a major&#xD;
      dysregulation of glutamatergic systems involved in epileptogenesis and tumor growth.&#xD;
      Targeting this glutamatergic system seems particularly interesting from a physiopathological&#xD;
      point of view. Perampanel is a recent antiepileptic treatment with a novel mode of action&#xD;
      targeting AMPA glutamate receptors. It has been shown to be effective in patients with&#xD;
      drug-resistant epilepsies. He has demonstrated his tolerance in these patients. He has&#xD;
      obtained a marketing authorization and is therefore used in routine epileptology without&#xD;
      serious problems of tolerance being reported. It is neither an inducer nor an enzyme&#xD;
      inhibitor, avoiding the problems of interaction with chemotherapy and is used in a daily dose&#xD;
      facilitating compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, there may be specific antiepileptic efficacy of perampanel in patients with&#xD;
      glioma. Nevertheless, the only current data is limited to a retrospective study of 12&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this protocol is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of perampanel in&#xD;
      patients with glioma with drug-resistant epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      a prospective randomized study with two parallel arms: antiepileptic combination therapy with&#xD;
      perampanel and antiepileptic combination therapy without perampanel (free choice of the&#xD;
      practitioner). The main criterion of judgment will be the decrease of the monthly frequency&#xD;
      of crisis. Secondary endpoints will assess tolerance, efficacy on responder rate (at least&#xD;
      50% decrease in seizure frequency), seizure severity (secondary generalization, loss of&#xD;
      consciousness), and quality. patients' lives (quality of life questionnaires, side effects&#xD;
      and anxiety / depression). The duration of participation per patient will be 23 weeks (6&#xD;
      weeks of baseline, 5 weeks of titration and 12 weeks of maintenance). The recruitment period&#xD;
      will be 3 years. Investigators plan to recruit 120 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the context of no recommendation in the management of these patients, superior efficacy of&#xD;
      perampanel compared with other antiepileptic drugs is expected. This would allow targeted&#xD;
      treatment in this population and confirm the tolerance of this treatment in these patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: Gliomas are primitive brain tumors frequently associated with epilepsy. In a&#xD;
      significant number of these patients epilepsy is resistant to antiepileptic drugs. There are&#xD;
      currently no recommendations for the management of these drug-resistant epilepsies associated&#xD;
      with glioma. In addition, few studies have addressed the subject and no treatment appears to&#xD;
      be superior to others in the literature for this indication. In addition, many antiepileptic&#xD;
      drugs pose problems of tolerance or interaction with chemotherapy in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rational: Fundamental studies on glioma-associated epilepsies have shown that there is a&#xD;
      major dysregulation of glutamatergic systems involved in epileptogenesis (= perpetuation of&#xD;
      epileptic seizures) and tumor growth (Huberfeld and Vecht, 2016). Targeting this&#xD;
      glutamatergic system seems particularly interesting from a physiopathological point of view.&#xD;
      Perampanel is a recent antiepileptic treatment with a novel mode of action targeting AMPA&#xD;
      glutamate receptors. It has been shown to be effective in patients with drug-resistant&#xD;
      epilepsies. He has demonstrated his tolerance in these patients. He has obtained a marketing&#xD;
      authorization and is therefore used in routine epileptology without serious problems of&#xD;
      tolerance being reported. It is neither an inducer nor an enzyme inhibitor, avoiding the&#xD;
      problems of interaction with chemotherapy and is used in a daily dose facilitating&#xD;
      compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, there may be specific antiepileptic efficacy of perampanel in patients with&#xD;
      glioma. Nevertheless, the only current data is limited to a retrospective study of 12&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this protocol is to evaluate the efficacy and safety of perampanel in&#xD;
      patients with glioma with drug-resistant epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators want to perform a prospective randomized study with two parallel arms:&#xD;
      antiepileptic combination therapy with perampanel and antiepileptic combination therapy&#xD;
      without perampanel (free choice of the practitioner). The main criterion of judgment will be&#xD;
      the decrease of the monthly frequency of crisis. Secondary endpoints will assess tolerance,&#xD;
      efficacy on responder rate (at least 50% decrease in seizure frequency), seizure severity&#xD;
      (secondary generalization, loss of consciousness), and quality. patients' lives (quality of&#xD;
      life questionnaires, side effects and anxiety / depression). The duration of participation&#xD;
      per patient will be 23 weeks (6 weeks of baseline, 5 weeks of titration and 12 weeks of&#xD;
      maintenance). The recruitment period will be 3 years. The investigators plan to recruit 120&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expected benefits: In the context of no recommendation in the management of these patients,&#xD;
      the investigators hope to demonstrate superior efficacy of perampanel compared with other&#xD;
      antiepileptic drugs. This would allow targeted treatment in this population and confirm the&#xD;
      tolerance of this treatment in these patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Numbers of crisis at baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The monthly frequency of crisis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Numbers of crisis under treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>5 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The monthly frequency of crisis during treatment period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Refractory Epilepsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>they will receive conventional antiepileptic treatment (antiepileptic combination therapy) without perampanel</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>they will receive conventional antiepileptic treatment (antiepileptic combination therapy) with perampanel</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Perampanel</intervention_name>
    <description>Perampanel is an antiepileptic with a novel mechanism of action as it targets post-synaptic AMPA receptors. It has been shown to be effective as adjunctive therapy (dual therapy) for partial / focal epilepsy seizures and generalized in patients over 12 years of age.</description>
    <arm_group_label>experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>conventional antiepileptic treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>choice of the molecule is left to the discretion of the clinician excluding the following benzodiazepines: clobazam, clonazepam, diazepam. Antiepileptic drugs allowed are therefore: lamotrigine, levetiracetam, lacosamide, sodium valproate, carbamazepine, oxcarbabazepine, slicarbazepine, pregabalin, gabapentin, topiramate, phenytoin, phenobarbital, zonisamide, vigabatrin.</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient, male or female, over 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Glioma confirmed by histology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not in progression (clinico-radiological criterion RANO, (Wen et al., 2014), see&#xD;
             appendix 1)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No clinical worsening (excluding epileptic seizures)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No increase greater than 25% in contrast enhancement after gadolinium injection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No increase in the T2 / FLAIR hyper signal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of new lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of drug-resistant epilepsy according to international epilepsy definitions&#xD;
             (Fisher 2014 and Kwan 2010, see Appendices 2 and 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
             o Repeated epileptic seizures despite testing of two effective dose antiepileptic&#xD;
             drugs tried at least 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  With at least 2 attacks per month (to ensure visibility on the duration of the study&#xD;
             of the antiepileptic effect, see below)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with epileptic seizures not limited to only subjective signs&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating woman&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impossibility of signing consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No affiliation to a social security scheme (beneficiary or beneficiary)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person in emergency,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person of legal age subject to a legal protection measure (major under guardianship,&#xD;
             guardianship or court order), or unable to express his or her consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with at least 2 generalized tonic-clonic seizures per month.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>EMILIE GARRIDO PRADALIE</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>APHM</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>stanislas lagarde, md</last_name>
    <phone>+33 491385554</phone>
    <email>Stanislas.LAGARDE@ap-hm.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assistance Publique Des Hopitaux de Marseille</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <state>Paca</state>
        <zip>13354</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>STANISLAS LAGARDE, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+33 491385554</phone>
      <email>Stanislas.LAGARDE@ap-hm.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Epileptology and Cerebral Rhythmology, Hôpital La Timone, APHM</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <zip>13385</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stanislas Lagarde</last_name>
      <email>stanislas.lagarde@ap-hm.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Olivier Chinot</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fabrice Bartolomei</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Emeline Tabouret</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Agnes Trebuchon</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Maryline Barrie</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Chantal Campello</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gregorio Petrirena</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aileen McGonigal</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Francesca Bonini</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marjorie Faure</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 16, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 16, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Drug Resistant Epilepsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anticonvulsants</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

