<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03631511</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Direct capping RetroMTA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03631511</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Histological Evaluation of Hard Tissue Formation After Direct Pulp Capping With RetroMTA</brief_title>
  <acronym>RetroMTA</acronym>
  <official_title>Histological Evaluation of Direct Pulp Capping on Human Pulp Tissue Using a RetroMTA</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pomeranian Medical University Szczecin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pomeranian Medical University Szczecin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study presents a clinical and histological evaluation of human pulp tissue responses&#xD;
      after direct capping using RetroMTA. Seven teeth were subjected to pulp exposure, direct&#xD;
      capping with RetroMTA, and restoration with a composite resin. Seven months later, the teeth&#xD;
      were clinically and radiographically evaluated. The teeth were then extracted and subjected&#xD;
      to histological processing and evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study was conducted in accordance with the tenets of the World Medical Association&#xD;
      Declaration of Helsinki. Seven caries-free, intact, maxillary, and mandibular third molars&#xD;
      from humans, aged 30-37 years, which were scheduled for extraction for orthodontic or&#xD;
      surgical purposes, were included in the study. The patients received a thorough explanation&#xD;
      of the experimental rationale, clinical procedures, and possible complications. All&#xD;
      experimental protocols were independently reviewed and approved by the Local Ethics Committee&#xD;
      of Pomeranian Medical University, Szczecin, Poland (approval number KB-0012/27/13).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical protocol. For all included teeth, periapical radiographs were taken to exclude the&#xD;
      presence of caries or periapical pathology. Tooth sensitivity was assessed by thermal testing&#xD;
      (Kältespray; M&amp;W Dental, Büdingen, Germany) and electric sensitivity testing (Vitality&#xD;
      Scanner Pulp Vitality Tester; SybronEndo, Orange, CA, USA). These teeth were subjected to&#xD;
      pulp exposure, direct capping with RetroMTA, and restoration with a composite resin. Seven&#xD;
      months later, the teeth were clinically and radiographically evaluated. Clinical assessment&#xD;
      was performed at 1 week and at 7 months after the procedure. During clinical interviews, the&#xD;
      patients were asked about the presence of pain, and its type and duration. Reactions to&#xD;
      thermal stimuli were classified into three categories: 1 = normal response (pain lasting up&#xD;
      to 10 s); 2 = an extended response (pain &gt; 10 s); 3 = no response. An electrical test was&#xD;
      performed using a Vitality Scanner, and was repeated three times. Seven months after the&#xD;
      procedure the teeth were extracted and subjected to histological processing and evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Histological processing. Immediately after extraction, the teeth were immersed in a 10%&#xD;
      neutral buffered formalin solution, and gently washed from blood and saliva. After brief&#xD;
      prefixation (≤10 minutes), special precautions were taken to facilitate pulp tissue fixation.&#xD;
      The roots were separated 5 mm apically to the cemento-enamel junction, using a diamond disk&#xD;
      under copious water cooling. Then the teeth were grinded with a high speed cylindrical&#xD;
      diamond bur under water spray in a mesio-distal or bucco-lingual plane until exposing one or&#xD;
      more pulp horns. Photographs and radiographs were taken of each sample before successive&#xD;
      steps. For demineralization, the specimens were immersed for 3 to 4 weeks in an aqueous&#xD;
      solution consisting of a mixture of 22.5% (v/v) formic acid and 10% (w/v) sodium citrate,&#xD;
      with radiographic determination of the end-point. Then all specimens were washed in running&#xD;
      tap water for 24 hours, dehydrated using ascending grades of ethanol, cleared in xylene,&#xD;
      infiltrated, and embedded in paraffin (melting point of 56 °C) following standard procedures.&#xD;
      The paraffin blocks were trimmed. With the microtome set at 5 μM, serial sections were taken&#xD;
      until exhausting the entire pulp tissue in the chamber. Six to eight sections were collected&#xD;
      on each slide. Every fifth slide was stained with haematoxylin and eosin for screening and&#xD;
      evaluation of mineralized tissue formation. These stained sections were used to locate the&#xD;
      areas exhibiting the most severe inflammatory reactions, and those with less favourable&#xD;
      bridging. Based on this initial evaluation, all slides adjacent to the location with the less&#xD;
      favourable conditions were stained. In addition, the selected slides were subjected to a&#xD;
      modified Brown and Brenn technique (Taylor 1966) for staining bacteria. Next, cover slips&#xD;
      were placed on the slides, and the sections were examined using a light microscope. For each&#xD;
      pulp, the worst histologic condition observed was recorded. If bacteria were observed on the&#xD;
      cavity walls or in the area of exposure, the case was excluded from evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two intact teeth (one maxillary and one mandibular third molar) extracted for pericoronitis&#xD;
      were used as control. To test the reliability of the bacterial stain, two teeth with deep&#xD;
      caries were examined, extracted because deemed non-restorable. These teeth were processed&#xD;
      using the same protocol as the experimental group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Slides were observed under a light microscope (Leica DMLB; Leica Microsystems, Wetzlar,&#xD;
      Germany) and digital photographs were taken (Leica DFC420; Leica Microsystems, Wetzlar,&#xD;
      Germany). Following aspects were observed with particular care: 1) Presence and type of&#xD;
      mineralized tissues formed in the area of the surgical exposure; 2) Morphology of cells&#xD;
      layering this mineralized tissue; 3) Presence and degree of inflammatory reactions in the&#xD;
      pulpal area subjacent to the newly formed tissue; and 4) Presence of stainable bacteria in&#xD;
      the experimental cavity or the area of pulp exposure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 3, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 18, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 20, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Histological Evaluation of Direct Pulp Capping on Human Pulp Tissue Using a RetroMTA</measure>
    <time_frame>7 months</time_frame>
    <description>Each histomorphologic section was scored from 1-3, with 1 representing the most desired result and 3 representing the least desired result.&#xD;
Mineralized tissue bridge&#xD;
Complete&#xD;
Incomplete&#xD;
Absent&#xD;
Mineralized tissue morphology&#xD;
Dentin associated with irregular hard tissue&#xD;
Only irregular hard tissue deposition&#xD;
No hard tissue deposition&#xD;
Inflammatory response&#xD;
Absent&#xD;
Mild (inflammatory cells next to dentin bridge or area of pulp exposure only)&#xD;
Severe (all of the coronal pulp is infiltrated or necrotic)&#xD;
Odontoblastic cell layer&#xD;
Presence of odontoblast cells and odontoblast-like cells&#xD;
Presence of odontoblast-like cells only&#xD;
Absent&#xD;
Presence of bacteria&#xD;
Absence&#xD;
Presence of stained bacterial profiles along the coronal or apical walls&#xD;
Presence of stained bacterial profiles within the dental pulp</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Examination of Direct Pulp Capping on Human Pulp Tissue Using a RetroMTA</measure>
    <time_frame>7 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with adverse events related to RetroMTA treatment&#xD;
Periapical pathology&#xD;
absent&#xD;
present&#xD;
The presence of pain&#xD;
absent&#xD;
present&#xD;
Tooth sensitivity:&#xD;
I. Reactions to thermal stimuli&#xD;
present&#xD;
absent&#xD;
II. Electric sensitivity&#xD;
present&#xD;
absent&#xD;
1 representing the most desired result and 2 representing the least desired result.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">3</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Pulp Exposure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RetroMTA</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Direct pulp capping with RetroMTA (BioMTA, Daejeon, Korea)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>direct pulp capping with RetroMTA</intervention_name>
    <description>The study included seven caries-free third molars from three adults. These teeth were subjected to pulp exposure, direct capping with RetroMTA, and restoration with a composite resin. Seven months later, the teeth were clinically and radiographically evaluated. The teeth were then extracted and subjected to histological processing and evaluation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>RetroMTA</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The inclusion criteria were healthy patients with no contributing systemic conditions,&#xD;
             who had at least one caries-free mature permanent third molar&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The exclusion criteria included patients who had pulp inflammation, pulp necrosis,&#xD;
             root resorption or periapical diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>37 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alicja Nowicka, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Conservative Dentistry and Endodontics, Pomeranian Medical University, Al. Powstańców Wielkopolskich 72, 70-111, Szczecin, Poland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Till Dammaschke, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Periodontology and Operative Dentistry, Westphalian Wilhelms-University, Albert-Schweitzer-Campus 1, building W 30, 48149 Münster, Germany</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mariusz Lipski, DDS, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Preclinical Conservative Dentistry and Preclinical Endodontics, Pomeranian Medical University, Al. Powstańców Wielkopolskich 72, 70-111, Szczecin, Poland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Domenico Ricucci, MD, DDS</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Private Practice, Piazza Calvario, 7, 87022 Cetraro (CS), Italy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pomeranian Medical University in Szczecin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Szczecin</city>
        <state>Rybacka 1</state>
        <zip>70-111</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 24, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 15, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 10, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 10, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 15, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Pomeranian Medical University Szczecin</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alicja Nowicka</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>DDS, PhD Alicja Nowicka</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>direct pulp capping, RetroMTA, histological evaluation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Pulp Exposure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

