<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04920331</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-006424</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04920331</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of Intravenous Erenumab in Patients With Status Migrainosus</brief_title>
  <official_title>STATUS STUDY: Pilot Open-Label Trial of Intravenous Erenumab in Patients With Status Migrainosus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mayo Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will evaluate the efficacy for use of intravenous erenumab 140mg for&#xD;
      treatment of status migrainosus in an open-label, pilot study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This will be a single-center, open-label, pilot study. The investigators will enroll 15&#xD;
      subjects. Subjects will be recruited from the outpatient Mayo Headache Clinic. The Headache&#xD;
      Clinic employs 5 headache specialists and 1 fellow which is sufficient staffing to support&#xD;
      this study and recruitment of patients with status migrainosus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject participation would be for a total of 28 days. Subjects will be screened at&#xD;
      outpatient clinic visit appointments or when they call into the clinic regarding an episode&#xD;
      of status migrainosus and interested qualified subjects will be consented and offered&#xD;
      participation in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once consent has been obtained, subjects will have evaluation of vital signs, pregnancy&#xD;
      status, complete blood count, and comprehensive metabolic panel. Abnormal metabolic profile,&#xD;
      kidney or liver function will exclude subjects. Pregnancy will exclude subjects. Qualifying&#xD;
      subjects will be administered a single dose of intravenous erenumab at our Infusion Center at&#xD;
      the first available appointment within 24 hours of qualifying for participation if they&#xD;
      continue to have moderate to severe pain and monitored on-site for a minimum of 2 hours after&#xD;
      start of drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will fill out two headache diaries following treatment. The first diary is an hourly&#xD;
      diary with entries once every hour for 24 hours, with time point 0 defined as time of when&#xD;
      treatment begins. Diary entry at hour 24 coincides with the time point for post-treatment day&#xD;
      1. Follow-up will occur by phone at post-treatment day 1. If pain and symptoms persist,&#xD;
      patients will be directed to contact their primary headache provider to receive further&#xD;
      management. From this point and onwards, patients will be instructed to fill out a second&#xD;
      diary once daily for 28 consecutive calendar days following treatment. A final visit will be&#xD;
      conducted at the end of the study at 28 days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain relief at 2 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects with decreased pain from moderate or severe at baseline to mild or none at 2 hours after treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain freedom at 2 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects who become pain free at 2 hours after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absence of most bothersome symptom at 2 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects with absence of most bothersome symptom at 2 hours after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relief of most bothersome symptom at 2 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects with decrease in most bothersome symptom from moderate or severe at baseline to mild or none at 2 hours after treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain freedom at 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects who become pain free at 24 hours after treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pain relief at 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects with decrease in pain from moderate or severe at baseline to mild or none at 24 hours after treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained pain freedom at 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects who are pain free at 24 hours with no use of rescue medications or relapse within 24 hours of the initial treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained pain freedom at 48 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects who are pain free at 48 hours with no use of rescue medications or relapse within 48 hours of the initial treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained pain relief at 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects who have pain relief at 24 hours with no use of rescue medications or relapse within 24 hours of the initial treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sustained pain relief at 48 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>48 hours after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of subjects who have pain relief at 48 hours with no use of rescue medications or relapse within 48 hours of the initial treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pain intensity at 2 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using a self-reported questionnaire to rate headache pain on a numerical rating scale from 0-10, where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain imaginable.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in pain intensity at 24 hours</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using a self-reported questionnaire to rate headache pain on a numerical rating scale from 0-10, where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain imaginable.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Status Migrainosus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Erenumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects with episodes of status migrainosus will receive a single dose of IV erenumab</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Erenumab</intervention_name>
    <description>140mg single intravenous administration (60 minutes)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Erenumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years to 70 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of migraines (with or without aura) for ≥ 12 months and history of at least 1&#xD;
             episode of status migrainosus based on medical records and/or patient self-report in&#xD;
             their lifetime.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently experiencing an episode of status migrainosus (non-menstrually related) per&#xD;
             ICHD3 criteria of ≥ 3 and &lt; 6 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Migraine frequency: ≥ 2 and &lt; 10 migraine days per month on average across the 3&#xD;
             months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Headache (i.e., migraine and non-migraine headache) frequency: &lt; 15 headache days per&#xD;
             month on average across the 3 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to withhold acute treatments for 24 hours after receiving erenumab IV unless&#xD;
             medically necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Older than 50 years of age at migraine onset.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cluster headache or hemiplegic migraine headache.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Past (within 4 months) or present exposure to a CGRP monoclonal antibody or CGRP small&#xD;
             molecule receptor antagonist for migraine treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present exposure to lasmiditan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New acute treatment within 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  New preventive treatment within 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &gt; 15 days acute treatment use, opioid or barbiturate use &gt; 4 days per month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of acute treatment within 6 hours of the infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to differentiate migraine from other headaches.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Procedures (e.g., nerve blocks) or neuromodulatory devices within 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of major psychiatric disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or evidence of any unstable or clinically significant medical condition, that&#xD;
             in the opinion of the investigator, would pose a risk to subject safety or interfere&#xD;
             with the study evaluation, procedures, or completion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of myocardial infarction, stroke, transient ischemic attack, unstable angina,&#xD;
             coronary artery bypass surgery, or other revascularization procedures within 12 months&#xD;
             prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant, breastfeeding, or who are trying to become pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not willing to use a reliable form of contraception (for women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential) through 16 weeks after the last dose of erenumab. Acceptable methods of&#xD;
             birth control include not having intercourse, hormonal birth control methods,&#xD;
             intrauterine devices, surgical contraceptive methods, or two barrier methods (each&#xD;
             partner must use a barrier method) with spermicide. A reliable form of contraception&#xD;
             must be started prior to or at the time of starting the run-in phase. Not being of&#xD;
             childbearing potential is defined as any woman who:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is post-menopausal by history, defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 55 years of age with cessation of menses for 12 or more months; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Younger than 55 years of age but no spontaneous menses for at least 2 years; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Younger than 55 years of age and spontaneous menses within the past 1 year, but&#xD;
             currently amenorrheic (e.g., spontaneous or secondary to hysterectomy), AND with&#xD;
             postmenopausal gonadotropin levels (luteinizing hormone and follicle-stimulating&#xD;
             hormone levels at least 40 IU/L) or postmenopausal estradiol level (less than 5 ng/dL)&#xD;
             or according to the definition of &quot;postmenopausal range&quot; for the laboratory involved;&#xD;
             OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underwent bilateral oophorectomy; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underwent hysterectomy; OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underwent bilateral salpingectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving treatment in another drug study or an investigational device&#xD;
             study, or less than 90 days prior to screening since ending treatment on another&#xD;
             investigational device or drug study(-ies).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unlikely to be able to complete all protocol required study visits or procedures,&#xD;
             and/or to comply with all required study procedures.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juliana VanderPluym, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Arizona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85054</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shan Luc-Kenney</last_name>
      <phone>480-301-9769</phone>
      <email>Luc-Kenney.Shan@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mayo.edu/research/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Mayo Clinic Clinical Trials</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 3, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mayo Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Juliana H. VanderPluym</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Migraine Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Erenumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

