<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04925557</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>00003884</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04925557</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess the Efficacy of Mayzent on Microglia in Secondary Progressive Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Open-label, Single-blind, Observational, Comparative, Prospective, 36-month, Longitudinal, Controlled Study to Assess Efficacy of Siponimod (Mayzent速) on Microglia in Patients With Active Secondary Progressive Forms of Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Robert Zivadinov, MD, PhD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University at Buffalo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To assess the efficacy of Mayzent on microglia pathology in patients with active SPMS, as&#xD;
      compared to the active control group of MS patients treated with the Ocrevus, as measured by&#xD;
      changes in microglial activation in the lesional and non-lesional NAWM and NAGM and in the&#xD;
      peri-plaque area of chronic lesions in the brain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Multiple sclerosis (MS) is primarily a demyelinating disease of the central nervous system&#xD;
      (CNS), but many patients also undergo progressive atrophy, especially in the gray matter&#xD;
      (GM). GM atrophy plays a particularly prominent role in development of cognitive and physical&#xD;
      disability in MS. Evidence is mounting that there is a profound infiltration of activated&#xD;
      microglia and blood-borne macrophages throughout the lesions, whereas in slowly expanding&#xD;
      (smoldering) or chronic active expanding lesions, the microglia and macrophages are&#xD;
      concentrated as a dense rim around the lesions. Microglia is also activated, in a more&#xD;
      diffuse way, in the white matter (WM) and GM with concomitant axonal degeneration and&#xD;
      meningeal inflammation. Thus, chronic activation of microglia has been linked to&#xD;
      neurodegeneration in the progressive phase of the disease and development of brain atrophy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No longitudinal studies in MS examined the association between development of&#xD;
      microglia-related pathology in patients treated with siponimod (Mayzent速). This will be the&#xD;
      first study to examine the treatment effect of Mayzent on microglia in MS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in PET Activation at 12 Months</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in PET activation of PBR06 in lesional and non-lesional NAWM and NAGM in the brain of the patients under treatment with Mayzent when 100% of patients reach 12 months;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in PET activation at 6,12,24 and 36 months between Mayzent and active comparator</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline in PET activation of PBR06 in lesional and non-lesional NAWM and NAGM in the brain of the patients treated with Mayzent and active control group at 6, 12, 24 and 36 months from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of new ultrasmall superparamagnetic iron oxide particles</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The cumulative number of new ultrasmall superparamagnetic iron oxide (USPIO) particles contrast enhancing (CE) active lesions on T1-weighted images between Mayzent and active control group, as measured at 6, 12, 24 and 36 months from baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>MRI Measures between Mayzent and control-treated groups (PBVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percent brain volume change (PBVC) between baseline and 12, 24, and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>MRI Measures between Mayzent and control-treated groups (PCVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percent cortical volume change (PCVC), between baseline and 12, 24, and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>MRI Measures between Mayzent and control-treated groups(PTVC)</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Percent thalamus volume change (PTVC) between baseline and 12, 24, and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>MRI Measures between Mayzent and control-treated groups (QSM)</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quantitative susceptibility mapp (QSM) change between baseline and 12, 24, and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative number of new gadolinium CE lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The cumulative number of new gadolinium CE lesions on T1-weighted images at months 6, 12, 24 and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative number of new or newly enlarging T2 lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The cumulative number of new or newly enlarging hyperintense T2 lesions measured at months 6, 12, 24 and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute change in Hyperintense T2 Lesions volume</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The absolute change in hyperintense T2-lesion volume (LV) measured at months 6, 12, 24 and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute change in Hypo-intense T1 Lesions volume</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The absolute change in hypo-intense T1-lesion volume (LV) measured at months 6, 12, 24 and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute change in serum neurofilament and glial protein</measure>
    <time_frame>6, 12, 24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The absolute change in serum neurofilament light chain (sNfL) and glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) at 6, 12, 24 and 36 months</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Association between imaging and clinical and cognitive outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>24 and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>The association between imaging and clinical and cognitive outcomes, incl. the composite EDSS+SDMT, over 24 and 36 months of the study</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with Treatment related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, and 36 months</time_frame>
    <description>Safety of Mayzent and active control group over 12, 24, and 36 months of the study</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Secondary-progressive Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ocrevus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients diagnosed with secondary-progressive multiple sclerosis who have been prescribed Ocrevus by their neurologist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mayzent</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients diagnosed with secondary-progressive multiple sclerosis who have been prescribed Mayzent by their neurologist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mayzent</intervention_name>
    <description>PET imaging to evaluate the effects of Mayzent on the microglia of the brain.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Mayzent</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ocrevus</intervention_name>
    <description>PET imaging to evaluate the effects of Ocrevus on the microglia of the brain.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ocrevus</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with active SPMS according to the Lublin 2014 criteria. Activity is&#xD;
             determined by MRI activity (contrast-enhancing lesions; new and unequivocally&#xD;
             enlarging T2 lesions) and/or clinical relapses in the 24 months prior to the study&#xD;
             baseline. If the clinical MRI is not available to determine the activity&#xD;
             (contrast-enhancing lesions; new and unequivocally enlarging T2 lesions), then a&#xD;
             screening MRI will be offered to the subjects to determine inclusion/exclusion&#xD;
             criteria eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have EDSS scores between 3.0 and 6.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment na誰ve to both Mayzent and to Ocrevus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not being on S1P modulators or B-cell therapies for the last 9 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects starting treatment as part of their clinical routine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be willing and able to comply with the study procedures for the duration of the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have given written informed consent and signed Health Insurance Portability and&#xD;
             Accountability Act (HIPAA) authorization before any study-related activities are&#xD;
             carried out&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal kidney functioning (creatinine clearance &gt;59)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No known hypersensitivity reactions to contrast agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None of the exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received treatment within 30 days prior to enrollment with steroids or any other&#xD;
             concomitant immunomodulatory therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have received an investigational drug or experimental procedure within the past 30&#xD;
             days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low affinity (LAB) for the DNA single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) of the TSPO gene&#xD;
             on chromosome 22q13.2, using a TaqMan assay&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A CYP2C9*3/*3 genotype&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have experienced myocardial infarction, unstable angina, stroke, TIA, decompensated&#xD;
             heart failure requiring hospitalization, or Class III/IV heart failure in the last 6&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of Mobitz type II second-degree, third-degree AV block, or sick sinus&#xD;
             syndrome, unless patient has a functioning pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active HBV confirmed by positive results for HBsAg and anti-HBV tests&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Conditions that may be associated with iron overload (e.g. hemochromatosis,&#xD;
             thalassemia and recent blood transfusions)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known hypersensitivity to Feraheme速 or any of its components or a&#xD;
             history of allergic reaction to any intravenous iron product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant, lactating or of childbearing age who do not consent to&#xD;
             approved contraceptive use during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are scheduled for a routine diagnostic MRI exam in the next 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other warnings and precautions to Mayzent or Ocrevus treatment according to&#xD;
             Prescribing Information (PI) will be examined on an individual basis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robert Zivadinov, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>716-859-7040</phone>
    <email>rzivadinov@bnac.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Cheryl Kennedy, LMSW, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>716-888-4847</phone>
    <email>ckennedy@bnac.net</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University at Buffalo, Buffalo General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Buffalo</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>14203</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cheryl L Kennedy, LMSW, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>716-859-7068</phone>
      <email>ckennedy@bnac.net</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Robert Zivadinov, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Bianca Weinstock-Guttman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University at Buffalo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Robert Zivadinov, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director and Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis, Chronic Progressive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ocrelizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Siponimod</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

