<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04929444</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>4R21/003</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>PI19/00736</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04929444</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Training to Improve Vertigo Management in Primary Care</brief_title>
  <acronym>VERTAP</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of a Training Intervention to Improve the Approach of Patients With Vertigo in Primary Care. VERTAP Clinical Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Catalan Society of Family Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Instituto de Salud Carlos III</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jordi Gol i Gurina Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objectives: To verify the effectiveness of a blended course in PC to improve adherence to&#xD;
      clinical practice guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: randomized community trial, by clusters (control group -CG- / intervention group&#xD;
      -IG-) Scope: 20 PCT (primary care teams)(10 per group) Outcome variables will be: Diagnostic&#xD;
      records (proportion of nonspecific diagnoses such as dizziness and vertigo, with respect to&#xD;
      specific diagnoses such as BPPV, vestibular neuritis); Derivations to otorhinolaryngologist&#xD;
      (ENT) and neurologist; Prescription of antivertiginous medications and Number of days off&#xD;
      work caused by vertigo-related.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis:Descriptive statistics of all the baseline variables will be carried out&#xD;
      and, the differences between groups in the post-intervention outcome variables will be&#xD;
      evaluated through the t-test. In the IG, a multivariate logistic regression model will&#xD;
      identify response patterns based on the baseline variables of professionals and centers&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Vertigo is a prevalent pathology whose most frequent cause is benign paroxysmal positional&#xD;
      vertigo (BPPV). Treatment of this disease are the relocation manoeuvres. Although these&#xD;
      manoeuvres are effective in primary care (PC), they are not done routinely. Attention to&#xD;
      other causes of vertigo in PC also has a wide margin for improvement. Objectives: To verify&#xD;
      the effectiveness of a blended course in PC to improve adherence to clinical practice&#xD;
      guidelines. Design: randomized community trial, by clusters (CG / IG), multicenter and open,&#xD;
      taking as unit of allocation the primary care team (PCT). The professionals of the PCT that&#xD;
      are in IG would receive the training at the beginning of the study and those of the control&#xD;
      group will be offered after the conclusion of the same. Scope: 20 PCT (10 per group) selected&#xD;
      from the &quot;Costa de Ponent&quot; Primary Care Directorate of the Catalan Health Institute.&#xD;
      Variables: The outcome variables will be: Diagnostic records (proportion of nonspecific&#xD;
      diagnoses such as dizziness and vertigo, with respect to specific diagnoses such as BPPV,&#xD;
      vestibular neuritis); Derivations to otorhinolaryngologist (ENT) and neurologist;&#xD;
      Prescription of antivertiginous medications and Number of days off work caused by&#xD;
      vertigo-related illnesses during the study period. Other study variables will be&#xD;
      characteristics of the professionals (age, sex) and centers (teachers, number of tutors,&#xD;
      rural / urban). All the variables will be collected in an aggregated form by computerized&#xD;
      data download during the year following the training intervention in the PCT. Statistical&#xD;
      analysis: Following the CONSORT Cluster Guide, the baseline comparability of the two study&#xD;
      groups will be analyzed to analyze the homogeneity. Descriptive statistics of all the&#xD;
      baseline variables will be carried out and, the differences between groups in the&#xD;
      post-intervention outcome variables will be evaluated through the t-test. In the IG, a&#xD;
      multivariate logistic regression model will identify response patterns based on the baseline&#xD;
      variables of professionals and centers. Conclusions: Positive results of the study could&#xD;
      imply a paradigm shift in the approach to vertigo in primary care, which would be easy to&#xD;
      extend to other areas since the most important part of the training course will be done&#xD;
      online.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized community trial, by clusters (CG /IG), multicenter and open, taking as unit of allocation the primary care team (PCT). The professionals of the PCT that are in IG would receive the training at the beginning of the study and those of the control group will be offered after the conclusion of the same</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnostic records</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
    <description>proportion of nonspecific diagnoses such as dizziness and vertigo, with respect to specific diagnoses such as BPPV, vestibular neuritis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Derivations to otorhinolaryngologist (ENT) and neurologist</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of referrals made during the study period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prescription of antivertiginous medications</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of prescriptions of betahistine, sulpiride, dimenhydrinate made during the study period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Days off work</measure>
    <time_frame>One year</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days off work caused by vertigo-related illnesses during the study period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Vertigo</condition>
  <condition>Vertigo, Paroxysmal</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Training group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The professionals of the primary care teams that are in Intervention group would receive the training at the beginning of the study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Common Practice</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The professionals of the primary care teams that are in Control group will be offered the training after the conclusion of the study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Training on vertigo</intervention_name>
    <description>Online training on vertigo management in primary care with a face-to-face session.&#xD;
On the one hand, the course will contain theoretical content and clinical cases will be used as the methodology of the course, with feedback paths for each correct or incorrect answer from the students and videos recorded expressly for the course. In addition, there will be a face-to-face session where all participants must perform the diagnostic and therapeutic maneuvers proposed in the course, to evaluate the use of the training and also to standardize the way of doing them for the study</description>
    <arm_group_label>Training group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  20 randomized primary care teams out of the 56 that make up the &quot;Costa de Ponent&quot;&#xD;
             Primary Care Department that serve a population of 1.3 million people.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary care teams in which&gt; 60% of their professionals have received a course on&#xD;
             vertigo in the last 5 years will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary care teams who are not interested in participating in the study will be&#xD;
             excluded&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>José L Ballve, MD, PHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>IDIAP Jordi Gol</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eva Peguero, MD. PHD</last_name>
    <phone>#34630053772</phone>
    <email>pegueroeva@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>primary care</keyword>
  <keyword>vertigo</keyword>
  <keyword>randomized clinical trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vertigo</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dizziness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

