<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04927312</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C3591036</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04927312</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Assess Efficacy and Safety of PF-06947386 in Japanese Adult Patients With Complicated Intra-abdominal Infection</brief_title>
  <official_title>A PHASE 3, MULTICENTER, OPEN-LABEL, SINGLE-ARM STUDY TO ASSESS THE EFFICACY AND SAFETY OF CEFTAZIDIME-AVIBACTAM (PF-06947386) PLUS METRONIDAZOLE IN JAPANESE ADULT PATIENTS WITH COMPLICATED INTRA-ABDOMINAL INFECTION REQUIRING HOSPITALIZATION</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pfizer</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study C3591036 is a Phase 3 study to assess the efficacy and safety of PF-06947386 in&#xD;
      Japanese adult patients with complicated intra-abdominal infection requiring hospitalization.&#xD;
      This is a multicenter, open-label, single-arm study. All eligible participants will receive&#xD;
      intravenous infusion of PF-06947386 followed by intravenous infusion of metronidazole.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in clinically evaluable (CE) analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>Test of Cure (TOC) on study Day 28-35</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in CE analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated as the primary estimand of the primary endpoint. As an efficacy evaluation criterion, it will be confirmed that the point estimate of proportion of patients with clinical cure at TOC visit in the CE analysis set (the primary analysis) is ≥78%.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in modified intent-to-treat (MITT) analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>TOC on study Day 28-35</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in MITT analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated as the supportive estimand of the primary endpoint.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in microbiological modified intent-to-treat (mMITT) analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>TOC on study Day 28-35</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated as the supportive estimand of the primary endpoint.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in microbiologically evaluable (ME) analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>TOC on study Day 28-35</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated as the supportive estimand of the primary endpoint.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in extended microbiologically evaluable (eME) analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>TOC on study Day 28-35</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants eME analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated as the supportive estimand of the primary endpoint</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in CE analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>End of Treatment (EOT, within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion) and LFU (Late Follow-Up) on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in CE analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in MITT analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion) and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in MITT analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion) and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion) and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion) and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having clinical cure will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-patient</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-patient will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-patient</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-patient will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-patient</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-patient will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in mMITT analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in ME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in eME analysis set having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants experiencing Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a minimum of approximately 28 days after the last administration of the study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability profile of PF-06947386 plus metronidazole in the treatment of patients with cIAIs will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants experiencing Serious Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a minimum of approximately 28 days after the last administration of the study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability profile of PF-06947386 plus metronidazole in the treatment of patients with cIAIs will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ceftazidime plasma concentrations by nominal sampling window</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3, Day 4</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacokinetics of ceftazidime in patients with cIAIs will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Avibactam plasma concentrations by nominal sampling window</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 3, Day 4</time_frame>
    <description>Pharmacokinetics of avibactam in patients with cIAIs will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having clinical cure</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having clinical cure will be calculated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having favorable microbiological response per-patient</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having favorable microbiological response per-patient will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories</measure>
    <time_frame>EOT (within 24 hours after completion of last IV infusion), TOC on study Day 28-35, and LFU on study Day 42-49</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of participants in the sepsis population having favorable microbiological response per-pathogen by MIC categories will be calculated. Participants with &quot;Indeterminate&quot; are not included in the denominator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants experiencing Adverse Events in the sepsis population</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a minimum of approximately 28 days after the last administration of the study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability profile of PF-06947386 plus metronidazole in the sepsis population will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of participants experiencing Serious Adverse Events in the sepsis population</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to a minimum of approximately 28 days after the last administration of the study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability profile of PF-06947386 plus metronidazole in the sepsis population will be evaluated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Complicated Intra-abdominal Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PF-06947386 + Metronidazole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Multiple intravenous infusion of ceftazidime-avibactam followed by intravenous infusion of metronidazole, repeated every 8 hours for 5-14 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PF-06947386</intervention_name>
    <description>Ceftazidime-Avibactam powder for concentrate for solution for infusion 2.0 g/ 0.5 g. Dosage will be adjusted based on renal function after enrollment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PF-06947386 + Metronidazole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Metronidazole</intervention_name>
    <description>Metronidazole 0.5 g solution for injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PF-06947386 + Metronidazole</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who is capable of giving signed, dated and timed informed consent (or by&#xD;
             their legally acceptable representative)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant aged 20 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who is willing and able to comply with all scheduled visits, treatment&#xD;
             plan, laboratory tests, and other study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmation of infection by surgical intervention within 24 hours of entry: evidence&#xD;
             of systemic inflammatory response; physical findings consistent with intra-abdominal&#xD;
             infection; supportive radiologic imaging findings of intra-abdominal infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intraoperative/postoperative enrollment with visual confirmation (presence of pus&#xD;
             within the abdominal cavity) of an intra-abdominal infection associated with&#xD;
             peritonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant will undergo surgery for traumatic bowel perforation within 12 hours or&#xD;
             perforation of gastroduodenal ulcers within 24 hours. Other intra-abdominal processes&#xD;
             that are not infectious.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has abdominal wall abscess or bowel obstruction without perforation or&#xD;
             ischemic bowel without perforation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant whose surgery will include staged abdominal repair, or &quot;open abdomen&quot;&#xD;
             technique, or marsupialization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has evidence of sepsis with shock not responding to IV fluid challenge or&#xD;
             anticipated to require the administration of vasopressors for &gt;24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has suspected intra-abdominal infections due to fungus, parasites (eg,&#xD;
             amebic liver abscess), virus, or tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is considered unlikely to survive the 6- to 8-week study period or has a&#xD;
             rapidly progressive or terminal illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has received systemic antibacterial agents within the 72-hour period prior&#xD;
             to study entry except for cases specified in the protocol such that participant is&#xD;
             considered to have failed the previous treatment regimen, or participant has received&#xD;
             systemic antibiotic agents no more than 24 hours (no more than one daily dose) within&#xD;
             the 72-hour period prior to study entry, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Estimated CrCL ≤50 mL/min calculated by Cockcroft-Gault method.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Pfizer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>1-800-718-1021</phone>
    <email>ClinicalTrials.gov_Inquiries@pfizer.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nagoya Ekisaikai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nagoya</city>
        <state>Aichi</state>
        <zip>454-8502</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Nagoya Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nagoya</city>
        <state>Aichi</state>
        <zip>460-0001</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Toyohashi Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toyohashi</city>
        <state>Aichi</state>
        <zip>440-8510</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fukuoka Tokushukai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kasuga</city>
        <state>Fukuoka</state>
        <zip>816-0864</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St.Mary's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kurume</city>
        <state>Fukuoka</state>
        <zip>830-8543</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fukuoka Shinmizumaki Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Onga-gun</city>
        <state>Fukuoka</state>
        <zip>807-0051</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saiseikai Maebashi Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maebashi</city>
        <state>Gunma</state>
        <zip>371-0821</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Fukuyama Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukuyama</city>
        <state>Hiroshima</state>
        <zip>720-8520</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Teine Keijinkai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sapporo</city>
        <state>Hokkaido</state>
        <zip>006-8555</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>KKR Sapporo Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sapporo</city>
        <state>Hokkaido</state>
        <zip>062-0931</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ishikawa Prefectural Central Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kanazawa</city>
        <state>Ishikawa</state>
        <zip>920-8530</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Kanazawa Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kanazawa</city>
        <state>Ishikawa</state>
        <zip>920-8650</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kawasaki Saiwai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kawasaki-shi</city>
        <state>Kanagawa</state>
        <zip>212-0014</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sagamihara Kyodo Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sagamihara</city>
        <state>Kanagawa</state>
        <zip>252-5188</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Yokohama Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yokohama</city>
        <state>Kanagawa</state>
        <zip>245-8575</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tohoku University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sendai</city>
        <state>Miyagi</state>
        <zip>980-8574</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Suwa Red Cross Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Suwa</city>
        <state>Nagano</state>
        <zip>392-8510</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Nagasaki Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Omura</city>
        <state>Nagasaki</state>
        <zip>856-8562</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nagaoka Chuo General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nagaoka</city>
        <state>Niigata</state>
        <zip>940-8653</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Naha City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Naha</city>
        <state>Okinawa</state>
        <zip>902-8511</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rinku General Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Izumisano</city>
        <state>Osaka</state>
        <zip>598-8577</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Osaka Minami Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kawachinagano</city>
        <state>Osaka</state>
        <zip>586-8521</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Higashi Ohmi General Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Higashiomi</city>
        <state>Shiga</state>
        <zip>527-8505</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yamanashi Prefectural Central Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kofu</city>
        <state>Yamanashi</state>
        <zip>400-8506</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Chiba Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chiba</city>
        <zip>260-8606</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fukui-Ken Saiseikai Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukui</city>
        <zip>918-8503</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fukuoka Wajiro Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukuoka</city>
        <zip>811-0213</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Kumamoto Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kumamoto</city>
        <zip>860-0008</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Hospital Organization Kyoto Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kyoto</city>
        <zip>612-8555</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Okayama City General Medical Center Okayama City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Okayama</city>
        <zip>700-8557</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Osaka Saiseikai Nakatsu Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Osaka</city>
        <zip>530-0012</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Toyama University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toyama</city>
        <zip>930-0194</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yamagata City Hospital Saiseikan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yamagata</city>
        <zip>990-8533</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pmiform.com/clinical-trial-info-request?StudyID=C3591036</url>
    <description>To obtain contact information for a study center near you, click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Ceftazidime-avibactam,</keyword>
  <keyword>Metronidazole,</keyword>
  <keyword>complicated intra-abdominal infection</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intraabdominal Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Metronidazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Pfizer will provide access to individual de-identified participant data and related study documents (e.g. protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP), Clinical Study Report (CSR)) upon request from qualified researchers, and subject to certain criteria, conditions, and exceptions. Further details on Pfizer's data sharing criteria and process for requesting access can be found at: https://www.pfizer.com/science/clinical_trials/trial_data_and_results/data_requests.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>https://www.pfizer.com/science/clinical_trials/trial_data_and_results/data_requests</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

