<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04920292</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P1773-20A</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04920292</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PK, Safety and Tolerability of Single and Multiple Doses of Oxfendazole Tablets</brief_title>
  <acronym>HELP-OFZ</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Bioavailability Study to Investigate the Pharmacokinetics, Safety and Tolerability of an Oxfendazole Tablet Formulation in a Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Design After Single and Multiple Oral Dosing in Healthy Adult Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Swiss Tropical &amp; Public Health Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ifakara Health Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Drugs for Neglected Diseases</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Swiss Tropical &amp; Public Health Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The study evaluates the pharmacokinetics (PK), safety and tolerability of oxfendazole, after&#xD;
      administration as a tablet formulation in healthy male and female participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, placebo-controlled, double blinded, single center phase I&#xD;
      bioavailability study with two Single Dose cohorts and one Multiple Doses cohort in a total&#xD;
      of 30 healthy male and female healthy volunteers (10 per cohort).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration curve from time zero to the last quantifiable concentration at time t (AUC0-t) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 48 hours after single dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For single dose arms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration curve (AUC) from time zero extrapolated to infinity (AUC0-∞) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 48 hours after single dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For single dose arms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed concentration (Cmax) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 48 hours after single dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For single dose arms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to maximum observed concentration (Tmax) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 48 hours after single dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For single dose arms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination half-life (t1/2) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 48 hours after single dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For single dose arms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration curve over dosing interval (AUCtau) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 72 hours after last dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For multiple doses arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accumulation Ratio (Racc) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 72 hours after last dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For multiple doses arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum observed concentration (Cmax) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 72 hours after last dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For multiple doses arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to maximum observed concentration (Tmax) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 72 hours after last dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For multiple doses arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Elimination half-life (t1/2) of oxfendazole and its metabolites fenbendazole and fenbendazole sulfone</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from pre-dose up to 72 hours after last dose administration</time_frame>
    <description>For multiple doses arm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of oxfendazole as measured by number of participants with treatment related adverse events and serious adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>From Day 1 to Day 14.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with treatment related adverse events and serious adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of oxfendazole as measured by number of participants with physical examination findings</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from baseline to Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with physical examination findings. Standard examination done on skin, lymph nodes, head, eyes, ears, nose, throat, respiratory, cardiovascular, abdomen, extremities, musculoskeletal, and neurological.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of oxfendazole as measured by number of participants with vital signs findings</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from baseline to Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with vital signs findings (heart rate, blood pressure, axillar temperature, respiratory rate,)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of oxfendazole as measured by number of participants with clinical laboratory test findings</measure>
    <time_frame>At different time points from baseline to Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with relevant abnormal clinical laboratory tests results (hematology (hemoglobin, white blood cells (differentiation of eosinophils and neutrophils) and platelets), coagulation (prothrombin time and activated partial thromboplastin time), biochemistry (Creatinine, Alanine aminotransferase, Aspartate aminotransferase, total bilirubin, sodium, potassium, chloride, bicarbonate, blood urea nitrogen), urinalysis (proteinuria and glucose))</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of oxfendazole as measured by number of participants with 12-lead ECG findings Safety and tolerability of oxfendazole as measured by the change in ECG parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-dose, 1 and 2 hours after single dose administration on Day 1; Pre-dose, 1 and 2 hours after dose administration on Day 1 and pre-dose, 1 and 2 hours after dose administration on Day 5 (last dose) for multiple doses administration arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with 12-lead ECG findings (heart rate (HR), PR interval, QRS, QT, QTcB, QTcF, cardiac rhythm and T wave morphology)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Filariasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Dose of 100mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>8 participants will receive a single oral dose of 100mg of oxfendazole. 2 participants will receive a single oral dose of placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Dose of 400mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>8 participants will receive a single oral dose of 400mg of oxfendazole. 2 participants will receive a single oral dose of placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple Doses of 400mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>8 participants will receive multiple oral doses of 400mg of oxfendazole on 5 consecutive days.&#xD;
2 participants will receive multiple oral doses of placebo on 5 consecutive days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oxfendazole</intervention_name>
    <description>Oxfendazole is a benzimidazole anthelminthic drug.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple Doses of 400mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Dose of 100mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Dose of 400mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>The placebo tablet is made using the same non-active ingredients and matches the investigational tablet.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Multiple Doses of 400mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Dose of 100mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Dose of 400mg Oxfendazole versus Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy adult male and non-pregnant (confirmed by pregnancy test) and&#xD;
             non-breastfeeding female participants (18 to 45 years of age at the time of consent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to give written consent to participate in the trial, after reading the&#xD;
             participant information and consent form and after having had the opportunity to&#xD;
             discuss the trial with the Investigator or any delegate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to read and write and to understand the participant information sheet and the&#xD;
             nature of the trial and any hazards from participating in it. Ability to communicate&#xD;
             satisfactorily with the Investigator and to participate in, and comply with the&#xD;
             requirements of, the entire trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must agree to use a highly effective form of&#xD;
             contraception in combination with a barrier method from at least 28 days prior to&#xD;
             first dosage to 30 days after last dosage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants must be willing to ensure the use of condoms from the first dosage&#xD;
             to 90 days after last dosage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal body weight range (body mass index (BMI) between 18 and 29.9 kg/ m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another clinical trial within 3 months prior to the study, or within&#xD;
             5-times the half-life of the drug tested in the previous clinical trial, whichever is&#xD;
             longer. (Time calculated relative to the last dose in the previous clinical trial).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular daily consumption of more than one liter of xanthine-containing beverages&#xD;
             (e.g. chocolates, tea, coffee or cola drinks).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Regular daily consumption of more than 5 cigarettes daily.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of a prescription medicine during the 28 days before the first dose of trial&#xD;
             medication or use of an over-the-counter medicine, during the 7 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of trial medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of dietary supplements or herbal remedies (such as St John's Wort) known to&#xD;
             interfere with the CYP3A4 and/or P-gp metabolic pathway during the 28 days before the&#xD;
             first dose of trial medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Therapies which may impact on the interpretation of study results in the opinion of&#xD;
             the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical, social condition, psychiatric disorder or occupational reasons that, in the&#xD;
             judgment of the Investigator, is a contraindication to protocol participation, may&#xD;
             impair the volunteer's ability to give informed consent or effectively participate in&#xD;
             the study, may significantly increase the risk to the volunteer because of&#xD;
             participation in the study or may impair interpretation of the study data.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood pressure and heart rate in supine position at the screening examination outside&#xD;
             one (or more) of the ranges 105-136 mm Hg systolic, 58-84 mm Hg diastolic; heart rate&#xD;
             56- 96 beats/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Febrile illness within 1 week before the start of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of relevant diseases of vital organs, of the central nervous system or other&#xD;
             organs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a history of allergies, non-allergic drug reactions, adverse&#xD;
             reaction to any drug, or multiple drug allergies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a hypersensitivity to the investigational drug, related&#xD;
             benzimidazole compounds or the control agent and/ or to inactive constituents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence or history of drug or alcohol abuse in the last 10 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgery (e.g. stomach bypass) or medical condition that might affect absorption of&#xD;
             study drug taken orally.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically relevant abnormal medical history, concurrent medical condition, acute or&#xD;
             chronic illness or history of chronic illness sufficient to invalidate the subject's&#xD;
             participation in the trial or make it unnecessarily hazardous.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Relevant pathological abnormalities in the ECG such as a second or third-degree&#xD;
             atrioventricular (AV) block, prolongation of the QRS complex over 120 msec or of the&#xD;
             QTcF-interval over 450 msec (corrected interval according to Fridericia's formula).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for hepatitis B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive pregnancy test (WOCBP).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive stool or urine test for helminth infestation by Kato-Katz, urine filtration&#xD;
             or Baermann test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive for malaria by thick blood smear.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for (neuro-) cysticercosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for echinococcosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive test for onchocerciasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of abnormal physical findings, ECG, or laboratory values at the screening&#xD;
             assessment that could interfere with the objectives of the trial or the safety of the&#xD;
             subject.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Paris</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Swiss TPH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eveline Ackermann</last_name>
    <phone>+41612848111</phone>
    <email>eveline.ackermann@swisstph.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Elisabeth Reus</last_name>
    <email>elisabeth.reus@swisstph.ch</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ifakara Health Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bagamoyo</city>
        <country>Tanzania</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Said Jongo</last_name>
      <email>sjongo@ihi.or.tz</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Said Jongo</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Tanzania</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Onchocerciasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Parasitic Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Neglected Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Phase I</keyword>
  <keyword>Safety</keyword>
  <keyword>Tolerability</keyword>
  <keyword>Pharmacokinetics</keyword>
  <keyword>Bioavailability</keyword>
  <keyword>Volunteers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Filariasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Oxfendazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>It is intended that Summary results will be shared once Clinical Study Report will be available.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

