<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04922528</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H21-01375</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04922528</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Visualization of the Extrahepatic biliaRy Tree Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>VERT</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluate the Efficacy of ICG Fluorescent Cholangiography for Visualization of Extrahepatic Biliary Anatomy in Emergency Cholecystectomy: A Single-Center, Randomized, Controlled, Parallel-Group Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective randomized controlled trial evaluating the use of a fluorescent&#xD;
      dye, indocyanine green (ICG), in the identification of important bile duct anatomy during&#xD;
      emergent same-admission cholecystectomy. Participants will be randomized into either the&#xD;
      control arm, which uses the standard of care white light during laparoscopy or the&#xD;
      intervention arm, which will use ICG fluorescent cholangiography as an adjunct to white light&#xD;
      to visualize the biliary anatomy. The investigators hypothesize that the use of fluorescent&#xD;
      cholangiography will increase the rates of identification of important biliary anatomy during&#xD;
      laparoscopic cholecystectomy. The effectiveness, feasibility, and safety will be compared&#xD;
      between the two groups using a post-operative survey form the surgeons will complete prior to&#xD;
      exiting the operating room.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Near-infrared fluorescent imaging techniques have shown promise in aiding to delineate and&#xD;
      visualize extrahepatic biliary structures. Indocyanine green (ICG) is a water-soluble&#xD;
      fluorescent dye that has been shown to improve visualization of biliary anatomy under&#xD;
      fluorescent cholangiography. The standard of care for many acute biliary disease conditions,&#xD;
      such as acute cholecystitis, remains early laparoscopic cholecystectomy. Even though&#xD;
      real-time fluorescent cholangiography using ICG has the potential to enhance the&#xD;
      visualization of biliary structures and anatomy, and therefore reduce the risk for bile duct&#xD;
      injury, the majority of the studies published to date exclude acute biliary disease patients.&#xD;
      The pathophysiology of acute biliary disease processes is associated with inflammation and&#xD;
      adhesions that increase the challenge of achieving a critical view of safety. The&#xD;
      investigators propose that using ICG and fluorescent cholangiography near-infrared imaging&#xD;
      techniques as an adjunct in acute care laparoscopic cholecystectomies has the potential to&#xD;
      help mitigate the increased risk of bile duct injury by increasing extrahepatic biliary&#xD;
      structure detection and surgeon confidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients will be identified through their initial clinical evaluation, which will be&#xD;
      verified by the patient's primary surgeon. If and once a patient has been confirmed as&#xD;
      eligible, the surgeon or designate will introduce the clinical trial design in detail. If&#xD;
      after being introduced to the study and having had the opportunity to ask questions, the&#xD;
      patient is willing to participate, the patient will be asked to review and sign the informed&#xD;
      consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon entry into the clinical trial, the allocation sequence will be generated using a block&#xD;
      randomization schema with computer-generated random numbers in a 1:1 ratio, with block sizes&#xD;
      of 4 by a co-investigator with no clinical involvement in the trial. The same co-investigator&#xD;
      will prepare sequentially numbered, opaque, sealed and stapled envelopes and stored them in a&#xD;
      locked cabinet in the operating room control desk. Each envelope contained instructions for&#xD;
      the arm the participant had been randomly assigned to, either treatment (ICG cholangiography)&#xD;
      or control (standard white light only) arms. After the research team member has obtained the&#xD;
      participant's consent, the surgeon or designates will obtain the next consecutively numbered&#xD;
      envelope and proceed to open it after the patient is anesthetized and prior to beginning the&#xD;
      surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patient will be blinded to the result of the randomization until after surgery as the&#xD;
      envelope will be opened only after the patient has received their general anesthetic. No&#xD;
      blinding of the surgical team, research team members or outcomes assessors will be used in&#xD;
      this study given the procedural nature and acute condition of the patients included.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The intervention and comparator arms will be ran in parallel, with a block randomization sequence determining the participants allocations.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Due to the procedural nature of the intervention, we have chosen to run this trial single-blinding, with only the participant being masked to the intervention.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection rate of extrahepatic biliary structures</measure>
    <time_frame>Intraoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>The extrahepatic biliary structures which we will be assessing the identification of include: Cystic Duct (CD), Right Hepatic Duct (RHD), Common Hepatic Duct (CHD), Common Bile Duct (CBD), Cystic Duct - Gall Bladder junction (CD-GB), and Cystic Duct - Common Bile Duct junction (CD-CBD).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Operative success</measure>
    <time_frame>Intraoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of laparoscopic subtotal cholecystectomy and laparoscopic cholecystostomy tube placement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rates of conversion</measure>
    <time_frame>Intraoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of conversion to open cholecystectomy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Operative time</measure>
    <time_frame>Intraoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>From the time of opening the skin to the time of closure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Surgeon satisfaction</measure>
    <time_frame>Through participant discharge, an average of 1 week</time_frame>
    <description>Operating surgeons satisfaction (as rated by post-procedural survey) with the utility and feasibility of the modality.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Through participant discharge, an average of 1 week</time_frame>
    <description>Any adverse events associated with the administration or use of ICG fluorescent cholangiography</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Procedural complications</measure>
    <time_frame>Through participant discharge, an average of 1 week</time_frame>
    <description>Any complications associated with the cholecystectomy</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">340</enrollment>
  <condition>Cholecystitis, Acute</condition>
  <condition>Acute Cholangitis</condition>
  <condition>Gallstone Pancreatitis</condition>
  <condition>Choledocholithiasis</condition>
  <condition>Cholecystolithiasis</condition>
  <condition>Gallbladder Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Biliary Tract Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Digestive System Disease</condition>
  <condition>Calculi</condition>
  <condition>Pathological Conditions, Anatomical</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Near-Infrared Fluorescence Cholangiography</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard laparoscopic cholecystectomy completed with a combination of white light imaging and near-Infrared fluorescence cholangiography after administering 5 mg of a 25 mg/10 mL solution of indocyanine green (ICG) intravenously prior to the operation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>White Light Imaging</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard laparoscopic cholecystectomy completed with only standard white light imaging only</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy with Fluorescent Cholangiography</intervention_name>
    <description>Indocyanine green is a fluorophore molecule which is metabolized by the liver and excreted exclusively through the biliary system. Intra-operatively, near-infared imaging via the laparoscope will be used to visualize the biliary anatomy in the intervention arm, as an adjunct to standard of care white-light imaging.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Near-Infrared Fluorescence Cholangiography</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy with White Light Imaging</intervention_name>
    <description>As per the current standard of care, patients undergoing laparoscopic cholecystectomies will have it completed using white light imaging through the laparoscope.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Near-Infrared Fluorescence Cholangiography</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>White Light Imaging</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admission or consultation by the Acute Care Surgery (ACS) service&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of acute biliary disease requiring index laparoscopic cholecystectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnoses of acute cholangitis, choledocholithiasis, and gall stone pancreatitis may&#xD;
             be included. However, they must have cleared ducts confirmed via endoscopic&#xD;
             ultrasound, ultrasound, ERCP, and/or laboratory investigations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and follow study procedures and protocols, and provide signed&#xD;
             informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant or currently breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known pre-existing liver disease, including cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to iodine or shellfish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to indocyanine green (ICG)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean Philip Dawe, CD MD FRCSC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Clinical Assistant Professor</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Karan J D'Souza, MD MPH MM</last_name>
    <phone>6048755094</phone>
    <email>karan.dsouza@alumni.ubc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jean Philip Dawe, CD MD FRCSC</last_name>
    <phone>6048755094</phone>
    <email>philip.dawe@vch.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vancouver General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V5Z 1M9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jean Philip Dawe, CD MD FRCSC</last_name>
      <phone>6048755094</phone>
      <email>philip.dawe@vch.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Karan J D'Souza, MD MPH MM</last_name>
      <phone>6048755094</phone>
      <email>karan.dsouza@alumni.ubc.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zroback C, Chow G, Meneghetti A, Warnock G, Meloche M, Chiu CJ, Panton ON. Fluorescent cholangiography in laparoscopic cholecystectomy: the initial Canadian experience. Am J Surg. 2016 May;211(5):933-7. doi: 10.1016/j.amjsurg.2016.01.013. Epub 2016 Feb 23.</citation>
    <PMID>27151917</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bleszynski MS, DeGirolamo KM, Meneghetti AT, Chiu CJ, Panton ON. Fluorescent Cholangiography in Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy: An Updated Canadian Experience. Surg Innov. 2020 Feb;27(1):38-43. doi: 10.1177/1553350619885792. Epub 2019 Nov 19.</citation>
    <PMID>31744398</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of British Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Philip Dawe</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cholangiography</keyword>
  <keyword>Indocyanine green</keyword>
  <keyword>ICG</keyword>
  <keyword>Fluorescent cholangiography</keyword>
  <keyword>Biliary Anatomy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholangitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecystitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gallstones</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholelithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecystolithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Digestive System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gastrointestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Choledocholithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gallbladder Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Biliary Tract Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cholecystitis, Acute</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Calculi</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pathological Conditions, Anatomical</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

