<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04921436</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10031967MM</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04921436</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Modulation of Microbiota Metabolism in Cardiac Surgery Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>MMMMODCS</acronym>
  <official_title>Modulation of Microbiota Metabolism in Cardiac Surgery Patients With at High Risk of Postoperative Multiple Organ Dysfunctions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Petrovsky National Research Centre of Surgery</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Federal Research and Clinical Centre of Intensive Care Medicine and Rehabilitology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Petrovsky National Research Centre of Surgery</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      An imbalance in the microbiota (most often intestinal) largely determines the onset of a&#xD;
      disease state, and often a critical state. Cardiac surgery accompanied by heart failure and&#xD;
      hypoperfusion is a proven risk factor for the development of metabolic disorders of the&#xD;
      intestinal flora and bacterial translocation. Previously, it was shown that the change in&#xD;
      serum concentrations of phenolic metabolites of the intestinal microbiota reflects the&#xD;
      dynamics of the severity of the patient's condition and can be used for objective monitoring&#xD;
      of treatment. Preoperative analysis of microbial metabolites makes it possible to reliably&#xD;
      identify the group of patients with the highest risk of developing postoperative organ&#xD;
      dysfunctions. In patients with a baseline level of the sum of phenolic acid concentrations&#xD;
      over 3.5 mmol / L, the likelihood of postoperative complications is 10 times higher (OR -&#xD;
      10.5; 95% CI 1.35-81.7, p = 0.026). Reducing the metabolic activity of opportunistic bacteria&#xD;
      and the level of aromatic microbial metabolites associated with sepsis through the&#xD;
      prophylactic use of antibiotics belonging to the group of protein synthesis inhibitors at the&#xD;
      level of bacterial cell ribosomes is of great interest.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      MMMMODCS (Modulation of Microbiota Metabolism Multiple Organ Dysfunctions in Cardiac Surgery)&#xD;
      is a single-center clinical study, during which it is planned to study the safety and&#xD;
      efficacy of the perioperative use of antibiotic inhibitors of protein synthesis at the&#xD;
      ribosome level of bacterial cells (hereinafter: antibiotic inhibitors) in patients with high&#xD;
      the risk of developing multiple organ dysfunction (MOD) of infectious genesis. The high-risk&#xD;
      group is represented by patients who are planned to have surgery on the thoracoabdominal&#xD;
      aorta; combined operations on coronary vessels and heart valves; patients with initially low&#xD;
      heart ejection fraction (less than 45%). The study was designed to find out if the&#xD;
      prophylactic use of a combination of antibiotic inhibitors prevents an increase in&#xD;
      concentration (or contributes to a decrease with an initial increase) of aromatic microbial&#xD;
      metabolites (AMM) above 3.5 mmol / L and the development of MOD, requiring a long stay in an&#xD;
      intensive care unit more than 6 days). After signing an informed consent prior to surgery,&#xD;
      patients will be randomized into one of two cohorts: with or without a combination of&#xD;
      antibiotic inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a cohort with prophylactic treatment, in addition to standard antibiotic prophylaxis (I,&#xD;
      II generation cephalosporins), combinations of the following antibiotic inhibitors&#xD;
      (Doxycycline or Rimfampicin + Gentamicin or Clarithromycin) will be used orally or&#xD;
      intravenously, depending on the patient's condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The AMM level will be measured in blood serum samples on a gas chromatography-mass&#xD;
      spectrometer before the operation, on the 3rd and 6th days after the operation. The rest of&#xD;
      the indicators will be discussed at the same points.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>In group I, antibiotics-inhibitors of microbial metabolism are used in the perioperative period and the next 2 postoperative days The second group uses standard antibiotic prophylaxis</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>the first patient gets into the group of preventive therapy, the next one does not get into the group, and so on (1:1)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AMM level</measure>
    <time_frame>3 - 6 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>the frequency of detecting patients with an AMM level in the blood serum of no more than 3.5 μmol / l (according to the results of GC-MS analysis)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the duration of stay in the ICU</measure>
    <time_frame>one week</time_frame>
    <description>the frequency of detecting patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse events associated with taking antibiotics (allergic / anaphylactic reactions); cases of sepsis (according to the criteria of Sepsis-3) / septic shock; patients with SOFA more than 7 points more</measure>
    <time_frame>6 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>the frequency of detecting patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Organ Dysfunction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cardiac surgery patients with preventive treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In addition to standard antibiotic prophylaxis (cefazolin 2 g 60 minutes before skin incision and 2 g 3 times a day after surgery), the following antibiotic regimens will be used perioperatively:&#xD;
Doxycycline (the day before surgery 200 mg and 100 mg on days 1 and 2 after surgery) or Rimfampicin (150 mg 2 times a day before and after surgery) + Gentamicin (240 mg 3 times a day before and 2 days after surgery) or Clarithromycin (500 mg once daily for up to 2 days after surgery).&#xD;
The route of administration (oral / intravenous) will depend on the condition of the patient.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>cardiac surgery patients without preventive treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>standard antibiotic prophylaxis (cefazolin 2 g 60 minutes before skin incision and 2 g 3 times a day after surgery)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cardiac surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>prophylactic use of antibiotic-inhibitors</description>
    <arm_group_label>cardiac surgery patients with preventive treatment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with aneurysmal aortic disease / aortic rupture;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with ischemic heart disease and dysfunction of the valves;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with initially low heart ejection fraction (less than 45%)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  tolerance to antibacterial drugs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  taking oncological chemotherapy drugs;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  taking probiotics and nutritional supplements within the last month;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  intraoperative complications (shock of any etiology, allergic reactions).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>MAXIM BABAEV, D.Sc.(medical)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Petrovsky National Research Centre of Surgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>MAXIM BABAEV, D.Sc.(medical)</last_name>
    <phone>+79160269066</phone>
    <email>maxbabaev@mail.ru</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Petrovsky National Reasearch Centre of Surgery</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <zip>119991</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>MAXIM BABAEV, D.Sc.(medical)</last_name>
      <phone>89160269066</phone>
      <email>maxbabaev@mail.ru</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>microbiota;</keyword>
  <keyword>sepsis;</keyword>
  <keyword>antibiotics;</keyword>
  <keyword>cardiac surgery</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

