<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04923035</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MISP #60200</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04923035</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Paediatric Pneumococcal Pneumonia in Malaysia Prior to and During Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine (PCV) Implementation</brief_title>
  <acronym>MSIP PCV</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Burden of Paediatric Pneumococcal Pneumonia in Malaysia Prior to and During Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine (PCV) Implementation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>International Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Malaya</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universiti Sains Malaysia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>International Islamic University Malaysia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Southampton</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>International Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this research is to provide baseline surveillance of pneumonia in young&#xD;
      children in Malaysia before and during the implementation of the pneumococcal conjugate&#xD;
      vaccine (PCV). Pneumonia is a respiratory infection that can cause mild to life-threatening&#xD;
      disease among all age groups but is the leading infectious cause of death among children&#xD;
      globally. The most common cause of pneumonia is infection with a bacteria called&#xD;
      Streptococcus pneumoniae, also known as pneumococcus. Hence, immunisation with a pneumococcal&#xD;
      vaccine is an effective way to prevent pneumonia. In Malaysia, pneumococcal vaccination under&#xD;
      the National Immunisation Programme (NIP) for children has since commenced in December 2020,&#xD;
      comprising of 3 doses at four, six and 15 months. The routine use of PCV in children will&#xD;
      contribute to reducing the burden of pneumococcal infections in the country, especially&#xD;
      severe infections. The ongoing COVID-19 pandemic may also have implications on the&#xD;
      pneumococcal serotype and clinical presentation of infections in the community.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will be a multi-centre prospective case-control study and the recruitment of&#xD;
      clinically diagnosed pneumonia patients and healthy controls aged 5 years and below will be&#xD;
      conducted at the three university hospitals; University Malaya Medical Centre (UMMC), Sultan&#xD;
      Ahmad Shah Medical Centre@International Islamic University Malaysia (SASMEC@IIUM) and&#xD;
      Hospital University Sains Malaysia (HUSM). Subject recruitment and sample collection will be&#xD;
      carried out for 24 months. Informed consent and general questionnaire will be administrated&#xD;
      by the on-site researchers. Clinical samples will be taken according to approved protocol and&#xD;
      local policy to include nasopharyngeal (NP) swab and urine sample. NP swab in a transport&#xD;
      medium will be store at -80°C before shipment to the International Medical University (IMU)&#xD;
      Advanced Microbiology Collaborative Research Laboratory (AMCRL) in Kuala Lumpur for&#xD;
      polymerase chain reaction (PCR) analysis. The data obtained may provide crucial data to&#xD;
      support policy decisions on pneumococcal vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      . Specific Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine the prevalence of Streptococcus pneumoniae (SPN) nasopharyngeal (NP)&#xD;
           carriage among children 5 years of age and below with pneumonia and invasive pneumonia&#xD;
           disease (IPD) using polymerase chain reaction (PCR) analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To determine SPN serotypes in young children during the coronavirus disease 2019&#xD;
           (COVID-19) pandemic by whole-genome sequencing analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To identify potential changes in clinical presentation and severity of pneumococcal&#xD;
           infection in young children during the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To evaluate the correlations between SPN serotypes detected in NP carriage and urine&#xD;
           sample from the same individual/child.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. To estimate sensitivity and specificity for SPN serotypes detection in urine among&#xD;
           children with pneumonia and IPD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Nasopharyngeal (NP) pneumococcal carriages prevalence rate among young children</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The absence/presence of nasopharyngeal pneumococcal carriages will be tested using standard bacteriological methods and Streptococcus Pneumoniae (SPN) isolates will be inoculated for DNA extraction and further tested by polymerase chain reaction (PCR) for pneumococcal carriage detection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Streptococcus pneumoniae (SPN) detection in urine samples among young children</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the correlations between SPN isolates detected in NP carriage and urine sample from the same individual/child.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Pneumonia, Pneumococcal</condition>
  <condition>Pneumonia Childhood</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Case</arm_group_label>
    <description>Children aged 5 years and below with clinically diagnosed pneumonia and attending the outpatient's department or admitted as a hospital inpatient at three sentinel sites. Pneumonia. Suspected pneumonia cases will be identified by a family physician or paediatrician based on medical history and clinical symptoms.&#xD;
Pneumonia is defined as (WHO Fact Sheet 2019) patient with history of:&#xD;
cough and/or&#xD;
difficulty/rapid breathing and/or&#xD;
intercostal recession,&#xD;
with or without fever. and supported by chest x-ray findings.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy children aged 5 years and below without any intercurrent respiratory illness and who is in good health as determined by a brief medical history and/or clinical judgement of the investigator whose parent/LAR is willing and able to give informed consent.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Nasopharyngeal swab and urine sample for cases and control aged 5 years and below.&#xD;
      Nasopharyngeal swab will be cultured and Streptococcus Pneumoniae isolates will be inoculated&#xD;
      for DNA extraction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a prospective case-control study in which all children aged 5 years and below with&#xD;
        clinically diagnosed community-acquired pneumonia and healthy controls will be recruited at&#xD;
        three study sites. As per assumptions of 95% confidence interval (CI), 80% power and&#xD;
        detectable odds ratio (OR) of 1.5, The investigators estimate 164 cases and 164 healthy&#xD;
        controls per each sentinel hospital site. Thus, the investigators aim to recruit a total of&#xD;
        500 confirmed pneumonia cases and 500 healthy controls for this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Any child aged 5 years and below who meets the case and control definition and whose&#xD;
        parent/legal authorized representative (LAR) is willing to give consent on his/her behalf.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  who does not meet the case and control definition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  whose parent/guardian does not give consent on his/her behalf&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  who has nasal surgery&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>5 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lokman Hakim H Sulaiman, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>International Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nurul Hanis Ramzi, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+60173396532</phone>
    <email>nurulhanis@imu.edu.my</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Nur Alia Johari, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+60 12-234 5651</phone>
    <email>NurAliaJohari@imu.edu.my</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Malaya Medical Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kuala Lumpur</city>
        <state>Federal Territory Of Kuala Lumpur</state>
        <zip>57000</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anna Marie Nathan, PhD</last_name>
      <email>psr9900@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Cindy Teh, PhD</last_name>
      <email>cindysjteh@um.edu.my</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anna Marie Nathan, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universiti Sains Malaysia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kota Bharu</city>
        <state>Kelantan</state>
        <zip>16150</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mohd Ikram Illias, MBBS</last_name>
      <email>drikram@usm.my</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mohd Ikram Illias, MBBS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sultan Ahmad Shah Medical Centre @International Islamic University Malaysia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kuantan</city>
        <state>Pahang</state>
        <zip>57000</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Muhd Alwi, MBBS</last_name>
      <email>muhdalwi@iium.edu.my</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Asrar Abu Bakar, MBBS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>La Vincente SF, von Mollendorf C, Ulziibayar M, Satzke C, Dashtseren L, Fox KK, Dunne EM, Nguyen CD, de Campo J, de Campo M, Thomson H, Surenkhand G, Demberelsuren S, Bujinlkham S, Do LAH, Narangerel D, Cherian T, Mungun T, Mulholland EK. Evaluation of a phased pneumococcal conjugate vaccine introduction in Mongolia using enhanced pneumonia surveillance and community carriage surveys: a study protocol for a prospective observational study and lessons learned. BMC Public Health. 2019 Mar 21;19(1):333. doi: 10.1186/s12889-019-6639-y.</citation>
    <PMID>30898094</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Adetifa IMO, Adamu AL, Karani A, Waithaka M, Odeyemi KA, Okoromah CAN, Bello MM, Abubakar IS, Inem V, Scott JAG. Nasopharyngeal Pneumococcal Carriage in Nigeria: a two-site, population-based survey. Sci Rep. 2018 Feb 22;8(1):3509. doi: 10.1038/s41598-018-21837-5.</citation>
    <PMID>29472635</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>International Medical University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lokman Hakim Sulaiman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Institute of Research, Development and Innovation (IRDI)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>surveillance</keyword>
  <keyword>polymerase chain reaction</keyword>
  <keyword>whole-genome sequencing</keyword>
  <keyword>pneumococcal urine antigen detection</keyword>
  <keyword>correlation analysis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia, Pneumococcal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

