<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04926467</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>020-476</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04926467</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chemotherapy + Anakinra in Patients With Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma (PDAC)</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open Label, Phase II Study of Chemotherapy + Anakinra in Patients With Resectable, Locally Advanced or Potentially Resectable Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma (PDAC)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Baylor Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Baylor Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Based on a central role of inflammation in pancreas cancer, the role of IL 1 in acute and&#xD;
      chronic inflammation , the inhibitory effect of IL 1 alfa and beta by anakinra and&#xD;
      preliminary experience with anakinra in combination with chemotherapy in metastasis (with&#xD;
      FOLFIRINOX) and localized disease (with gemcitabine/abraxane/cisplatin), a phase 2 study with&#xD;
      anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy for patients with PDAC is being&#xD;
      proposed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open-label, single-arm, prospective phase II study conducted by Baylor Scott and&#xD;
      White Research Institute in Dallas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will enroll patients with pancreatic adenocarcinoma that are planned to receive&#xD;
      pre-operative chemotherapy followed by surgical resection and post operative treatment. Local&#xD;
      surgical/biopsy and pathology reports will constitute adequate documentation of&#xD;
      histology/cytology for study inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive pre- and post-operative chemotherapy plus Anakinra. Specifically, the&#xD;
      pre-operative chemotherapy regimen will be a combination of Nab-paclitaxel, gemcitabine and&#xD;
      cisplatin, while post-operative chemotherapy will use 5-Fluorouracil, oxaliplatin, and&#xD;
      irinotecan. Patients will also receive growth factor (Neupogen followed by Neulasta) for&#xD;
      safety and to ensure that treatment is not delayed due to neutropenic effects of&#xD;
      chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anakinra will be self-administered by the participants through out the treatment period. A&#xD;
      treatment break of 2 days will be given prior to the surgery day.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the percentage of patients that have a normalization of CA19-9 after pre-op treatment with the combination of nab-paclitaxel (abraxane), gemcitabine, cisplatin and anakinra.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the effect of anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy on overall survival (OS) of PDAC patients. A benchmark of 24 months OS will be used to determine how many patients meet or exceed this goal.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the effect of anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy on the median disease free survival (DFS). A benchmark of 12 months DFS will be used to determine how many patients meet or exceed this goal.</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the effect of anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy on response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the R0 resection rates (complete tumor removal with negative resection margins) obtained with anakinra + pre-operative chemotherapy.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To describe the effect of anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy on the prevalence and severity of pain by monitoring patients' pain level using memorial pain assessment card (MPAC).</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the effect of anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy on patients' health-related quality of life by monitoring patients using EORTC quality of life survey questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-C30).</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the effect of anakinra in combination with perioperative chemotherapy on the inflammasomes ( IL6, CRP, IL1α and IL1β) in blood and in the resected pathology specimens.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Pancreatic Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anakinra plus Chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive Anakinra during both pre-operative chemotherapy with Nab-paclitaxel, gemcitabine and cisplatin, followed by surgery and post-operative chemotherapy with 5-fluorouracil, oxaliplatin, and irinotecan.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anakinra</intervention_name>
    <description>Pre-operative treatment: Nab-paclitaxel (125 mg/m2), gemcitabine (1000 mg/m2), and cisplatin (25 mg/m2) will be given on Day 1 and 8 of a 21-day cycle. Patients will receive anakinra 100 mg injection twice a day starting on day 1 of chemotherapy. Anakinra will be self-administered by the patients and will be discontinued 2 days prior to surgery. Total number of cycles = 4.&#xD;
Post-operative treatment: 5-Fluorouracil (2400 mg/m2 CI for 48 hours), oxaliplatin (85 mg/m2), and irinotecan (150 mg/m2) will be given once every 2 weeks (1 cycle =14 days). Patients will receive anakinra 100 mg injection subcutaneously twice a day starting on day 1 of chemotherapy (initiated within 4-8 weeks after surgery). Anakinra will be self-administered by the patient throughout the treatment without any break. Total number of cycles = 8.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anakinra plus Chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A patient will be eligible for inclusion in this study if he or she meets all of the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Histologically or Cytologically confirmed pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Mixed&#xD;
                  subtypes of adenocarcinoma are acceptable as long as majority of cells are ductal&#xD;
                  adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Resectable, locally advanced or potentially resectable pancreatic adenocarcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. American Joint Committee on Cancer (AJCC) Stage I-III Pancreatic carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patient has Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group( ECOG ) Performance Status 0 to 1&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Serum albumin ≥2.0 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Adequate hematologic function as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ≥1500/mm3;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Platelets ≥70,000 x 10^3/µl;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Hemoglobin ≥9 g/dL (in the absence of red blood transfusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Adequate liver function, as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Serum total bilirubin ≤2 x ULN mg/dL, prior to initiation of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. ALT (SGPT) and AST (SGOT) ≤2.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Adequate renal function, as defined by serum creatinine≤ 1.5 x ULN, or creatinine&#xD;
                  clearance ≥50 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Women of child bearing potential and men must agree to use contraception&#xD;
                  throughout the study and for one month after the last anakinra administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Subjects must understand and sign the informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Patients must be accessible for treatment and follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A patient will be ineligible for inclusion in this study if he or she meets any of the&#xD;
             following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. &lt;18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. History of organ transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients with islet cell neoplasms&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients with stage IV pancreatic carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Active, uncontrolled bacterial, viral, or fungal infection(s) requiring systemic&#xD;
                  therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Known active infection with hepatitis B or hepatitis C&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Presence of clinically significant cirrhosis as determined by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Known HIV positive status.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Current, active immunosuppressive therapy such as cyclosporine, tacrolimus, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Major surgery or vascular device placement within 2 weeks prior to Day 1 of&#xD;
                  treatment in study&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Prior chemotherapy or radiation for pancreatic cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. History of allergy or hypersensitivity to the study drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Patient is enrolled in any outside therapeutic clinical protocol or&#xD;
                  investigational trial with an investigational drug within 5 half-lives prior to&#xD;
                  Study ID assignment&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Previous or current treatment with anakinra, canakinumab or any other IL-1&#xD;
                  inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. Other malignancy within five years(except cutaneous, non-melanoma malignancies or&#xD;
                  cervical carcinoma in site), unless the probability of recurrence of the prior&#xD;
                  malignancy is &lt;5% as determined by the Principal Investigator based on available&#xD;
                  information.&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Significant cardiac disease (uncontrolled congestive heart failure (CHF),&#xD;
                  myocardial infarction or significant ventricular arrhythmias) within the last six&#xD;
                  months.&#xD;
&#xD;
              17. Other severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions (e.g: prior gastrointestinal&#xD;
                  (GI) disease or history of prior pelvic or abdominal radiation) or other&#xD;
                  conditions deemed by investigator as unsuitable for participation/enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
              18. Peripheral sensory neuropathy &gt; or equal to grade 2 at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
              19. Abnormal liver function tests as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Total bilirubin of &gt; 2 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. AST or ALT &gt; 5x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
              20. Serum albumin ˂ 2.0 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
              21. Abnormal hematologic function as follows :&#xD;
&#xD;
                    1. Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) ˂ 1500/mm3;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    2. Platelets ˂ 70,000 x 10^3/µl;&#xD;
&#xD;
                    3. Hemoglobin ˂ 9 g/dL (in the absence of red blood transfusion).&#xD;
&#xD;
              22. Pregnant or nursing women&#xD;
&#xD;
              23. No signed Informed consent form&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos Becerra, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Charles A. Sammons Cancer Center/Texas Oncology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Heather Williams, MS</last_name>
    <phone>(214) 818-7879</phone>
    <email>Heather.Williams1@BSWHealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Joyce Ghormley</last_name>
    <phone>(214) 818-8961</phone>
    <email>Joyce.Ghormley@BSWHealth.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor University Medical Center, Charles A Sammons Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75246</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Interleukin 1 Receptor Antagonist Protein</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

