<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04926207</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20633</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04926207</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of Interrupting Prolonged Sitting With Bouts of Physical Activity on Neurocognitive Function in Obesity</brief_title>
  <acronym>SITLess</acronym>
  <official_title>SIT Less! Interrupting Prolonged Sitting With Brief Physical Activity Bouts to Improve Neurocognitive Function in Adults With Obesity</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is projected that by 2030 almost 50% of adults in the USA will have obesity. High&#xD;
      sedentariness and physical inactivity contribute to the obesity pandemic. Neurocognitive&#xD;
      deficits compound the global burden of obesity. Specifically, adults with obesity&#xD;
      underperform on tasks of executive functioning, which underpin goal-directed behavior and&#xD;
      have been linked to occupational success. Growing evidence suggests poorer executive&#xD;
      functioning among more sedentary adults. Emergent studies have shown that accumulating&#xD;
      sedentary time in prolonged bouts (e.g., remaining sedentary continuously 20 min or more) may&#xD;
      decrease the ability to control distractions along with working memory. Interrupting&#xD;
      prolonged sitting with brief bouts of physical activity is an effective strategy to improve&#xD;
      postprandial glucose metabolism. However, the effects of this simple intervention on neural&#xD;
      processes supporting executive functioning remain unknown. Accordingly, the aim of this study&#xD;
      is to test the effects of interrupting prolonged sitting with frequent (every 30 min) but&#xD;
      brief (3 min) physical activity bouts on inhibitory control, working memory, and their&#xD;
      neuroelectric indices (N2, P3a, and P3b components of event-related brain potentials). Our&#xD;
      secondary aim is to explore the potential mechanisms underlying the effects of interrupting&#xD;
      prolonged sitting with physical activity on cognitive and brain function through glucose&#xD;
      metabolism and insulin physiology. Findings from this study will help advance our&#xD;
      understanding of how restructuring sedentary time may help improve cognitive and brain&#xD;
      functions among adults with obesity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Measurements of cognitive and brain function will be taken before, and after three hours of&#xD;
      prolonged sitting. Metabolic, heart rate, and blood pressure measures, along with the ratings&#xD;
      of fatigue will be collected before and during the three-hour prolonged sitting time. The&#xD;
      prolonged sitting time will be either interrupted with physical activity breaks or with&#xD;
      sedentary breaks (attention control). Habitual physical activity, sedentary behavior, sleep,&#xD;
      and dietary intake will also be assessed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuroelectric measures of inhibitory control - P3 component of event-related potentials (ERPs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in the P3 component measured during the modified flanker task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuroelectric measures of inhibitory control - N2 component of event-related potentials (ERPs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in the N2-ERP component measured during the modified flanker task.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Inhibitory control measured with a modified flanker task - accuracy</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in accuracy on the modified flanker task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Inhibitory control measured with a modified flanker task - reaction time</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in measures of reaction time on the modified flanker task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuroelectric measures of working memory - P3-ERP component</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in the P3-ERP component during the n-back task.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Working memory measured with an n-back task - accuracy</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in accuracy on the n-back task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Working memory measured with an n-back task - reaction time</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed immediately before and after the intervention (on the same day as intervention)</time_frame>
    <description>The difference between experimental and control conditions in measures of reaction time on the n-back task</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-prandial insulin response during an oral glucose tolerance test</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Insulin Area Under the Curve (AUC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-prandial glucose response during an oral glucose tolerance test</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Glucose Area Under the Curve (AUC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Matsuda index</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Insulin Sensitivity measured with Matsuda index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stumvoll metabolic clearance rate (MCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed during the intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Insulin Sensitivity expressed as Stumvoll metabolic clearance rate</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physical Activity Breaks Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will sit continuously for 3 hours and interrupt their sitting by walking on a treadmill at a moderate intensity for 3 min.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Talking Breaks Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will sit continuously for 3 hours. They will interrupt solitary sitting activities (while remaining seated) by talking to a researcher for 3 min on pre-selected topics of general interest.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical Activity Breaks Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be asked to walk on a treadmill for 3 min at a moderate intensity (55% of heart rate reserve) at an increasing speed and incline to reach and maintain their target heart rate.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physical Activity Breaks Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Talking Breaks Control</intervention_name>
    <description>Every 30 min a researcher will start a brief conversation with a participant based on a pre-selected topic, which will change with each break. Topics are standardized across participants and include, for example, pollution, smart clothes, and hydration. A presentation will be followed by questions and answers. The break will last 3 min.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Talking Breaks Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age 21-55 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  BMI within ≥ 30 and &lt; 40 kg/m2 range&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pre-menopausal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fasting plasma glucose (FPG) &lt; 100 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Resting blood pressure: systolic &lt; 160 mmHg or diastolic &lt; 100 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Employed in sedentary occupation (i.e., participants reporting sitting on average&#xD;
                  6 h/d on a weekday and with objectively assessed sitting time ≥ 8 h/day)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Physically inactive (i.e., engaging in &lt; 150 min of moderate or &lt; 75 min of&#xD;
                  vigorous or any combination of the two intensities per week)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants must have had no prior diagnosis of cognitive or physical disability&#xD;
                  (e.g., ADHD, severe asthma, epilepsy, chronic kidney disease, or dependence upon&#xD;
                  a wheelchair/walking aid)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Free of medication that could affect cognitive function or metabolism&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Normal or corrected-to-normal vision based on the minimal 20/20 standard in order&#xD;
                  to complete the cognitive task (below 20/20 vision)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Must be able to engage in vigorous exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fluency in English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Impaired glucose tolerance defined as fasting plasma glucose (FPG) &lt; 100 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT) blood glucose values ≥ 200 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with any psychiatric, neurological or metabolic disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants who have or are currently taking the medication that could affect&#xD;
                  cognitive function, metabolism or weight status&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with a standardized score on the test of general cognitive abilities&#xD;
                  below 85&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Participants with anemia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant women or those with a possible pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of injury to the spinal cord&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dominika M Pindus, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dominika M Pindus, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>1217300-7317</phone>
    <email>pindus@illinois.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign</name>
      <address>
        <city>Urbana</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>61801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Dominika M Pindus, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>217-300-7317</phone>
      <email>pindus@illinois.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sedentary Behavior</keyword>
  <keyword>Executive Function</keyword>
  <keyword>Event Related Potentials</keyword>
  <keyword>Insulin</keyword>
  <keyword>Glucose</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

