<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04924400</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0438</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04924400</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Complete Health Improvement Program for Geisinger Health Plan Members With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <acronym>CHIP-RCT</acronym>
  <official_title>Complete Health Improvement Program to Improve Glycemic Control and Reduce Cost of Care for Geisinger Health Plan Members With Type 2 Diabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Thomas Morland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Geisinger Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Complete Health Improvement Program (CHIP) is a lifestyle improvement program intended to&#xD;
      prevent and/or manage cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and other health conditions. This is&#xD;
      a pilot-scale randomized-controlled trial comparing the clinical, utilization, and financial&#xD;
      outcomes of adult health plan members with type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) offered CHIP&#xD;
      versus those only offered standard health plan coverage. We hypothesize that Geisinger Health&#xD;
      Plan (GHP) members with T2DM offered CHIP in addition to standard insurance coverage will&#xD;
      have improvement in HbA1c and improvements in other biometrics, biomarkers, psychometrics and&#xD;
      utilization/financial outcomes, including LDL-C, systolic blood pressure, body mass index,&#xD;
      waist circumference, number of diabetes medications prescribed, Wellbeing360 survey, and&#xD;
      total cost of healthcare.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a pilot prospective randomized-controlled trial of 60 patients randomized to either&#xD;
      the intervention group; in which patients enroll in the CHIP program, or the control group,&#xD;
      in which patients follow their usual diabetes care. We hypothesize that Geisinger Health Plan&#xD;
      members with T2DM offered CHIP in addition to standard insurance coverage will have&#xD;
      improvement in HbA1c and improvements in other biometrics, biomarkers, psychometrics and&#xD;
      utilization/financial outcomes, including LDL-C, systolic blood pressure, body mass index,&#xD;
      waist circumference, number of diabetes medications prescribed, Wellbeing360 survey, and&#xD;
      total cost of healthcare.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention group will attend 18 classes covering topics such as diet, sleep, exercise&#xD;
      instruction, stress management, and toxic substance avoidance. Biometrics (weight, BMI, waist&#xD;
      circumference, systolic/diastolic blood pressure), biomarkers (HbA1c, LDL-C) and&#xD;
      psychometrics (Wellbeing 360 survey) will be collected on all participants at baseline,&#xD;
      3-months and 6-months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The CHIP curriculum will be administered during twice weekly 1-hour classes over a 6-week&#xD;
      period, followed by weekly 1-hour classes for an additional 6 weeks. The protocol will begin&#xD;
      with a 1-month in-person period, with participants subsequently offered the choice between&#xD;
      in-person and online attendance for the remaining sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary aim is to compare change in HbA1c, LDL-C, systolic blood pressure, body mass&#xD;
      index, and waist circumference for GHP members offered CHIP versus members offered standard&#xD;
      insurance coverage at 3- and 6-months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Through this pilot study, we hope to gain insight into whether and how such an application of&#xD;
      CHIP could be a cost-effective tool for health plans such as GHP to achieve clinical and&#xD;
      financial goals for adult members with T2DM.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical endpoint:</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in HbA1c percentage at 6 months compared to baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility endpoint:</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>What percentage of individuals contacted agree to participate; what percentage of individuals contacted are excluded from the study based on lack of access to transportation or Internet; what percentage of participants enrolled complete the intervention?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c control at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in HbA1c percentage at 3 months compared to at baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LDL-C at 3 and 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in LDL-C levels at 3 and 6 months compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biometrics at 3 and 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in weight, body mass index, blood pressure at 3 and 6 months compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychosocial/behavioral at 3 and 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Wellbeing360 survey at 3 and 6 months compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health behaviors, as measured by CHIP participation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Overall program completion, attendance stratified by in-person versus online, proportion of required in-person attended</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of diabetes medications prescribed at 3 and 6 months</measure>
    <time_frame>3 and 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in number of diabetes medications at 3 and 6 months compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total cost of care over 6 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change in total cost of care at 6 months compared to baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CHIP Program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>GHP members randomized to the intervention arm will participate in the CHIP Program.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Diabetes Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>GHP members assigned to the control arm will receive the routine standard of care for GHP members.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CHIP Program</intervention_name>
    <description>GHP members randomized to the intervention arm will participate in the following activities:&#xD;
Attend 2 group meetings per week over 6 weeks, followed by one group meeting per week for 6 weeks (12 weeks total); each meeting will last about one hour. CHIP classes for weeks 1-4 and week 12 require in-person attendance, while week 5-11 classes can be attended either virtually or in-person.&#xD;
Receive a copy of The Optimal Diet, The Official CHIP Cookbook.&#xD;
The following data will be collected at weeks 1,12 and 26:&#xD;
Biometrics: weight, BMI, waist circumference, systolic and diastolic blood pressure&#xD;
Biomarkers (blood tests): HbA1c, LDL-C&#xD;
Psychometrics: Wellbeing360 survey</description>
    <arm_group_label>CHIP Program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Usual Care</intervention_name>
    <description>GHP members assigned to the control arm will receive the routine standard of care for GHP members. Members will receive a summary of diabetes-related benefits available to members with type 2 diabetes.&#xD;
The following data will be collected at weeks 1,12 and 26:&#xD;
Biometrics: Weight, BMI, waist circumference, systolic and diastolic blood pressure&#xD;
Biomarkers (blood tests): HbA1c, LDL-C&#xD;
Psychometrics: Wellbeing360 survey</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Diabetes Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Geisinger Health Plan member for a full year prior to enrollment in the study, with&#xD;
             plans to remain covered for a full year after the first study visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HbA1c resulted within a year of enrollment in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current type 2 diabetes diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living in the five-county region served by the Miller Center (Lycoming, Montour,&#xD;
             Northumberland, Snyder and Union) with the ability to arrange their own transportation&#xD;
             to the Miller Center in Lewisburg at least 10 times in a 3-month period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to computer, phone, or tablet with sufficient internet to complete program&#xD;
             activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of medical condition requiring specific diet (e.g., Celiac disease,&#xD;
             phenylketonuria)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of medical condition contraindicating participation in CHIP, as determined by&#xD;
             the Principal Investigator (e.g. cancer on active treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or plan to become pregnant within one year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to give informed consent due to mental or psychiatric impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in the Fresh Food Farmacy program&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Thomas B Morland, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Geisinger Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thomas B Morland, MD</last_name>
    <phone>570-214-5025</phone>
    <email>tmorland@geisinger.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Katie E Wintersteen, BS</last_name>
    <phone>570-764-5003</phone>
    <email>kewintersteen@geisinger.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Geisinger Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thomas Morland</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Sponsor-Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 2 Diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

