<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04927494</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>60704</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>K01CA251487</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04927494</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cervical Cancer Prevention for Black Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>Promoting Cervical Cancer Screening Among African American and Sub Saharan African Immigrants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AdegboyegaA</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Kentucky</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this study is to develop and pilot test an intervention, entitled Health is&#xD;
      Wealth: A Cervical Health Program, designed to promote screening and reduce perceived&#xD;
      barriers to Cervical Cancer (CC) screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: Examine general awareness and cultural factors (fatalism, religiosity/spirituality,&#xD;
      temporal orientation, medical mistrust, and acculturation) related to cancer control and&#xD;
      prevention among African Americans (AA) and Sub Saharan African (SAI) Immigrants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Examine the socioecological barriers and facilitators to CC screening and&#xD;
      self-sampling to inform tailoring of an evidenced based cervical health program to promote CC&#xD;
      screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: Assess feasibility, acceptability, and preliminary efficacy in a pilot test of the&#xD;
      Health is Wealth: A Cervical Health Program among 30 AA and 30 SAI women using&#xD;
      quasi-experimental design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will take place in 2 phases.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In phase 1, the investigators will conduct a cross-sectional survey with 150 Black men and&#xD;
      women to examine factors impacting cervical cancer screening. Also, as part of phase 1, Aim 2&#xD;
      employs focus groups and a quantitative Health Belief Model checklist with 30 participants to&#xD;
      guide development of a tailored intervention. In phase 2, Aim 3 will assess feasibility,&#xD;
      acceptability, and preliminary efficacy of the Health is Wealth: A Cervical Health Program&#xD;
      intervention among 30 African American and 30 Sub-Saharan African immigrant women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion of HPV self-sampling</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>HPV self-sampling kit return</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Cervical cancer Knowledge</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Cervical cancer awareness will be assessed with Likert style questions (strongly disagree-1 to strongly agree-5) from the cervical cancer awareness toolkit. Awareness of warning signs and risk factors will be assessed with a prompted checklist. This instrument has been found to be valid and reliable in multiple populations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HPV knowledge</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will complete 16 items assessing knowledge of HPV, 6 items about HPV testing, and 7 items about the vaccination. Response options included &quot;True,&quot; &quot;False,&quot; and &quot;Don't know,&quot; with scoring allocating one point for each correct response, and zero points for incorrect or &quot;Don't know&quot; responses, summed across items, for a potential range of 0-29. This instrument has been found to be valid and reliable in multiple populations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Self-efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Self-efficacy will be assessed with 10 items measured on a five-point Likert-like scale response choices: strongly disagree (scores 1 point), disagree (scores 2point), neutral (scores 3 point), agree (scores 4 point) and strongly agree (scores 5 points), with higher scores indicating stronger feelings toward the construct. This is a well validated and reliable instrument.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in perceived barriers to screening</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Barriers will be assessed with 14 items measured on a five-point Likert-like scale response choices: strongly disagree (scores 1 point), disagree (scores 2point), neutral (scores 3 point), agree (scores 4 point) and strongly agree (scores 5 points), with higher scores indicating stronger feelings toward the construct</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in benefits</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Benefits will be assessed with 4 items measured on a five-point Likert-like scale response choices: strongly disagree (scores 1 point), disagree (scores 2 point), neutral (scores 3 point), agree (scores 4 point) and strongly agree (scores 5 points), with higher scores indicating stronger feelings toward the construct</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in susceptibility</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Susceptibility will be assessed with 4 items measured on a five-point Likert-like scale response choices: strongly disagree (scores 1 point), disagree (scores 2 point), neutral (scores 3 point), agree (scores 4 point) and strongly agree (scores 5 points), with higher scores indicating stronger feelings toward the construct</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in seriousness</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months (Baseline, immediately post-test, 6 month follow up)</time_frame>
    <description>Seriousness will be assessed with 7 items measured on a five-point Likert-like scale response choices: strongly disagree (scores 1 point), disagree (scores 2 point), neutral (scores 3 point), agree (scores 4 point) and strongly agree (scores 5 points), with higher scores indicating stronger feelings toward the construct.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Cervical Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Black women cervical cancer screening</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this group with receive the Health is Wealth intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Health is Wealth: A Cervical Health Program</intervention_name>
    <description>Health is Wealth: A Cervical Health Program will be introduced in a one-time 2-hour educational session, participants will be given HPV self-sampling kits, and instructional sheet that visually depicts the steps for self-sampling. The program will be culturally tailored to increase self-efficacy and knowledge while simultaneously addressing perceived health beliefs associated with cervical cancer and barriers associated with cervical cancer screening and HPV self-sampling. Content will be delivered in a group format (about 10-15 participants) by lecture, demonstration, and interactive exercises.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Black women cervical cancer screening</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-identify as Black woman (African American or Sub-Saharan African Immigrant)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No pap smear within the last three years or no pap smear/HPV co-test within past five&#xD;
             years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to speak and write in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reside in Kentucky&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not self-identify as Black woman (African American or Sub-Saharan African&#xD;
             Immigrant)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hysterectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cervical cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to speak and write in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not reside in Kentucky&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Anatomically female with a cervix.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adebola Adegboyega, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Kentucky</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adebola Adegboyega, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>859-323-5196</phone>
    <email>aoadeg2@uky.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kentucky</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lexington</city>
        <state>Kentucky</state>
        <zip>40536</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adebola Adegboyega, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>859-323-5196</phone>
      <email>aoadeg2@uky.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Kentucky</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>AdegboyegaA</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cervical cancer screening</keyword>
  <keyword>HPV self-sampling</keyword>
  <keyword>African American</keyword>
  <keyword>Sub-Saharan African immigrants</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

