<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04926831</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CINC280AUS12</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04926831</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II of Neoadjuvant and Adjuvant Capmatinib in NSCLC</brief_title>
  <acronym>Geometry-N</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Neoadjuvant and Adjuvant Capmatinib in Participants With Stages IB-IIIA, N2 and Selected IIIB (T3N2 or T4N2) NSCLC With MET Exon 14 Skipping Mutation or High MET Amplification (Geometry-N)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Novartis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine if neoadjuvant capmatinib can improve outcomes in&#xD;
      participants with stages I-IIIA non-small cell lung cancer with MET exon 14 mutations and/or&#xD;
      high MET amplification beyond those achieved with surgery, chemotherapy, and radiation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This trial is a phase II, two cohort study of neoadjuvant capmatinib treatment (pre-surgery)&#xD;
      which will be given for 8 weeks prior to a surgical resection and then followed by a three&#xD;
      year adjuvant capmatinib treatment (post surgery). Following treatment, there will be a two&#xD;
      year survival follow-up. The two molecularly defined cohorts will be enrolled in parallel.&#xD;
      Approximately 38 evaluable participants will be enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During treatment participants will visit their treating physician to assess overall health&#xD;
      status which will include lab-work and other safety assessments. Survival follow-up will be&#xD;
      every 6 months which can be conducted via a telephone visit for up to approximately 2 years&#xD;
      after end of treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 4, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 21, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Major pathological response (MPR) rate based on local review</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to time of surgery (approximately 8 to 10 weeks after first dose)</time_frame>
    <description>MPR rate in each cohort defined as the percentage of participants with ≤ 10% residual viable cancer cells</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete pathologic response (pCR) rate based on central and local review</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to time of surgery (approximately. 8- 10 weeks after first dose)</time_frame>
    <description>Complete pathologic response (pCR) rate is defined as the percentage of participants with no residual viable cancer cells.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) based on local investigator assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to time of surgery (approximately 8 - 10 weeks after first dose)</time_frame>
    <description>Overall response rate (ORR) is defined as the percentage participants with best overall response (BOR) of complete response (CR) or partial response ( PR) according to RECIST v1.1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of adverse events and serious adverse events as assessed by CTCAE criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline up to approximately 40 months</time_frame>
    <description>The occurrence of adverse events will be reported from first day of treatment through end of treatment plus 30 days.&#xD;
Serious adverse events which are treatment related will be reported through the end of study participation. Adverse events also may be detected or through physical examination findings, laboratory test findings, or other assessments.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease free survival rate (DFS) from start of adjuvant therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>From time of surgery and at 24, 36, and 60 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time from end of surgery (start of adjuvant therapy) until the recurrence of cancer or death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with NSCLC with MET exon 14 skipping mutations, irrespective of MET gene copy number (GCN) will take 400 mg tablet orally twice per day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with NSCLC with high level MET amplification will take 400 mg tablet orally twice per day</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>capmatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>150 mg and 200 mg tablets for oral administration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort B</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>INC280</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed NSCLC stage IB-IIIA, N2 and selected IIIB (T3N2 or T4N2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must have either MET exon 14 mutations and/or high level MET amplification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must be eligible for surgery and scheduled for surgical resection within&#xD;
             approximately 2 weeks after the last does of neoadjuvant study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with unresectable or metastatic disease. All participants should have&#xD;
             brain imaging (either MRI brain or CT brain with contrast) prior to enrollment to&#xD;
             exclude brain metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with any MET inhibitor or HGF-targeting therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery (e.g., intra-thoracic, intra-abdominal or intra-pelvic) within 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to starting study treatment, or who have not recovered from side effects of such&#xD;
             procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior systemic anti-cancer therapy (chemotherapy, immunotherapy, biologic therapy,&#xD;
             vaccine) or investigational agents for NSCLC within the past 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of or current interstitial lung disease or pneumonitis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other protocol-defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply at the end&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-669-6682</phone>
    <email>novartis.email@novartis.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Novartis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California Davis Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Karen Kelly</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Irving Pavilion; Diabetes Research Unit</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032-3784</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>212-305-8797</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shu Catherine</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>MET exon 14 skipping mutation</keyword>
  <keyword>High MET amplification</keyword>
  <keyword>Neoadjuvant</keyword>
  <keyword>Prior to surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Adjuvant</keyword>
  <keyword>After surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>INC280</keyword>
  <keyword>MET inhibition</keyword>
  <keyword>adult</keyword>
  <keyword>capmatinib</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Novartis is committed to sharing with qualified external researchers, access to patient-level data and supporting clinical documents from eligible studies. These requests are reviewed and approved by an independent review panel on the basis of scientific merit. All data provided is anonymized to respect the privacy of patients who have participated in the trial in line with applicable laws and regulations.&#xD;
This trial data availability is according to the criteria and process described on https://www.clinicalstudydatarequest.com/.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

