<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04922957</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ENX-CL-03-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04922957</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 2b Multi-Center, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study, Evaluating Efficacy and Safety of Allocetra-OTS in Patients With Severe or Critical COVID-19 With Associated Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2b Multi-Center, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Study, Evaluating Efficacy and Safety of Allocetra-OTS in Patients With Severe or Critical COVID-19 With Associated Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome (ARDS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Enlivex Therapeutics Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Enlivex Therapeutics Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2b multi-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study&#xD;
      evaluating the efficacy and safety of intravenous (IV) Allocetra-OTS 10x10^9 cells vs placebo&#xD;
      (1:1) in adult hospitalized patients with severe or critical Coronavirus Disease 2019&#xD;
      (COVID-19) with associated acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). Patients will be&#xD;
      followed for efficacy and safety for 6 months. The trial will include periodic and ad-hoc&#xD;
      DSMB review during the study period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 2b multi-center, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study&#xD;
      evaluating the efficacy and safety of intravenous (IV) Allocetra-OTS 10x10^9 cells vs placebo&#xD;
      (1:1) in adult hospitalized patients with severe or critical Coronavirus Disease 2019&#xD;
      (COVID-19) with associated acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Severe and critical COVID-19 are defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Severe COVID-19: shortness of breath at rest, or respiratory distress, or respiratory rate&#xD;
      (RR) ≥30 per minute, or SpO2 ≤93% on room air at sea level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Critical COVID-19: respiratory failure, requiring at least one of the following: oxygen&#xD;
      delivered by high-flow nasal cannula or noninvasive positive pressure ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a patient has signed the informed consent form (ICF), and after confirmation that the&#xD;
      patient meets all eligibility criteria, the patient will be enrolled in the study. The two&#xD;
      subpopulations, severely ill and critically ill patients, will be randomized 1:1 into the&#xD;
      active treatment and placebo groups via two separate randomizations schemes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study treatment (Investigational Product or placebo) administration will occur on Day 1 as&#xD;
      close as possible to and no later than 48 hours from randomization. Assessments, performed on&#xD;
      Day 1 prior to study treatment administration, will be considered as baseline assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed for efficacy and safety through 6 months. Following study treatment&#xD;
      administration, patients will be assessed daily for a period of 7 days. The next visits are&#xD;
      planned to occur on Days 14, 28 and 60. A safety follow-up phone call will be scheduled to&#xD;
      occur 6 months post study treatment. Hospitalized patients will be monitored on a daily basis&#xD;
      until discharge or up to 60 days post study treatment administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples for safety assessment will be analyzed locally as per institutional guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional blood samples will be collected for potential exploratory analyses. Such biomarker&#xD;
      analyses will be performed centrally as per Sponsor requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who drop out within the interval between the randomization and study treatment&#xD;
      administration will be replaced to keep the originally planned sample size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The trial will include periodic and ad-hoc Data Safety Monitoring Board (DSMB) review during&#xD;
      the study period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>152 patients will be allocated in a 1:1 ratio between the 2 cohorts:&#xD;
Placebo&#xD;
Single Intravenous (IV) dose of Allocetra-OTS (10x10^9 cells)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Randomization will be in a double blinding fashion. The IP will be delivered with a cover to maintain blinding.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time (days) to improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The first day, during the period of 28 days post study treatment, when a patient reached the score of 6, 7 or 8 on the 8-point ordinal scale. If no improvement is reached by Day 28, the patient will be assigned a maximal score of 29.&#xD;
The 8-point ordinal scale of the clinical severity status scores is as follows:&#xD;
Death=1; Hospitalized, on IMV or ECMO=2; Hospitalized, on noninvasive ventilation or high-flow oxygen devices=3; Hospitalized, requiring supplemental oxygen by mask or nasal canula=4; Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen=5; Hospitalized, not requiring supplemental oxygen and not requiring ongoing inpatient medical care=6; Not hospitalized, limitations on activities=7; Not hospitalized, no limitations on activities=8.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Support by IMV/ECMO</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>If required during the period of 28 days post study treatment, a patient will be assigned the maximal score of 29.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Mortality by Day 28 post study treatment administration. Deceased patients will be assigned the maximal score of 29.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time (days) to improvement, defined as the first day, during a period of 28 days and 60 days post study treatment administration, when the patient reached the score of 6, 7 or 8 on the 8-point ordinal scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality during the period of 28 days and 60 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients alive and free of respiratory failure, defined as need for IMV, ECMO, noninvasive ventilation, or high-flow nasal cannula oxygen delivery on Days 28 and 60.</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative number of vasopressor-free days during the period of 28 days and 60 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative number of days in the hospital during the period of 28 days and 60 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative number of days in the ICU or Intermediate Care Unit (IMU) during the period of 28 days and 60 days.</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety - Number and severity of adverse events (AEs) and serious adverse events (SAEs) throughout 60-day follow-up period</measure>
    <time_frame>60 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety - Number and severity of AEs and SAEs throughout 180-day follow-up period</measure>
    <time_frame>180 days</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">152</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Ringer's lactate solution</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ALLOCETRA-OTS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single IV dose of Allocetra-OTS containing 10x10^9 cells</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ALLOCETRA-OTS</intervention_name>
    <description>The product contains allogeneic donor mononuclear enriched cells in the form of a liquid suspension containing early apoptotic cells.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ALLOCETRA-OTS</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Cell based therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Apoptotic cells</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Ringer's lactate solution</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male and female &gt;18 and &lt;85 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Laboratory confirmation of SARS-CoV-2 infection by RT-PCR from any diagnostic sampling&#xD;
             source.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient hospitalized due to COVID-19 within 7 days prior to enrollment, meeting the&#xD;
             criteria for severe or critical COVID-19 as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Severe COVID-19 - defined as shortness of breath at rest, or respiratory&#xD;
                  distress, or RR ≥30 per minute, or SpO2≤93% on room air at sea level.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Critical COVID-19 - defined as respiratory failure, requiring at least one of the&#xD;
                  following: oxygen delivered by high-flow nasal cannula or noninvasive positive&#xD;
                  pressure ventilation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient with mild to moderate ARDS:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. 100&lt; PaO2/FiO2 ≤300; based on the Berlin Definition of ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. 148&lt; SpO2/FiO2 ≤315; based on the Kigali modification for ARDS&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  If available, PaO2 will be obtained, otherwise, SpO2 will be used for ARDS&#xD;
                       assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Signed written informed consent by the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women and men who are of childbearing potential, willing to use acceptable&#xD;
             contraceptive measures during 4 weeks from enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient on IMV/ECMO.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Woman who is pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient with weight &lt;50 kg or &gt;120 kg or BMI &gt;40 kg/m^2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient with stage 4 or 5 chronic kidney disease or estimated glomerular filtration&#xD;
             rate &lt;30 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient with an active malignant tumor (diagnosed or on active treatment for the past&#xD;
             6 months).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient who is participating in other concurrent interventional clinical trials or has&#xD;
             been treated with any experimental agents within 30 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient who based on their medical history and receipt of therapies that would suggest&#xD;
             infection, has suspected serious, active bacterial (including a suspected clinical&#xD;
             diagnosis of current active tuberculosis [TB] or, if known, latent TB treated for less&#xD;
             than 4 weeks with appropriate anti-TB therapy per institutional guidelines), fungal,&#xD;
             or viral (including, but not limited to, active HBV, HCV, or HIV/AIDS) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient with known immunocompromised state or immunosuppressive medications taken for&#xD;
             indications other than SARS-CoV-2 as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prednisone or equivalent to a dose &gt;10 mg/day, methotrexate &gt;15 mg/week, within&#xD;
                  the last 60 days. cyclophosphamide, cyclosporine A (unless as ophthalmic&#xD;
                  formulation), leflunomide/teriflunomide (unless as monotherapy), tacrolimus&#xD;
                  (unless as a topical formulation), everolimus, temsirolimus, or azathioprine, in&#xD;
                  the last 60 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Methylprednisolone, dexamethasone, cortisone, or betamethasone for more than 7&#xD;
                  days within the last 28 days or within 5 half-lives, whichever is longer;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chemotherapy in the last 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mycophenolate mofetil (MMF) or sirolimus for solid organ transplant or bone&#xD;
                  marrow transplant;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Thalidomide within the last 72 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Anti-tumor necrosis factor (TNF) agents, interleukin (IL)-1 receptor antagonists&#xD;
                  (IL-1-RA), CTLA-4 fusion proteins, anti-CD20, anti-CD52, anti-IL-2, anti-IL-6R,&#xD;
                  anti-IL-12/23, anti-B-cell activation factor (BAFF) or integrin inhibitor agents&#xD;
                  within the last 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient with known New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III and IV heart failure or&#xD;
             unstable angina, ventricular arrhythmias, ischemic heart disease, or myocardial&#xD;
             infarction within 6 months prior to diagnosis of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient with known active upper gastrointestinal (GI) tract ulceration or hepatic&#xD;
             dysfunction including but not limited to biopsy-proven cirrhosis; end-stage cirrhosis&#xD;
             (Child Pugh Class C); portal hypertension; episodes of past upper GI bleeding&#xD;
             attributed to portal hypertension; or prior episodes of hepatic failure,&#xD;
             encephalopathy, or coma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient with known idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patient with chronic respiratory disease requiring home oxygen therapy on a regular&#xD;
             basis for more than 6 hours per day.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient with known chronic obstructive pulmonary disease GOLD 4 (forced expiratory&#xD;
             volume in one second &lt;30% predicted).&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient with any medical, psychiatric or substance abuse condition, concurrent medical&#xD;
             therapies, or abnormal laboratory values that in the opinion of the site Investigator&#xD;
             may influence response to study product, or interfere with the study assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patient with GCS &lt;13 with verbal score &lt;5.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patient with hemoglobin &lt;8 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patient with history of chronic liver disease, evidence of acute cholangitis or&#xD;
             cholecystitis. Patients with at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT or AST &gt;10xULN (upper limit of normal)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin &gt;5xULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Combination of ALT/AST &gt;7xULN and elevated direct bilirubin &gt;ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Patient with known history of transfusion reactions, hemolytic anemia, or repetitive&#xD;
             allergic reaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patient with previous history of organ allograft or stem cell transplantation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oren Hershkovitz, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Enlivex Therapeutics R&amp;D</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Odelia Ben Shitrit, MBA</last_name>
    <phone>+972-548887609</phone>
    <email>odelia@enlivexpharm.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lior Binder</last_name>
    <phone>+972-548054899</phone>
    <email>lior@enlivexpharm.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hadassah Ein Kerem Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Jerusalem</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Rachel Kleinhaus</last_name>
      <phone>972-52-4347504</phone>
      <email>KlRachel@hadassah.org.il</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cell therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Allocetra-OTS</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Distress Syndrome, Newborn</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acute Lung Injury</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Patient data will not contain any information which would make the patient identifiable. Data will be processes and shared using patient study number only.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

