<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04928261</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REaCT-HER TIME</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04928261</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating 6-months of HER2-targeted Therapy in Patients With HER2 Positive Early-stage Breast Cancer That Achieve a Pathological Complete Response to Neoadjuvant Systemic Therapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single-arm, Multicentre, Pragmatic Trial Evaluating 6-months of HER2-targeted Therapy in Patients With HER2 Positive Early-stage Breast Cancer That Achieve a Pathological Complete Response to Neoadjuvant Systemic Therapy (REaCT-HER TIME)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The activity of trastuzumab in early-stage, HER2-positive breast cancer, has been&#xD;
      demonstrated in many studies, with meta-analyses showing that in combination with a variety&#xD;
      of chemotherapy backbones, trastuzumab reduces the risk of recurrence by nearly half, and&#xD;
      death by a third. However, treatment with trastuzumab can result in cardiotoxicity, including&#xD;
      heart failure, as well as the significant cost of treatment and the requirement for patients&#xD;
      to attend the chemotherapy unit for treatment every 3 weeks for one year. Therefore there has&#xD;
      been increasing interest in identifying which patients can safely have less treatment. The&#xD;
      investigators therefore propose a real-world, single arm, multicentre trial evaluating 6&#xD;
      months of HER2 targeted therapy, for patients with early-stage, HER2 positive breast cancer,&#xD;
      who achieve a pathological complete response (pCR) with upfront systemic chemotherapy and&#xD;
      HER2 targeted therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The activity of trastuzumab in early-stage, HER2-positive breast cancer, has been&#xD;
      demonstrated in many studies, with meta-analyses showing that in combination with a variety&#xD;
      of chemotherapy backbones, trastuzumab reduces the risk of recurrence by nearly half, and&#xD;
      death by a third. However, treatment with trastuzumab can result in cardiotoxicity, including&#xD;
      heart failure, as well as the significant cost of treatment and the requirement for patients&#xD;
      to attend the chemotherapy unit for treatment every 3 weeks for one year. Therefore there has&#xD;
      been increasing interest in identifying which patients can safely have less treatment. The&#xD;
      duration of adjuvant trastuzumab in early-stage breast cancer in the majority of studies was&#xD;
      empirically set at 12 months, which became the de facto standard of care. Neoadjuvant&#xD;
      treatment has become the new standard of care for patients with early-stage HER2-positive&#xD;
      disease. While patients with residual disease benefit from further alternative treatment&#xD;
      those with a pathological complete response (pCR) have an excellent outcome and are&#xD;
      candidates for treatment de-escalation. The investigators therefore propose a real-world,&#xD;
      single arm, multicentre trial evaluating 6 months of HER2 targeted therapy, for patients with&#xD;
      early-stage, HER2 positive breast cancer, who achieve a pCR with upfront systemic&#xD;
      chemotherapy and HER2 targeted therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Multiple site activation</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after first participant is accrued</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluating the feasibility of multiple Canadian site activation within the first year of study accrual. Achieved by the activation of at least 4 Canadian sites within 1 year of the first patient being accrued into the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Medical oncologist active participation</measure>
    <time_frame>Through to end of accrual - average 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluating the number of medical oncologists at each study site who actively participate in the trial. Active participation includes approaching eligible patients for the study, as well as following up with the patients who are taking part in the study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Enrolment of at least 50 participants across all sites within 9 months of the fourth site accruing its first participant</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months after fourth site accrues first participant</time_frame>
    <description>Enrolment of at least 50 participants across all sites within 9 months of the fourth site accruing its first participant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac events</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years after study enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>Cardiac events defined as death from a cardiac or heart failure of New York Heart Association (NYHA) class III or IV, or with a decrease in the left ventricular ejection fraction of at least 10 percentage points from baseline to a value of less than 50%. Cardiac monitoring will be assessed as per physician standards</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of HER2-positive treatment discontinuation</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after study enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>De-escalated HER2-positive treatment discontinuation and the reasons why treatment was discontinued</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 3, 6, 12 and 36 months after study enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life measure using the EuroQol-5 Dimension-5 Level (EQ-5D-5L) questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incremental cost-effectiveness ratios</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years from study enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>The difference in cost between 6 months of HER2-positive therapy versus the standard 12 months of HER2-positive therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years from study enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>Disease Free Survival (DFS), defined as the percentage of people in the trial who are alive and disease-free (no local invasive breast cancer recurrence, new local invasive breast cancer) at 3 years</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years from study enrolment</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival (OS), defined as the number of people alive, with or without signs of cancer at 3 years</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>De-escalated HER2 targeted treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with early-stage HER2-positive breast cancer who demonstrate a pathological complete response at time of surgery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Trastuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients with early-stage HER2-positive breast cancer who demonstrate a pathological complete response at time of surgery will be treated with HER2 targeted therapy for a total of 9 treatments every 3 weeks (or its equivalent if given weekly) including the treatment received preoperatively.</description>
    <arm_group_label>De-escalated HER2 targeted treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Herceptin</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Early-stage (I-III, i.e. non-metastatic) as per AJCC 8th edition, ER/PR positive or&#xD;
             negative, HER2-positive as per 2018 American Society of Clinical Oncology/College of&#xD;
             American Pathologists human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2) testing in&#xD;
             breast cancer guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treated with neoadjuvant chemotherapy and HER2 targeted therapy preoperatively with a&#xD;
             pathological complete response (pCR) defined as the absence of residual invasive&#xD;
             cancer on hematoxylin and eosin evaluation of the complete resected breast specimen&#xD;
             and all sampled regional lymph nodes following completion of neoadjuvant systemic&#xD;
             therapy at surgery. Must have received less than 6 months of HER2 targeted therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide verbal consent and complete questionnaires in English or French&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residual invasive disease following neoadjuvant therapy, or metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to further HER2-targeted therapy following completion of neoadjuvant&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any psychological, familial, sociological or geographical condition potentially&#xD;
             hampering compliance with the trial protocol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sharon McGee, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ottawa Hospital Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lisa Vandermeer, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>6137377700</phone>
    <phone_ext>73039</phone_ext>
    <email>lvandermeer@toh.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Michelle Liu</last_name>
    <phone>613-737-7700</phone>
    <phone_ext>79150</phone_ext>
    <email>miliu@ohri.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 15, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cardiac toxicities</keyword>
  <keyword>Her2 Positive</keyword>
  <keyword>Pathological complete response</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Trastuzumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

