<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04928053</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>N°IDRCB 2018-A1459-46</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04928053</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COG-PSYCHO : Social Cognition and Psychotic Characteristics: Genetic and Phenomic Approach</brief_title>
  <acronym>COG-PSYCHO</acronym>
  <official_title>Cognition Sociale et caractéristiques Psychotiques : Approche génétique et phénomique</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Bipolar disorder (BD), schizophrenia and depression can feature cognitive impairment,&#xD;
      especially in social cognition (SC). According to previous studies, some genes from the&#xD;
      oxytocin and dopamine pathways may be involved SC performance. Our endophenotype approach&#xD;
      aimed to demonstrate that SC deficits are more severe in schizophrenia and BD or depression&#xD;
      with psychotic symptoms (PBP) and are associated with certain Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms&#xD;
      (SNPs) variants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      600 patients with schizophrenia, BD ou depression with and without psychotic symptoms will be&#xD;
      recrited. Social Cognition was assessed using 4 paradigms: Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test&#xD;
      (RMET), Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI), Empathy Quotient (QE), and a modified Delay&#xD;
      Discounting task. After DNA extraction from blood or saliva sample, we used PCR amplification&#xD;
      and real-time detection to genotype SNPs from Oxytocin pathways. he level of ocytocine will&#xD;
      be also mesured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Schizophrenia and mood disorders represent two severe and frequent disease with heterogeneous&#xD;
      phenotype sharing some clinical symptoms (possible presence of psychotic symptoms in mood&#xD;
      disorders, systematic in schizophrenia) and neurocognitive impairments including social&#xD;
      cognition. These disorders result from an interaction of several minor effect genes with&#xD;
      various early or late environmental factors, with psychosocial or biological origin.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The association of these pathologies with dysfunctions of major neurotransmission systems has&#xD;
      been the subject of numerous studies, but the results have often been contradictory for&#xD;
      methodological, clinical (phenotypic heterogeneity) and finally genetic reasons. The&#xD;
      definition of the phenotype is an essential issue in research on the genetics of mental&#xD;
      disorders. The risk of phenotypic misclassification of subjects during genetic studies&#xD;
      confirms the need for a better delimitation of homogeneous patient sub-populations. The&#xD;
      development by the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH) of clinical research criteria&#xD;
      is essential to bring sufficient power to modern research in genetics, but also in imaging,&#xD;
      neuroscience or behavioral sciences of mental disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of our work is to study a restricted phenotype of schizophrenia and mood disorders:&#xD;
      the assessment of social cognitions. Deficits in social cognition constitute one of the&#xD;
      subconstructs described by the NIMH and lead to functional and clinical maladjustment&#xD;
      hindering psychosocial rehabilitation. Indeed, oxytocin is reported to be a mediator of the&#xD;
      regulation of social cognition (including empathy and theory of mind) and emotional behaviors&#xD;
      (Meyer-Lindenberg, 2011).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current project involves the analysis of several social cognition tasks that measure&#xD;
      social perception, facial recognition of affect and empathy. The objective of this work is to&#xD;
      highlight an association between performance on the 4 social cognition paradigms and&#xD;
      polymorphisms of the OXT and OXTR genes and in a population of subjects suffering from&#xD;
      schizophrenia or mood disorder with or without psychotic symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main hypothesis of this study is that these genes have an impact on social cognition in&#xD;
      each of the populations recruited (patients with schizophrenia or patients with a mood&#xD;
      disorder). The secondary hypothesis is to show that this impact of the genotype is more&#xD;
      marked in patients with psychotic symptoms (suffering from mood disorders or schizophrenia)&#xD;
      compared to patients suffering from mood disorders without psychotic symptoms (interaction&#xD;
      mechanism).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Main objective : To show the association between variants of the OXT and OXTR genes and the&#xD;
      deficit in social cognition observed in patients with schizophrenia or a mood disorder with&#xD;
      or without psychotic features.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint : Performance on the Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test (RMET), which&#xD;
      measures the ability to attribute emotions to others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To show the impact of the OXT and OXTR genes on 3 other paradigms of social cognition,&#xD;
           and in the following subgroups: schizophrenic patients, patients with mood disorders,&#xD;
           patients with psychotic symptoms and patients without psychotic symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To highlight interactions between genetic variants of the OXT and OXTR genes with the&#xD;
           main impaired cognitive and neurological capacities in schizophrenia and mood disorders&#xD;
           (attention, executive and memory function).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To search for an association between traumatic life events in childhood and delusional&#xD;
           clinical phenotype and impaired cognition in mood disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To demonstrate that plasma oxytocin levels are decreased in patients with psychotic&#xD;
           symptoms compared to patients without psychotic symptoms and correlated with social&#xD;
           cognition performance in the total sample of subjects as well as in each of these&#xD;
           subgroups.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. To demonstrate that OXTR gene expression is reduced in patients with psychotic symptoms&#xD;
           (schizophrenia or mood disorder with psychotic symptoms) compared to subjects without&#xD;
           psychotic symptoms (mood disorder without psychotic symptoms), and correlated with&#xD;
           social cognitive performance in the total sample of subjects and in each of these&#xD;
           subgroups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Evaluation Criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Performance on three other tests measuring social cognitions: Delay Discouting applied&#xD;
           to social cognitions, Interpersonal Reactivity Index and Empathy Quotient (Berthoz et&#xD;
           al., 2008)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. RMET test performance&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Potentially traumatic life events (CTQ questionnaire)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Plasma determination of circulating oxytocin&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. mRNA expression level of the OXTR gene measured by RT-qPCR Monocentric cross-sectional&#xD;
           study evaluating social cognition in patients suffering from schizophrenia, mood&#xD;
           disorder with or without psychotic symptoms in search of genetic determinants involved&#xD;
           in social cognition performance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients undergo biological sampling (genotyping of variants of the OXT and OXTR genes,&#xD;
      quantification of circulating oxytocin and quantification of OXTR transcript expression) and&#xD;
      undergo several evaluations (RMET, Delay Discounting, Interpersonal Reactivity Index, Empathy&#xD;
      Quotient).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Criteria for inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Major patient under 75 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Presenting the DSM-5 criteria for schizophrenia, bipolar disorder or major depressive&#xD;
           episode.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Capable of giving consent or under curatorship&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Benefiting from a health insurance plan Criteria for non-inclusion Pregnancy (urine test&#xD;
           performed prior to inclusion in the program) Procedure A single three-hour face-to-face&#xD;
           interview will be carried out at the inclusion, in an inpatient or outpatient setting.&#xD;
           Patients will have a 30-minute social cognition assessment by the RMET, two empathy&#xD;
           self-questionnaires: IRI and QE, and a computerized update time stamp.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The collection of standardized psychiatric and addictological diagnoses using the DIGS is&#xD;
      under the responsibility of Professor DUBERTRET (Hôpital Louis Mourier) in order to define&#xD;
      the groups of subjects. There is no follow-up on a day-by-day basis; patient participation is&#xD;
      one day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will have a blood sample in order to perform genetic analyses including&#xD;
      genotyping of the genes tested, quantification of OXTR mRNA expressed in peripheral venous&#xD;
      blood (biogps) by RT-qPCR and oxytocin assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of patients 600 patients&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 (monocentric study) Duration of inclusion: 5 years Duration of participation (treatment +&#xD;
      follow-up):1 day Total research duration 5 years&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 4, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 4, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Showing an correlation between SNPs of OXT et OXTR genes and social performence observed in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar or depressed patients with or without psychotic characteristics.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>performence at RMET (Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Impact of OXT, OXTR genes and social performence emesured with Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI) observed in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar or depressed patients with or without psychotic characteristics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Empathy Quotient (QE)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Impact of OXT, OXTR genes and social performence emesured with Empathy Quotient (QE) observed in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar or depressed patients with or without psychotic characteristics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>modified Delay Discounting task</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Impact of OXT, OXTR genes and social performence emesured with a modified Delay Discounting task observed in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar or depressed patients with or without psychotic characteristics.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive performence</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>correlation between SNPs of OXT et OXTR genes and general cognition scores (attention, executive and mnesisic fonction)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Potentially traumatic life events (CTQ questionnaire)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Association between traumatic events and psychotic characteristics and cognition scores</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma determination of circulating oxytocin</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>- Plasma determination of oxytocin in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar, depressed patients and those without psychotic characteristics</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mRNA expression level of the OXTR gene measured by RT-qPCR</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Expression of OXT et OXTR genes reduced and associated with social performence observed in patients with schizophrenia and bipolar or depressed patients with psychotic characteristics compared with those without</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Social Cognition of Schizophrenia, Bipolas or Depressed Patients</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>phenotypic data and a blood prelevment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Genetic</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ocytocine dosage and genetic analyse</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients are assessed using 4 paradigms: Reading the Mind in the Eyes Test (RMET), Interpersonal Reactivity Index (IRI), Empathy Quotient (QE), and a modified Delay Discounting task. They have a blood prelevment</description>
    <arm_group_label>phenotypic data and a blood prelevment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        &quot;Inclusion criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  - Major patient under 75 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presenting the DSM-5 criteria for schizophrenia, bipolar disorder or major depressive&#xD;
             episode.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capable of giving consent or under curatorship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Benefiting from a health insurance plan&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy (urine test performed prior to inclusion in the program)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &quot;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Caroline Dubertret</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>APHP</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Caroline Dubertret, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>33147606409</phone>
    <email>caroline.dubertret@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital Louis Mourier</name>
      <address>
        <city>Colombes</city>
        <zip>92700</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>social cognition of schizophrenia, bipolas or depressed patients</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

