<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04929977</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OPP1182699</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04929977</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>m-Health System for Tracking Kangaroo Mother Care and Temperature in Southern India</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of a m-Health System for Tracking Kangaroo Mother Care and Temperature for Providing Feedback to Family Care Givers or Front-line Workers to Enhance Kangaroo Mother Care Adherence</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. John's Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. John's Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The product innovation is a wearable device that (combined with a smartphone and back-end&#xD;
      analytics system) acts as a sensor, processor and actuator, and is therefore designed to&#xD;
      identify critical parameters (Kangaroo Mother Care adherence and temperature of neonate on a&#xD;
      24/7 basis and temperature of mother during these episodes), make intelligent and early&#xD;
      diagnosis of (persistent or impending) neonatal hypothermia, maternal/neonatal fever and&#xD;
      non-adherence to Kangaroo Mother Care and then trigger audio or visual alerts (via the&#xD;
      wearable or smart-mobile phone) for action by the care-giver or front-line healthcare worker&#xD;
      to enhance Kangaroo Mother Care duration or referral to a health facility as needed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Project design and implementation plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The logic model envisioned in this study as i) wearable sensors, technology design and&#xD;
      development with research team personnel as 'inputs'; ii) data analytics deployment with&#xD;
      detection of abnormalities as 'processes'; and iii) feedback alerts appraisal as the&#xD;
      'outputs' for this phase of testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental plan comprises of two steps: a non-clinical phase and a clinical phase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      i) The non-clinical phase comprises of the design, development and deployment of the data&#xD;
      capture and analytics system. This includes mobile phone app building with features such as&#xD;
      push notifications, offline data storage and synchronization on connectivity, local data&#xD;
      analysis (with sequentially increasing capabilities as more data comes in) and alerting&#xD;
      stakeholders. In addition, capability development of primary nodes for temporary storage and&#xD;
      real-time data analysis as also for long-term data storage capabilities that could be scaled&#xD;
      to district-level and state-level expansion in future will be done. Data monitoring capacity&#xD;
      will be built on real-time visualization dashboards and raising alerts for targeted&#xD;
      stakeholders. The entire computational hardware, algorithms/AI engine, network architecture,&#xD;
      overall data visualization including heat maps (infrastructure) for this proposed study will&#xD;
      be developed by industry experts (will be subcontracted).&#xD;
&#xD;
      ii)In the second phase, it is proposed to undertake a technological-feasibility study as a&#xD;
      small-scale clinical trial (in a convenient sample of 20 mother-baby pairs) for testing in&#xD;
      real-world conditions while the mother-infant pairs are in the hospital for a few days and&#xD;
      when they are discharged for follow-up at home for up to a week. This phase will also include&#xD;
      a qualitative research component to study acceptability and feasibility of alerting and&#xD;
      actionable advisories sent to care-givers and field staff. All data obtained from this&#xD;
      program will reside within dedicated servers with storage facilities within the selected&#xD;
      hospital from where mother-infant pairs are recruited. Institutional Ethics Committee&#xD;
      approval, clinical trial registration and data safety monitoring board constitution will be&#xD;
      undertaken to protect human research participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Wearable device combined with a smart mobile phone and back-end analytics system that acts as a temperature and touch sensor and actuator will be evaluated.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Device Feasibility</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of hypothermia episodes through the wearable device (remote bio-monitoring - RBM) in real world</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>1. Number of hypothermia (less than 36.5 degree centigrade) episodes</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of touch through the wearable device (remote bio-monitoring - RBM) in real world</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>1. No Kangaroo Mother Care ( Skin to skin contact between mother and baby) for 6 hours (alerted through RBM device)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of entire computational hardware of the remote bio-monitoring device</measure>
    <time_frame>8 months</time_frame>
    <description>No of alert messages from the RBM to project staffs.&#xD;
No of heat map views - total and within 24 hrs.&#xD;
No of responses to failure of normal temperature range (36.5-37 degree centigrade/ Kangaroo Mother Care alerts)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Preterm Infant</condition>
  <condition>Low Birth Weight Infant</condition>
  <condition>Kangaroo Mother Care</condition>
  <condition>Hypothermia, Newborn</condition>
  <condition>Fever</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Wearable device with smart mobile phone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>20 mother/care provider-infant pairs practicing Kangaroo Mother Care, from a tertiary super-specialty hospital selected to wear the device ( few days in the hospital and for a week at home when discharged)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Wearable device with smart mobile phone</intervention_name>
    <description>The wearable device will act as a sensor designed to identify critical parameters such as Kangaroo Mother Care adherence and temperature of the infant 24/7 and of the mother-infant pairs during these sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Wearable device with smart mobile phone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable LBW babies who are less than 2000 grams&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Kangaroo care provider who could preferably be the mother or any other family member&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extreme preterm infants (corrected gestational age less than 28 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any family member who is unwilling to hold the infant in Kangaroo Mother Care position&#xD;
             with the wearable device or if presenting with any infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>49 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Prem K Mony, MD; MSc-Epi</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>St. John's Research Institute, Bangalore 560034</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Johns Medical College and Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bangalore</city>
        <state>Karnataka</state>
        <zip>560034</zip>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.healthynewbornnetwork.org/blog/energy-independent-appropriate-medical-devices-winding-up-social-innovations-for-newborn-health/</url>
    <description>Energy independent appropriate medical devices-winding up social innovations for newborn health</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Conde-Agudelo A, Díaz-Rossello JL. Kangaroo mother care to reduce morbidity and mortality in low birthweight infants. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2014 Apr 22;(4):CD002771. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD002771.pub3. Review. Update in: Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;8:CD002771.</citation>
    <PMID>24752403</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baig MM, Gholamhosseini H, Connolly MJ. A comprehensive survey of wearable and wireless ECG monitoring systems for older adults. Med Biol Eng Comput. 2013 May;51(5):485-95. doi: 10.1007/s11517-012-1021-6. Epub 2013 Jan 19. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23334714</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bergh AM, Manu R, Davy K, van Rooyen E, Asare GQ, Williams JK, Dedzo M, Twumasi A, Nang-Beifubah A. Translating research findings into practice--the implementation of kangaroo mother care in Ghana. Implement Sci. 2012 Aug 13;7:75.</citation>
    <PMID>22889113</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Engmann C, Wall S, Darmstadt G, Valsangkar B, Claeson M; participants of the Istanbul KMC Acceleration Meeting. Consensus on kangaroo mother care acceleration. Lancet. 2013 Nov 30;382(9907):e26-7. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)62293-X. Epub 2013 Nov 16.</citation>
    <PMID>24246562</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fink G, Ross R, Hill K. Institutional deliveries weakly associated with improved neonatal survival in developing countries: evidence from 192 Demographic and Health Surveys. Int J Epidemiol. 2015 Dec;44(6):1879-88. doi: 10.1093/ije/dyv115. Epub 2015 Jun 30.</citation>
    <PMID>26130739</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lawn JE, Kinney MV, Belizan JM, Mason EM, McDougall L, Larson J, Lackritz E, Friberg IK, Howson CP; Born Too Soon Preterm Birth Action Group. Born too soon: accelerating actions for prevention and care of 15 million newborns born too soon. Reprod Health. 2013;10 Suppl 1:S6. doi: 10.1186/1742-4755-10-S1-S6. Epub 2013 Nov 15. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24625252</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee YG, Jeong WS, Yoon G. Smartphone-based mobile health monitoring. Telemed J E Health. 2012 Oct;18(8):585-90. doi: 10.1089/tmj.2011.0245.</citation>
    <PMID>23061640</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mony PK, Jayanna K, Bhat S, Rao SV, Crockett M, Avery L, Ramesh BM, Moses S, Blanchard J. Availability of emergency neonatal care in eight districts of Karnataka state, southern India: a cross-sectional study. BMC Health Serv Res. 2015 Oct 6;15:461. doi: 10.1186/s12913-015-1126-3.</citation>
    <PMID>26444272</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lund C. Medical adhesives in the NICU. Newborn and Infant Nursing Reviews 2014; 14; 14(4):160-165. DOI: 10.1053/j.nainr.2014.10.001</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Udani RH, Hinduja ARA, Rao SPN, Kabra NS. Role of Kangaroo Mother Care in Preventing Neonatal Morbidity in the Hospital and Community: A review article. Journal of Neonatology, Oct-Dec 2014; 28 (4):29-36.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Varkey P, Horne A, Bennet KE. Innovation in health care: a primer. Am J Med Qual. 2008 Sep-Oct;23(5):382-8. doi: 10.1177/1062860608317695.</citation>
    <PMID>18820143</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 19, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 18, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypothermia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Birth Weight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

