<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04924075</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>6482-015</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>MK-6482-015</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-005028-13</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>PT2977</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04924075</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Belzutifan/MK-6482 for the Treatment of Advanced Pheochromocytoma/Paraganglioma (PPGL) or Pancreatic Neuroendocrine Tumor (pNET) (MK-6482-015)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Belzutifan (MK-6482, Formerly PT2977) Monotherapy in Participants With Advanced Pheochromocytoma/Paraganglioma (PPGL) or Pancreatic Neuroendocrine Tumor (pNET)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of Belzutifan monotherapy in participants&#xD;
      with advanced pheochromocytoma/paraganglioma (PPGL) or pancreatic neuroendocrine tumor&#xD;
      (pNET). The primary objective of the study is to evaluate the objective response rate (ORR)&#xD;
      of belzutifan per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors Version 1.1 (RECIST 1.1) by&#xD;
      blinded independent central review (BICR).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 3, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 3, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response Rate (ORR) as Assessed by Blinded Independent Central Review (BICR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>ORR is the percentage of participants with complete response (CR: disappearance of all target lesions) or partial response (PR: at least a 30% decrease in the sum of diameters of target lesions, taking as reference the baseline sum of the diameters of target lesions) until progressive disease (PD, at least a 20% increase in the sum of diameters of target lesions, taking as reference the smallest sum on study. The appearance of one or more new lesions is also considered progression) or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response (DOR) as Assessed by BICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>DOR is the time from first documented evidence of CR or PR until disease progression or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Response (TTR) as Assessed by BICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>TTR is defined as the time from first dose of belzutifan to first documented evidence of CR or PR.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Control Rate (DCR) as Assessed by BICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Disease control is a confirmed CR, PR, or stable disease (SD, neither sufficient shrinkage to qualify for PR nor sufficient increase to qualify for PD, taking as reference the smallest sum diameters while on study).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progressive Free Survival (PFS) as Assessed by BICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>PFS is the time from first dose of belzutifan to the first documented PD or death from any cause, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>OS is the time from first dose of belzutifan until death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Experiencing Adverse Events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any unfavorable and unintended sign including an abnormal laboratory finding, symptom or disease associated with the use of a medical treatment or procedure, regardless of whether it is considered related to the medical treatment or procedure, that occurs during the course of the study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants Discontinuing Study Drug due to an AE</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to approximately 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>An adverse event (AE) is defined as any unfavorable and unintended sign including an abnormal laboratory finding, symptom or disease associated with the use of a medical treatment or procedure, regardless of whether it is considered related to the medical treatment or procedure, that occurs during the course of the study. The number of participants who discontinue study treatment due to an AE will be presented.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Pheochromocytoma/Paraganglioma</condition>
  <condition>Pancreatic Neuroendocrine Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Belzutifan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Belzutifan, 120 mg, oral, once daily (QD) until progressive disease or discontinuation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Belzutifan</intervention_name>
    <description>Belzutifan, 120 mg, oral, once daily (QD) until progressive disease or discontinuation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Belzutifan</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MK-6482</other_name>
    <other_name>WELIREG™</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort A1: Pheochromocytoma/Paraganglioma (PPGL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Has documented histopathological diagnosis (local report) of pheochromocytoma or&#xD;
        paraganglioma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Participants are allowed to receive therapy in first line where a satisfactory&#xD;
        treatment option does not exist and if participants are not candidates for systemic&#xD;
        chemotherapy or have refused such therapy. There is no limit on number of prior systemic&#xD;
        therapies. Locoregional therapies or adjuvant/neoadjuvant therapies are not considered a&#xD;
        line of prior systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has locally advanced or metastatic disease that is not amenable to surgery or curative&#xD;
             intent treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has adequately controlled blood pressure defined as blood pressure ≤150/90 mm Hg&#xD;
             (≤135/85 mm Hg for adolescents) and with no change in antihypertensive medications&#xD;
             (for participants with concomitant hypertension) for at least 2 weeks prior to start&#xD;
             of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohort A2: Pancreatic Neuroendocrine Tumor (pNET)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has documented histopathological or cytopathological diagnosis (local report) of&#xD;
             well-differentiated, low, or intermediate grade (G1 or G2 pNET per 2017 World Health&#xD;
             Organization (WHO) classification and grading) pNET.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has locally advanced disease or metastatic disease that is:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Not amenable for surgery, radiation, locoregional therapies or combination&#xD;
                  modality of such treatments with curative intent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Experienced disease progression on or after at least 1 line of prior systemic&#xD;
                  therapy that includes an approved targeted agent such as everolimus or sunitinib.&#xD;
                  Participants who have received &gt;3 prior systemic therapies will be capped to ≤20%&#xD;
                  of the cohort.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Chemoembolization/radiofrequency ablation/locoregional therapies,&#xD;
        neoadjuvant/adjuvant treatments, or somatostatin analog monotherapy or interferon&#xD;
        monotherapy will not count as 1 line of prior systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Cohorts A1 and A2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has disease progression within the past 12 months from screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has measurable disease per Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors version 1.1&#xD;
             (RECIST v1.1) by computed tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) as&#xD;
             assessed by local site investigator/radiology assessment and verified in real time by&#xD;
             blinded independent central review (BICR). BICR must confirm the presence of&#xD;
             radiologically measurable disease per RECIST 1.1 for the participant to be eligible&#xD;
             for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Irradiated lesions or lesions treated with locoregional therapies should not be&#xD;
                  used as target lesions unless they clearly demonstrate growth since completion of&#xD;
                  radiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Metastatic lesions situated in the brain are not considered measurable and should&#xD;
                  be considered nontarget lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Only lesions of the primary indication for the cohort may be evaluated for&#xD;
                  measurability; other neoplastic lesions will be documented by the investigator&#xD;
                  and this information provided to the independent reviewers to ensure that such&#xD;
                  lesions are not included in the RECIST assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Participants who are adolescents (12-17 years of age) need to have a body weight&#xD;
                  of 40 kilograms (kg) or more.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male participants are eligible to participate if they agree to the following during&#xD;
             the intervention period and for at least 7 days after the last dose of study&#xD;
             intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Be abstinent from heterosexual intercourse as their preferred and usual lifestyle&#xD;
                  (abstinent on a long-term and persistent basis) and agree to remain abstinent OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Must agree to use contraception unless confirmed to be azoospermic (vasectomized&#xD;
                  or secondary to medical cause as detailed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i. Agree to use a male condom plus partner use of an additional contraceptive method&#xD;
             when having penile-vaginal intercourse with a woman/women of childbearing potential&#xD;
             (WOCBP) who is not currently pregnant. Note: Men with a pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
             partner must agree to remain abstinent from penile-vaginal intercourse or use a male&#xD;
             condom during each episode of penile-vaginal penetration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A female participant is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant or&#xD;
             breastfeeding, and at least one of the following conditions applies:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Is not a WOCBP). OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Is a WOCBP and using a contraceptive method that is highly effective (with a&#xD;
                  failure rate of &lt;1% per year), or be abstinent from heterosexual intercourse as&#xD;
                  their preferred and usual lifestyle (abstinent on a long-term and persistent&#xD;
                  basis), for at least 30 days after the last dose of study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Submit an archival tumor tissue sample or newly obtained core or excisional biopsy of&#xD;
             a tumor lesion (not previously irradiated). Formalin-fixed, paraffin embedded (FFPE)&#xD;
             tissue blocks are preferred to slides. Newly obtained biopsies are preferred to&#xD;
             archived tissue if the lesion is accessible and a biopsy is not clinically&#xD;
             contraindicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: If participant has only 1 measurable lesion per RECIST 1.1, the biopsy specimen&#xD;
        should be obtained from a nontarget lesion or archival tissue. Bone biopsies should not be&#xD;
        submitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of either 0 or 1,&#xD;
             as assessed within 7 days of treatment initiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has adequate organ function.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is unable to swallow orally administered medication or has a disorder that might&#xD;
             affect the absorption of belzutifan.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of a second malignancy, unless potentially curative treatment has been&#xD;
             completed with no evidence of malignancy for 2 years with the following exceptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: The time requirement does not apply to participants who underwent successful&#xD;
        definitive resection of basal cell carcinoma of the skin, squamous cell carcinoma of the&#xD;
        skin, superficial bladder cancer, in situ cervical cancer, or other in situ cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with history of Von-Hippel Lindau (VHL) disease (germline VHL mutation&#xD;
             documented by a local test report or with clinical diagnosis) will be permitted&#xD;
             provided concurrent lesions (other than PPGL for Cohort A1 and pNET for Cohort A2) are&#xD;
             localized without immediate need for intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior history of surgical resection(s) for concurrent localized VHL disease-associated&#xD;
             tumors is allowed provided there is no history of metastatic disease from concurrent&#xD;
             tumors; history of systemic therapy for concurrent tumors will be exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with history of other genetic syndromes (such as those with succinate&#xD;
             dehydrogenase subunit genes (SDHx) germline mutation or multiple endocrine&#xD;
             neoplasia/MEN) will be allowed provided concurrent tumors (outside of the organ&#xD;
             affected in Cohort A1 and Cohort A2, respectively) are localized and do not require&#xD;
             immediate intervention; history of metastatic disease in concurrent tumors or history&#xD;
             of systemic therapy for concurrent tumors will be exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has known central nervous system (CNS) metastases and/or carcinomatous meningitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has clinically significant cardiac disease, including unstable angina, acute&#xD;
             myocardial infarction, or arterial bypass (CABG) or percutaneous transluminal coronary&#xD;
             angioplasty (PTCA) ≤6 months from Day 1 of study drug administration, or New York&#xD;
             Heart Association Class III or IV congestive heart failure. Concurrent uncontrolled&#xD;
             hypertension defined as blood pressure &gt;150/90 mm mercury (Hg) despite optimal&#xD;
             antihypertensive medications within 2 weeks prior to the first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Medically controlled arrhythmia stable on medication is permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known psychiatric or substance abuse disorder that would interfere with&#xD;
             cooperation with the requirements of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has had major surgery ≤4 weeks prior to first dose of study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior treatment (except somatostatin analogs) with chemotherapy, targeted&#xD;
             therapy, or other investigational therapy within the past 4 weeks of study entry, or&#xD;
             prior biologics or immunotherapy within the past 6 weeks of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior locoregional therapies or radiation within the past 4 weeks of&#xD;
             study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior treatment with Peptide Receptor Radionuclide Therapy&#xD;
             (PRRT)/radionuclide therapy (such as 177Lu-Dotatate) or other radiopharmaceutical&#xD;
             therapy within the past 12 weeks from screening for participants with pNET.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received meta-iodobenzylguanidine (MIBG) therapy or other radiopharmaceutical&#xD;
             therapy within the past 12 weeks from screening for participants with PPGL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received prior treatment with any HIF-2α inhibitor (including belzutifan).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known hypersensitivity to the study treatment and/or any of its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has toxicities from prior locoregional or systemic or any other therapies that is not&#xD;
             recovered to baseline or Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) ≤Grade&#xD;
             1 (with the exception of alopecia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has received colony-stimulating factors (e.g., granulocyte colony-stimulating factor&#xD;
             (G-CSF), granulocyte macrophage colony-stimulating factor (GM-CSF), or recombinant&#xD;
             Erythropoietin (EPO) ≤28 days prior to the first dose of study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently receiving strong (e.g., itraconazole, telithromycin, clarithromycin,&#xD;
             protease inhibitors boosted with ritonavir or cobicistat, indinavir, saquinavir,&#xD;
             nelfinavir, boceprevir, telaprevir) inhibitors of Cytochrome P450 3A4 (CYP3A4) that&#xD;
             cannot be discontinued for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently receiving either strong (phenobarbital, enzalutamide, phenytoin,&#xD;
             rifampicin, rifabutin, rifapentine, carbamazepine, nevirapine and St John's Wort) or&#xD;
             moderate (e.g., bosentan, efavirenz, modafinil) inducers of CYP3A4 that cannot be&#xD;
             discontinued for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is currently enrolled in and receiving study therapy, was enrolled in a study of an&#xD;
             investigational agent, and received study therapy or used an investigational device&#xD;
             within 4 weeks (28 days) of the first dose of study intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a known history of hepatitis B or known active hepatitis C (HCV) infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Cohort A2, has a tumor histology consistent with poorly differentiated pNET,&#xD;
             neuroendocrine carcinoma, or neuroendocrine tumor (NET) of nonpancreatic origin.&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Poorly differentiated or high grade pancreatic pNET or pancreatic neuroendocrine&#xD;
                  carcinoma; mixed adenoneuroendocrine carcinoma of the pancreas or concurrent&#xD;
                  pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma will not be allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Neuroendocrine tumor of nonpancreatic origin such as gastrointestinal,&#xD;
                  lung/thoracic, unknown primary, or other organs (including adenocarcinoid/goblet&#xD;
                  cell carcinoid/small cell carcinoma/large cell carcinoma). Note: Neuroendocrine&#xD;
                  carcinoma of any origin is exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Cohort A2, participants who have uncontrolled symptoms from functional pNETs at&#xD;
             study entry.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Medical Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Toll Free Number</last_name>
    <phone>1-888-577-8839</phone>
    <email>Trialsites@merck.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center ( Site 0110)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>310-933-4470</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Hospital-Sidney Kimmel Comprehensive Cancer Center - Developmental Therapeutics ( Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21287</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>443-467-3904</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University Medical Center ( Site 0107)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>800-811-8480</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center ( Site 0112)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>713-792-2841</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rigshospitalet-Department of Endocrinology ( Site 0303)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <state>Hovedstaden</state>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>35457562</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Strasbourg-Hautepierre-Medecine Interne, Endocrinologie et Nutrition ( Site 0402)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Strasbourg</city>
        <state>Alsace</state>
        <zip>67098</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+(0)3 88 12 75 93</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Edouard Herriot-oncologie ( Site 0405)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lyon</city>
        <state>Rhone-Alpes</state>
        <zip>69003</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+33472119692</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gustave Roussy ( Site 0403)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Villejuif</city>
        <state>Val-de-Marne</state>
        <zip>94800</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+33142114211</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopitaux Universitaires Paris Centre-Hopital Cochin ( Site 0404)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75679</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+33158411439</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Naples Federico II-Dipartimento di Medicina Clinica e Chirurgia ( Site 0704)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Naples</city>
        <state>Campania</state>
        <zip>80100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+390817462132</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Istituto Europeo di Oncologia IRCCS-Divisione di Oncologia Medica Gastrointestinale e Tumori Neuroe</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milano</city>
        <zip>20141</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+390257489258</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria Integrata Verona - Ospedale Borgo Roma ( Site 0703)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Verona</city>
        <zip>37134</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+390458128131</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GBUZ Republican Clinical Oncological Dispensary ( Site 0804)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ufa</city>
        <state>Baskortostan, Respublika</state>
        <zip>450054</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>79050022295</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saint Petersburg State University-Clinic of advanced medical technologies n. a. Nicolay I. Pirogov (</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <state>Leningradskaya Oblast</state>
        <zip>190020</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+79811228254</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saint-Petersburg City Clinical Oncology Dispensary-Department of chemotherapy ( Site 0803)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Saint Petersburg</city>
        <state>Leningradskaya Oblast</state>
        <zip>198255</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+79675231218</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fed State Budgetary Inst N.N. Blokhin Med Center of Oncology MHRF ( Site 0801)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <state>Moskva</state>
        <zip>115478</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+74993244383</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Endocrinology Research Center of Rosmedtechnologies-Surgery ( Site 0809)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Moscow</city>
        <state>Moskva</state>
        <zip>117036</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+74991243422</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario Central de Asturias-Medical Oncology ( Site 1101)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oviedo</city>
        <state>Asturias</state>
        <zip>33011</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>34646662756</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MD Anderson Cancer Center-Oncology ( Site 1102)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <state>Madrid, Comunidad De</state>
        <zip>28033</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>917878600 ext 2527</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitari Vall d'Hebron ( Site 1100)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08035</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>34934894350</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Skanes University Hospital Lund ( Site 1200)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lund</city>
        <state>Skane Lan</state>
        <zip>22185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+4646171000</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Akademiska sjukhuset-Blod- och tumörsjukdomar ( Site 1201)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uppsala</city>
        <state>Uppsala Lan</state>
        <zip>751 85</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>+46186110000</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ege University Medicine of Faculty ( Site 0900)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bornova</city>
        <state>Izmir</state>
        <zip>35100</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>00902323903911</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hacettepe Universitesi-oncology hospital ( Site 0901)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <zip>06230</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Study Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>00903123052910</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
    <country>Sweden</country>
    <country>Turkey</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIF-2a</keyword>
  <keyword>Pheochromocytoma/paraganglioma</keyword>
  <keyword>Pancreatic NET</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuroendocrine Tumors</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pheochromocytoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenoma, Islet Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paraganglioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carotid Body Tumor</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>http://engagezone.msd.com/doc/ProcedureAccessClinicalTrialData.pdf</ipd_description>
    <ipd_url>http://engagezone.msd.com/ds_documentation.php</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

