<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04926220</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP210311</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-A00088-33</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04926220</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dynamic Estimation of Cardiac Output in the Operating Room</brief_title>
  <acronym>TRIPLEFLOW</acronym>
  <official_title>Estimation of Cardiac Output in the Operating Room by Pulse Wave Analysis and Esophageal Doppler Blood Velocity: Comparison of the Two Methods</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>INSERM UMR-942, Paris, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      During major surgery, it is recommended to monitor invasive arterial blood pressure and&#xD;
      cardiac output (CO) during hemodynamic interventions (fluid challenge or vasopressors).&#xD;
      Esophageal Doppler is currently considered as the reference method for monitoring cardiac&#xD;
      output in the operating room. The PRAM method (pressure recording analytical method) with the&#xD;
      MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) and the LTIA method (long time interval analysis)&#xD;
      allow cardiac output estimation derived from non-calibrated arterial pressure waveform&#xD;
      analysis. Few studies have looked at relative changes in cardiac output during hemodynamic&#xD;
      intervention with these two methods. The aim of this study is to compare the relative changes&#xD;
      in cardiac output during hemodynamic interventions as measured using PRAM and LTIA methods,&#xD;
      compared to esophageal Doppler.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Hemodynamic optimization is a major issue in the perioperative and intensive care settings.&#xD;
      The titration of fluid in the operating room and in intensive care guided by the variations&#xD;
      of the stroke volume (SV) and therefore of the cardiac output (CO) improves morbimortality.&#xD;
      Esophageal Doppler is currently considered as the reference method for monitoring cardiac&#xD;
      output in the operating room. However, when its use is not possible, there are devices that&#xD;
      allow continuous estimation of cardiac output from the pulse wave contour (i.e. an invasive&#xD;
      blood pressure signal). The PRAM method (pressure recording analytical method) with the&#xD;
      MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) and the LTIA method (long time interval analysis)&#xD;
      using an analog-to-digital converter connected to the patient's scope seem to be promising&#xD;
      pulse wave analysis techniques. The majority of studies investigating these devices have&#xD;
      focused on cardiac output values from a purely static perspective. Few studies have looked at&#xD;
      changes in cardiac output during hemodynamic intervention (fluid challenge or use of&#xD;
      vasopressors). However, in daily clinical practice, it is the dynamic information on CO that&#xD;
      informs doctors on the effectiveness of therapeutic challenges. Thus, our hypothesis is to&#xD;
      compare the variations in cardiac output estimated by PRAM et LTIA methods with those&#xD;
      obtained using esophageal Doppler, during surgical procedures under general anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main goal of this study is to compare the relative changes in cardiac output obtained&#xD;
      during hemodynamic interventions (fluid challenge or vasopressors) using PRAM and LTIA versus&#xD;
      esophageal doppler. Parameters measured for the primary objective: 1. Continuous measurement&#xD;
      and recording of the invasive blood pressure signal 2. Continuous and simultaneous&#xD;
      measurement of cardiac output by MostCareUp (Vytech, Padova, Italy) and esophageal doppler.&#xD;
      3. Estimation of cardiac output from the arterial pressure signal by means of a digital&#xD;
      analog converter using the LTIA algorithm connected to the patient's scope. For all patients,&#xD;
      data from the cardiac output monitors are recorded throughout the procedure and the&#xD;
      resuscitation stay. The secondary objective is to study the hemodynamic parameters of&#xD;
      ventriculoarterial coupling calculated by the PRAM method and measured by esophageal doppler,&#xD;
      other than CO and SV during therapeutic challenges. Parameters measured for the secondary&#xD;
      objective: Global Afterload Angle (GALA), the value of the dicrote wave, dP/dtmax (myocardial&#xD;
      contractility index), cardiac efficiency (CCE), arterial elastance, the total impedance of&#xD;
      the system (Ztot).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental design: this is a single-center, observational prospective study The study&#xD;
      concerns adult patients benefiting from intraoperative hemodynamic optimization under general&#xD;
      anesthesia, including routine monitoring of blood pressure and measurement of cardiac output&#xD;
      by esophageal Doppler.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is &quot;non-interventional&quot; on adult patients undergoing interventional radiology,&#xD;
      surgery under general anesthesia, or admitted to the ICU for postoperative organ failure. All&#xD;
      measurements are obtained from standard monitoring including blood pressure and cardiac&#xD;
      output measurement by transesophageal Doppler. Monitoring includes continuous&#xD;
      electrocardiogram, SpO2, ventilatory parameters and depth of anesthesia by Bispectral Index.&#xD;
      During the anaesthesia consultation, the patients will be given a letter of information on&#xD;
      the objectives and the course of the study. Their non-opposition to participating in this&#xD;
      study will be collected at the latest during the pre-anesthetic visit, the day before the&#xD;
      operation. The protocol starts on the day of the operation. For all patients, the procedures&#xD;
      will be performed under general anesthesia with an intravenous anesthesia protocol with a&#xD;
      concentration objective (Orchestra® Base Primea - Fresenius Kabi France). The protocol does&#xD;
      not interact with the care procedure. On the day of the procedure, the MostCareUp (Vytech,&#xD;
      Padova, Italy) will be connected in series with the pressure head already in place. The blood&#xD;
      pressure signals will be continuously recorded to allow estimation of the cardiac output by&#xD;
      the LTIA method using an analog-to-digital converter. This calculation is made from the&#xD;
      signal that has been transmitted to the multiparametric scope monitor and is therefore not&#xD;
      directly connected to the patient. The acquisition of the analog signal is done via USB2.0&#xD;
      thanks to a Video Capture Card equipped with a converter. The software recalculates with its&#xD;
      algorithm an estimation of the cardiac output from the data. The clinician in charge in the&#xD;
      operating room will use only the hemodynamic data from the esophageal Doppler to guide his&#xD;
      therapeutic strategy. Synchronization of the 2 devices. Recording of events during&#xD;
      therapeutic tests if there is an indication for treatment. Usual protocol of the therapeutic&#xD;
      challenges service: Patient receiving intraoperative vascular filling titration to optimize&#xD;
      cardiac output (maximize SV/CO), patient with persistent arterial hypotension (MAP &lt; 65 mmHg&#xD;
      or &lt; 80% of baseline) during the procedure despite adequate depth of anesthesia (BIS 40-50)&#xD;
      and optimized cardiac output motivating vasopressor injection. For all patients, data from&#xD;
      the 2 cardiac output monitors and hemodynamics will be collected during and after the&#xD;
      therapeutic tests. Under no circumstances will a decision on therapeutic strategy be made&#xD;
      based on PRAM or LTIA data. No additional complementary examination will be performed. The&#xD;
      physician in charge of the study collecting the data does not intervene at any time in the&#xD;
      management of the patient. The implementation of this type of intraoperative monitoring does&#xD;
      not prolong the duration of anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The measure of agreement the investigators will use is the intra-class correlation&#xD;
      coefficient. To compare 3 measurement modalities, assuming that the intraclass correlation&#xD;
      coefficient for the measurement of VES variations will be 0.85 with a confidence interval&#xD;
      with width of 0.1 and a first-species risk of 0.05, 84 patients must be included. It is&#xD;
      expected that the signals of 10% of the included patients will be of insufficient quality for&#xD;
      their exploitation. Therefore, the calculated sample size is 92 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results will be expressed as mean (standard deviation) or median (interquartile range)&#xD;
      depending on the normality of the data distribution. A Bland-Altman analysis for repeated&#xD;
      measures will be used to evaluate the agreement between the cardiac output measured by&#xD;
      esophageal Doppler and the cardiac output estimated by the two pulse wave monitors. It will&#xD;
      be associated with a calculation of the bias and its 95% confidence interval, the upper/lower&#xD;
      limits of agreement and their 95% confidence intervals, and the percentage error. A&#xD;
      percentage of error less than or equal to 30% indicates the agreement of the technique with&#xD;
      the reference method. The agreement of cardiac output variations measured by esophageal&#xD;
      Doppler and pulse wave analysis will be evaluated by a Bland-Altman analysis. The percentage&#xD;
      of agreement will be evaluated using a four-quadrant plot. Acceptable agreement is defined as&#xD;
      greater than 90%. The analyses will be repeated in the filler and vasopressor subgroups. The&#xD;
      ability of pulse wave monitors to detect responders to filling will be assessed and compared&#xD;
      with esophageal doppler. Subjects will be defined as responders to volume expansion when the&#xD;
      filling test increases the ESV by more than 10%.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac output using the trans-esophageal Doppler technique</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of cardiac output with trans-esophageal doppler (CARDIOQ-ODM; Deltex Medical, Chichester, UK) in L/min (COTOD)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac output using the MostCareUp monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of cardiac output with MostCareUp (Vytech, Padova, Italy) in L/min (COPRAM)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiac output using the Argos monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>Measure of cardiac output with Argos monitor (Retia Medical, Valhalla, NY, USA) in L/min (COLTIA)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of the value of the dicrote wave with MostCareUp monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The value of the dicrote wave will be recorded with the MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of dP/dtmax (myocardial contractility index) with MostCareUp monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The dP/dtmax (myocardial contractility index) will be recorded with the MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of the cardiac efficiency (CCE) with MostCareUp monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The cardiac efficiency (CCE) will be recorded with the MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of arterial elastance with MostCareUp monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The arterial elastance will be recorded with the MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of the total impedance of the system (Ztot) with MostCareUp monitor</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The total impedance of the system (Ztot) will be recorded with the MostCareUp monitor (Vytech, Padova, Italy) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of the Global Afterload Angle (GALA) using the trans-esophageal Doppler technique</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The Global Afterload Angle (GALA) will be recorded with trans-esophageal Doppler (CARDIOQ-ODM; Deltex Medical, Chichester, UK) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of arterial elastance using the trans-esophageal Doppler technique</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the surgery (maximum 1 day)</time_frame>
    <description>The the arterial elastance will be recorded with trans-esophageal Doppler (CARDIOQ-ODM; Deltex Medical, Chichester, UK) during the whole procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">92</enrollment>
  <condition>Interventional Radiology</condition>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <condition>General Anesthesia</condition>
  <condition>Organ Failure</condition>
  <condition>Intensive Care</condition>
  <condition>Hemodynamic Instability</condition>
  <condition>Blood Pressure</condition>
  <condition>Cardiac Output</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing general anesthesia and benefiting from intraoperative hemodynamic optimization</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients undergoing general anesthesia and benefiting from intraoperative hemodynamic optimization, including routine monitoring of blood pressure and measurement of cardiac output by trans-esophageal Doppler.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Trans-esophageal Doppler monitoring</intervention_name>
    <description>Trans-esophageal Doppler monitoring (CARDIOQ-ODM; Deltex Medical, Chichester, UK) for monitoring of cardiac output</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing general anesthesia and benefiting from intraoperative hemodynamic optimization</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MostCareUP Haemodynamic Monitor</intervention_name>
    <description>MostCareUp (Vytech, Padova, Italy) waveform analysis cardiac output monitor</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing general anesthesia and benefiting from intraoperative hemodynamic optimization</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Argos Cardiac Output (CO) Monitor</intervention_name>
    <description>Argos monitor (Retia Medical, Valhalla, NY, USA) for cardiac output monitoring</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing general anesthesia and benefiting from intraoperative hemodynamic optimization</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients eligible for an interventional radiology procedure, surgery under general&#xD;
        anesthesia, or admitted to intensive care unit for postoperative organ failure, benefiting&#xD;
        from intraoperative and postoperative hemodynamic optimization in intensive care including&#xD;
        routine blood pressure monitoring and measurement of cardiac output by esophageal Doppler.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major patients (≥ 18 years )&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible for an interventional radiology procedure or surgery under general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Monitoring of invasive blood pressure and cardiac output by trans-esophageal Doppler.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients informed and having expressed their non-opposition to participation in this&#xD;
             research&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Atrial fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to trans-esophageal doppler&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient opposed to protocol participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant woman&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under judicial protection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient without affiliation to a social security scheme&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex HONG, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joaquim MATEO, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alex HONG, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 (0)149958309</phone>
    <email>alex.hong@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Joaquim MATEO, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 (0)149958374</phone>
    <email>joaquim.mateo@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AP-HP, Lariboisière Hospital, Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75010</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Alex HONG, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+33 (0)149958309</phone>
      <email>alex.hong@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Joaquim MATEO, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+33 (0)149958374</phone>
      <email>joaquim.mateo@aphp.fr</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cardiac output monitoring</keyword>
  <keyword>Pulse contour analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>Vasopressors</keyword>
  <keyword>Fluid challenge</keyword>
  <keyword>Trans-esophageal doppler</keyword>
  <keyword>Pressure recording analytical method</keyword>
  <keyword>Long time interval analysis</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

