<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04926922</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000231</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000231-I</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04926922</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>PREVAIL VIIIa: Evaluation of Latent Tuberculosis Infection Screening Methods in People Living With Retroviral Infection in Liberia</brief_title>
  <official_title>PREVAIL VIIIa: Evaluation of Latent Tuberculosis Infection Screening Methods in People Living With Retroviral Infection in Liberia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tuberculosis (TB) is a health threat for people living with human immunodeficiency virus&#xD;
      (HIV). People living with HIV are more likely than others to develop active TB. Also, TB&#xD;
      makes HIV progress faster. TB is a leading cause of death among people in the West African&#xD;
      country of Liberia. Researchers want to find an effective testing method for latent&#xD;
      tuberculosis infection (LTBI) to help people living with HIV in Liberia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To compare the interferon-gamma release assay (IGRA) and tuberculin skin test (TST) as LTBI&#xD;
      screening tests in people living with HIV in Liberia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 18 and older who take part in NIH study #19-I-N014 and are scheduled to have or&#xD;
      have had IGRA at a Month 12 HONOR study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a medical history and physical exam. Their medical records&#xD;
      and HONOR study records will be reviewed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have TST. Purified protein derivative will be placed in the skin of their&#xD;
      forearm. They will be observed for adverse reactions for 15 minutes. Between 48 and 72 hours&#xD;
      after placement, they will have a second study visit to have the TST read. If they miss this&#xD;
      time frame, they can return up to 7 days after placement. If they have a positive test&#xD;
      result, they will have a chest x-ray. They will have a third study visit to review the&#xD;
      results of the chest x-ray. They will be referred for clinical care if needed. They will take&#xD;
      a pregnancy test if needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation will last from 2 days to 6 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite the high burden of disease attributable to tuberculosis (TB) in Liberia and concerns&#xD;
      about its effect on HIV disease, screening for latent TB infection (LTBI) among people living&#xD;
      with HIV is not routinely performed in the country. This is a prospective study to compare&#xD;
      the interferon-gamma release assay (IGRA) and tuberculin skin test (TST) as LTBI screening&#xD;
      tests in people living with HIV in Liberia. Participants will be co-enrolled on the ongoing&#xD;
      HONOR (A CoHOrt Clinical, Viral, and ImmuNOlogic Monitoring Study of People Living with&#xD;
      Retroviral Infection in Liberia) study. A TST will be administered to eligible participants&#xD;
      who are being screened by IGRA on HONOR. There are little data on the correlation of TST vs.&#xD;
      IGRA in persons with HIV living in a high TB-burden setting such as Liberia. Whether IGRA can&#xD;
      more accurately identify persons with LTBI or active TB than TST in persons with HIV in&#xD;
      countries with high TB burden is still an area of active investigation. Since there is no&#xD;
      gold standard for diagnosing LTBI, the results of each method will be compared to evaluate&#xD;
      whether there is no difference in the probability of testing positive, assess the operational&#xD;
      functionality in the clinic and lab, and determine whether one test can be used with greater&#xD;
      sensitivity assuming comparable specificity. If shown to be an effective determination of&#xD;
      LTBI, the TST may be a simpler, more cost-effective, non-lab-based approach that could be&#xD;
      used to enhance medical decision-making in patients co-infected with HIV in resource-limited&#xD;
      areas.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of positive results using the IGRA and TST.</measure>
    <time_frame>48-72 hours after TST placement</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the sensitivity of the IGRA and TST as LTBI screening tools in people living with HIV in Liberia.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of each test type successfully completed and the result determined.</measure>
    <time_frame>48-72 hours after TST placement</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the operational functionality of the IGRA and TST.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <condition>HIV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HONOR participants at Month 12</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adult participants who agree to participate and meet the study-specific eligibility criteria at their Month 12 HONOR study visit</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult participants must be enrolled in the main HONOR study of people living with HIV in&#xD;
        Liberia and are at their Month 12 visit.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following&#xD;
&#xD;
        criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be a participant on the PREVAIL VIII/HONOR study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be at least 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Be scheduled to undergo or have undergone IGRA at a Month 12 HONOR study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to return to the clinic 48 to 72 hours after TST placement for reading.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this&#xD;
&#xD;
        study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received BCG vaccine &lt;=10 years prior.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or allergy to any component of the PPD product.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous severe reaction (e.g., necrosis, blistering, ulcerations, or anaphylactic&#xD;
             shock) to a TST.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented active TB or a clear history of treatment for latent infection or active&#xD;
&#xD;
        disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Extensive burns or eczema or other skin conditions on the forearms that could affect&#xD;
             placement and reading of the TST.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, would compromise the safety of&#xD;
             the study participant or staff, or would prevent proper conduct of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion of Special Populations (Children, Adults Who Lack Capacity to Consent and&#xD;
        Pregnant Women):&#xD;
&#xD;
        We are able to obtain knowledge about TST performance in Liberia without exposing children,&#xD;
        adults who lack capacity to consent, and pregnant women to the potential risk of reactions&#xD;
        to the TST.&#xD;
&#xD;
        INCLUSION OF VULNERABLE PARTICIPANTS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        N/A&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stephen A Migueles, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>C.H. Rennie Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kakata</city>
        <country>Liberia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duport Road Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monrovia</city>
        <country>Liberia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>JFK Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monrovia</city>
        <country>Liberia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Redemption Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monrovia</city>
        <country>Liberia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Liberia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 8, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Interferon-Gamma Release Assay (IGRA)</keyword>
  <keyword>Purified Protein Derivative (PPD)</keyword>
  <keyword>Tuberculin Skin Test (TST)</keyword>
  <keyword>TB</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Latent Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retroviridae Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

