<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04040907</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>XNW3009-1-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04040907</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of XNW3009 in Health Subject</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Dose-Escalation Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Single and Multiple Oral Doses of XNW3009 in Healthy Adult Subject</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sinovent Pty Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sinovent Pty Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      XNW3009 is a small molecule hURAT1 inhibitor developed independently by Sinovent Pty Ltd.,&#xD;
      and is intended to treat gout-related hyperuricemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Uricosuric drugs increase urinary uric acid excretion by blocking renal tubular reabsorption&#xD;
      of urate. The human urate transporter 1( hURAT1) is responsible for the majority of the&#xD;
      reabsorption of filtered urate, and the mutations in the hURAT1 gene have been demonstrated&#xD;
      to be responsible for urate non-homeostasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-escalation study to investigate&#xD;
      the safety, tolerability, PK and PD of XNW3009 after administration of single (Part A) and&#xD;
      multiple (Part B) oral doses in healthy adult subjects. Approximately six sequential dose&#xD;
      panels (single oral doses of 1, 5, 10, 20, 35 and 50 mg XNW3009) will be evaluated in SAD and&#xD;
      approximately three sequential dose panels (ten consecutive days for respectively daily oral&#xD;
      doses of 10, 20,35 mg, QD) will be evaluated in MAD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 13, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A Phase I, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Dose-Escalation Study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate incidence and severity of adverse eventsadministration in healthy adult subjects.</measure>
    <time_frame>From day1 to day7 for Part A</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study subject administered a medicinal product which does not necessarily have a causal relationship with this treatment.Adverse events will be coded using.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate incidence and severity of adverse eventsadministration in healthy adult subjects.</measure>
    <time_frame>From day1 to day24for Part B</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study subject administered a medicinal product which does not necessarily have a causal relationship with this treatment.Adverse events will be coded using.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate clinically significant changes from baseline in physical examinations</measure>
    <time_frame>From day1 to day7 for Part A</time_frame>
    <description>Physical examinations will be performed by a study delegated registered physician.Any findings made during the physical examination must be noted regardless of if they are part of the subject's medical history.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate clinically significant changes from baseline in physical examinations</measure>
    <time_frame>From day1 to day24 for Part B</time_frame>
    <description>Physical examinations will be performed by a study delegated registered physician.Any findings made during the physical examination must be noted regardless of if they are part of the subject's medical history.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the pharmacokinetic of maximum plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>From day1 to day4 for Part A</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected serially for analysis throughout the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the pharmacokinetic of maximum plasma concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>From day1 to day14 for Part B</time_frame>
    <description>Blood samples will be collected serially for analysis throughout the study period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Gout</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>XNW3009</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>XNW3009 placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>XNW3009</intervention_name>
    <description>XNW3009 is a small molecule hURAT1 inhibitor</description>
    <arm_group_label>XNW3009</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo and active drug will have the same appearance</description>
    <arm_group_label>XNW3009 placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Female (of non-child-bearing potential) or male, 18-45 years of age (both inclusive)&#xD;
             at the time of screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to give signed written informed consent form, and agree to comply with protocol&#xD;
             restrictions, including refraining from consuming alcohol, caffeinated beverages (i.e.&#xD;
             tea, coffee, etc.), and tobacco or nicotine containing products from 24 hours before&#xD;
             D-2 until the last PK blood sample collection is finished; Able to remain in-house for&#xD;
             the confinement period of the study without interruption;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Body mass index (BMI, weight [kg]/height [m]2) within 18.0-32.0 kg/m2 (both&#xD;
             inclusive);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. No clinically significant abnormal values on vital signs, B ultrasound and 12-lead&#xD;
             electrocardiogram (ECG). QT interval corrected for heart rate according to&#xD;
             Fridericia's formula (QTcF) must be within the following ranges: QTcF ≤450 msec for&#xD;
             male subjects, and QTcF ≤470 msec for female subjects. One repeat assessment is&#xD;
             permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Serum uric acid (sUA) level 4 mg/dL (0.24 mmol/L) to 8 mg/dL (0.48 mmol/L) for male&#xD;
             and 3.5 mg/dL (0.21 mmol/L) to 8 mg/dL (0.48 mmol/L) for female during screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. No clinically significant abnormal findings noted during screening for medical history&#xD;
             and physical examination, or clinically significant abnormal results during screening&#xD;
             clinical laboratory tests, including WBC, liver function and kidney function. One&#xD;
             repeat assessment is permitted at the discretion of the Investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. If male and if engaging in sexual intercourse with a female partner of childbearing&#xD;
             potential, willing to use a condom in addition to having the female partner use a&#xD;
             highly effective method of female contraception (See Section 5.5.3.1) from the time of&#xD;
             first study drug administration until the EOS visit. This requirement does not apply&#xD;
             to subjects in a same sex relationship or subjects with female partners of&#xD;
             non-childbearing potential. Male subjects must also be willing to not donate sperm for&#xD;
             the same period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. If female, be of non-childbearing potential: e.g. post-menopausal for ≥12 consecutive&#xD;
             months with follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) ≥40 mIU/mL at Screening; or surgical&#xD;
             sterilization for at least 90 days prior to screening e.g., tubal ligation or&#xD;
             hysterectomy. Note: Provision of documentation is not required for female&#xD;
             sterilization, verbal confirmation is adequate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Negative urine drug screen and alcohol breath testing at screening and Day-2. Note:&#xD;
             Screening urine drug test/ alcohol breath testing may be repeated once if deemed&#xD;
             appropriate by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1. Subjects who have a clinically relevant intolerance or allergy to drugs, or are&#xD;
             known or suspected to have hypersensitivity to any ingredient in the investigational&#xD;
             products or other URAT1 inhibitors; 2. Have a history of stomach or intestinal surgery&#xD;
             or resection that would potentially alter absorption and/or excretion of orally&#xD;
             administered drugs. Note: a subject who has had an appendectomy or hernia repair can&#xD;
             be enrolled in the study; 3. Subjects with a history or clinical manifestations of&#xD;
             significant metabolic, hematological, pulmonary, cardiovascular, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             neurologic, hepatic, renal, urological, or psychiatric disorders; 4. Current or&#xD;
             chronic history of liver disease or known hepatic or biliary abnormalities, including&#xD;
             but not limited to ALT, alkaline phosphatase and bilirubin &gt;ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. Current or history of cardiac arrhythmias (symptomatic or asymptomatic); 6. Recent&#xD;
             or current serious infection (within 30 days of screening). Examples include&#xD;
             cellulitis, pneumonia, septicemia. Subjects with mild upper respiratory tract&#xD;
             infection may be enrolled at the discretion of the investigator; 7. Estimating&#xD;
             glomerular filtration rate (using the Modification of Diet in Renal Disease method&#xD;
             based on serum creatinine and actual age) &lt; 90 ml/min/1.73m2; 8. Major illness or&#xD;
             surgery (except for minor outpatient surgery) within past 3 months of study Day 1, or&#xD;
             planned surgery during study; 9. Subjects with intolerance to direct venipuncture; 10.&#xD;
             Subjects with a history of, or signs and symptoms associated with, renal calculi or&#xD;
             gout; 11. Known or suspected history of drug abuse within the past 2 years or presence&#xD;
             of drug abuse within 3 months before screening, or evidence of such abuse on&#xD;
             laboratory assays at screening and Day -2 unless explained by a therapeutic dose of a&#xD;
             prescribed medication that was ceased at least 14 days prior to Day 1. Up to 1 repeat&#xD;
             permitted; 12. Habitual use of tobacco or nicotine products or smoking within 3 months&#xD;
             (more than 5 cigarettes per day) prior to screening, and, unwilling to refrain from&#xD;
             use of tobacco and nicotine containing products from 24 hours before Day -2 until&#xD;
             completion of the confinement period; 13. Unwilling to refrain from caffeinated&#xD;
             beverages (i.e. tea, coffee, etc) from 24 hours before Day -2 until completion of the&#xD;
             confinement period; 14. Participation in any clinical study with an investigational&#xD;
             drug, biologic or device within 4 weeks or 5 times the half-life of the specific&#xD;
             drug/biologics (whichever is longer), prior to dosing; 15. Donated blood &gt;400 mL or&#xD;
             significant blood loss equivalent to 400 mL or received blood transfusion within 3&#xD;
             months of screening, or donated blood &gt;200 mL or significant blood loss equivalent to&#xD;
             200 mL within 1 month prior to screening; or plans to donate blood during the study;&#xD;
             16. Malignancy within 5 years of screening visit (excluding non-melanoma skin cancer&#xD;
             that has been resected); 17. Recent administration or plans to receive administration&#xD;
             of live vaccine within 12 weeks before Day 1 up to 30 days after the last dose of IP;&#xD;
             18. Use of any other drug, including prescription and over-the-counter medications,&#xD;
             within 7 days prior to the first dose of study medication should be discussed with the&#xD;
             Investigator. Where appropriate, such medication should be ceased prior to dosing. The&#xD;
             subject may be enrolled if the medication taken or residual drug present is not&#xD;
             expected to interfere either with subject safety or study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Paracetamol at a dose of &lt;2 g in 24 hours but no more than 1 g in 4 hours;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dietary vitamins may be allowed at the discretion of the investigator (e.g.&#xD;
                  Vitamin D taken at a standard replacement dose, and at a time remote from IP&#xD;
                  administration);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Herbal supplements are not permitted; 19. Use of food or beverages likely to&#xD;
                  influence liver metabolism 14 days prior to the first dose of the study drug&#xD;
                  (e.g. star fruit, pomelos, grapefruit &amp; seville oranges); 20. History of&#xD;
                  significant alcohol abuse within 6 months of screening or any indication of&#xD;
                  regular use of more than 14 units of alcohol per week (1 Unit=360 mL of beer or&#xD;
                  45 mL of alcohol 40% or 150 mL of wine) and, unwilling to refrain from&#xD;
                  consumption of alcohol from 24 hours before Day -2 until completion of the&#xD;
                  confinement period; 21. Positive screening test for any one or more: serum&#xD;
                  hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg), hepatitis C antibody, or HIV; 22. Pregnant&#xD;
                  or lactating women; 23. Subject who is considered unsuitable for participating in&#xD;
                  the study in the opinion of investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sam Salman</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Linear Clinical Research</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sam Salman</last_name>
    <phone>0863825100</phone>
    <phone_ext>0863825100</phone_ext>
    <email>ssalman@linear.org.au</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Linear Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Perth</city>
        <state>West Austrialia</state>
        <zip>6009</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nicola Norton</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 2, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 1, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

