<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04044326</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201802047DIPB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04044326</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Safety and Efficacy of Spherical Microwave Ablation for the Treatment of Malignant Liver Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Safety and Efficacy of Spherical Microwave Ablation for the Treatment of Malignant Liver Tumors Closed to Inferior Vena Cava</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Liver cancer including primary hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and metastatic liver cancers is&#xD;
      one the most common malignancies in the world. Over 10000 new cases per year are diagnosed in&#xD;
      Taiwan. Several pre-clinical studies have already demonstrated microwave ablation (MWA) is a&#xD;
      safe and effective treatment for live cancers. The system (Solero Microwave Tissue Ablation&#xD;
      System) with 2.45 GHz microwave generator could create a spherical ablation zone, and has&#xD;
      certificated by CE (Conformité Européenne) mark and U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA)&#xD;
      approval in 2017. However, there are still few experiences in using MWA for tumor ablation in&#xD;
      Taiwan. In this study, the researchers will perform MWA for 20 inoperable patients with liver&#xD;
      cancers adjacent to inferior vena cava (IVC). The researchers will appraisal the clinical&#xD;
      feasibility and advantage of the system by this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Liver cancer including primary hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) and metastatic liver cancers is&#xD;
      one the most common malignancies in the world. Over 10000 new cases per year are diagnosed in&#xD;
      Taiwan. Despite the many treatment options, the prognosis of HCC remains dismal. More than&#xD;
      8000 people died of this cancer every year in Taiwan. A majority (70% to 85%) of patients&#xD;
      present with advanced or unresectable disease. In contrast, small liver cancers can be cured&#xD;
      with an appreciable frequency. Five-year disease-free survival exceeding 50% has been&#xD;
      reported for surgical resection, and for the inoperable patients who do not have vascular&#xD;
      invasion or extrahepatic spread. Radiofrequency ablation (RFA) is recommended as an&#xD;
      alternative curative therapy. However, the main drawback of RFA is its limitation to tumor&#xD;
      location. The tumors located adjacent to big vessels such as inferior vena cava (IVC), could&#xD;
      not be ablated completely sometimes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Microwave ablation (MWA) can ablate tumor by higher temperature than RFA, so is supposed not&#xD;
      to be diminished by adjacent vessels. Several pre-clinical studies have already demonstrated&#xD;
      MWA is a safe and effective treatment for live cancers. The system (Solero Microwave Tissue&#xD;
      Ablation System) with 2.45 GHz microwave generator could create a spherical ablation zone,&#xD;
      and has certificated by CE mark and FDA approval in 2017. However, there are still few&#xD;
      experiences in using MWA for tumor ablation in Taiwan. In this study, we will perform MWA for&#xD;
      20 inoperable patients with liver cancers adjacent to IVC in our hospital. The researchers&#xD;
      will evaluate the potential side effect and ablate effect of tumors by abdominal CT or MRI,&#xD;
      and the researchers will also follow-up this patients for 4 months to evaluate the complete&#xD;
      ablation rate and local recurrence rate. We will appraisal the clinical feasibility and&#xD;
      advantage of the system by this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Machine cannot provide&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 22, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 6, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>microwave ablation</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the efficacy of microwave ablation for the treatment of primary or secondary liver cancers: modified RECIST criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>up to one year</time_frame>
    <description>The primary measure for this will be the evaluation of tumor response according to the modified RECIST criteria by CT or MR imaging performed 1 month after treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>safety and local tumor recurrences</measure>
    <time_frame>within 30 days of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The safety endpoint will be treatment-related Serious Adverse Events occurring within 30 days of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>microwave ablation (MWA)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>20 patients with liver cancer, considered for local treatment of liver tumors of size measuring &lt;5 cm and without any signs of extra-hepatic metastasis, will be enrolled to be treated with microwave ablation (MWA)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The Solero Microwave Ablation</intervention_name>
    <description>The Solero Microwave Ablation system (Angiodynamics Ltd, USA) with a single microwave applicator operating at a 2.45 GHz will be used to perform MWA</description>
    <arm_group_label>microwave ablation (MWA)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Patients must meet all of the following inclusion criteria to be eligible for this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The diagnosis of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) or metastatic liver cancers with&#xD;
             pathologic proven, and the diagnosis of HCC will be made by pathology / cytology or&#xD;
             according to the AASLD(2010) diagnostic criteria. In brief, Nodules larger than 1 cm&#xD;
             found on ultrasound screening of a cirrhotic liver should be investigated further with&#xD;
             either tri-phase multidetector CT scan or dynamic contrast enhanced MRI. If the&#xD;
             appearances are typical of HCC (i.e., hypervascular in the arterial phase with washout&#xD;
             in the portal venous or delayed phase), the lesion should be treated as HCC. If the&#xD;
             findings are not characteristic or the vascular profile is not typical, a second&#xD;
             contrast enhanced study with the other imaging modality should be performed, or the&#xD;
             lesion should be biopsied. Biopsies of small lesions should be evaluated by expert&#xD;
             pathologists. Tissue that is not clearly HCC should be stained with all the available&#xD;
             markers including CD34, CK7, glypican 3, HSP-70, and glutamine synthetase to improve&#xD;
             diagnostic accuracy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Unsuitable for surgical resection but local ablation is indicated, however, the&#xD;
             distance between tumour and inferior vena cava is smaller than 1 cm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have at least one, but less than or equal to 3 tumors,&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Each tumor must be ≤ 5 cm in diameter,&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Child-Pugh class A-B,&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) score of 0-1,&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. American Society of Anaesthesiologists (ASA) score ≤ 3,&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate bone marrow and liver function (1). Platelet count ≥ 100 K/Μl(2). Total&#xD;
             bilirubin ≦ 3 mg/dL(3). ALT and AST &lt; 5 x upper limit of normal (4). PT-INR ≦ 2.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The disease status is not suitable to receive transarterial chemoembolization or other&#xD;
             standard treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Prior Informed Consent Form&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Life expectancy of at least 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients presenting with any of the following will not be enrolled into this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Women who are pregnant or women of child-bearing potential who are not using an&#xD;
             acceptable method of contraception,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received treatment with an investigational agent/ procedure within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             microwave ablation&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who cannot tolerate RFA procedure, including the patients have tumors closed&#xD;
             to gall bladder, pancreas, liver hilum and main bile ducts&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Acute infection or inflammation, acute and severe dysfunction of heart, liver and&#xD;
             kidney, and the patients with metallic implantation including pacemaker.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Known history of HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Concurrent extrahepatic cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kai-Wen Huang, MDPHD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NTUH</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <state>Test2</state>
        <zip>100</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 1, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 2, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 5, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 10, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 10, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>消融</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

