<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04059809</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2.777.676</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04059809</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Photobiomodulation for Breast Cancer Radiodermatitis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Photobiomodulation for Breast Cancer Radiodermatitis Prevention. A Randomized Controlled Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AC Camargo Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AC Camargo Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A prospective single blind controlled randomized trial to evaluate the superiority of&#xD;
      photobiomodulation (PBM) using LED-therapy in reducing the prevalence of radiodermatitis in&#xD;
      breast cancer compared to usual local care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Breast cancer is the second most common cancer in the world, the most common among women in&#xD;
      Brazil and accounts for approximately 25% of new cases of cancer in women. One of the pillars&#xD;
      of treatment is the radiotherapy, being able to generate a toxic effect in the neoplastic&#xD;
      cells and also deleterious in healthy cells, with early and late side effects, being&#xD;
      radiodermatitis one of these affections. Moreover, radiodermatitis may cause discontinuation&#xD;
      of radiotherapy until the skin is able to receive the appropriate dose. Photobiomodulation&#xD;
      (PBM) is a non-invasive, a-thermal treatment modality based on the effect of light in&#xD;
      biological systems leading to the activation of epithelial healing through the modulation of&#xD;
      several metabolic processes through photochemical reactions. PBM use in an oncologic setting&#xD;
      has become an interesting object of study in recent years and even though there are different&#xD;
      possibilities for the use in breast cancer and physicians are not yet familiar with this&#xD;
      therapy. Several in vitro studies with different cell types ranging from keratinocytes,&#xD;
      endothelial cells and fibroblasts have been performed showing that PBM is capable of&#xD;
      enhancing cell migration, proliferation, local metabolism, inducing collagen synthesis and&#xD;
      secretion of growth factors, self-regulation of the production of proinflammatory cytokines&#xD;
      and cellular apoptosis, aiding in the recovery of the dermis and epidermis. The aim of this&#xD;
      study will be to evaluate the superiority of the use of photobiomodulation using LED-therapy&#xD;
      in relation to the development of radiodermatitis in breast cancer compared to usual local&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will included 110 women after informed consent will be randomly assigned into two&#xD;
      groups. There will be 11 groups of 10 envelopes each, where each group will contain a code&#xD;
      that allocates patients in group A (05 patients) and group B (05 patients). After the&#xD;
      allocation of the 10 patients, a new envelope group will be available until the total number&#xD;
      of patients scheduled for this study is reached (110, 55 in each group). Group A (GA) will be&#xD;
      the control group of usual care according to the orientation of the radiation therapy clinic&#xD;
      responsible for the radiotherapy treatment and with the use of the PBM device switched off.&#xD;
      Group B (GB) will be the intervention group, which in addition to the usual care oriented in&#xD;
      the radiotherapy clinic responsible for the radiotherapy treatment will use the attached PBM.&#xD;
      Both groups will use a pair of glasses that will block the visualization of the light emitted&#xD;
      by the PBM device, precisely so that they do not know in which research group it is located.&#xD;
      Treatment will be done twice weekly, Tuesday and Thursday. The Photobiomodulation will be&#xD;
      with the Cicatrillux (Cosmedical®) LED that contains 36 red light emitters in a 10x12 cm&#xD;
      neoprene plate with 650 nm LED wave length whose optical spot diameter is 5 mm and with an&#xD;
      average wave length of 2 ~ 5 mw for 10 minutes that will be placed over the area that will be&#xD;
      irradiated for 10 minutes; the LED board will be wrapped in a plastic film that will be&#xD;
      changed between each use. Both, the control group and the intervention group, will be&#xD;
      evaluated for radiodermatitis by the oncologist who accompanies them and by a nurse, and both&#xD;
      evaluators will not know in which group the person evaluated belongs. Concomitant to the&#xD;
      radiotherapy sessions, both groups will be evaluated by a clinical and sociodemographic&#xD;
      questionnaire, by the &quot;Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System&quot; (BRFSS), by the&#xD;
      Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand Questionnaire (DASH) by the Analog Visual Scale&#xD;
      for Pain, Radiodermatitis Assessment through the Radiation Therapy Oncology Group (RTOG),&#xD;
      application of the European Organization for Research and Treatment of Breast Cancer-Specific&#xD;
      Quality of Life Questionnaire questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-BR23) and the European Organization&#xD;
      for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC QLQ-30), all questionnaires have already been&#xD;
      translated and validated into the Portuguese language. The classification of radiodermatitis&#xD;
      and pain assessment will be repeated 90 days after the start of radiotherapy. A descriptive&#xD;
      and comparative analysis of the intervention groups will be performed in relation to the&#xD;
      selected variables. The evaluation of the outcomes will be performed by intention to treat&#xD;
      and by adherence to the protocol, through relative risk, and 95% confidence interval. To&#xD;
      analyze the data will be used &quot;Statistical Package for Social Sciences&quot; (SPSS) v.23 Demo&#xD;
      (SPSS Inc., Chicago, Illinois, United States). The McNemar test will be used to compare pain&#xD;
      levels between groups. For inter-group assessments of the proportion of radiodermatitis, the&#xD;
      chi-square test will be used to compare the intervention and control of the group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives will be to describe the socio-demographic and clinical characteristics&#xD;
      of the studied population; to evaluate the incidence of radiodermatitis in people with breast&#xD;
      cancer, immediately after and 90 days post-radiotherapy according to study intervention&#xD;
      group; to evaluate the adherence and satisfaction to treatment with PMB using LED-therapy in&#xD;
      people with breast cancer; to compare the occurrence of pain and its graduation according to&#xD;
      the intervention group, immediately after the radiotherapy and in the follow-up of 90 days in&#xD;
      people with breast cancer; to evaluate the quality of life of people submitted to&#xD;
      radiotherapy for breast cancer according to the intervention group and changes in&#xD;
      radiotherapy treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria are women older than 18 years with histological diagnosis of breast&#xD;
      cancer who underwent conservative surgery or mastectomy, without immediate breast&#xD;
      reconstruction, treated with conventional radiotherapy referred by the oncologist who&#xD;
      accompanies her regularly and who have availability of 20 minutes before the radiotherapy&#xD;
      session to CORSB Radiation Therapy and Megavoltage to apply the LED-therapy and accept to&#xD;
      participate in the research signing the Free and Informed Consent Term (TCLE). Patients who&#xD;
      have undergone mastectomy with immediate breast reconstruction and those who suffer from&#xD;
      collagen diseases will be excluded from this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators hypothesized that photobiomodulation can stop the progression of&#xD;
      radiodermatitis or lead to a faster cure, in turn, would have beneficial effects on the&#xD;
      quality of life of these people. Then, it is expected that, at the end of radiotherapy&#xD;
      sessions, people treated with therapy would have less severe skin reactions and higher&#xD;
      quality of life when compared to people in the control group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 26, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 20, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized single blind controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>The participant and care provider will be blinded regarding the status of photobiomodulation device (if switched on or off).</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade of Radiodermatitis</measure>
    <time_frame>During radiation treatment</time_frame>
    <description>&quot;Radiation Therapy Oncology Group&quot; (RTOG) grading</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade of Radiodermatitis</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>&quot;Radiation Therapy Oncology Group&quot; (RTOG) grading</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance</measure>
    <time_frame>One day after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS) Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System (BRFSS) Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Arm Disabilities</measure>
    <time_frame>One day after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand Questionnaire (DASH)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Arm Disabilities</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>Disabilities of the Arm, Shoulder and Hand Questionnaire (DASH)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Breast Cancer-Specific Quality of Life Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>One day after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>European Organization for Research and Treatment of Breast Cancer-Specific Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-BR23)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Breast Cancer-Specific Quality of Life Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>European Organization for Research and Treatment of Breast Cancer-Specific Quality of Life Questionnaire (EORTC QLQ-BR23)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Quality of Life Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>One day after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC QLQ-30)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Quality of Life Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days after radiotherapy completion</time_frame>
    <description>European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer (EORTC QLQ-30)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Radiodermatitis</condition>
  <condition>Radiotherapy Side Effect</condition>
  <condition>Radiation Dermatitis</condition>
  <condition>Radiation Toxicity</condition>
  <condition>Radiation Injuries</condition>
  <condition>Quality of Life</condition>
  <condition>Breast Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group will have usual care according to the orientation of the radiation therapy faculty responsible for the radiotherapy treatment the PBM device will be switched off</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Photobiomodulation (PBM)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Additionally to the usual care, the patients will receive the PBM. Treatment will be done twice a week.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Photobiomodulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Photobiomodulation will be with the Cicatrillux (Cosmedical®) LED that contains 36 red light emitters in a 10x12 cm neoprene plate with 650 nm LED wave length whose optical spot diameter is 5 mm and with an average wave length of 2 ~ 5 mw for 10 minutes that will be placed over the area that will be irradiated for 10 minutes;</description>
    <arm_group_label>Photobiomodulation (PBM)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mastectomy or breast conserving surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy schedule completion&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Auto-immune disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immediate reconstruction&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Glauco Baiocchi, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>AC Camargo Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universidade do Vale do Itajai - UNIVALI</name>
      <address>
        <city>Itajai</city>
        <state>Santa Catarina</state>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 13, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 14, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Laser</keyword>
  <keyword>Photobiomodulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Radiodermatitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dermatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Radiodermatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Radiation Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

