<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04054752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>190134</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>19-C-0134</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04054752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Vaccine Response With NT-I7</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1/1b Study of Enhancement of Immune Reconstitution and Vaccine Responses With Administration of Recombinant Human IL-7-hyFc (NT-I7) in Older Subjects Following Chemotherapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>NeoImmuneTech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People with cancer, and especially older people, have a weakened immune system (the defense&#xD;
      system of the body). This is often caused by the treatments for cancer. Older cancer&#xD;
      survivors are therefore more prone to getting infections, some of which are preventable&#xD;
      through vaccines. But because their immune systems are weakened, their response to vaccines&#xD;
      is poor. Researchers want to see if a new drug, NT-I7, can help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To see if NT-I7 can boost the immune system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults 60 and older who have recently finished chemotherapy for breast, colorectal, or&#xD;
      bladder cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a physical exam, medical history, and blood and urine&#xD;
      samples. Their heart s electrical activity will be checked. They will have an ultrasound of&#xD;
      their spleen. They may give a tissue sample from a previous biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in phase 1a of the study will get 1 dose of NT-I7. It will be given by injection&#xD;
      with a needle into the muscle of the upper arm, thigh, or buttocks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in phase 1b will get 5 vaccines over a few months. They may get an optional&#xD;
      booster and/or 6th vaccine. They will also get NT-I7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will repeat the screening tests during the study. They may get a peripheral&#xD;
      intravenous catheter in a vein in their hand or arm for blood draws.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may have apheresis. For this, blood is taken from an arm vein. The white blood&#xD;
      cells are separated from the blood. The rest of the blood, minus the white blood cells, is&#xD;
      returned into a vein in the other arm. A catheter may be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have follow-up visits for 1 year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interleukin-7 is a homeostatic cytokine with a critical role in lymphoid homeostasis through&#xD;
      which it exerts its immune-restorative effects, particularly re-expansion of the na(SqrRoot)&#xD;
      ve and memory T-cell subsets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical implications of the kinetics, nature and extent of immune reconstitution defects&#xD;
      following standard or ablative chemotherapy in older adults with cancer (in particular the&#xD;
      lack of reconstitution of large pools of na(SqrRoot) ve T-cell with broad repertoire&#xD;
      diversity and of memory T-cells) are not well characterized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As chemotherapy often induces only temporary complete or partial disease responses but no&#xD;
      cure, candidates for novel immunotherapy strategies may be significantly impeded in their&#xD;
      responses to active immunotherapy attempts, the therapeutic potential of which is becoming&#xD;
      increasingly utilized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recombinant human IL-7 (rhIL-7) may play a role in immune reconstitution and immune&#xD;
      enhancement in various circumstances of immune insufficiency in older individuals following&#xD;
      chemotherapy or in the context of enhancing cancer immunotherapy or during immune senescence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Elderly cancer survivors are vulnerable to vaccine-preventable diseases and are known to have&#xD;
      poor anti-vaccine-specific immune responses. Effective prevention of communicable diseases is&#xD;
      important for cancer survivorship.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will use NT-I7, a long acting IL-7 cytokine, composed of human IL-7 and a hybrid&#xD;
      Fc (hyFc) region to extend half-life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1: Select optimal biological dose (OBD) of NT-I7 in older subjects with breast,&#xD;
      bladder, prostate or a gastrointestinal cancer following chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1b: Evaluate and quantify the functional impact of NT-I7 therapy on specific immune&#xD;
      responses to selected vaccines in older subjects following chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults greater than or equal to 60 year of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diagnosis of non-metastatic breast, bladder or a gastrointestinal cancer following adjuvant /&#xD;
      neo-adjuvant chemotherapy; or metastatic breast, gastrointestinal or prostate cancer after&#xD;
      chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Completed a treatment with chemotherapy a minimum of 4 weeks and no more than 12 months prior&#xD;
      to entry with no evidence of disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reasonable expectation that no cancer-specific therapy will be given in the subsequent 6&#xD;
      months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be enrolled into this single center Phase 1/1b study following the specific&#xD;
      therapy for their respective diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Phase 1 part of the study, two dose levels, 720 micro g/kg and 960 micro g/kg, will be&#xD;
      compared. Six subjects will be enrolled in each dose level, and a single dose of NT-I7 will&#xD;
      be delivered intramuscularly. The purpose of this part of the study is to select the OBD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBD is defined as the dose that yields the greatest rise in peak absolute total T-cell counts&#xD;
      (peak value at any timepoint during the first 28 days post NT-I7 administration) with&#xD;
      corresponding rise in na(SqrRoot) ve subsets of CD4+ and CD8+ T cells without accompanying&#xD;
      substantial toxicities. Absolute increase is a delta between the baseline counts and the peak&#xD;
      counts within each subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once OBD is determined, the Phase 1b portion of this study will begin. Subjects will undergo&#xD;
      immunizations with various antigens, randomized to be administered either before or after a&#xD;
      single dose of NT-I7 at OBD. This inter-subject randomization of the order in which the&#xD;
      immunizations are administered (according to the Sequence 1 or to the Sequence 2 schedule)&#xD;
      will allow all immunocompromised subjects entered on the Phase 1b portion of the study to&#xD;
      receive NT-I7.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The vaccines, randomly assigned to be administered before NT-I7 therapy are administered six&#xD;
      weeks before the administration of NT-I7 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The vaccines, randomly assigned to be administered after NT-I7 therapy are administered 3&#xD;
      weeks after NT-I7 injection.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 19, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 19, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1: Safety of NT-I7 in elderly patients after chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days after treatment</time_frame>
    <description>List of adverse events and frequency</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase 1b: Evaluate and quantify if NT-I7 at optimal biological dose (OBD) has impacts on specific immune responses to vaccines</measure>
    <time_frame>day 42 and day 106</time_frame>
    <description>vaccine titers</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">68</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Colorectal Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Bladder Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1/Arm 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>NT-I7 administered at 720 and 960g/kg to select the OBD of NT-I7</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2/Arm 2a</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Administration of 4 vaccines according to Sequence 1 + NT-I7 administration at OBD to assess vaccine response</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3/Arm 2b</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Administration of 5 vaccines according to Sequence 2 + NT-I7 administration at OBD to assess vaccine response</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Recombinant human IL-7-hyFc (NT-I7)</intervention_name>
    <description>NT-I7 administered at escalating doses of 720, and 960g/kg to determine OBD of NT-I7</description>
    <arm_group_label>1/Arm 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vaccine sequence 1</intervention_name>
    <description>Day 1 Immunization Pre-NT-I7:Td and Polio Day 64, Immunization Post-NT-I7: Hep A#1, Hep B#1 Day 106: Hep B#2 (Optional) 6 Month Post NT-I7 Vaccines (Optional): Polio, Hep A#2, Hep #3, PPSV23#1</description>
    <arm_group_label>2/Arm 2a</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vaccine sequence 2</intervention_name>
    <description>Day 1 Immunization Pre-NT-I7: Hep A#1, Hep B#1 Day 64, Immunization Post-NT-I7:Td and Polio, PCV13 Day 106: no Vaccine 6 Month Post NT-I7 Vaccines (Optional): Polio, Hep A#2, Hep #3, PPSV23#1</description>
    <arm_group_label>3/Arm 2b</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 60 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documentation of positive diagnosis based on pathology/histology report (no need for&#xD;
             archival tissue or new biopsy) for any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stage I-III breast carcinoma following neo-adjuvant/adjuvant chemotherapy and&#xD;
                  appropriate surgery and/or radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stage II or III gastrointestinal cancer following appropriate surgery and&#xD;
                  adjuvant chemotherapy or following appropriate neoadjuvant chemoradiation/surgery&#xD;
                  and adjuvant chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stage II or III bladder carcinoma following neo-adjuvant chemotherapy and&#xD;
                  appropriate surgery or following adjuvant chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stage IV breast, gastrointestinal, or prostate cancer, following surgery and&#xD;
                  chemotherapy, or chemotherapy alone&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: &quot;Appropriate therapy&quot; for each disease must be consistent with NCCN Clinical Practice&#xD;
        Guidelines in Oncology available at the time of treatment in the opinion of the&#xD;
        investigator (http://www.nccn.org/professionals/physician_gls/f_guidelines.asp)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completed cancer specific therapy (including surgery, radiotherapy and/or systemic&#xD;
             therapy) at least 4 weeks and no more than 12 months prior to registration. (Subjects&#xD;
             with hormone receptor positive breast carcinoma maintained on hormonal therapy&#xD;
             following chemotherapy and radiation are eligible. Subjects with HER2 positive breast&#xD;
             carcinoma maintained on anti-HER2 agents after definitive therapies are also&#xD;
             eligible).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reasonable expectation that no cancer-specific therapy, with the exception noted in&#xD;
             the previous criteria, will be given in the subsequent 6 months (PI's discretion).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function, as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST/ALT: &lt; 3 times upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin: &lt; 1.5 times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute Neutrophil Count: &gt; 1000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count: &gt; 75,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  INR/PTT: &lt;1.5 times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum Creatinine: &lt;1.5 times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CPK: &lt;2.5 times ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin: greater than or equal to 3g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum electrolytes: within normal limits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance status greater or equal to 70%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Effects of NT-I7 on the developing human fetus are unknown. For these reasons the&#xD;
             following measures apply:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects enrolled on the study must not be planning to father children within the&#xD;
                  projected duration of the trial, starting with the pre-screening/screening visit&#xD;
                  through 90 days after the administration of NT-I7.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men with partners of childbearing potential (defined as any female who has&#xD;
                  experienced menarche and who has not undergone successful surgical sterilization&#xD;
                  or who is not postmenopausal (i.e., amenorrheic for greater than or equal to 12&#xD;
                  months without alternative medical cause) must use effective contraception prior&#xD;
                  to study entry, and for 90 days after the administration of NT-I7.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while her partner is&#xD;
                  participating in this study, the study participants' treating physician should be&#xD;
                  informed immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who are receiving any other investigational agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant heart disease defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Significant coronary arterial disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction in the last 6 months, angina in the previous 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Troponin elevation above reference range set by each institution where the&#xD;
                  troponin measurement was performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ischemic changes on ECG&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Atrio-ventricular block greater than 1st degree, in absence of pacemaker&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QTc (using Fridericia and Framingham correction formula) greater than 480ms&#xD;
                  (CTCAE 5.0 grade 1 abnormality is acceptable)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of ventricular arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Left Ventricular Ejection Fraction of less than 50% determined by&#xD;
                  echocardiography&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive serology for HTLV-I or HIV, or serology findings indicative of ongoing&#xD;
             infection with hepatitis A, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C. Subjects with serology&#xD;
             findings indicative of previous exposure to hepatitis A or B vaccination will not be&#xD;
             excluded from Phase 1 part of the study but will be excluded from Phase 1b part of the&#xD;
             study (see below for additional exclusion criteria for the Phase-1b part of the study&#xD;
             only).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of autoimmune disease EXCEPT for the following: subjects with vitiligo or&#xD;
             endocrine disease controlled by replacement therapy including diabetes, thyroid, and&#xD;
             adrenal disease may be enrolled&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects requiring chronic immunosuppressive therapy (including corticosteroids above&#xD;
             physiologic replacement dosage) for any medical condition. We will permit 1) systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids at physiologic replacement dosage which are not to exceed 10 mg/day of&#xD;
             prednisone or an equivalent, 2) intranasal or inhaled corticosteroids, 3)&#xD;
             intraarticular injection of corticosteroids, 4) topical corticosteroids, 5) or a&#xD;
             short-term use of systemic corticosteroids greater than 10 mg/day of prednisone or an&#xD;
             equivalent for 10 days or less.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Splenomegaly or history of proliferative hematologic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation or solid organ&#xD;
             transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of medical or psychiatric disease, or cognitive impairment, which, in the view&#xD;
             of the principal investigator would preclude safe treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious bleeding diathesis based on clinical history of significant bleeding&#xD;
             attributed to coagulation/bleeding disorders, documentation of abnormal coagulation&#xD;
             factors/platelet function studies at the discretion of PI, or those who are on&#xD;
             therapeutic anticoagulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects who have received immune checkpoint inhibitors in the previous 12 months, or&#xD;
             subjects who have received immunomodulatory drugs in the previous 4 weeks for any&#xD;
             medical indications. Subjects who have received intravesical BCG administration for&#xD;
             non-muscle invasive bladder cancer will be included in this study (i.e., not one of&#xD;
             exclusion criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Additional exclusion criteria for the Phase-1b part of the study only are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Known hypersensitivity to any of the following: diphtheria toxoid, neomycin,&#xD;
                  polymixin B, streptomycin, 2 phenoxyethanol, formaldehyde, aluminum hydroxide,&#xD;
                  yeast&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous exposure to Hepatitis A or B vaccines or history of hepatitis A or B&#xD;
                  infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects who received a Td or Tdap immunization in the previous 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of anaphylaxis or serious allergic reactions to previous administration&#xD;
                  of any of the vaccines&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subjects who had received one or more doses of the PPSV23 vaccine in the previous&#xD;
                  12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Latex allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A history of Guillain-Barre syndrome within six weeks of administration of&#xD;
                  previous tetanus toxoid containing vaccines.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ronald E Gress, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ronald E Gress, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(240) 760-6167</phone>
    <email>gressr@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact National Cancer Institute Referral Office</last_name>
      <phone>888-624-1937</phone>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2019-C-0134.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 5, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 10, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Breast Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Colorectal Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Immune Insufficiency</keyword>
  <keyword>Bladder Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Immunocompromised Host</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

