<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04054453</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NIHR200144</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04054453</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prevention of Epilepsy by Reducing Neonatal Encephalopathy</brief_title>
  <acronym>PREVENT</acronym>
  <official_title>Prevention of Epilepsy by Reducing Neonatal Encephalopathy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Thayyil, Sudhin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University College, London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Oxford</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Manchester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Madras Medical College</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bangalore Medical College and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Government Medical College, Kozhikode</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Thayyil, Sudhin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to examine if a pragmatic, evidenced based and generalisable&#xD;
      intrapartum care bundle involving birth companions and empowering mothers will reduce birth&#xD;
      injury-related epilepsy at 18 months of age in India.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The care bundle will have four key elements (interventions): (1) birth companion providing&#xD;
      constant 1:1 care during labour and early perinatal period; (2) fetal surveillance during&#xD;
      active labour by a nurse or midwife using a graphic display Doppler; (3) labour management by&#xD;
      an electronic partogram with an 'alert' and 'nag' feature based on the current WHO&#xD;
      guidelines; (4) brain oriented early newborn care with resuscitation where indicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The care bundle will be evaluated using a prospective interrupted time series design,&#xD;
      recruiting 80,000 women delivering in one of the three participating centres in south India,&#xD;
      over two years. Accurate baseline data will be collected during the first year and the&#xD;
      optimised care bundle will be introduced during the second year. All full term newborn&#xD;
      infants admitted to the neonatal unit with perinatal brain injury during both periods, will&#xD;
      have detailed assessments including video electroencephalography, and magnetic resonance&#xD;
      imaging, and will be followed up until 18 months of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome is the number of infants with epilepsy (categorised per current ILAE&#xD;
      guidelines) at 18 months of age expressed as per 1000 term livebirths. The investigators will&#xD;
      use a segmented logistic regression to divide the time series into pre- and post-intervention&#xD;
      segments, with the intervention date as the intersection between segments. The difference in&#xD;
      the two segments will be quantified using the level (step change) and slope (trend change).&#xD;
      The total duration of the study is four years including 24 months of recruitment and 18&#xD;
      months of follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Epilepsy is a condition where individuals are prone to recurrent epileptic seizures; which&#xD;
      means a change in the electrical activity of the brain resulting in a change in behaviour or&#xD;
      movement. Epilepsy is a symptom of the condition of which there are many different causes,&#xD;
      including brain injury occurring around the time of birth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Worldwide approximately 50-70 million people have epilepsy, and 4.6 million develop epilepsy&#xD;
      each year. The incidence of epilepsy in low and middle-income countries (LMICs) (1.3 per 1000&#xD;
      people) is 2 to 3 times higher than that in high-income countries (0.49 per 1000 people). The&#xD;
      Prevention Task Force of the International League Against Epilepsy [1] estimated that&#xD;
      perinatal brain insults accounted for the largest attributable fraction of paediatric and&#xD;
      adult epilepsy in LMICs with median (95% confidence intervals) estimated fractions of 17.4%&#xD;
      (14.7 to 18.9) and 11.4% (7.8 to 15.4). The contribution (population attributable risk) of&#xD;
      perinatal brain insults towards preventable epilepsy is 3 times higher than that of central&#xD;
      nervous system infections with parasites, virus and bacteria (5.3%), and traumatic brain&#xD;
      injury (6.6%). The task force concluded that health programmes to improve prenatal and&#xD;
      intrapartum care in LMIC may prevent a substantial proportion of epilepsy in LMICs[1].&#xD;
&#xD;
      12 million people were estimated to be living with epilepsy in India in 2015, accounting for&#xD;
      1/6th of the global epilepsy burden [2]. The annual economic burden of epilepsy to the Indian&#xD;
      economy was estimated to be £1.3 billion ($1.74 USD) with a cost of £260 ($344 USD) per&#xD;
      patient per year in 2001[3], based on the burden of 5 million people with epilepsy in India&#xD;
      at that time. Hence the current costs, based on 12 million people with epilepsy in 2015 [2],&#xD;
      may be much higher. Approximately 500,000 new epilepsy cases occur in India every year[3], of&#xD;
      which 87,000 (17.4%) are likely to be related to a birth related brain injury. The vast&#xD;
      majority of these cases will have additional neurodisabilities including cerebral palsy,&#xD;
      deafness and blindness. Hence, the social and economic burden of epilepsy related to&#xD;
      perinatal brain injury is likely to be much higher than isolated epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis. Epilepsy from perinatal brain injury can be reduced by the use of a pragmatic,&#xD;
      evidenced based and generalisable intrapartum care bundle that involves birth companions,&#xD;
      intelligent fetal heart rate monitoring, an e-partogram and brain oriented neonatal&#xD;
      resuscitation, in Indian public sector hospitals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. Aims and objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary aim&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. To examine if epilepsy caused by birth related brain injury in Indian public sector&#xD;
      hospitals can be prevented by pragmatic care bundle for improving the intra-partum care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary aims&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To examine if the intra-partum care bundle reduces the incidence of neonatal&#xD;
           encephalopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To examine if the intra-partum care bundle reduces the incidence of neonatal seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To examine if the intra-partum care bundle reduces caesarean rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To examine the acceptability of the care bundle by families and frontline labour room&#xD;
           staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. To examine the cost-benefits of the intrapartum care bundle&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Methods The study will be conducted over a four-year period. Baseline data will be&#xD;
           collected during year 1, and the care bundle will be introduced during year 2. The&#xD;
           primary outcome will be assessed at 18 months of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Element I: Constant birth companion providing 1:1 care during labour and early perinatal&#xD;
           period&#xD;
&#xD;
           Following necessary training, the companion will contribute towards maternal empowerment&#xD;
           through support described below during the entire first and second stage:&#xD;
&#xD;
           (i) Hydration/nutrition: provide drinking water and light refreshments to women as&#xD;
           desired, during labour.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (ii) Mobilisation/massage/reassurance: encourage and assist women to be mobile during&#xD;
           labour, massage back and body as required, and provide constant reassurance.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (iii) Prompt healthcare staff to perform regular observations as described under fetal&#xD;
           surveillance.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (iv) Prompt staff to adhere to WHO's infection and control guidelines and hand hygiene.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (v) Encouragement during 2nd stage: support women to push at appropriate times. (vi)&#xD;
           Assist in immediate skin to skin care after delivery and early breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Element 2: Fetal surveillance during active labour by a nurse or midwife (i) Clinical&#xD;
           assessment of the woman with appropriate risk categorisation (ii) Intelligent&#xD;
           auscultation on admission using graphic display Doppler, and subsequent fetal heart&#xD;
           recording every 30-45 minutes in 1st stage, and every 5-10 minutes in 2nd stage, and&#xD;
           after each contraction.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (iii) Escalation to medical staff when appropriate&#xD;
&#xD;
           Element 3. Labour management by an electronic medical record with an 'alert' and 'nag'&#xD;
           feature (e-partogram) (i) Prompt, regular observation of maternal, and fetal wellbeing&#xD;
           and progress of labour with the 'alert feature' and 'nag' feature of the software on a&#xD;
           Tablet computer.&#xD;
&#xD;
           (ii) Rationalise induction and augmentation i.e. artificial rupture of membranes and use&#xD;
           of oxytocin only with infusion pumps.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Element 4. Brain oriented early newborn care with resuscitation where indicated (i)&#xD;
           Early skin to skin care after birth, promoting early feeding (ii) Newborn resuscitation&#xD;
           (NLS) by nurses/midwives and doctors as indicated (iii) Prevention of hyperthermia in&#xD;
           babies with suspected brain injury&#xD;
&#xD;
           Although, the primary focus of the care bundle is prevention, rather than treatment of&#xD;
           perinatal brain injury, inadequate resuscitation and hyperthermia can worsen the brain&#xD;
           injury, and hence may increase the risk of epilepsy. All recruiting centres in the study&#xD;
           currently have good neonatal resuscitation facilities managed by neonatal doctors, and&#xD;
           this will be maintained in both phases of the study. In most cases, the inadvertent&#xD;
           hyperthermia can be prevented by not using radiant warmers, or by securely attaching the&#xD;
           servo control temperature probes over the abdomen when such warmers are used. This&#xD;
           element of the care bundle will be further modified based on the baseline data on the&#xD;
           exact incidence of neonatal meningitis and isolated symptomatic hypoglycaemia with&#xD;
           occipital brain injury in these settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Assessment of Neonatal brain injury The following data will be collected on all babies&#xD;
           admitted to the neonatal unit or presenting with brain injury (e.g. seizures,&#xD;
           encephalopathy, meningitis, intracranial bleeds) before 72 hours of age, following&#xD;
           informed parental consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Clinical examination including accurate staging of neonatal encephalopathy using&#xD;
                the NICHD Neonatal Research Network modified Sarnat staging. The NICHD examination&#xD;
                will be performed between 1 to 6 hours age and repeated at 24 hours and 72 hours of&#xD;
                age. The babies will be classified as having mild, moderate or severe hypoxic&#xD;
                ischemic encephalopathy based on the neurological examination between 1 to 6 hours&#xD;
                of birth, if in addition these babies have evidence of intra partum hypoxia as&#xD;
                defined by - an acute perinatal event (e.g. cord prolapse, cord rupture, uterine&#xD;
                rupture, maternal trauma, haemorrhage, or acute cardiorespiratory arrest) and&#xD;
                either a 10-minute Apgar score of 5 or less at 5 minutes or assisted ventilation&#xD;
                initiated at birth and continued for at least 5 minutes. In cases where a blood gas&#xD;
                is available, a pH of 7.0 or less or a base deficit of 16 mmol/L or more in a&#xD;
                sample of umbilical cord blood or any blood during the first hour after birth will&#xD;
                be used an evidence of an acute intrapartum event [27].&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Infection screening including automated blood cultures and cerebrospinal fluid&#xD;
                examination in all babies with suspected early onset (age &lt;72 hours) sepsis. Part&#xD;
                of this blood will be collected and stored for transcriptomic analysis of infection&#xD;
                and encephalopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. Twelve lead video EEG and amplitude integrated EEG for at least 4 hours using a&#xD;
                dedicated research EEG monitor in all babies with encephalopathy or suspected&#xD;
                seizures. Approximately 2 to 3 EEG will be performed daily at each centre. The EEG&#xD;
                will be uploaded on to a secure cloud-based server for central reporting, while the&#xD;
                aEEG will be reported locally in real time for clinical decision making.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Many neonatal seizures manifest with subtle clinical signs or may remain entirely&#xD;
                subclinical despite the presence of clear electrographic seizure activity on&#xD;
                EEG[28]. The investigators will classify neonatal seizures as per the levels of&#xD;
                diagnostic certainty proposed by the recent Brighton Collaboration Neonatal&#xD;
                Seizures Working Group led by Dr Ronit Pressler[29]. A neonatal seizure will be&#xD;
                defined as a transient electrographic change in the brain due to an abnormal,&#xD;
                excessive or synchronous neuronal activity either with the occurrence of clinical&#xD;
                signs (electro-clinical) or without them (electrographic-only).&#xD;
&#xD;
                Level 1 (Definite seizures) - Seizures confirmed on conventional EEG with&#xD;
                (electro-clinical seizure) or without (electro-graphic only) clinical&#xD;
                manifestations.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Level 2a (Probable seizures) - Seizures confirmed on aEEG with (electro-clinical&#xD;
                seizure) or without clinical manifestations (electro-graphic only) Level 2b&#xD;
                (Probable seizures) - Clinically assessed focal clonic or focal tonic seizure&#xD;
                directly witnessed or reviewed on video by experienced medical personnel when EEG&#xD;
                or aEEG was not available.&#xD;
&#xD;
                Level 3: (Possible seizure) - Clinical events suggestive of epileptic seizures&#xD;
                other than focal clonic or focal tonic seizures, directly witnessed or reviewed on&#xD;
                video by experienced medical personnel Level 4: (Not seizure) - Reported seizure&#xD;
                event (as previously defined) but insufficient evidence to meet the case definition&#xD;
                Level 5: (Not seizure) - Reported seizure event (as previously defined), documented&#xD;
                or witnessed by experienced medical personnel and evaluated by simultaneous&#xD;
                conventional EEG or aEEG and determined NOT to be a case of neonatal seizure.&#xD;
&#xD;
                The investigators will use an optimised neonatal EEG with predefined positions for&#xD;
                easy application of the electrodes by research nurses. These leads will provide&#xD;
                both a 12 montage EEG and aEEG, which will be uploaded on the cloud server for&#xD;
                reporting (Figure 1B and C).&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. 3 Tesla magnetic resonance imaging, diffusion tensor imaging and single voxel&#xD;
                thalamic proton spectroscopy using the HELIX trial sequences. Approximately 3 to 4&#xD;
                neonatal MR scans per week will be performed at each centre, during year 1 and 2.&#xD;
                In addition, repeat MR scans will be performed at around 18 months of age in all&#xD;
                children with epilepsy. Thus, approximately 3 to 5 repeat MRI scans per month will&#xD;
                be performed during years 3 and 4, at each centre. The anonymised MR data will be&#xD;
                uploaded on to a central server at Imperial College. The conventional MR images&#xD;
                will be reported locally in real time, while DTI and MRS will be analysed centrally&#xD;
                at Imperial College London following the study completion.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Neurodevelopmental follow up and Epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. All babies admitted to the neonatal unit with a birth related brain injury within&#xD;
                72 hours of birth will be followed up until 18 months. This will include all babies&#xD;
                with HIE, seizures, proven early onset neonatal meningitis, symptomatic&#xD;
                hypoglycaemia associated with brain injury, or any other birth related injury on&#xD;
                the MRI scan (e.g. intracranial bleed, arterial stroke) associated with increased&#xD;
                risk of epilepsy. The same criteria for follow up will be strictly followed during&#xD;
                both phases of the study to avoid a selection bias in the follow up.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. The research nurses will provide information and training (including video&#xD;
                demonstration of seizures) to parents on recognising seizures at home and will&#xD;
                advise on the subsequent actions to be taken. A 24/7 mobile phone contact number&#xD;
                will be provided to the parents for reporting any seizures. In addition, the&#xD;
                research nurses will maintain a monthly telephone/WhatsApp message contact with the&#xD;
                parents after discharge for a clinical update. If seizures are present, information&#xD;
                on the seizure type, exact age at onset of seizures, frequency and medication use&#xD;
                will be collected. The research nurses will also encourage parents to video record&#xD;
                the seizure episodes on mobile phones, whenever possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. A dedicated monthly multi-disciplinary research clinic will be established at each&#xD;
                of the three recruiting centres at Chennai, Bangalore and Calicut. The clinic will&#xD;
                be jointly conducted by a neonatologist, paediatric neurologist, speech and&#xD;
                language therapist and physiotherapist, and care pathway will be provided to each&#xD;
                infant based on a detailed neurological assessment including Prechtl's at 3 months.&#xD;
                Depending on these babies will have 3 to 7 further clinic appointment until 18&#xD;
                months of age. The speech and language and the physiotherapy teams at the&#xD;
                recruiting sites will be trained and supervised by the study occupational therapy&#xD;
                consultant.&#xD;
&#xD;
             4. Any infant developing seizure will be asked to attend the next monthly&#xD;
                multidisciplinary research clinic for further evaluation (please see more details&#xD;
                under the evaluation phase). It is very likely and expected that the acute&#xD;
                management of the seizure would be at the nearest health care facility, either in a&#xD;
                private or public sector, rather than the recruiting centre. These data will be&#xD;
                captured by the research nurses. The clinical data will be entered into the study&#xD;
                database using an electronic case report form. The diagnosis of epilepsy will be&#xD;
                based on the standard ILAE criteria of two or more unprovoked seizures 24 hours&#xD;
                apart beyond the neonatal period[62]. A repeat video EEG may be performed any time&#xD;
                in selected cases, if clinically required or if there is any diagnostic&#xD;
                uncertainty.&#xD;
&#xD;
             5. At 18 months of age, all children with brain injury (with or without epilepsy) will&#xD;
                have a detailed neurological examination for cerebral palsy, hearing and vision&#xD;
                assessment and a Bayley Scales of Infant developmental examination (Version III).&#xD;
                The children with epilepsy may have a repeat MRI scan under light oral sedation,&#xD;
                full montage sleep and awake video EEG if clinically appropriate. All&#xD;
                neurodevelopmental assessments will be performed by a Bayley III certified&#xD;
                neurodevelopmental paediatrician or occupational/physiotherapist.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Interrupted Time Series Evaluation</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Magnetic resonance biomarkers will be quantified masked to the interventional group</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Epilepsy</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months of age</time_frame>
    <description>Two of more unprovoked seizures at least 24 hours apart</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal encephalopathy</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours of birth</time_frame>
    <description>Moderate or severe neonatal encephalopathy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neonatal Seizures</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month of age</time_frame>
    <description>Definite or probable seizures as per ILAE classification</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Thalamic N-aspartate levels</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of age</time_frame>
    <description>Proton MR spectroscopy thalamic NAA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain injury on conventional MR imaging</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks of age</time_frame>
    <description>Significant basal ganglia, cortical or white matter injury</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Neonatal Encephalopathy</condition>
  <condition>Epilepsy</condition>
  <condition>Newborn Morbidity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pre-intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Baseline data on neonatal encephalopathy and epilepsy before the introduction of the care bundle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Post-intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Baseline data on neonatal encephalopathy and epilepsy after the introduction of the care bundle</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intra-partum care bundle invoking 4 elements</intervention_name>
    <description>Care bundle involving all the 4 elements</description>
    <arm_group_label>Post-intervention</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Birth companion</other_name>
    <other_name>Intelligent fetal heart rate monitoring by graphic doppler</other_name>
    <other_name>Electronic partogram</other_name>
    <other_name>Brain oriented neonatal resuscitation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All pregnant women delivering at 36 weeks or later&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Premature deliveries&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sudhin Thayyil, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00447912888700</phone>
    <email>s.thayyil@imperial.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stuti Pant, MSc</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Obstetrics and Gynaecology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chennai</city>
        <state>TamilNadu</state>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Shobha K, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Geetha Mahadevan, MD</last_name>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bangalore Medical College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bangalore</city>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Savitha Chandraih, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Calicut Medical College</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calicut</city>
        <country>India</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mini Chenicheri, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mini Chenicheri, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Noorul Amin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Salah Basheer, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Krishna Kumar, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sudhin Thayyil</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>India</country>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 11, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 11, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 3, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 3, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

