<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01154062</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>114155</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01154062</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Evaluate Pazopanib Tablets in Patients Who Have Neovascular Age-related Macular Degeneration</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Open-label Pilot Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability,Pharmacokinetics, Exploratory Efficacy and Pharmacodynamics of Oral Pazopanib Administered for 28 Days to Neovascular Age-relatedmacular Degeneration Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GlaxoSmithKline</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A study to evaluate pazopanib tablets in male and female adults of non-child bearing&#xD;
      potential with subfoveal CNV due to neovascular AMD. The goal is to assess safety and how&#xD;
      well the subjects tolerate the drug. The study will also look at how the body breaks down and&#xD;
      metabolizes the drug. All subjects will start the study up to 8 days prior to receiving drug.&#xD;
      Once started subjects will take one tablet each day for 28 days. A follow up visit will occur&#xD;
      approximately 2 weeks after drug is stopped.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a multi-center, open label study of pazopanib administered for 28 days in adult&#xD;
      patients with subfoveal CNV due to neovascular AMD. The primary aim is to evaluate safety and&#xD;
      tolerability in patients with neovascular AMD and a secondary aim is to evaluate&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics. This study does not include a control treatment group&#xD;
      (e.g. placebo or active comparator), and instead will be benchmarked to visual acuity and OCT&#xD;
      changes observed following treatment with other anti-angiogenic agents in a similar patient&#xD;
      population over the same treatment period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All subjects will receive tablets administered once daily. Subjects will be screened within&#xD;
      eight days prior to treatment assignment and initiation of study treatment. The duration of&#xD;
      treatment will be 28 days, and subjects will participate in a baseline and four subsequent&#xD;
      weekly study visits during the treatment phase. Subjects will also return for a follow-up&#xD;
      visit approximately two weeks after last dose of study medication.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 16, 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 29, 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 29, 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety endpoints include complete ophthalmic examination, visual acuity, vital signs (heart rate and blood pressure), clinical laboratory tests, clinical monitoring and adverse event reporting</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in visual acuity, central retinal thickness, central retinal lesion thickness, retinal morphology, neovascular size, lesion size, and characteristics by fluoresceinangiography and fundus photography. Also, (CL/F), (V/F), (Ka), and (Cτ)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Macular Degeneration</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>low dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pazopanib tablet</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pazopanib</intervention_name>
    <description>Pazopanib tablet</description>
    <arm_group_label>low dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age-related macular degeneration patients diagnosed with subfoveal choroidal&#xD;
             neovascularization in the study eye, with all of the following characteristics&#xD;
             required and confirmed by a central reading center:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CNV caused by AMD that extends under the geometric center of the foveal avascular&#xD;
                  zone&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CNV comprises ≥ 50% of lesion area&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total lesion area no greater than 12 disc areas on fluorescein angiography, where&#xD;
                  the lesion complex includes CNV, blood, blocked fluorescence not from blood, and&#xD;
                  serous detachment of the retinal pigment epithelium&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  classic CNV comprises &lt;50% of the lesion area&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  fibrosis comprises ≤ 25% of lesion area&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Center subfield &gt; 320 microns on SD-OCT (inclusive of subretinal fluid)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  if no evidence of classic CNV, then presumed to have recent disease progression&#xD;
                  because of deterioration (≥ 5 letter decrease in vision or evidence of growth of&#xD;
                  a CNV lesion on fluorescein angiography ) within last 3 months or evidence of&#xD;
                  hemorrhage from CNV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Best-corrected ETDRS visual acuity score in the study eye of between 25 and 73 letters&#xD;
             (approximately equivalent to Snellen VA of 20/320 to 20/32) at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female ≥ 50 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A female subject is eligible to participate if she is of non-childbearing potential&#xD;
             defined as either pre-menopausal with a documented tubal ligation or hysterectomy, or&#xD;
             postmenopausal defined as 12 months of spontaneous amenorrhea. In questionable cases&#xD;
             of postmenopausal status a blood sample with simultaneous follicle stimulating hormone&#xD;
             (FSH) &gt; 40 MlU/ml and estradiol &lt; 40 pg/ml (&lt;140 pmol/L) or value consistent with&#xD;
             local laboratory recommended value is confirmatory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is willing and able to return for all study visits, and is willing and able to&#xD;
             comply with all protocol requirements and procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is capable of giving written informed consent, which includes compliance with&#xD;
             the requirements and restrictions listed in the consent form. If the subject is unable&#xD;
             to read the consent form due to visual impairment then the consent must be read to the&#xD;
             subject verbatim by person administering the consent, a family member or legally&#xD;
             acceptable representative. (Note: Consent by legally acceptable representative is&#xD;
             allowed where this is in accordance with local laws, regulations and ethics committee&#xD;
             policy.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  QTcF &lt;450msec; or QTcF&lt;480msec in subjects with Bundle Branch Block.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AST, ALT, alkaline phosphatase and bilirubin ≤ 1.5xULN (isolated bilirubin &gt;1.5xULN is&#xD;
             acceptable if bilirubin is fractionated and direct bilirubin &lt;35%).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Additional eye disease in the study eye that could compromise best-corrected visual&#xD;
             acuity (e.g. glaucoma with documented visual field loss, clinically significant&#xD;
             diabetic retinopathy, ischemic optic neuropathy, infection or retinitis pigmentosa).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CNV in the study eye due to other causes unrelated to age-related macular&#xD;
             degeneration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of retinal angiomatous proliferation (RAP) in the study eye, as&#xD;
             determined by the investigator (confirmation by indocyanine green angiography is not&#xD;
             required).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Geographic atrophy involving the center of the fovea in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anterior segment and vitreous abnormalities in the study eye that would preclude&#xD;
             adequate observation of the fundus for photographs, fluorescein angiography and&#xD;
             SD-OCT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vitreous, subretinal or retinal hemorrhage in the study eye that is unrelated to AMD.&#xD;
             Any previous treatment in the study eye for neovascular AMD, approved or&#xD;
             investigational.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current intravitreal anti-VEGF therapy in the fellow eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within 6 months prior to the Screening Visit, use of any systemically administered&#xD;
             anti-angiogenic agent (e.g., bevacizumab, sunitinib, cetuximab, sorafenib, pazopanib),&#xD;
             approved or investigational.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intraocular surgery in the study eye within 3 months of dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aphakia or total absence of the posterior capsule (Yttrium aluminum garnet (YAG)&#xD;
             capsulotomy permitted) in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of vitrectomy in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of RPE tear in the study eye.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has uncontrolled glaucoma (intraocular pressure &gt;25 mmHg) despite treatment&#xD;
             with anti-glaucoma medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within 6 months prior to the Screening Visit, use of medications known to be toxic to&#xD;
             the retina, lens or optic nerve (e.g. desferoximine, chloroquine/hydrochloroquine,&#xD;
             chlorpromazine, phenothiazines, tamoxifen, nicotinic acid, and ethambutol).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of systemic steroids (&gt;10 mg prednisone or equivalent/day) within 14 days of first&#xD;
             dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A positive pre-study Hepatitis B surface antigen or positive Hepatitis C antibody&#xD;
             result within 3 months of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or chronic history of liver disease, or known hepatic or biliary abnormalities&#xD;
             (with the exception of Gilbert's syndrome or asymptomatic gallstones).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Medical history or unresolved medical condition, for example:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus, with hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) &gt; 10%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myocardial infarction or stroke within 6 months of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active bleeding disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 3 months of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatic impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically relevant thyroid disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled hypertension, based on criteria provided in Section 4.4.1.2.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Subject has a history within the past 2 years of alcohol, substance abuse, or&#xD;
                  psychiatric disorder likely to confound the efficacy or safety assessments. A&#xD;
                  history of known HIV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Use of prohibited medications listed in Section 9.2 within the restricted&#xD;
                  timeframe relative to the first dose of study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of sensitivity to any of the study medications, or components thereof or&#xD;
                  a history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the investigator or&#xD;
                  GSK Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A condition or situation, which, in the opinion of the investigator, may result&#xD;
                  in significant risk to the patient, confound the study results or interfere&#xD;
                  significantly with participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of sensitivity to any of the study medications, or components thereof or&#xD;
                  a history of drug or other allergy that, in the opinion of the investigator or&#xD;
                  GSK Medical Monitor, contraindicates their participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>GSK Clinical Trials</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>GlaxoSmithKline</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Beverly Hills</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90211</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95819</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95841</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winter Haven</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33880</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Indianapolis</city>
        <state>Indiana</state>
        <zip>46290</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grand Rapids</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>49525</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GSK Investigational Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 29, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 29, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 30, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 7, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 7, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>age-related macular degeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>pazopanib</keyword>
  <keyword>choroidal neovascularization</keyword>
  <keyword>GW786034</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

