<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00617110</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>07-1064</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2R01ES013611</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00617110</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Diesel Exhaust Followed by Administration of Nasal Spray Flu Vaccine on Individuals With &amp; Without Allergies</brief_title>
  <acronym>FLAIR</acronym>
  <official_title>Effects of Diesel Exhaust Particles on Influenza-induced Nasal Inflammation in Allergic Rhinitics and Non-allergic Individuals</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences (NIEHS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Allergic rhinitis (AR) is a condition that exists when an individual with a specific allergy&#xD;
      reacts to that allergen resulting in a runny and/or stuffy nose, postnasal drip, and possible&#xD;
      symptoms of sneezing, scratchy throat, itchy nose, ears or throat. When the allergic person&#xD;
      is exposed to such an allergen, the body reacts with overproduction of certain chemicals&#xD;
      which cause inflammation and subsequent symptoms of AR. These responses are related to the&#xD;
      body's hyperreactive response to exposure to an otherwise harmless substance such as dust,&#xD;
      ragweed, pollen, cat dander etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are data to suggest that air pollution resulting from diesel exhaust can increase the&#xD;
      body's response to airway inflammation caused by virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this research study is to determine if individuals with AR have increased&#xD;
      inflammatory responses to flu virus following exposure to diesel exhaust (DE) vs exposure to&#xD;
      clean air compared to how individuals who do not have allergies respond to the same exposure&#xD;
      conditions. The hypothesis for this study is that diesel exhaust exacerbates LAIV-induced&#xD;
      allergic nasal inflammation, using controlled exposures in AR volunteers compared to&#xD;
      non-allergic individuals&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Screening day: This visit will occur approximately 2-4 weeks before your exposure day. You&#xD;
      will come to the research facility where you will discuss this consent form with the study&#xD;
      coordinator and complete the signature areas. Your vital signs (pulse, temperature, BP,&#xD;
      oxygenation saturation) will be measured and the following evaluations will be performed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For females of child bearing potential, a urine pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Review your medical history and any recent health changes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Completion of a questionnaire regarding your allergy symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of spirometric (pulmonary function testing) data will be performed. You must&#xD;
           demonstrate normal pulmonary function in order to continue in the study. You will be&#xD;
           asked to inhale as deeply as possible, then exhale as rapidly and completely as possible&#xD;
           into a mouthpiece which is connected to a computer which measures various lung volumes&#xD;
           and which will tell us if your lung function is normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood draw from a hand or arm vein to test for HIV and recent influenza exposure, as&#xD;
           well as serum markers, T cell stimulation and WBC characterization. The volume of blood&#xD;
           will be up to 50 cc (approximately 3 tablespoons).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A buccal swab will be performed for genotyping which entails rubbing a toothbrush on the&#xD;
           inside of your cheeks to loosen the cells followed by repeating the rubbing in the same&#xD;
           place with a soft swab (similar to a Q tip® with a longer stick).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Physical examination by a study physician&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Allergy skin test if this has not been performed during the previous 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of nasal lavage fluid which will involve spraying some salt water into your&#xD;
           nose repeatedly and then blowing your nose into a cup&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal biopsy during which the researcher gently scrapes the inside lining of your nose&#xD;
           with a plastic stick&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 0 (Monday): You will be asked to eat a light breakfast and arrive at the EPA in early to&#xD;
      mid morning. You will need to wear comfortable clothes and shoes, and bring a lunch.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Collection of vital sign measurements and update in medical condition as well as&#xD;
           medications taken since the previous visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine pregnancy test, if applicable&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A telemetry monitor will be placed so that your heart rhythm can be monitored during&#xD;
           your chamber exposure. This will include having monitor wires attached to your chest and&#xD;
           shoulders with an adhesive pad. The other end of the wires is connected to a box that&#xD;
           can be tied to your waste and which will transmit your heart rhythm to a screen so we&#xD;
           can observe it&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Spirometry measurements: This test measures the volume of air that can be exhaled and&#xD;
           the rate of airflow during exhalation after a maximal inhalation. You will inhale as&#xD;
           deeply as possible, then exhale as rapidly and completely as possible into the&#xD;
           spirometer. Measurements obtained from each maneuver include the forced vital capacity&#xD;
           (FVC), the forced expiratory volume in the first second (FEV1), the maximal&#xD;
           mid-expiratory flow rate (FEF 25-75%) and the peak flow (PF). The largest FVC and FEV1,&#xD;
           from at least 3 acceptable trials, are selected for analysis; the flow rates are&#xD;
           selected from the trial with the largest sum of FVC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal lavage&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will have a 2 hour exposure to either diesel particles or air. The type of exposure&#xD;
           you will receive will be randomized, meaning that you will be assigned to the air or&#xD;
           diesel exposure group by chance, like flipping a coin. The exposure will be double blind&#xD;
           which means that neither you nor the study investigators and staff will know whether you&#xD;
           are being exposed to diesel exhaust or air except in the event of any emergency when&#xD;
           this information could be revealed. If you are randomized to receive a diesel exposure,&#xD;
           the diesel will be generated from an engine mounted on a vehicle located outside of the&#xD;
           EPA Human studies Facility (HSF). The diesel exhaust (DE) is then introduced into the&#xD;
           exposure chamber after dilution with clean filtered and humidified air by approximately&#xD;
           1/30th to give a chamber concentration of approximately 100 μg/m3. The amount of DE used&#xD;
           for exposure in this study would be equivalent to concentrations encountered at busy&#xD;
           intersections in large urban areas. DE concentrations proposed are below occupational&#xD;
           levels for some truck drivers (generally about 100-300 µg/m3) and 1-2 mg/m3 for some&#xD;
           mines. Some areas of heavily trafficked streets in Los Angeles and New York City have&#xD;
           had DE levels &gt; 20 µg/m3, and nearby residents could have exposure to these&#xD;
           concentrations over several hours. If you are randomized to clean air, you will receive&#xD;
           Chapel Hill air which has been filtered to remove ambient air pollutants&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After your exposure you will have additional spirometry testing and return to the&#xD;
           medical station where you will be monitored for 3 hours. You will also have time to eat&#xD;
           your lunch which we are requesting that you bring with you from home&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Both before and after your exposure, the level of carbon monoxide in your blood will be&#xD;
           tested&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Three hours after your exposure is complete, the FluMist® vaccine will be administered&#xD;
           by spraying the vaccine once into each nostril. Shortly after that you will be&#xD;
           discharged home&#xD;
&#xD;
      Days 1-3 (Tuesday-Thursday). Each day, the following will be obtained:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs and update any changes in medical condition&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal lavage&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 4 (Friday):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs and medical update&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal lavage&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal biopsy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood draw - serum markers, WBC characterization. The volume of blood will be up to 50cc&#xD;
           (approximately 3 tablespoons)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 9 +/- 1 day (one visit sometime between the Tuesday through Thursday after the week you&#xD;
      have received the FluMist®):&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs and health update&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Nasal lavage&#xD;
&#xD;
      Day 21 +/-7 days after the FluMist dose&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Vital signs and health update&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine pregnancy test, if applicable&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood draw to check your post -vaccine anti-influenza titer, as well as serum markers, T&#xD;
           cell stimulation and WBC characterization. The volume of blood will be up to 50 cc&#xD;
           (approximately 3 tablespoons)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>January 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in IL-13 and ECP in nasal lavage fluids (NLF) compared to pre-virus baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>1-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration/quantity of virus shedding</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in inflammatory cells in NLF at specific time points compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in inflammatory cytokines/chemokines and other mediators (PGE2, tryptase, MPO, adenosine) in NLF at specific time points compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post LAIV change in overall &quot;oxidative stress&quot; in nasal epithelial cells</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post LAIV change in epithelial gene expression profiles for innate immune and oxidant/antioxidant network arrays in nasal epithelial biopsies</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in levels and activities of circulating white blood cells, including eosinophils, basophils, monocytes, and lymphocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Outcomes for GSTM1 null vs. sufficient genotype individuals</measure>
    <time_frame>0-21 days post challenge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">54</enrollment>
  <condition>Allergic Rhinitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>allergic clean air</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>subjects with allergic rhinitis will be exposed to clean air followed by LAIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Allergic diesel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>subjects with allergic rhinitis will be exposed to diesel exhaust particles followed by LAIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control clean air</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy control subjects will be exposed to clean air followed by LAIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control diesel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Healthy control will be exposed to diesel followed by LAIV</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>live attenuated influenza virus (LAIV) with clean air</intervention_name>
    <description>Allergic subjects will be exposed to air followed by administration of live attenuated influenza virus</description>
    <arm_group_label>allergic clean air</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>control clean air</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>FluMist</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LAIV and diesel exhaust particles</intervention_name>
    <description>subjects with allergic rhinitis will be exposed to diesel exhaust particles followed by LAIV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Allergic diesel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control diesel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>FLuMist</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Normal lung function, defined as (Knudsen 1976/1984 predicted set):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  FVC of &gt; 75 % of that predicted for gender, ethnicity, age and height&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  FEV1 of &gt; 75 % of that predicted for gender, ethnicity, age and height&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  FEV1/FVC ratio of .70&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Oxygen saturation of &gt; 94 %&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Normal blood pressure (Systolic between 140 - 90, Diastolic between 90-60 mm Hg)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Symptom Score no greater than 6 (out of a possible 39) for total symptom score&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. On the day of a challenge, body temperature must be no greater than 37.8 degrees,&#xD;
             measured orally&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A history of significant chronic illnesses (to include diabetes, autoimmune diseases,&#xD;
             immunodeficiency state, known ischemic heart disease, chronic respiratory diseases&#xD;
             such as chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or asthma, hypertension)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Allergy to any medications which may be used in the course of this study (albuterol,&#xD;
             acetaminophen, aspirin or non-steroidal anti-inflammatory agents, corticosteroids)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Positive pregnancy test within 48 hours of the time of challenge&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Medications which may impact the results of the experimental viral infection,&#xD;
             interfere with any other medications potentially used in the study (to include nasal&#xD;
             or oral corticosteroids, beta adrenergic antagonists, non-steroidal anti-inflammatory&#xD;
             agents) or suggest an ongoing illness (such as antibiotics)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Acute, non-chronic, medical conditions, including (but not limited to) pneumonia or&#xD;
             bronchitis requiring antibiotics, febrile illnesses, flu-like symptoms must be totally&#xD;
             resolved symptomatically for 3 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Unspecified illnesses, which in the judgment of the investigator increase the risk&#xD;
             associated with the experimental LAIV infection, will be a basis for exclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Use of any inhaled substance (for medical or recreational purposes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Receipt of flu vaccine of any type (injection or nasal spray) during the prior season&#xD;
             (2006/2007)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Current use of allergy immunotherapy (&quot;allergy shots&quot;)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Terry Noah, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Dept of Pediatrics / Center for Environmental Medicine, Asthma and Lung Biology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>US EPA Human Studies Facility</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chapel Hill</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27514</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 5, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 14, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 15, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 1, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 1, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">June 3, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Terry Noah, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Pediatrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>diesel exhaust particles</keyword>
  <keyword>live attenuated influenza virus vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>flu vaccine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rhinitis, Allergic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

