<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01593267</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>02BN090</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01593267</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial</brief_title>
  <acronym>BRAT</acronym>
  <official_title>Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center, Phoenix</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Barrow Neurological Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, San Francisco</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center, Phoenix</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      With evolving endovascular technologies there is a growing debate centered on the relative&#xD;
      safety and efficacy of the currently accepted alternatives for the treatment of ruptured&#xD;
      cerebral aneurysms in the face of acute subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH). The purpose of this&#xD;
      study is to compare the safety and efficacy of microsurgical clipping and endovascular&#xD;
      coiling of acutely ruptured cerebral aneurysms in a prospective, randomized fashion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The planned trial enrolled 250 subjects per arm. Subjects are followed postoperatively and&#xD;
      outcome endpoints will be assessed at Discharge, 6 Months, 1 Year, 3 Years, and 6 Years. One&#xD;
      hundred (100) subjects will participate in neuropsychological testing at 1 Year; after the&#xD;
      100th subject an interim data analysis will be performed and the viability of future&#xD;
      neuropsychological testing will be determined. Subjects will receive preoperative,&#xD;
      intraoperative or postoperative, 3 Year follow up, and 6 Year follow up angiograms. In this&#xD;
      fashion immediate clinical outcome, including peri-procedural morbidity and mortality, will&#xD;
      be assessed as will long term outcome, both clinical and angiographic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 25, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Rankin Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>10 years</time_frame>
    <description>Primary Outcome Measure is Modified Rankin Scale &lt; or = to 2. Data will be analyzed on intent to treat basis with crossover to the alternative treatment analyzed as a data subset. The null hypothesis is that no difference in outcome will be detected between the endovascular and surgical treatment arms. A statistically significant difference will then be considered evidence in favor of the alternative hypothesis, that one treatment is superior to the other.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Ruptured Cerebral Aneurysm</condition>
  <condition>Subarachnoid Hemorrhage (SAH)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Endovascular</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects randomized to endovascular coil embolization will be treated by one of two neurosurgeons expert in such treatment. All endovascular coil embolization treatments will be accomplished using accepted techniques.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects randomized to surgical clip occlusion repair will receive treatment from one of two neurosurgeons expert in clip occlusion surgery for ruptured aneurysms.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>coil embolization</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects randomized to endovascular therapy will be treated by one of two neurosurgeons expert in such treatment. All endovascular treatments will be accomplished using accepted techniques.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Endovascular</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>clip occlusion</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects randomized to surgical therapy will receive treatment from one of two neurosurgeons expert in surgery for ruptured aneurysms.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Surgical</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute subarachnoid hemorrhage (SAH)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed by CT scan or lumbar puncture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to give informed consent (subject or legally authorized representative)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No anatomic inclusions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Traumatic subarachnoid hemorrhage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presents to hospital &gt;14 days post-bleed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SAH caused by other primary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No anatomic exclusions&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Robert F Spetzler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Barrow Brain and Spine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Phoenix</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85013</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Catapano JS, Zabramski JM, Baranoski JF, Brigeman S, Morgan CD, Hendricks BK, Mooney MA, Albuquerque FC, Nakaji P, Spetzler RF. The Prognostic Significance of a Cast Fourth Ventricle in Ruptured Aneurysm Patients With Intraventricular Hemorrhage in the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial (BRAT). Neurosurgery. 2019 Aug 1;85(2):E275-E283. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyy493.</citation>
    <PMID>30476225</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mascitelli JR, Lawton MT, Hendricks BK, Nakaji P, Zabramski JM, Spetzler RF. Analysis of Wide-Neck Aneurysms in the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. Neurosurgery. 2019 Nov 1;85(5):622-631. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyy439.</citation>
    <PMID>30346618</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mooney MA, Simon ED, Brigeman S, Nakaji P, Zabramski JM, Lawton MT, Spetzler RF. Long-term results of middle cerebral artery aneurysm clipping in the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. J Neurosurg. 2018 Apr 27;130(3):895-901. doi: 10.3171/2017.10.JNS172183.</citation>
    <PMID>29701554</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mooney MA, Brigeman S, Bohl MA, Simon ED, Sheehy JP, Chang SW, Spetzler RF. Analysis of overlapping surgery in patients undergoing microsurgical aneurysm clipping: acute and long-term outcomes from the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. J Neurosurg. 2018 Sep;129(3):711-717. doi: 10.3171/2017.5.JNS17394. Epub 2017 Nov 3.</citation>
    <PMID>29099301</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Spetzler RF, Zabramski JM, McDougall CG, Albuquerque FC, Hills NK, Wallace RC, Nakaji P. Analysis of saccular aneurysms in the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. J Neurosurg. 2018 Jan;128(1):120-125. doi: 10.3171/2016.9.JNS161301. Epub 2017 Feb 24.</citation>
    <PMID>28298031</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>McDougall CG, Spetzler RF, Albuquerque FC, Zabramski JM, Nakaji P. Crossover and clinical outcomes in the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. Response. J Neurosurg. 2014 Feb;120(2):572.</citation>
    <PMID>24645176</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McDougall CG, Spetzler RF, Zabramski JM, Partovi S, Hills NK, Nakaji P, Albuquerque FC. The Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. J Neurosurg. 2012 Jan;116(1):135-44. doi: 10.3171/2011.8.JNS101767. Epub 2011 Nov 4.</citation>
    <PMID>22054213</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Spetzler RF, McDougall CG, Albuquerque FC, Zabramski JM, Hills NK, Partovi S, Nakaji P, Wallace RC. The Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial: 3-year results. J Neurosurg. 2013 Jul;119(1):146-57. doi: 10.3171/2013.3.JNS12683. Epub 2013 Apr 26. Erratum in: J Neurosurg. 2014 Feb;120(2):581.</citation>
    <PMID>23621600</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Spetzler RF, McDougall CG, Zabramski JM, Albuquerque FC, Hills NK, Nakaji P, Karis JP, Wallace RC. Ten-year analysis of saccular aneurysms in the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial. J Neurosurg. 2019 Mar 8;132(3):771-776. doi: 10.3171/2018.8.JNS181846.</citation>
    <PMID>30849758</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mascitelli JR, Cole T, Yoon S, Nakaji P, Albuquerque FC, McDougall CG, Zabramski JM, Lawton MT, Spetzler RF. External Validation of the Subarachnoid Hemorrhage International Trialists (SAHIT) Predictive Model Using the Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial (BRAT) Cohort. Neurosurgery. 2020 Jan 1;86(1):101-106. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyy600.</citation>
    <PMID>30566611</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Spetzler RF, McDougall CG, Zabramski JM, Albuquerque FC, Hills NK, Russin JJ, Partovi S, Nakaji P, Wallace RC. The Barrow Ruptured Aneurysm Trial: 6-year results. J Neurosurg. 2015 Sep;123(3):609-17. doi: 10.3171/2014.9.JNS141749. Epub 2015 Jun 26.</citation>
    <PMID>26115467</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 30, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 8, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>St. Joseph's Hospital and Medical Center, Phoenix</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lisa Arnold</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Operations Manager</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>intracranial aneurysm</keyword>
  <keyword>subarachnoid hemorrhage</keyword>
  <keyword>randomized trial</keyword>
  <keyword>coil embolization</keyword>
  <keyword>clip occlusion</keyword>
  <keyword>vascular disorders</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Subarachnoid Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intracranial Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm, Ruptured</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

