<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04529928</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CVP-3473-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04529928</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Initial Evaluation of the Carillon Mitral Contour System for Treatment of Atrial Function Mitral Regurgitation</brief_title>
  <acronym>AFIRE</acronym>
  <official_title>An Initial Evaluation of the Carillon Mitral Contour System for Treatment of Atrial Function Mitral Regurgitation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cardiac Dimensions Pty Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cardiac Dimensions Pty Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this prospective, multi-center trial is to assess the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      CARILLON Mitral Contour System in treating patients with moderate-to-severe atrial functional&#xD;
      mitral regurgitation (aFMR)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The AFIRE Trial is a prospective, multi-center clinical trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The centers will utilize pre-screening of existing medical records to identify potentially&#xD;
      eligible subjects. Once informed consent has been obtained, the subject will undergo baseline&#xD;
      assessments, which include: Transthoracic echocardiography, transesophageal echocardiography,&#xD;
      and functional assessments (Six-Minute Walk Test, NYHA, and Quality of Life Questionnaires).&#xD;
      Following final eligibility determination, eligible subjects will under the index procedure&#xD;
      to implant the Carillon device (includes coronary sinus venogram). Subject will be discharged&#xD;
      following one-night in-hospital stay and discharge assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who have the Carillon implant procedure attempted but were not successfully&#xD;
      implanted (Non-Implanted subjects) will be followed through discharge or resolution of safety&#xD;
      events, whichever is longer, and then discharged from the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Implanted subjects will have follow-up assessments performed at 1 month, 6 months, and 12&#xD;
      months post index procedure. Follow-up assessments will include transthoracic&#xD;
      echocardiography, Six-Minute Walk Test, and Quality of Life Questionnaires.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in mitral regurgitant volume (mL) associated with the Carillon device at 6 months post-implant, as compared to baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>6 Months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Functional Mitral Regurgitation</condition>
  <condition>Atrial Fibrillation</condition>
  <condition>Atrial Functional Mitral Regurgitation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Implanted</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects successfully implanted with the Carillon Mitral Contour System</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carillon Mitral Contour System</intervention_name>
    <description>Eligible subjects will be implanted with the Carillon Device, utilizing the Carillon Mitral Contour System. The device is a permanent implant in the coronary sinus/great cardiac vein, designed to cinch the mitral annulus. The implant procedure is minimally invasive, conducted via catheter placement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Implanted</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Carillon</other_name>
    <other_name>Carillon Device</other_name>
    <other_name>Carillon Implant</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Moderate-to-severe non-primary Mitral Regurgitation (as assessed by qualitative,&#xD;
             semi-quantitative and/or quantitative echocardiographic assessment in the setting of&#xD;
             all of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Severe left atrial (LA) dilatation as defined by at least two (2) of the following:&#xD;
             i. LA area ≥ 41cm2 ii. Indexed LA volume &gt; 48mL/m2 iii. LA diameter ≥ 52 mm for men&#xD;
             and ≥ 46 mm for women b. Preserved left ventricular contractility (Left Ventricular&#xD;
             Ejection Fraction ≥50% by Simpson's biplane technique) c. No more than mild left&#xD;
             ventricular dilatation as defined by: i. LV diastolic volume/BSA (mL/m2) &lt;90 mL/m2 for&#xD;
             men and &lt;71 mL/m2 for women ii. LV systolic volume/BSA (mL/m2) &lt;39 mL/m2 for men and&#xD;
             &lt;33 mL/m2 for women&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class II, III or ambulatory IV heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Stable heart failure medication regimen for at least 30 days prior to index procedure&#xD;
             including antihypertensives and/or diuretics to achieve controlled BP (&lt; 140 mmHg&#xD;
             systolic) and adequate heart rate control (&lt;100 bpm resting HR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient deemed appropriate candidate for transcatheter mitral valve repair by the&#xD;
             local multidisciplinary heart team&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject meets anatomic screening criteria as determined by angiographic screening at&#xD;
             the time of the index procedure to ensure that implant can be sized and placed in&#xD;
             accordance with the Instructions for Use&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Female subjects of child-bearing potential must have a negative serum BHCG test&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Age ≥ 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. The subject has read the informed consent, agrees to comply with the requirements, and&#xD;
             has signed the informed consent to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hospitalization in past three (3) months due to myocardial infarction, coronary artery&#xD;
             bypass graft surgery, and/or unstable angina&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Evidence of transient ischemic attack or stroke within three (3) months prior to&#xD;
             intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Percutaneous coronary intervention in the last 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects expected to require any cardiac surgery, including surgery for coronary&#xD;
             artery disease or for pulmonic, aortic, or tricuspid valve disease within one (1) year&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects expected to require any percutaneous coronary intervention within 30 days of&#xD;
             the index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pre-existing device (e.g., pacing lead) in coronary sinus (CS) / great cardiac vein&#xD;
             (GCV), or anticipated need for cardiac resynchronization therapy (CRT) within twelve&#xD;
             (12) months&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence of a coronary artery stent under the CS / GCV in the implant target zone&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Presence of left atrial appendage (LAA) clot.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Presence of primary renal dysfunction or significantly compromised renal function as&#xD;
             reflected by a serum creatinine &gt; 2.2 mg/dL (194.5 µmol/L) OR estimated Glomerular&#xD;
             Filtration Rate (eGFR) &lt; 30 ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Poorly controlled atrial fibrillation or flutter, with poor ventricular rate control&#xD;
             (&gt; 100 bpm resting HR), or other poorly controlled symptomatic brady- or&#xD;
             tachy-arrhythmias&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Uncontrolled hypertension (BP &gt; 180 mmHg systolic and/or &gt;105 mmHg diastolic) or&#xD;
             hypotension (BP &lt; 90 mmHg systolic) at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Presence of severe mitral annular calcification&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Prior mitral valve surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Presence of a mechanical mitral heart valve, mitral bio-prosthetic valve or mitral&#xD;
             annuloplasty ring&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Echocardiographic evidence of intracardiac mass, thrombus, or vegetation&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Active endocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Severe aortic stenosis (aortic valve area &lt;1.0 cm2) or severe aortic regurgitation&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Infiltrative cardiomyopathies (e.g., amyloidosis, hemochromatosis, sarcoidosis)&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, restrictive cardiomyopathy, constrictive pericarditis, or&#xD;
             any other structural heart disease causing heart failure other than atrial functional&#xD;
             mitral regurgitation&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subjects with echocardiographic documentation of non-compaction cardiomyopathy with&#xD;
             associated hypercontractility of the cardiac structures supporting the mitral annulus&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Hemodynamic instability requiring inotropic support or mechanical heart circulatory&#xD;
             support&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Active infections requiring current antibiotic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Severe right ventricular failure or severe tricuspid regurgitation&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. History of bleeding diathesis or coagulopathy, or subject who refuses blood&#xD;
             transfusions&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Significant organic mitral valve pathology (e.g., moderate or severe myxomatous&#xD;
             degeneration, with or without mitral leaflet prolapse, rheumatic disease, full or&#xD;
             partial chordal rupture)&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Allergy to contrast dye that cannot be pre-medicated&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Pregnant or planning pregnancy within next 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         28. Chronic severe pathology limiting survival to less than 12-months in the judgement of&#xD;
             the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
         29. Anticipated need of left ventricular assist device within twelve (12) months&#xD;
&#xD;
         30. Currently participating or has participated in another investigational study where the&#xD;
             study primary endpoint was not reached at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         31. Patient requires emergent/emergency treatment for mitral regurgitation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Royal Prince Alfred</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sydney</city>
        <state>New South Wales</state>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Avalon Moonen, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Martin Ng, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>European Interbalkan Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Thessaloníki</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nikoleta Ioannidou</last_name>
      <phone>+30 2310 400929</phone>
      <email>vittoria6182@hotmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Vlasios Ninios, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 28, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mitral Valve Insufficiency</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

