<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04524182</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KA-19006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04524182</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Acute Effect of Lumbosacral Mobilization in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Acute Effect of Lumbo-sacral Mobilization on Functional Activities, Balance and Gait in Patients With Idiopathic Parkinson's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hacettepe University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hacettepe University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Parkinson's disease is a neurodegenerative disease including resting tremor, bradykinesia,&#xD;
      rigidity and postural instability. In addition, postural disorders, motor freezing, gait&#xD;
      disturbances, decreased arm swing and axial rotation loss accompany the disease. There is an&#xD;
      important relationship between axial rotation and turning, which is one of many activities in&#xD;
      daily life. Parkinson's patients with loss of axial rotation have a difficulty gait, daily&#xD;
      living activities and is associated with falls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Classical physiotherapy methods for Parkinson's patients such as stretching, strengthening&#xD;
      and posture exercises, balance, coordination and gait training, and different methods such as&#xD;
      motor imagery, sensory stimuli and neurophysiological approaches can be used in the treatment&#xD;
      of Parkinson's patients. Although there are applications that can increase axial rotation in&#xD;
      physiotherapy programs, all programs may be able to focus adequately on the treatment of this&#xD;
      symptom. In addition, according to the literature, the effects of all physiotherapy&#xD;
      approaches emerge as a result of long-term training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mobilization techniques are applications that are included in physiotherapy programs and have&#xD;
      a wide area of use. It is divided into three subtitles according to its severity and degree:&#xD;
      Grade A (mobilization), grade B (mobilization) and grade C (manipulation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering the effects of mobilization on muscle activation and balance, grade A and grade B&#xD;
      mobilization applications are likely to increase the mobility of this area when applied on&#xD;
      the lumbosacral region. Therefore, these practices can affect balance, gait and functional&#xD;
      activities by regulating muscle tone (rigidity) and muscle activation and reducing axial&#xD;
      symptoms in Parkinson's patients. Based on this information, the aim of our study is to&#xD;
      investigate the acute effect of lumbosacral mobilization on balance, gait and functional&#xD;
      activities in patients with Parkinson's disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Parkinson's disease is a neurodegenerative disease defined by James Parkinson in 1817,&#xD;
      resulting from the progressive loss of dopaminergic neurons in the basal ganglion and&#xD;
      substantia nigra. The four main motor signs of the disease are resting tremor, bradykinesia,&#xD;
      rigidity and postural instability. In addition, postural disorders, motor freezing, gait&#xD;
      disturbances, decreased arm swing and axial rotation loss accompany the disease. There is an&#xD;
      important relationship between axial rotation and turning, which is one of many activities in&#xD;
      daily life. Turning is a complex action that involves head and trunk rotation in the&#xD;
      transverse plane. En bloc turning occurs with the decrease of inter-segment coordination in&#xD;
      Parkinson's patients with loss of axial rotation, which refers to the almost simultaneous&#xD;
      rotation of the head, trunk and pelvis. This problem affects a large percentage of people&#xD;
      with Parkinson's disease, hinders daily living activities, is associated with falls, and has&#xD;
      a significant impact on quality of life. Losses in axial rotation also can affect properties&#xD;
      of gait such as speed and stride length.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physiotherapy is effective in improving gait, balance and functional activities in&#xD;
      Parkinson's patients. Classical physiotherapy methods such as stretching, strengthening and&#xD;
      posture exercises, balance, coordination and gait training, and different methods such as&#xD;
      motor imagery, sensory stimuli and neurophysiological approaches can be used in the treatment&#xD;
      of Parkinson's patients. Although there are applications that can increase axial rotation in&#xD;
      physiotherapy programs, all programs may be able to focus adequately on the treatment of this&#xD;
      symptom. In addition, according to the literature, the effects of all physiotherapy&#xD;
      approaches emerge as a result of long-term training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mobilization techniques are applications that are included in physiotherapy programs and have&#xD;
      a wide area of use. It is divided into three subtitles according to its severity and degree:&#xD;
      Grade A (mobilization), grade B (mobilization) and grade C (manipulation). Grade A&#xD;
      (mobilization) is active, active-assisted or passive mobilization in the spinal joints within&#xD;
      the painless range of motion. It is generally applied in the middle range in spinal joints.&#xD;
      It is especially preferred in the treatment of acute, irritable spinal lesions. Grade B&#xD;
      (mobilization) refers to mobilization in the form of continuous stretching at the end of the&#xD;
      range of motion in the spinal joints. Grade C (manipulation) is a minimal amplitude high&#xD;
      velocity passive pushing motion performed at the end of the joint range of motion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering the effects of mobilization on muscle activation and balance, grade A and grade B&#xD;
      mobilization applications are likely to increase the mobility of this area when applied on&#xD;
      the lumbosacral region. Therefore, these practices can affect balance, gait and functional&#xD;
      activities by regulating muscle tone (rigidity) and muscle activation and reducing axial&#xD;
      symptoms in Parkinson's patients. Based on this information, the aim of our study is to&#xD;
      investigate the acute effect of lumbosacral mobilization on balance, gait and functional&#xD;
      activities in patients with Parkinson's disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>randomized controlled</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Static Posturography Assesment (NeuroCom® Balance Master® Systems)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after mobilization</time_frame>
    <description>It measures stability while standing statically and dynamically. The device has a computerized force platform that measures the vertical forces (center of pressure) applied on the feet of the patients to measure the position of the center of gravity and postural control. Among the parameters evaluated by the device (stability limits test, modified sensory integration and clinical assessment of balance test, sit to stand test, straight walking (walk across), standing and fast walking test (step / There are tests such as quick turn)).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamic Gait Index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after mobilization</time_frame>
    <description>It is a measurement tool that can be used to assess dynamic balance, gait, and risk for falls. Balance and walking pattern changes are scored during tasks such as changing gait speed, gait with vertical and horizontal head turns, pivot turn, step over obstacle, step around obstacles and climbing stairs. Each item of this 8-item scale is scored between 0 and 3. &quot;0&quot; indicates the lowest level of function and &quot;3&quot; the highest level of function.Total score is 24 for this scale and higher scores indicate higher level of function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Parkinson Activity Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after mobilization</time_frame>
    <description>It is used to determine the limitations in daily activities. It consists of three sub-sections: chair transfer, walking akinesia and bed mobility. There are 2 items for chair transfer, 6 items for walking akinesia and 6 items for bed mobility. The scoring of each item in the scale consisting of 14 items is between 0 (dependent)-4(normal). The total score range is between 0-56. Higher scores indicate higher level of function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and immediately after mobilization</time_frame>
    <description>It is used to evaluate the symptoms of the disease and complications related to treatment. In this scale consisting of 4 parts, the scoring of each item is between 0-4 points. (I = Mental state, behavior and mental state, II = Activities of daily living, III = Motor examination, IV = Treatment complications). Increase in total score reflects increase in severity of symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Mini-Mental State Examination</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Mini-Mental Status Examination offers a quick and simple way to quantify cognitive function and screen for cognitive loss. It tests the individual's orientation, attention, calculation, recall, language and motor skills. Each section of the test involves a related series of questions or commands. The individual receives one point for each correct answer. To give the examination, seat the individual in a quiet, well-lit room. Ask him/her to listen carefully and to answer each question as accurately as he/she can. Don't time the test but score it right away. To score, add the number of correct responses. The individual can receive a maximum score of 30 points. A score below 20 usually indicates cognitive impairment.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The Modified Hoehn and Yahr Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>It is used to describe the symptom progression of Parkinson disease. It was designed to be a descriptive staging scale to evaluate both disability and impairment related to clinical disease progression.The scale is included stages 1 through 5 stages.&#xD;
Modified Hoehn and Yahr Staging&#xD;
STAGE 0 = No signs of disease. STAGE 1 = Unilateral disease. STAGE 1.5 = Unilateral plus axial involvement. STAGE 2 = Bilateral disease, without impairment of balance. STAGE 2.5 = Mild bilateral disease, with recovery on pull test. STAGE 3 = Mild to moderate bilateral disease; some postural instability; physically independent.&#xD;
STAGE 4 = Severe disability; still able to walk or stand unassisted. STAGE 5 = Wheelchair bound or bedridden unless aided.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">28</enrollment>
  <condition>Idiopathic Parkinson's Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>There was no intervention in the control group during the study (At the end of study all patients were received home-based exercise)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>mobilization group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Lumbo-sacral mobilization was applied to the mobilization group. Lumbo-sacral mobilization techniques were applied for 10 minutes to lumbo-sacral region in the supine position.&#xD;
(At the end of study all patients were received home-based exercise)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>control group</intervention_name>
    <description>There was no intervention in the control group during study.&#xD;
At the end of study all patients were received home-based exercise tailored to each individual's needs which include stretching, strengthening, balance and gait exercise and posture exercise</description>
    <arm_group_label>control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>mobilization group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>mobilization group</intervention_name>
    <description>Lumbosacral mobilization for 10 minutes in the study group (pelvis forward and backward distraction, passive rotation of the lower body, short lever rotation, long lever rotation, lumbar central posterior-anterior, lumbar unilateral posterior-anterior, anterior rotation-posterior superior iliac spine- down, posterior rotation-posterior superior iliac spine-up were applied.&#xD;
At the end of study all patients were received home-based exercise tailored to each individual's needs which include stretching, strengthening, balance and gait exercise and posture exercise</description>
    <arm_group_label>mobilization group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having been diagnosed with Idiopathic Parkinson's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being between the ages of 50-80&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients scoring &gt;24 on Standardized Mini Mental State Examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Modified Hoehn and Yahr stage 2-3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No medication or dose changes during treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not participating in the physiotherapy and rehabilitation program in the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteering to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having other neurological diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of postural hypotension affecting balance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vision problem (not compensated for with the correct lens) or presence of vestibular&#xD;
             disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiopulmonary diseases affecting gait (previous history of myocardial infarction)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Orthopedic problems that cause movement limitation and affect gait and evaluations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous use of corticosteroids&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Büşra Seçkinoğulları, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Hacettepe University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ayla Fil Balkan, Assoc. Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Hacettepe University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bülent Elibol, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Hacettepe University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gül Yalçın Çakmaklı, Assoc. Prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hacettepe University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Songül Aksoy, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Hacettepe University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hacettepe University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <zip>06100</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rana AQ, Ahmed US, Chaudry ZM, Vasan S. Parkinson's disease: a review of non-motor symptoms. Expert Rev Neurother. 2015 May;15(5):549-62. doi: 10.1586/14737175.2015.1038244. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25936847</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jankovic J. Parkinson's disease: clinical features and diagnosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008 Apr;79(4):368-76. doi: 10.1136/jnnp.2007.131045. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18344392</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wright WG, Gurfinkel VS, Nutt J, Horak FB, Cordo PJ. Axial hypertonicity in Parkinson's disease: direct measurements of trunk and hip torque. Exp Neurol. 2007 Nov;208(1):38-46. Epub 2007 Jul 17.</citation>
    <PMID>17692315</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hong M, Earhart GM. Effects of medication on turning deficits in individuals with Parkinson's disease. J Neurol Phys Ther. 2010 Mar;34(1):11-6. doi: 10.1097/NPT.0b013e3181d070fe.</citation>
    <PMID>20212362</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vaugoyeau M, Viallet F, Mesure S, Massion J. Coordination of axial rotation and step execution: deficits in Parkinson's disease. Gait Posture. 2003 Dec;18(3):150-7.</citation>
    <PMID>14667948</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ramaker C, Marinus J, Stiggelbout AM, Van Hilten BJ. Systematic evaluation of rating scales for impairment and disability in Parkinson's disease. Mov Disord. 2002 Sep;17(5):867-76.</citation>
    <PMID>12360535</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Geldhof E, Cardon G, De Bourdeaudhuij I, Danneels L, Coorevits P, Vanderstraeten G, De Clercq D. Static and dynamic standing balance: test-retest reliability and reference values in 9 to 10 year old children. Eur J Pediatr. 2006 Nov;165(11):779-86.</citation>
    <PMID>16738867</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keus SH, Nieuwboer A, Bloem BR, Borm GF, Munneke M. Clinimetric analyses of the Modified Parkinson Activity Scale. Parkinsonism Relat Disord. 2009 May;15(4):263-9. doi: 10.1016/j.parkreldis.2008.06.003. Epub 2008 Aug 8.</citation>
    <PMID>18691929</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hacettepe University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>ayla fil balkan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc. Prof.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Parkinson's disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Lumbosacral Region</keyword>
  <keyword>Postural Balance</keyword>
  <keyword>Gait</keyword>
  <keyword>Manual Therapies</keyword>
  <keyword>Activities of Daily Living</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

