<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04529083</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>18-016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04529083</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mixed Reality Based System to Manage Phantom Pain Phantom Pain for Patients With Lower Limb Amputation</brief_title>
  <acronym>MrMAPP</acronym>
  <official_title>Feasibility and Functional Outcomes of a Novel Mixed Reality Based System to Manage Phantom Pain for Patients With Lower Limb Amputation.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dallas VA Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The University of Texas at Dallas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dallas VA Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary goals of this pilot research project are a) to design and develop the a mixed&#xD;
      reality based system for managing phantom pain and b) to evaluate the feasibility and&#xD;
      preliminary functional outcomes of this system in a sample of patients with lower limb&#xD;
      amputation. Findings from this pilot study will serve as preliminary data to inform regarding&#xD;
      a fully powered clinical trial to determine the effectiveness and practical implementation of&#xD;
      these findings in real-world settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim1: Design and develop a feasible mixed reality based system to manage phantom pain in&#xD;
      patients with lower limb amputation qualifying for on-going mirror therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1: The investigators hypothesize that the mixed reality based system to manage&#xD;
      phantom pain will be feasible and well-received by a sample of patients with lower limb&#xD;
      amputation needing mirror therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim2: Evaluate functional outcomes in a sample of lower limb amputees (n=10), using this&#xD;
      mixed reality based system to manage phantom pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 2: Using this system, the investigators hypothesize that patients who participate&#xD;
      in the mixed reality based system will show improvements in functional mobility based on&#xD;
      performance evaluations and patient reported outcome measures (PROs). The investigators also&#xD;
      hypothesize that this mixed reality based system will help to alleviate the phantom pain&#xD;
      based on McGill Pain questionnaire and visual analog scale (VAS).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary goals of this pilot research project are a) to design and develop the a mixed&#xD;
      reality based system for managing phantom pain and b) to evaluate the feasibility and&#xD;
      preliminary functional outcomes of this system in a sample of patients with lower limb&#xD;
      amputation. Findings from this pilot study will serve as preliminary data to inform regarding&#xD;
      a fully powered clinical trial to determine the effectiveness and practical implementation of&#xD;
      these findings in real-world settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim1: Design and develop a feasible mixed reality based system to manage phantom pain in&#xD;
      patients with lower limb amputation qualifying for on-going mirror therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1: The investigators hypothesize that the mixed reality based system to manage&#xD;
      phantom pain will be feasible and well received by a sample of patients with lower limb&#xD;
      amputation needing mirror therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim2: Evaluate functional outcomes in a sample of lower limb amputees (n=10), using this&#xD;
      mixed reality based system to manage phantom pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 2: Using this system, the investigators hypothesize that patients who participate&#xD;
      in the mixed reality based system will show improvements in patient-reported outcome measures&#xD;
      (PROs). The investigators also hypothesize that this mixed reality based system will help to&#xD;
      alleviate the phantom pain based on Pain questionnaires and visual analog scale (VAS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients 18 years of age and over with history of lower limb amputation and complaint of&#xD;
      phantom limb pain. Phantom limb pain is a condition experienced commonly by patients with&#xD;
      major limb amputations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Men and women, over the age of 18 with lower limb amputations (greater than 3 months post&#xD;
      surgery) with phantom limb pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      -Exclusion criteria: ---&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with lower limb amputations with open wounds or active infection in residual or&#xD;
           contralateral limbs&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with history of seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with visual (self-reported) or cognitive impairment (assessed by the&#xD;
           mini-mental state examination) that interferes with ability to interact with,&#xD;
           participate in, and adhere to a computerized rehabilitation system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any patient with a cardiac event in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any patient with an active medical issue to minimize risk of exacerbating their&#xD;
           condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Lives more than 60 miles away from the Dallas VA Medical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any patient with the motion sickness induced by head mounted displays (HMDs) or&#xD;
           immersive environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any patient experiencing the motion sickness induced by HMDs during the therapy session&#xD;
           can also opt out of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this exploratory, pilot study, a convenience sample of 10 patients will be recruited. A&#xD;
      sample of 10 subjects is adequate and consistent with other pilot behavioral intervention&#xD;
      trials at the VA that have been completed and published.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a pilot study is intended to yield preliminary data that will inform a fully powered&#xD;
      trial to determine effectiveness of the novel Mixed Reality based system to manage phantom&#xD;
      pain.A HIPAA waiver will be obtained to screen patients with lower limb amputation in the&#xD;
      outpatient PM&amp;R clinics. Eligible study candidates will be identified either during an&#xD;
      initial visit as an outpatient during clinic visit with the physiatrist. or review of prior&#xD;
      visit with physiatrist. The eligible, pre-screened subjects will undergo a basic evaluation&#xD;
      (by rehabilitation physician ). After the evaluation, the patient will be asked to&#xD;
      participate in the study or sent invitation letter. Once the eligible patient consents to&#xD;
      enroll in the study with specific emphasis on safely performing the exercises independently&#xD;
      at home. The research team will provide the laptop, camera and instruct the patient in its&#xD;
      use at their home. The patient will then use the system and perform the personalized home&#xD;
      exercises every day for a 1 month period (to evaluate sustainability of exercise behavior).&#xD;
      At the end of this period, the system will be returned. At initial clinic visit, visit at&#xD;
      week 1 and 1 month visit, the patient will fill out pain questionnaires, functional&#xD;
      questionnaire without any identifiable PHI. The images of the patients performing the&#xD;
      exercises will be stored in the encrypted laptop and analyzed at UTD. Also, that the videos&#xD;
      at UTD will be destroyed after 5 years, but a copy will be kept at the Dallas VA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A HIPAA waiver will be obtained to screen patients with lower limb amputation in the&#xD;
      outpatient clinics. Eligible study candidates will be identified based on visit as an&#xD;
      outpatient, following hospital discharge, the eligible, pre-screened subjects will undergo a&#xD;
      basic evaluation (by rehabilitation physician). After the evaluation, the patient will be&#xD;
      asked to participate in the study in person or by invitation letter. Once the eligible&#xD;
      patient consents to enroll in the study with specific emphasis on safely performing the&#xD;
      exercises independently at home. The research team will provide the laptop, camera and&#xD;
      instruct the patient in its use at their home. The patient will then use the system and&#xD;
      perform the personalized home exercises every day for a 1 month period (to evaluate&#xD;
      sustainability of exercise behavior). At the end of this period, the system will be returned&#xD;
      by the patient at the final study visit or can be retrieved at subject's home at subjects&#xD;
      request if unable to bring to final visit by research assistant. Setting of the Study: The&#xD;
      subject will be participating in a therapy session of 15 minutes per day for a duration of 4&#xD;
      weeks. Before starting a session, the subject will be provided with oral instructions about&#xD;
      the overall system and the purpose of study. They will be asked to fill out a questionnaire&#xD;
      asking the status of phantom pain, phantom limb movement, stress level etc. After completing&#xD;
      the questionnaire, they will be allowed to move in virtual world to get acquainted. Each&#xD;
      session consists of three sub-sections where the subject is asked to play three different&#xD;
      virtual games. These virtual games are designed specifically for lower limb amputees. Each&#xD;
      game is targeting certain types of muscle movement. We focused mainly on three types of&#xD;
      movements: 1) knee flexion and extension, 2) ankle dorsiflexion and planar flexion, and 3)&#xD;
      tandem coordinated bilateral lower extremity movement. Each game will be played only for 5&#xD;
      minutes. After completing each sub-session, the subject is asked to fill out similar&#xD;
      questionnaire to record the effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
      System Overview: The system consists of one Microsoft Kinect camera, Oculus Rift and a&#xD;
      computer system with sufficient processing power. Microsoft Kinect is used to scan the person&#xD;
      and to create corresponding 3D model. As shown in Figure 3, the 3D model for the phantom limb&#xD;
      is obtained by mirroring the 3D model of the intact limb. So, the subject will be able to&#xD;
      perceive both the limb in the virtual world. The system provides a mixed reality based&#xD;
      implementation of mirror therapy for managing phantom pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Major features of this system include:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Unconstrained movement: As patient will be performing exercise in virtual environment, the&#xD;
      movement is not restricted by limited space as in case of traditional mirror box therapy&#xD;
      where user can only move in the limits of box dimension, Realistic illusion of phantom limb:&#xD;
      As the Mr.MAPP framework is using RGB-D camera to capture the movement of patients intact&#xD;
      limb and mirror it to create the illusion of the phantom limb, the illusion obtained is very&#xD;
      realistic instead of using pre-built 3D model of a limb (See Figure 4), Patient&#xD;
      Encouragement: Use of an immersive gaming environment motivates and keeps the patient&#xD;
      engaging while performing exercise. With the help of virtual reality, various engaging game&#xD;
      can be developed that helps to remove monotonousness in therapy sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Feedback with positive Reinforcement: As each game is designed to encourage a patient to&#xD;
      perform certain type of exercise, the points earned in the game motivates the patient to&#xD;
      perform better, Adherence and compliance monitoring: by recording and annotating the therapy&#xD;
      sessions, the coaching software will monitor parameters such as number of repetitions, dates&#xD;
      and times of exercises, as well as correctness of performing the exercises. This will serve&#xD;
      as a real-time diary which is considered more reliable than self-report diaries that rely on&#xD;
      patient recall of activity,Functional Outcome Measures: a) Visual Analog Scale for pain&#xD;
      measurement (VAS) and b) McGill Pain questionnaire, c) Additional questions that composite of&#xD;
      the Mobility, Activities of Daily Living/Instrumental Activities of Daily Living, and Social&#xD;
      Participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the study, the patient will have the option to leave feedback and suggestions&#xD;
      for future use of this system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Descriptive methods will be used to characterize the sample population. Pre-post t-tests or&#xD;
      equivalent will be used to compare outcomes at one week and 1 month. Given the pilot nature&#xD;
      of this proposed study, inferential statistics (and reporting of statistical significance)&#xD;
      will not be used. Feasibility outcomes will be descriptive, including calculating the percent&#xD;
      of individuals enrolled in the study versus those eligible and the percent of individuals who&#xD;
      remain in the study at month 1. Aims 1 and 2 will help establish intervention acceptability&#xD;
      and feasibility. The images of the patients will be stored in the encrypted laptop and&#xD;
      analyzed at UTD. Also, that the videos at UTD will be destroyed after 5 years, but a copy&#xD;
      will be kept at the Dallas VA .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using weekly telephone support and online ad-hoc support features of the proposed system,&#xD;
      adverse event data will be obtained and further intervention will be initiated as needed for&#xD;
      any safety issues that may arise during this pilot study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 21, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Pilot study to evaluate feasibility</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Numerical Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1-month</time_frame>
    <description>Pain intensity; 0-10; higher is worse</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in McGill Pain Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1-month</time_frame>
    <description>Pain intensity and interference; multiple scales; higher is worse</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Patient Specific Functional Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline, 1-month</time_frame>
    <description>Patient specific functional questionnaire; multiple scales; higher is better</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Phantom Limb Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Mixed Reality System for virtual mirror therapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mr. MAPP</intervention_name>
    <description>Mixed reality device to provide virtual mirror therapy to patients with phantom pain</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women, over the age of 18 with lower limb amputations (greater than 3 months&#xD;
             post surgery) with phantom limb pain&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with lower limb amputations with open wounds or active infection in residual&#xD;
             or contralateral limbs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of seizures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with visual (self-reported) or cognitive impairment (assessed by the&#xD;
             mini-mental state examination) that interferes with ability to interact with,&#xD;
             participate in, and adhere to a computerized rehabilitation system.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient with a cardiac event in the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient with an active medical issue to minimize risk of exacerbating their&#xD;
             condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lives more than 60 miles away from the Dallas VA Medical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient with the motion sickness induced by head mounted displays (HMDs) or&#xD;
             immersive environment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any patient experiencing the motion sickness induced by HMDs during the therapy&#xD;
             session can also opt out of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gargi Raval, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>North Texas Veterans Healthcare System</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Thiru M Annaswamy, MD</last_name>
    <phone>2148570273</phone>
    <email>thiru.annaswamy@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gargi Raval, MD</last_name>
    <email>gargi.raval@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA North Texas Health Care System</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75216</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thiru Annaswamy, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gargi Raval, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dallas VA Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Thiru Annaswamy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Staff Physician and Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>mixed reality</keyword>
  <keyword>phantom limb pain</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Phantom Limb</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data may be shared upon approval from concerned authorities if needed</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

