<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04522752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>XJTU1AF-CRF-2018-016</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04522752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long-term Endoscopic Follow-up of Benign Epithelial Gastric Polyps</brief_title>
  <acronym>LEFBEGP</acronym>
  <official_title>Long-term Endoscopic Follow-up of Benign Epithelial Gastric Polyps: a Multicenter Prospective Large Sample Cohort Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>First Affiliated Hospital Xi'an Jiaotong University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>First Affiliated Hospital Xi'an Jiaotong University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Benign epithelial gastric polyps are benign raised lesions that originate from the gastric&#xD;
      mucosa or submucosa and protrude from the gastric cavity with a wide base or a pedicle.The&#xD;
      diagnosis and treatment of benign epithelial gastric polyps are currently controversial.&#xD;
      There is still a lack of clinical research evidence especially for the malignant tendency and&#xD;
      related treatments of gastric polyps. Many doctors have ambiguous understanding of benign&#xD;
      epithelial gastric polyps and their endoscopic management is still in a&quot;one size fits&#xD;
      all&quot;mode in China, which greatly wastes medical resources and increases the medical risks of&#xD;
      patients, So it is imminent to formulate management practices for the diagnosis and treatment&#xD;
      of gastric polyps. Therefore, a full understanding of the clinical characteristics,&#xD;
      endoscopic characteristics and long-term follow-up trends of benign epithelial gastric polyps&#xD;
      is of great significance for clinicians to formulate reasonable treatment and follow-up&#xD;
      plans. This study is a prospective, large-sample observational cohort study. It is planned to&#xD;
      include 200 patients with biopsy confirmed benign epithelial gastric polyps participating in&#xD;
      this study from September 10, 2020 to December 31, 2021 and followed up for 18 months. The&#xD;
      main research endpoint is the correlation between size and pathological type of benign&#xD;
      epithelial gastric polyps and polyps development. The secondary research endpoint is the&#xD;
      correlation between type of benign epithelial gastric polyps and Helicobacter pylori&#xD;
      infection. The research results will help provide long-term follow-up data for benign&#xD;
      epithelial gastric polyps of different pathological types, thereby providing first-hand&#xD;
      evidence-based medical data for formulating gastric polyp management guidelines, helping to&#xD;
      efficiently screen high-risk groups and guiding their examination, treatment and long-term&#xD;
      follow-up to achieve early detection and early treatment of gastric cancer, thereby reducing&#xD;
      the mortality rate.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 10, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between size and pathological type of benign epithelial gastric polyp and polyp development.</measure>
    <time_frame>The planned observation period of this study is 18 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Gastroscopy and pathological examination were performed at 6, 12, and 18 months after inclusion to observe the correlation between size and pathological type of benign epithelial gastric polyps and polyp development.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation between helicobacter pylori infection and pathological type of benign epithelial gastric polyp.</measure>
    <time_frame>The planned observation period of this study is 18 months.</time_frame>
    <description>To investigate the infection status of the subjects with Helicobacter pylori and analyze its correlation with the pathological types of benign epithelial gastric polyps.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Benign Gastric Polyp</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Gastric Polyp</arm_group_label>
    <description>The included subjects were patients with benign epithelial gastric polyps confirmed by gastroscopy and biopsy pathology. The size and pathology type of polyps were identified. Gastroscopy and biopsy were followed up six, twelve and eighteen months later to observe the relationship between the size, pathology types of polyps and the development of gastric polyps. Other factors including the relationship between helicobacter pylori infection and polyp type were also observed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Size and pathological type of benign epithelial gastric polyp</intervention_name>
    <description>All subjects will undergo gastroscopy and biopsy to determine the size and pathological type of benign epithelial gastric polyps.The correlation between polyp size and type and polyp development was observed at 6 months, 12 months and 18 months after inclusion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Gastric Polyp</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Biopsy of benign epithelial gastric polyps&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The subjects of this study are 18 to 70 years old patients who underwent gastroscopy from&#xD;
        September 10, 2020 to December 31, 2021 and were confirmed by biopsy to be benign&#xD;
        epithelial gastric polyps patients. At the same time, there are no exclusion criteria for&#xD;
        the research objects.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  After gastroscopy, gastric polyps are found and pathological biopsy is obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
        All polyps undergo endoscopic clamp biopsy, requiring at least one piece of tissue from&#xD;
        each polyp to be submitted for examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Submucosal raised lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastrointestinal bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant with gastric malignant tumor disease or previous gastric surgery for any&#xD;
             reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Benign polyps with a diameter greater than 1cm, regardless of the pathological type.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient also has other serious diseases that affect the evaluation of this study,&#xD;
             such as severe liver disease, heart disease, kidney disease, malignant tumors and&#xD;
             alcoholism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient cannot express his main complaint correctly, such as mental illness,&#xD;
             severe neurosis, and cannot cooperate with the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hongxia Li, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>First Affiliated Hospital Xi'an Jiaotong University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hongxia Li, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>0086-029-85323920</phone>
    <email>hongxia1105@126.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Yun Feng, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>0086-029-85323920</phone>
    <email>fengyun891120@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>First Affliated Hospital of Xi'an Jiaotong University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Xi'an</city>
        <state>Shaanxi</state>
        <zip>710061</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hongxia Li, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>0086-029-85323920</phone>
      <email>hongxia1105@126.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Yun Feng, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>0086-029-85323920</phone>
      <email>fengyun891120@163.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hongxia Li, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shuixiang He, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Shuying Wang, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Mudan Ren, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yun Feng, M.D.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Yan Zhao, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Schmitz JM, Stolte M. Gastric polyps as precancerous lesions. Gastrointest Endosc Clin N Am. 1997 Jan;7(1):29-46. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>8995111</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dinis-Ribeiro M, Areia M, de Vries AC, Marcos-Pinto R, Monteiro-Soares M, O'Connor A, Pereira C, Pimentel-Nunes P, Correia R, Ensari A, Dumonceau JM, Machado JC, Macedo G, Malfertheiner P, Matysiak-Budnik T, Megraud F, Miki K, O'Morain C, Peek RM, Ponchon T, Ristimaki A, Rembacken B, Carneiro F, Kuipers EJ; European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy; European Helicobacter Study Group; European Society of Pathology; Sociedade Portuguesa de Endoscopia Digestiva. Management of precancerous conditions and lesions in the stomach (MAPS): guideline from the European Society of Gastrointestinal Endoscopy (ESGE), European Helicobacter Study Group (EHSG), European Society of Pathology (ESP), and the Sociedade Portuguesa de Endoscopia Digestiva (SPED). Endoscopy. 2012 Jan;44(1):74-94. doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1291491. Epub 2011 Dec 23.</citation>
    <PMID>22198778</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Jalving M, Koornstra JJ, Wesseling J, Boezen HM, DE Jong S, Kleibeuker JH. Increased risk of fundic gland polyps during long-term proton pump inhibitor therapy. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2006 Nov 1;24(9):1341-8.</citation>
    <PMID>17059515</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Genta RM, Schuler CM, Robiou CI, Lash RH. No association between gastric fundic gland polyps and gastrointestinal neoplasia in a study of over 100,000 patients. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009 Aug;7(8):849-54. doi: 10.1016/j.cgh.2009.05.015. Epub 2009 May 22.</citation>
    <PMID>19465154</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tran-Duy A, Spaetgens B, Hoes AW, de Wit NJ, Stehouwer CD. Use of Proton Pump Inhibitors and Risks of Fundic Gland Polyps and Gastric Cancer: Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016 Dec;14(12):1706-1719.e5. doi: 10.1016/j.cgh.2016.05.018. Epub 2016 May 20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27211501</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hirota WK, Zuckerman MJ, Adler DG, Davila RE, Egan J, Leighton JA, Qureshi WA, Rajan E, Fanelli R, Wheeler-Harbaugh J, Baron TH, Faigel DO; Standards of Practice Committee, American Society for Gastrointestinal Endoscopy. ASGE guideline: the role of endoscopy in the surveillance of premalignant conditions of the upper GI tract. Gastrointest Endosc. 2006 Apr;63(4):570-80.</citation>
    <PMID>16564854</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>benign gastric polyp</keyword>
  <keyword>gastroendoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>pathological type</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stomach Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenomatous Polyps</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Polyps</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>We plan to share individual participant data with relevant industry researchers.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data will be open and shared by December 2022 for three years.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Registered and certified medical researchers.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

