<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04526028</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CIH-TZS-20190912</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04526028</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Palbociclib in Combination With Fulvestrant Versus Fulvestrant in Advanced Breast Cancer: A Real-world Study in China</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluate Efficacy and Safety of CDK4/6 Inhibitor Palbociclib in Combination With Fulvestrant Versus Fulvestrant in Female Patients With HR+/HER2- Advanced Breast Cancer: A Real-world Multicenter Observational Study in China</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute and Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute and Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate efficacy and safety of CDK4/6 inhibitor Palbociclib&#xD;
      in combination with Fulvestrant versus Fulvestrant in female patients with HR+/HER2- advanced&#xD;
      breast cancer in a real world setting in China. Primary study endpoint: progression-free&#xD;
      survival (PFS). Secondary study endpoints: overall survival (OS), overall response rate&#xD;
      (ORR), clinical benefit rate (CBR), objective response duration (DOR) and safety.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 13, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 28, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>41 months</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the progression-free survival for patients receiving CDK4/6 Inhibitor Palbociclib in Combination with Fulvestrant Versus Fulvestrant</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">612</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Fulvestrant</condition>
  <condition>Palbociclib</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Palbociclib combined with Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fulvestrant Injectable Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Fulvestrant is in the form of a prefilled syringe containing 5 ml of an injection solution of 250 mg of fulvestrant for intramuscular injection. The recommended dose is once every 28 days, once at a dose of 500 mg, and on the 15th day after the initial injection, a loading dose of fulvestrant 500 mg is added.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Palbociclib combined with Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Palbociclib</intervention_name>
    <description>Palbociclib is in the form of oral capsules, which are divided into three specifications: 75 mg, 100 mg and 125 mg. The recommended dose is 125 mg once daily for 21 days, followed by 7 days (3/1 dosage regimen), 28 Day is a treatment cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Palbociclib combined with Fulvestrant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        1. Female patients with advanced breast cancer aged 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Postmenopausal or premenopausal/perimmenopausal women can be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. HR-positive, HER2-negative breast cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must have: a) measurable lesions; b) unmeasurable osteolytic or mixed&#xD;
             (osteolytic + osteogenic) bone lesions in the absence of measurable lesions.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: 1) Female patients with advanced breast cancer aged 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2) Meet the inclusion criteria (2a) or the inclusion criteria (2b). Patients who met&#xD;
        inclusion criteria (2a) were included in cohort A, and patients who met inclusion criteria&#xD;
        (2b) were included in cohort B.&#xD;
&#xD;
        (2a) Meet any of the following criteria: a) recurrence and metastasis of evidence of&#xD;
        imaging progression for more than 1 year after completion of endocrine neoadjuvant or&#xD;
        adjuvant therapy and no endocrine therapy for recurrent metastatic disease; b) A primary&#xD;
        metastatic disease has occurred and no previous endocrine therapy has been received.&#xD;
&#xD;
        (2b) Meet any of the following criteria: a) previous endocrine-assisted treatment completed&#xD;
        2 years and above, and recurrence and metastasis of evidence of imaging progression during&#xD;
        treatment, and no subsequent endocrine therapy after progression; b) completion of adjuvant&#xD;
        endocrine After treatment, recurrence and metastasis of evidence of imaging progression&#xD;
        occurred within 1 year, and no subsequent endocrine therapy was received after progression;&#xD;
        c) recurrence and metastasis occurred after more than 1 year after completion of adjuvant&#xD;
        endocrine therapy, and then received anti-estrogen drugs or aromatase inhibitors as&#xD;
        evidence of disease progression after first-line endocrine therapy and evidence of imaging&#xD;
        progression, patients may not have more than 1 line of endocrine therapy for recurrent&#xD;
        metastatic disease; d) primary metastatic disease, and subsequent anti-acceptance Estrogen&#xD;
        drugs or aromatase inhibitors as a first-line metastatic disease after endocrine therapy&#xD;
        disease progression and evidence of imaging progression, patients can not receive more than&#xD;
        1 line of endocrine therapy for metastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3) Postmenopausal or premenopausal/perimmenopausal women can be enrolled. In postmenopausal&#xD;
        state, defined as meeting at least one of the following criteria: previous bilateral&#xD;
        ovarian surgery; age≥60 years; age &lt;60 years, menopause for at least 12 months (not because&#xD;
        of chemotherapy, tamoxifen, toremifene or ovarian suppression) and follicle stimulating&#xD;
        hormone (FSH) and estrogen levels are in the postmenopausal range.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Premenopausal or perimenopausal women can also be enrolled, but must be willing to receive&#xD;
        LHRHa treatment during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4) Pathological examination confirmed HR-positive, HER2-negative breast cancer patients&#xD;
        with local recurrence or metastasis evidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ER-positive and/or PR-positive is defined as: positively stained tumor cells account&#xD;
             for ≥1% of all tumor cells (confirmed by the investigator at the test center);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. HER2-negative is defined as: standard immunohistochemistry (IHC) detection is 0/1+;&#xD;
             ISH detection: the HER2/CEP17 ratio is less than 2.0 or the HER2 gene copy number is&#xD;
             less than 4 (confirmed by the researcher at the test center).&#xD;
&#xD;
             5) According to the RECIST1.1 standard, patients must have: a) measurable lesions; b)&#xD;
             unmeasurable osteolytic or mixed (osteolytic + osteogenic) bone lesions in the absence&#xD;
             of measurable lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
             6) Meet the inclusion criteria (6a) or the inclusion criteria (6b). Patients who meet&#xD;
             the inclusion criteria (6a) can be included in cohort A, and patients who meet the&#xD;
             inclusion criteria (6b) can be included in cohort B.&#xD;
&#xD;
             (6a) The following criteria are met: premenopausal patients are allowed to receive ≤1&#xD;
             line of chemotherapy for recurrent metastatic disease, and postmenopausal patients are&#xD;
             not allowed to receive any chemotherapy for recurrent metastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
             (6b) The following criteria are met: ≤1 line of chemotherapy for recurrent metastatic&#xD;
             disease is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
             7) The patient is receiving any of the following treatment regimens, the first dose is&#xD;
             administered within 2 months prior to enrollment, and the first efficacy assessment&#xD;
             has not been performed: a) Palbociclib in combination with Fulvestrant; b)&#xD;
             Fulvestrant.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. HER2 overexpression or gene amplification, such as immunohistochemical score 3+&#xD;
                  or fluorescent in situ hybridization.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Female patients during pregnancy or lactation.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients who are considered unsuitable for inclusion by the investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Zhongsheng Tong, Master</last_name>
    <phone>+86 18622221181</phone>
    <email>18622221181@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute and Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tianjin</city>
        <state>Tianjin</state>
        <zip>300061</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Zhongsheng Tong, Master</last_name>
      <phone>+86 18622221181</phone>
      <email>18622221181@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 25, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 25, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fulvestrant</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Palbociclib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

