<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04521855</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CHUB-Lombardo</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04521855</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Caregiver's Burden in Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Caregiver's Burden in Cerebral Palsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tatiana Besse-Hammer</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brugmann University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cerebral palsy (CP) results from damage to the developing brain of the fetus or infant. These&#xD;
      non-progressive lesions cause a set of permanent movement and posture disorders, responsible&#xD;
      for activity limitations. These disorders are often accompanied by sensory, perceptual,&#xD;
      cognitive impairments, communication and behavioral disorders, and sometimes epilepsy and/or&#xD;
      secondary musculoskeletal problems. It is the leading cause of motor disability in childhood&#xD;
      and affects 200 newborns per year in Belgium.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cerebral palsy affects two to three people in every 1,000 of the world's population. The&#xD;
      prevalence, incidence and most common causes have varied over time due to significant changes&#xD;
      in obstetric care and pediatric care. In 75% of all cases of cerebral palsy, the lesions&#xD;
      occurred before childbirth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The population of adults diagnosed with cerebral palsy is increasing as the survival rate of&#xD;
      children born with a disability increases. This population requires adapted and expert care&#xD;
      services for the continuous monitoring and management of their condition. In addition, the&#xD;
      development of additional health problems in adulthood increases the need for permanent&#xD;
      access to care structures. Adults with CP have a higher rate of chronic health problems&#xD;
      (ischemic heart disease) and a deterioration in their functional status. They would also have&#xD;
      difficulty having a social and professional life which negatively impacts their quality of&#xD;
      life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A large number of adults with CP cannot access appropriate care or medico-social structures.&#xD;
      This results in a significant involvement of caregivers (family environment or close&#xD;
      entourage).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The role of caregiver is at the origin of a significant physical and psychological burden,&#xD;
      whether for underage patients or adult patients. The study of this burden is well known in&#xD;
      certain neurological pathologies (head trauma, multiple sclerosis, brain tumors). In the&#xD;
      field of cerebral palsy, a study showed that the primary caregivers of children with CP had&#xD;
      higher levels of psychological and physical disorders than the control group studied&#xD;
      (caregivers of healthy children).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, there are very few studies assessing the burden of caregivers of adults with&#xD;
      cerebral palsy. The objective of this study is to analyze, through various specific&#xD;
      questionnaires, the quality of life and the presence of depressive symptoms linked to the&#xD;
      burden of caregivers of adults and children with cerebral palsy, taking into account&#xD;
      socio-economic and environmental data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 29, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Anxiety and depression scale (HAD)</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The HAD scale is an instrument used to screen for anxiety and depressive disorders. An overall score is calculated by adding the responses to the 14 items (varies from 0 to 42) as well as two sub-scores corresponding to the two subscales (ranging from 0 to 21). The higher the scores, the more severe the symptomatology.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ISPN (Nottingham Health Profile - NHP)</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The Nottingham Health Profile (NHP) is a general patient reported outcome measure which seeks to measure subjective health status. All questions have only yes/no answer options and each section score is weighted. The higher the score, the greater the number and severity of problems. The highest score in any section is 100.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Zarit scale</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The Zarit scale assesses the burden felt by caregivers. The total score, which is the sum of the scores obtained for each of 22 items, varies from 0 to 88. A lower score or equal to 20 indicates little or no charge; a score between 21 and 40 indicates a light load; a score between 41 and 60 indicate a moderate load; a score above 60 indicates a severe load.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SF12</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>The SF-12 is a self-reported outcome measure assessing the impact of health on an individual's everyday life. It is often used as a quality of life measure. A high score corresponds to a better state of health.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Cerebral Palsy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Caregivers</arm_group_label>
    <description>Caregivers (family environment or close entourage) for adults and children with cerebral palsy.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>Questionnaires in French on the quality of life, the burden of caregiving and a screening for depressive symptoms, completed during specific interviews.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Caregivers</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Healthy subjects, aged 18 to 75, caring for relatives of adults and children with cerebral&#xD;
        palsy, with a good understanding of the French language.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Healthy subjects, aged 18 to 75, caring for relatives of adults and children with&#xD;
        cerebral palsy, with a good understanding of the French language.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Subjects under 18 or over 75, presenting a language barrier (interview guide written in&#xD;
        French), subjects with a known history of psychiatric pathologies.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Costanza Lombardo, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Brugmann</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Costanza Lombardo, MD</last_name>
    <phone>024772858</phone>
    <email>Costanza.LOMBARDO@chu-brugmann.be</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brugmann University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <zip>1020</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Costanza Lombardo, MD</last_name>
      <email>Costanza.LOMBARDO@chu-brugmann.be</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Costanza Lombardo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 18, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brugmann University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tatiana Besse-Hammer</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of the clinical trial unit</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Caregiver Burden</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

