<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04525014</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-45787</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04525014</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>RRx-001 Given With Irinotecan and Temozolomide for Pediatric Patients With Recurrent or Progressive Malignant Solid and Central Nervous System Tumors</brief_title>
  <acronym>PIRATE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Trial of RRx-001 in Combination With Irinotecan and Temozolomide for Pediatric Patients With Recurrent or Progressive Malignant Solid and Central Nervous System Tumors</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>EpicentRx, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Texas Children's Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>EpicentRx, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The PIRATE study tests the experimental drug RRx-001 in combination with 2 chemotherapy drugs&#xD;
      that are commonly used in patients with cancer. RRx-001 has been used alone and with other&#xD;
      anti-cancer medicines in adults. However, the investigators do not know what effects it will&#xD;
      have in children and young adults.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The goals of the PIRATE study are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine if the adult dose of RRx-001 is safe when given together with 2 chemotherapy&#xD;
           drugs called irinotecan and temozolomide in children and young adults with&#xD;
           previously-treated cancerous tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine the side effects of RRx-001 in children and young adults when given together&#xD;
           with irinotecan and temozolomide&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Understand if the combination of RRx-001, irinotecan, and temozolomide is helpful for&#xD;
           children and young adults with previously-treated cancerous tumors&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In patients with brain tumors, measure if RRx-001 causes changes in the tumor on&#xD;
           Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Determine if RRx-001 causes changes in the immune system which may help the body&#xD;
           naturally fight the tumor&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recommended phase 2 dose</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Estimate the recommended phase 2 dose of RRx-001 administered every 3 weeks as an IV infusion in combination with oral irinotecan and temozolomide in pediatric patients with recurrent or progressive malignant solid or central nervous system (CNS) tumors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Grade 3 or higher CTCAE version 5.0 adverse event terms</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Describe the toxicities of RRx-001 in combination with irinotecan and temozolomide administered on this schedule in this population.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Describe the anti-tumor effects of RRx-001 in combination with irinotecan and temozolomide administered on this schedule in this population in the context of a Phase 1 trial.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Describe the anti-tumor effects of RRx-001 in combination with irinotecan and temozolomide administered on this schedule in this population in the context of a Phase 1 trial.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Summarize tumor response rates</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Imaging-based evaluation is preferred to evaluation by clinical examination unless the lesion(s) being followed cannot be imaged but are assessable by clinical exam.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in tumor perfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure treatment-induced change in tumor perfusion</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Response correlation for change in tumor perfusion</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of change in tumor perfusion to matched patient's best treatment response</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cellularity</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure treatment-induced change in cellularity</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Response correlation for change in cellularity</measure>
    <time_frame>15 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of change in cellularity to matched patient's best treatment response</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Ratio of M1 to M2 peripheral blood circulating monocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assess for change in the ratio of M1 to M2 peripheral blood circulating monocytes over the first 5 cycles of therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Response correlation for ratio of M1 to M2 peripheral blood circulating monocytes</measure>
    <time_frame>5 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of change in the ratio of M1 to M2 peripheral blood circulating monocytes over the first 5 cycles of therapy to matched patient's best treatment response.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Tumor, Recurrent</condition>
  <condition>Brain Tumor, Pediatric</condition>
  <condition>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Unspecified Childhood Solid Tumor, Protocol Specific</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RRx-001, Temozolomide and Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RRx-001</intervention_name>
    <description>RRx-001 will be administered every 3 weeks via intravenous infusion at three dose levels: 0.5 mg/m2 (Max 1 mg), 1 mg/m2 (Max 2 mg), and 2 mg/m2 (Max 4 mg).</description>
    <arm_group_label>RRx-001, Temozolomide and Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Temozolomide</intervention_name>
    <description>100 mg/m2 (children ≥0.5 m2) or 3 mg/kg (children &lt;0.5 m2) daily for 5 days beginning on day 1 of each cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>RRx-001, Temozolomide and Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Irinotecan</intervention_name>
    <description>90 mg/m2 taken orally daily for 5 days administered 1 hour after temozolomide</description>
    <arm_group_label>RRx-001, Temozolomide and Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Recurrent or progressive malignant (World Health Organization (WHO) grade 3 or 4&#xD;
             tumors) primary brain or spinal cord tumors and solid tumors (excluding lymphomas)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Eligible patients may have measureable or non-measurable but evaluable disease&#xD;
             according to the reviewed Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST)&#xD;
             guidelines version 1.1 criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must have a Karnofsky score of ≥50% if &gt;16 years old or a Lansky score of ≥50&#xD;
             if ≤16 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must have fully recovered from the acute treatment-related toxicities&#xD;
             (defined as &lt;grade 1) of their most recent prior anti-neoplastic therapy prior to&#xD;
             study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must be at least 4 weeks from major surgery including craniotomy or tumor&#xD;
             debulking/resection and at least 1 week from stereotactic biopsy prior to study&#xD;
             enrollment. Patients must have fully recovered from all acute effects of prior&#xD;
             surgical intervention excluding central line placement prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
             Patients must have fully recovered from all acute effects of central line placement&#xD;
             prior to initiation of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with neurological deficits should have deficits that are stable for a minimum&#xD;
             of 7 days prior to study enrollment. Patients with seizure disorders may be enrolled&#xD;
             if the seizures are well-controlled with a stable seizure frequency and duration for a&#xD;
             minimum 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients on chronic systemic steroids must be on a stable or decreasing dose for at&#xD;
             least 7 days prior to study enrollment. If used to modify immune adverse events&#xD;
             related to prior therapy, ≥ 14 days must have elapsed since last dose of&#xD;
             corticosteroid.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Platelet count ≥75,000/mm3. Patient must be transfusion independent defined as not&#xD;
             receiving platelet transfusions with a 7-day period prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Peripheral absolute neutrophil count ≥1000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Creatinine clearance or radioisotope glomerular filtration rate (GFR) ≥50 mL/min/1.73&#xD;
             m2 or a serum creatinine based on age and sex&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Conjugated bilirubin ≤1.5 times the institutional laboratory's upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamic-pyruvic transaminase (SGPT)) ≤3 times&#xD;
             the institutional laboratory's upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Aspartate transaminase (AST) (serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase (SGOT)) ≤3 times&#xD;
             the institutional laboratory's upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Adequate pulmonary function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Oxygen saturation as measured by pulse oximetry &gt; 93% on room air&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. No evidence of dyspnea at rest&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Left ventricular ejection fraction &gt; 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Patients of child-bearing potential of both genders must utilize contraception&#xD;
             including but not limited to hormonal contraception, barrier method, or abstinence for&#xD;
             the duration of the study and 28 days after completion of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Patients must have a central line in place prior to administration of the first dose&#xD;
             of RRx-001. Patients must have fully recovered from all acute effects of central line&#xD;
             placement prior to initiation of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. The patient or parent/legally authorized representative is able to understand the&#xD;
             consent and is willing to sign a written informed consent document according to&#xD;
             institutional guidelines. Assent, when appropriate, will be obtained according to&#xD;
             institutional guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Patients must be able to safely take oral medications either as liquid or tablet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Pregnant or breast feeding females&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with the following conditions will be excluded from study enrollment:&#xD;
             cyanotic heart disease, intermediate or severe β-thalassemia, known&#xD;
             glucose-6-phosphate dehydrogenase (G6PD) deficiency, active infections, concurrent&#xD;
             malignancy, a known thrombophilia syndrome, or a personal history of venous&#xD;
             thromboembolism including catheter-associated thrombi.31-34 Additionally, patients&#xD;
             with clinically significant or poorly controlled cardiac, pulmonary, hepatic, or other&#xD;
             organ dysfunction that, in the opinion of the investigator, would compromise the&#xD;
             patient's ability to tolerate protocol therapy, put them at additional risk for&#xD;
             toxicity, or interfere with the study procedures or results are not eligible for study&#xD;
             enrollment. Patients with a known coagulopathy or bleeding diathesis or who have&#xD;
             undergone either a solid organ or allogeneic bone marrow/stem cell transplant are not&#xD;
             eligible for study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients taking concurrent anti-cancer or investigational drug therapies are not&#xD;
             eligible for study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients taking anti-oxidants including alpha lipoic acid, vitamin E, N-&#xD;
             acetylcysteine, and omega 3 fatty acid supplements are not eligible for study&#xD;
             enrollment. Patients must be off these drugs for a minimum of 7 days prior to study&#xD;
             enrollment and must remain off anti-oxidant medications for the duration of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. While on study, concomitant use of clozapine, echinacea, leflunomide, natalizumab, and&#xD;
             tofacitinib are prohibited due to potential for increased temozolomide toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients who have received drugs that are strong inducers of CYP3A4 within 14 days&#xD;
             prior to study enrollment are not eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients who in the opinion of the investigator are unwilling or unable to return for&#xD;
             required follow-up visits or obtain follow-up studies required to assess toxicity to&#xD;
             therapy or to adhere to drug administration plan, other study procedures, and study&#xD;
             restrictions are not eligible for study enrollment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Bryan Oronsky, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>EpicentRx, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Holly Lindsay, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Texas Children's Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Daniela Westerhold</last_name>
    <phone>(832) 824-4552</phone>
    <email>diwester@texaschildrens.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Children's Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Daniela Westerhold</last_name>
      <phone>832-824-4552</phone>
      <email>diwester@texaschildrens.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Holly Lindsey, MD, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Patricia Baxter, MD, MBA, MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 21, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 24, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brain cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Pediatric cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Spinal cord tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Solid tumor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Central Nervous System Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Temozolomide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

