<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04528173</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>19-016618</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04528173</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Opioid-Free Anesthetic for Tonsillectomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Opioid-Free Versus Transitional Anesthetic With Opioids From Tonsillectomy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Tennessee Health Science Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prospective randomized controlled trial to determine if opioid-free anesthetic for&#xD;
      tonsillectomy is non-inferior to standard opioid-containing anesthetic&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary: To determine if an opioid-free anesthetic provides equivalent acute postoperative&#xD;
      pain relief in tonsillectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary: To determine if post-operative pain at home is not significantly different with an&#xD;
      opioid-free regimen compared to an opioid containing regimen for tonsillectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design: Prospective, randomized, multi-center trial study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Interventions and Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subject will be randomized to 1:1 intra-operative opioid-free (OFG) vs traditional care&#xD;
      anesthetic with opioids (TCG) group&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is the median pain score (calculated by a blinded validated observer in&#xD;
      the recovery room at two time intervals) between the two cohorts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 22, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Subject will be randomized to 1:1 intra-operative opioid-free (OFG) vs traditional care anesthetic with opioids (TCG) group.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The unblinded members are the treating anesthesiologist for the case, staff who randomize, and collect and enter intra-op medications into electronic data capture (EDC).&#xD;
Blinded members include the subject/family members, the surgeon, staff who perform post-op assessment, physician investigator who perform any adverse event/serious adverse event (AE/SAE) assessments, statistician and data safety monitoring board (DSMB).</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Median Maximum Pain Score</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Median Maximum Pain Score by investigational group in the recovery room, calculated by the blinded observer 15 and 30 minutes after awakening.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of nausea, vomiting, pruritis</measure>
    <time_frame>up to post-op day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Collected in recovery room and asked in questionnaires, collected from parents on post-operative days 1, 5, and 30.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of readmission and of seeking unplanned medical attention (phone calls, office visits, ED visits)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Chart review and questionnaires for readmission and medical reattendance, including calls to physician</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of non-artifactual percentage of oxygen saturation (SpO2)&lt;90% (&gt;30 seconds)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Collected in recovery room and chart review</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of patients receiving rescue opioids</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaires and chart review</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Family satisfaction with patient recovery based on seven-point Likert score</measure>
    <time_frame>up to post-op day 30</time_frame>
    <description>Follow-up questionnaire to family on post-op days 1, 5, and 30. Parents will be asked to rank how satisfied they are with their child's recovery by using these two prompts: &quot;I am satisfied with my child's recovery,&quot; and &quot;I am satisfied with my child's pain control at home.&quot; They will choose from the following options: &quot;Strongly agree = 1&quot;, &quot;Agree = 2&quot;, &quot;More or Less agree = 3&quot;, &quot;Undecided = 4&quot;, &quot;More or Less disagree = 5&quot;, &quot;Disagree = 6&quot;, &quot;Strongly Disagree =7.&quot; Minimum score is 1, Max is 7. Higher scores indicate worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding prevalence</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Follow-up questionnaires and chart review</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">550</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Use</condition>
  <condition>Tonsillitis</condition>
  <condition>Sleep Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional Care Group (TCG)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Traditional anesthetic with opioids group will receive institutional standard clinical care for tonsillectomy, including a standardized opioid dose at the beginning of the case and again at the end if needed. Dexmedetomidine and Ketorolac will not be used intra-operatively in this cohort to prevent confounding.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Opioid-Free Group (OFG)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Opioid-Free group will receive institutional standard clinical care for tonsillectomy, without opioids, but including Dexmedetomidine and Ketorolac.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketorolac</intervention_name>
    <description>Ketorolac (0.5mg/kg; maximum 15mg intravenously) will be given at end of procedure after evaluation for hemostasis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Opioid-Free Group (OFG)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Toradol</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexmedetomidine</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexmedetomidine (1ug/kg with maximum 50ug intravenously) will be given at beginning of procedure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Opioid-Free Group (OFG)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Precedex</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Morphine</intervention_name>
    <description>Morphine (0.05-0.1 mg/kg intravenously) will be given intra-operatively per institutional standard clinical care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional Care Group (TCG)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fentanyl</intervention_name>
    <description>Fentanyl (0.5-2 ug/kg intravenously) will be given intra-operatively per institutional standard clinical care.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Traditional Care Group (TCG)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or females age 2 to 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. American Society of Anesthesiologists {ASA) ≤ 3 physical classification system&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Girls after menarche must have a negative pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Scheduled tonsillectomy or tonsillectomy combined with adenoidectomy and/or ear tube&#xD;
             placement at the Children's Hospital of Philadelphia (CHOP) main or ambulatory&#xD;
             surgical centers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Parental/guardian permission (informed consent) and if appropriate, child assent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current (Within the last 30 days) opioid use for pain control&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. High risk for surgical site hemorrhage, determined by bleeding disorder diagnosis or&#xD;
             evidence or poor hemostasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Multiple scheduled surgeries at the same time other than adenoidectomy and/or ear tube&#xD;
             placement&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of drug abuse, chronic pain, bleeding disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Chronic disease such as sickle cell disease for which treatment with opioids may be&#xD;
             clinically indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Significant congenital disorders, medication allergies or comorbidities, specifically&#xD;
             a pre-disposition to bradycardia or conduction abnormalities, cyanotic cardiac disease&#xD;
             and use of medications that would increase risk of bleeding or bradycardia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of hepatic dysfunction, renal dysfunction, thrombocytopenia, or anemia&#xD;
             (including pre-surgery laboratory abnormalities)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of hypersensitivity to NSAIDs&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with asthma, including patients who have experienced aspirin- or&#xD;
             NSAID-sensitive asthma or a history of exacerbation when aspirin or NSAIDs are&#xD;
             administered (e.g. bronchospasm, urticaria, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects receiving medications that could impact metabolism of either study drug&#xD;
             should also be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Trisomy 21 diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Parents/guardians or subjects who, in the opinion of the Investigator, may be&#xD;
             non-compliant with study schedules or procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients on a Ketogenic diet&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Parents or subjects who do not speak English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tori Sutherland, MD,MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anthony Sheyn, MD, FACS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Tennessee Health Science Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Tori N Sutherland, MD,MPH</last_name>
    <phone>267-426-2961</phone>
    <email>sutherlant@chop.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Paula Hu, MSPH</last_name>
    <phone>(267) 426-0897</phone>
    <email>hup@chop.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tori N Sutherland, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>443-631-5032</phone>
      <email>sutherlant@chop.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Paula Hu, RN, MSPH</last_name>
      <phone>267-225-3214</phone>
      <email>hup@chop.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Tennessee Health Science Center; St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anthony Sheyn, MD</last_name>
      <phone>901-287-7337</phone>
      <email>asheyn@uthsc.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Madhu Mamidala, PHD</last_name>
      <phone>9014482134</phone>
      <email>mmamidal@uthsc.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.samhsa.gov/data/</url>
    <description>Key substance use and mental health indicators in the United States: Results from the 2016 National Survey on Drug Use and Health (HHS Publication No. SMA 17-5044). Center f</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.sealedenvelope.com/power/continuous-noninferior/</url>
    <description>Sealed Envelope Ltd. 2012. Power calculator for continuous outcome non-inferiority trial.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://med.virginia.edu/pediatrics/wp-content/uploads/sites/237/2015/12/201108.pdf</url>
    <description>Buck, ML. Use of Intravenous Ketorolac for Postoperative Analgesia in Infants: Pediatric Pharmacotherapy, A Monthly Newsletter. . 2011</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Julious SA. Sample sizes for clinical trials with normal data. Stat Med. 2004 Jun 30;23(12):1921-86. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15195324</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Volkow ND, Jones EB, Einstein EB, Wargo EM. Prevention and Treatment of Opioid Misuse and Addiction: A Review. JAMA Psychiatry. 2019 Feb 1;76(2):208-216. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2018.3126. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30516809</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Scholl L, Seth P, Kariisa M, Wilson N, Baldwin G. Drug and Opioid-Involved Overdose Deaths - United States, 2013-2017. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2018 Jan 4;67(5152):1419-1427. doi: 10.15585/mmwr.mm675152e1.</citation>
    <PMID>30605448</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Harbaugh CM, Lee JS, Hu HM, McCabe SE, Voepel-Lewis T, Englesbe MJ, Brummett CM, Waljee JF. Persistent Opioid Use Among Pediatric Patients After Surgery. Pediatrics. 2018 Jan;141(1). pii: e20172439. doi: 10.1542/peds.2017-2439. Epub 2017 Dec 4.</citation>
    <PMID>29203521</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Harbaugh CM, Nalliah RP, Hu HM, Englesbe MJ, Waljee JF, Brummett CM. Persistent Opioid Use After Wisdom Tooth Extraction. JAMA. 2018 Aug 7;320(5):504-506. doi: 10.1001/jama.2018.9023.</citation>
    <PMID>30088000</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kelly LE, Sommer DD, Ramakrishna J, Hoffbauer S, Arbab-Tafti S, Reid D, Maclean J, Koren G. Morphine or Ibuprofen for post-tonsillectomy analgesia: a randomized trial. Pediatrics. 2015 Feb;135(2):307-13. doi: 10.1542/peds.2014-1906.</citation>
    <PMID>25624387</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Franz AM, Dahl JP, Huang H, Verma ST, Martin LD, Martin LD, Low DK. The development of an opioid sparing anesthesia protocol for pediatric ambulatory tonsillectomy and adenotonsillectomy surgery-A quality improvement project. Paediatr Anaesth. 2019 Jul;29(7):682-689. doi: 10.1111/pan.13662. Epub 2019 Jun 19.</citation>
    <PMID>31077491</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Frauenknecht J, Kirkham KR, Jacot-Guillarmod A, Albrecht E. Analgesic impact of intra-operative opioids vs. opioid-free anaesthesia: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Anaesthesia. 2019 May;74(5):651-662. doi: 10.1111/anae.14582. Epub 2019 Feb 25.</citation>
    <PMID>30802933</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Elkassabany NM, Mariano ER. Opioid-free anaesthesia - what would Inigo Montoya say? Anaesthesia. 2019 May;74(5):560-563. doi: 10.1111/anae.14611. Epub 2019 Feb 25.</citation>
    <PMID>30802930</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mitchell RB, Archer SM, Ishman SL, Rosenfeld RM, Coles S, Finestone SA, Friedman NR, Giordano T, Hildrew DM, Kim TW, Lloyd RM, Parikh SR, Shulman ST, Walner DL, Walsh SA, Nnacheta LC. Clinical Practice Guideline: Tonsillectomy in Children (Update). Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2019 Feb;160(1_suppl):S1-S42. doi: 10.1177/0194599818801757.</citation>
    <PMID>30798778</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Baugh RF, Archer SM, Mitchell RB, Rosenfeld RM, Amin R, Burns JJ, Darrow DH, Giordano T, Litman RS, Li KK, Mannix ME, Schwartz RH, Setzen G, Wald ER, Wall E, Sandberg G, Patel MM; American Academy of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery Foundation. Clinical practice guideline: tonsillectomy in children. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2011 Jan;144(1 Suppl):S1-30. doi: 10.1177/0194599810389949.</citation>
    <PMID>21493257</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Coté CJ, Posner KL, Domino KB. Death or neurologic injury after tonsillectomy in children with a focus on obstructive sleep apnea: houston, we have a problem! Anesth Analg. 2014 Jun;118(6):1276-83. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0b013e318294fc47.</citation>
    <PMID>23842193</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McCabe SE, Schulenberg JE, O'Malley PM, Patrick ME, Kloska DD. Non-medical use of prescription opioids during the transition to adulthood: a multi-cohort national longitudinal study. Addiction. 2014 Jan;109(1):102-10. doi: 10.1111/add.12347. Epub 2013 Oct 22.</citation>
    <PMID>24025114</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McCabe SE, West BT, Boyd CJ. Medical use, medical misuse, and nonmedical use of prescription opioids: results from a longitudinal study. Pain. 2013 May;154(5):708-713. doi: 10.1016/j.pain.2013.01.011. Epub 2013 Jan 26.</citation>
    <PMID>23433943</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McCabe SE, West BT, Boyd CJ. Leftover prescription opioids and nonmedical use among high school seniors: a multi-cohort national study. J Adolesc Health. 2013 Apr;52(4):480-5. doi: 10.1016/j.jadohealth.2012.08.007. Epub 2012 Nov 22.</citation>
    <PMID>23298996</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Winters KC, Arria A. Adolescent Brain Development and Drugs. Prev Res. 2011;18(2):21-24.</citation>
    <PMID>22822298</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mason KP. Paediatric emergence delirium: a comprehensive review and interpretation of the literature. Br J Anaesth. 2017 Mar 1;118(3):335-343. doi: 10.1093/bja/aew477. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28203739</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Althunian TA, de Boer A, Klungel OH, Insani WN, Groenwold RH. Methods of defining the non-inferiority margin in randomized, double-blind controlled trials: a systematic review. Trials. 2017 Mar 7;18(1):107. doi: 10.1186/s13063-017-1859-x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28270184</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Strom BL, Berlin JA, Kinman JL, Spitz PW, Hennessy S, Feldman H, Kimmel S, Carson JL. Parenteral ketorolac and risk of gastrointestinal and operative site bleeding. A postmarketing surveillance study. JAMA. 1996 Feb 7;275(5):376-82.</citation>
    <PMID>8569017</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Forrest JB, Camu F, Greer IA, Kehlet H, Abdalla M, Bonnet F, Ebrahim S, Escolar G, Jage J, Pocock S, Velo G, Langman MJ, Bianchi PG, Samama MM, Heitlinger E; POINT Investigators. Ketorolac, diclofenac, and ketoprofen are equally safe for pain relief after major surgery. Br J Anaesth. 2002 Feb;88(2):227-33.</citation>
    <PMID>11883386</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mowatt G, Cook JA, Fraser C, McKerrow WS, Burr JM. Systematic review of the safety of electrosurgery for tonsillectomy. Clin Otolaryngol. 2006 Apr;31(2):95-102. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16620327</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chan DK, Parikh SR. Perioperative ketorolac increases post-tonsillectomy hemorrhage in adults but not children. Laryngoscope. 2014 Aug;124(8):1789-93. doi: 10.1002/lary.24555. Epub 2014 May 27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24338331</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>McClain K, Williams AM, Yaremchuk K. Ketorolac usage in tonsillectomy and uvulopalatopharyngoplasty patients. Laryngoscope. 2020 Apr;130(4):876-879. doi: 10.1002/lary.28077. Epub 2019 May 30.</citation>
    <PMID>31145482</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Patel A, Davidson M, Tran MC, Quraishi H, Schoenberg C, Sant M, Lin A, Sun X. Dexmedetomidine infusion for analgesia and prevention of emergence agitation in children with obstructive sleep apnea syndrome undergoing tonsillectomy and adenoidectomy. Anesth Analg. 2010 Oct;111(4):1004-10. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0b013e3181ee82fa. Epub 2010 Aug 12.</citation>
    <PMID>20705788</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Olutoye OA, Glover CD, Diefenderfer JW, McGilberry M, Wyatt MM, Larrier DR, Friedman EM, Watcha MF. The effect of intraoperative dexmedetomidine on postoperative analgesia and sedation in pediatric patients undergoing tonsillectomy and adenoidectomy. Anesth Analg. 2010 Aug;111(2):490-5. doi: 10.1213/ANE.0b013e3181e33429. Epub 2010 Jul 7.</citation>
    <PMID>20610555</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lee MS, Montague ML, Hussain SS. Post-tonsillectomy hemorrhage: cold versus hot dissection. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2004 Dec;131(6):833-6.</citation>
    <PMID>15577776</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Diercks GR, Comins J, Bennett K, Gallagher TQ, Brigger M, Boseley M, Gaudreau P, Rogers D, Setlur J, Keamy D, Cohen MS, Hartnick C. Comparison of Ibuprofen vs Acetaminophen and Severe Bleeding Risk After Pediatric Tonsillectomy: A Noninferiority Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2019 Jun 1;145(6):494-500. doi: 10.1001/jamaoto.2019.0269.</citation>
    <PMID>30946442</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mroszczak EJ, Jung D, Yee J, Bynum L, Sevelius H, Massey I. Ketorolac tromethamine pharmacokinetics and metabolism after intravenous, intramuscular, and oral administration in humans and animals. Pharmacotherapy. 1990;10(6 ( Pt 2)):33S-39S. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>2082311</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Macario A, Lipman AG. Ketorolac in the era of cyclo-oxygenase-2 selective nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs: a systematic review of efficacy, side effects, and regulatory issues. Pain Med. 2001 Dec;2(4):336-51.</citation>
    <PMID>15102238</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mitchell RB, Archer SM, Ishman SL, Rosenfeld RM, Coles S, Finestone SA, Friedman NR, Giordano T, Hildrew DM, Kim TW, Lloyd RM, Parikh SR, Shulman ST, Walner DL, Walsh SA, Nnacheta LC. Clinical Practice Guideline: Tonsillectomy in Children (Update)-Executive Summary. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2019 Feb;160(2):187-205. doi: 10.1177/0194599818807917. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30921525</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mudd PA, Thottathil P, Giordano T, Wetmore RF, Elden L, Jawad AF, Ahumada L, Gálvez JA. Association Between Ibuprofen Use and Severity of Surgically Managed Posttonsillectomy Hemorrhage. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2017 Jul 1;143(7):712-717. doi: 10.1001/jamaoto.2016.3839.</citation>
    <PMID>28472239</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gupta P, Whiteside W, Sabati A, Tesoro TM, Gossett JM, Tobias JD, Roth SJ. Safety and efficacy of prolonged dexmedetomidine use in critically ill children with heart disease*. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2012 Nov;13(6):660-6. doi: 10.1097/PCC.0b013e318253c7f1.</citation>
    <PMID>22791093</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mahmoud M, Mason KP. Dexmedetomidine: review, update, and future considerations of paediatric perioperative and periprocedural applications and limitations. Br J Anaesth. 2015 Aug;115(2):171-82. doi: 10.1093/bja/aev226. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26170346</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tsiotou AG, Malisiova A, Kouptsova E, Mavri M, Anagnostopoulou M, Kalliardou E. Dexmedetomidine for the reduction of emergence delirium in children undergoing tonsillectomy with propofol anesthesia: A double-blind, randomized study. Paediatr Anaesth. 2018 Jul;28(7):632-638. doi: 10.1111/pan.13397. Epub 2018 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>29752853</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Tonsillectomy</keyword>
  <keyword>Opioid-Free</keyword>
  <keyword>Ketorolac</keyword>
  <keyword>Dexmedetomidine</keyword>
  <keyword>Acute postoperative pain relief</keyword>
  <keyword>Opioid</keyword>
  <keyword>Morphine</keyword>
  <keyword>Fentanyl</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tonsillitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketorolac</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dexmedetomidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Morphine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 25, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/73/NCT04528173/Prot_SAP_002.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>August 4, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/73/NCT04528173/ICF_003.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

