<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04523649</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HUA-TUO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04523649</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Home-Based SolUtion for Remote Atrial Fibrillation Screening to PrevenT RecUrrence StrOke (HUA-TUO AF Trial)</brief_title>
  <acronym>HUA-TUO</acronym>
  <official_title>Protocol for Rationale and Design of Home-Based SolUtion for Remote Atrial Fibrillation Screening to PrevenT RecUrrence StrOke (HUA-TUO AF Trial): A Randomized Open-label Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Hong Kong</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Hong Kong</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Stroke remains the leading cause of mortality and morbidity worldwide. Patients surviving the&#xD;
      first ever stroke remain at high risk of stroke recurrence. While the cause of stroke&#xD;
      recurrence is multifactional, atrial fibrillation (AF) has been recognized as one of the most&#xD;
      important factors for stroke recurrence. Despite the fact that AF related stroke is highly&#xD;
      preventable with long-term oral anticoagulation therapy particularly the non-vitamin K oral&#xD;
      anticoagulants (NOAC), the arrhythmia is often not diagnosed until stroke recurrence due to&#xD;
      its paroxysmal and asymptomatic nature.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diagnosing AF before stroke recurrence has been recognized as one of the most important&#xD;
      objectives for stroke management. Strategies to detection AF in stroke survivors have been&#xD;
      recommended including 7-day or 14-day Holter monitoring at the early post-stroke period.&#xD;
      There's also study trial exploring the clinical application of insertable cardiac monitor to&#xD;
      detect AF in patients with recent cryptogenic stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the past decade, advance in ECG technology has made possible to record ECG using handheld&#xD;
      smartphone accessory devices in household setting. Together with the rapid developing&#xD;
      artificial intelligence-based ECG diagnosis and mobile communication, it is possible to&#xD;
      remotely monitor hundreds of thousand ECGs from patients at risk of AF. Few randomized trials&#xD;
      have assessed the effectiveness of handheld ECG recording device for AF detection in patients&#xD;
      with history of stroke. Here we test the hypothesis that long-term home-based ECG monitoring&#xD;
      will be more sensitive than standard care in detecting AF in patients with history of stroke&#xD;
      but no documented AF for 24 months. Secondarily, we will investigate whether early detection&#xD;
      of AF might confer a benefit on longer-term clinical outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The trial will primarily be conducted in Hong Kong SAR, Macau SAR, and mainland China. It is&#xD;
      a prospective, multi-centered, randomized controlled, parallel-group study to compare the&#xD;
      time to detect AF with portable handheld single lead ECG recorder versus conventional care in&#xD;
      patients with history of ischemic stroke without documented AF. Patients will be randomly&#xD;
      assigned in a 1:1 ratio to Home-based AF screening group and Control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The home-based AF screening system comprises (1) a handheld single lead electrocardiogram&#xD;
      (ECG) recorder (Comfit Healthcare Devices Limited, Hong Kong SAR, China), and (2) a&#xD;
      patient-facing smartphone application specially designed for the study. Patients randomized&#xD;
      to the home-based AF group will be instructed to record a 30-second single lead ECG using the&#xD;
      handheld ECG device every morning or when symptomatic. In addition, all study participants&#xD;
      will be instructed to measure and report their blood pressures in the morning and evening&#xD;
      through the patient-facing smartphone application. In addition, all study participants will&#xD;
      be encouraged to input their routine blood tests from the public hospitals through the&#xD;
      smartphone application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All remotely obtained data will be automatically transmitted in real-time through the study&#xD;
      smartphone application to a secured cloud hosting and displayed to display on a web-based&#xD;
      dashboard at the clinicians' offices for review. All ECG recordings will be analyzed using an&#xD;
      artificial intelligence based diagnosed system. When a diagnosis of AF is made with the&#xD;
      system, the patients will be called back for a formal cardiology consultation and standard&#xD;
      12-lead ECG to confirm the diagnosis within 1 week. This will be followed by echocardiogram&#xD;
      and blood tests to determine the possible options of long-term anticoagulation therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Prospective, multi-centered, randomized controlled, parallel-group study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Independent research officers and data staff responsible for data entry will be blinded from randomization assignment.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>First detection of AF</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>First detection of AF by the handheld ECG, defined as an episode of irregular heart rhythm, without detectable P waves, lasting more than 30 seconds</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrent stroke</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Existence of subsequent stroke after joining the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Transient ischemic attack (TIA)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Existence of subsequent TIA after joining the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Initiation of long-term anticoagulation therapy</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Initiation of long-term anticoagulation therapy after joining the study for any medical purposes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization of heart failure</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>First hospitalization of heart failure after joining the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cardiovascular death</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Death due to cardiovascular reasons after joining the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause death</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Death due to all causes after joining the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1740</enrollment>
  <condition>Stroke, Cardiovascular</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Home-based atrial fibrillation screening group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients in this group will be given a handheld single lead ECG recorder (Comfit Healthcare Devices Limited, Hong Kong SAR, China) and a patient-facing smartphone application specially designed for the study, and they will be requested to record daily ECG and certain vital measurement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Conventional medical care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Remote atrial fibrillation screening with handheld single lead ECG recorder</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in this group will be given a handheld single lead ECG recorder (Comfit Healthcare Devices Limited, Hong Kong SAR, China) and a patient-facing smartphone application specially designed for the study, and they will be requested to record daily ECG and certain vital measurement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Home-based atrial fibrillation screening group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt;= 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of ischemic stroke within 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  voluntarily agrees to participate by providing written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previously documented AF and/or atrial flutter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  long-term anticoagulation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  short life expectance (&lt; 1year) due to concomitant medical condition(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  cardiac implantable electronic device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  inability or refusal to provide inform consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of skills in operating simple electronic devices&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  unavailability of a mobile network service in the place of residence&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chung-Wah David Siu, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The University of Hong Kong</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chung-Wah David SIU, Prof</last_name>
    <phone>+852-2255-4694</phone>
    <email>cwdsiu@hku.hk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 19, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 19, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 19, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Atrial Fibrillation</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

