<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04528030</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CRR-WAVE-122-CIP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04528030</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A UK Interventional Trial in Premature Infants With Apnea of Prematurity Using a Simple, Non-invasive Vibratory Device to Study the Effectiveness in Supporting Breathing and General Stability</brief_title>
  <acronym>WAVE</acronym>
  <official_title>WAVE Trial in Premature Infants With Apnea of Prematurity Using a Simple, Non-invasive Vibratory Device to Study the Effectiveness in Supporting Breathing and General Stability</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Inspiration Healthcare</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Brighton and Sussex University Hospitals NHS Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Inspiration Healthcare</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Purpose of Study: Apnoea of Prematurity (AOP) is common, affecting the majority of infants&#xD;
      born &lt;34 weeks gestational age (GA). Apnea is accompanied by intermittent hypoxia (IH), which&#xD;
      contributes to multiple pathologies, including retinopathy of prematurity (ROP), sympathetic&#xD;
      ganglia injury, impaired pancreatic islet cell and bone development, and neurodevelopmental&#xD;
      disabilities. Standard of care for AOP/IH includes prone positioning, positive pressure&#xD;
      ventilation, and caffeine therapy. The objective of this device is to provide an adjunct to&#xD;
      current AoP treatment to support breathing in premature infants by using a simple,&#xD;
      non-invasive vibratory device placed over limb proprioceptor fibers, an intervention using&#xD;
      the principle that limb movements facilitate breathing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods Used: Premature infants (27+6 - 34+6 weeks GA) with clinical confirmed weeks with&#xD;
      diagnosis of Apnoea of Prematurity. Caffeine therapy was not a reason for exclusion. Small&#xD;
      vibration devices were placed on one hand and one foot and activated in a 6 hour ON/OFF&#xD;
      sequence for a total of 24 hours. Heart rate, respiratory rate, oxygen saturation (SpO2), and&#xD;
      breathing pauses were continuously collected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aim: To study the effect of (WAVE Device) limb proprioceptive stimulation using a vibratory&#xD;
      device on AoP events, intermittent hypoxic episodes (SpO2≤85%) and bradycardias(≤100bpm) in a&#xD;
      premature infant with confirmed clinical diagnosis of apnea of prematurity (AoP).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of the WAVE device is to provide an adjunct to current care to provide support&#xD;
      in apnea of prematurity (AOP). Recurrent apnea and accompanying resultant intermittent&#xD;
      hypoxic (IH) episodes are significant concerns commonly encountered in premature infants, and&#xD;
      optimal management is a challenge to neonatologists. AoP is defined as &gt;20s breathing pause&#xD;
      OR breathing pause of 10-20sec with clinical signs of Bradycardia (≤100bpm) and/or&#xD;
      desaturation (≤85% SpO2) in infants born less than 37 weeks of gestation. When these pauses&#xD;
      are longer (&gt; 20s), they are frequently prolonged by obstructed inspiratory efforts, most&#xD;
      likely secondary to loss of upper airway tonic activity. In extremely low birth weight (ELBW)&#xD;
      infants, the incidence of IH progressively increases over the first 4 weeks of postnatal&#xD;
      life, followed by a plateau and subsequent decline between 6-8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The incidence of AOP correlates inversely with gestational age and birth weight. Nearly all&#xD;
      infants born &lt;29 weeks gestation or &lt;1,000 g, 54% at 30 to 31 weeks, 15% at 32 to 33 weeks,&#xD;
      and 7% at 34 to 35 weeks gestation exhibit AOP (2). Both animal and human evidence show that&#xD;
      immature or impaired respiratory control and the resultant IH exposure contribute to a&#xD;
      variety of pathophysiologic issues via pro-inflammatory and/or pro-oxidant cascade as well as&#xD;
      cellular mechanisms, e.g., apoptosis, leading to acute and chronic morbidities (e.g.&#xD;
      retinopathy of prematurity, altered growth and cardiovascular regulation, disrupting zinc&#xD;
      homeostasis which hampers insulin production and there by predisposing to diabetes in later&#xD;
      life, cerebellar injuries and neurodevelopmental disabilities).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current standard of care for AOP includes prone positioning, continuous positive airway&#xD;
      pressure (CPAP) or nasal intermittent positive pressure ventilation (NIPPV) to prevent&#xD;
      pharyngeal collapse and alveolar atelectasis, and methylxanthine therapy (caffeine,&#xD;
      theophylline), which is the mainstay of treatment of central apnea. Apart from prone&#xD;
      positioning, none of these interventions are optimal for early development. CPAP masks will&#xD;
      distort the bony facial structure in early development, and methylxanthine interventions pose&#xD;
      serious questions of neural development interactions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Sequential Assignment&#xD;
In the same subject there were 2 periods:&#xD;
OFF cycles (6 hours x 2): 'No intervention' period (no vibrations) - two 6 hour epochs - total of 12 hours of 'No intervention' ON cycles (6hours x 2). Experimental period (with vibrations) - two 6 hour epochs - total of 12 hours of 'vibration intervention'&#xD;
In the same subjects cardio-respiratory parameters will be continuously monitored through the 24 hour treatment period of 4 cycles- heart rate, respiratory rate and oxygen saturation were compared during the experimental period (vibration) and during the no intervention period (no vibration).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The investigator analyzing the 4 cycles will not know whether it's an ON of OFF cycle during the 24 hour treatment period.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the cumulative burden of AoP with or without WAVE stimulation</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective is to compare the cumulative duration of breathing pauses related to Apnoea of Prematurity (AoP) between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation as adjunct to standard care.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the number of AoP events.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the number of AoP events between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the number of desaturations (SpO2&lt;86%) events</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the number of desaturations (SpO2&lt;86%) events between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the cumulative depth of desaturations.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the cumulative depth of desaturations (SpO2&lt;86%) between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the cumulative duration of desaturations (SpO2&lt;86%) events.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the cumulative duration of desaturations (SpO2&lt;86%) between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the number of bradycardia events.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the number of bradycardia events between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the cumulative depth of bradycardia events.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the cumulative depth of bradycardia events between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the cumulative duration of bradycardia events.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the cumulative duration of bradycardia events between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nursing assessment scores -NPASS scoring system (6).</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>To compare NPASS scores (6) between periods of presence and absence of tactile vibratory device stimulation adjunct to standard of care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Post trial feedback</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>To conduct post-trial surveys to gather feedback from bedside nurses and parents/legal guardians.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">17</enrollment>
  <condition>Apnea of Newborn</condition>
  <condition>Hypoxia Neonatal</condition>
  <condition>Bradycardia Neonatal</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment starting with an on ON cycle</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The treatment will start ON cycle for 6 hours, followed by OFF cycle for 6 hours, followed by OFF cycle for 6 hours and finished with ON cycle for 6 hours.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment starting with an on OFF cycle</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>The treatment will start OFF cycle for 6 hours, followed by ON cycle for 6 hours, followed by OFF cycle for 6 hours and finished with ON cycle for 6 hours.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>WAVE device</intervention_name>
    <description>WAVE applies a transcutaneous vibration to the soles of the foot and palms of the hand to elicit nerve signalling from pressure and other limb proprioceptor sensors to pontine, cerebellar, and medullary brain areas that coordinate limb movement and reflexively activate brain areas controlling breathing. The WAVE device is a battery-operated product to reduce the episodes of Apnoea of Prematurity by vibratory stimulation to the hand and foot.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment starting with an on OFF cycle</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment starting with an on ON cycle</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>limb proprioceptive stimulation</other_name>
    <other_name>kinesthetic stimulation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gestational age &gt; 27+6weeks, &lt; 34+1 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of apnoea of prematurity (AOP) on clinical observations (atleast 4 AoP&#xD;
             episodes and atleast one ABD event (equal and less 85% SpO2)- define clearly).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Caffeine treatment will not be an exclusion. If babies are on caffeine they need on&#xD;
             maintenance dose for atleats 48 hours. (72hours after first dose of caffeine (Infant&#xD;
             must be on maintenance dose)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  During screening baby must demonstrate &gt;4 AoP/1 ABD events&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum 48 hours after extubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inotropes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants with major congenital anomalies/malformations which will influence central&#xD;
             nervous system and long-term outcomes in these infants, such as cardiac anomalies&#xD;
             (except for Patent Ductus Arteriosus or Ventricular Septal Defect) or major&#xD;
             neurological malformations, like meningoencephalocele, holoprosencephaly&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neonates who have apnoea from airway issues like laryngomalacia or tracheomalacia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neonates with a history of hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy or Grade IV&#xD;
             intraventricular haemorrhage&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infants that are currently intubated and invasive ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Congenital skin malformations, skin conditions due to recurrent illness&#xD;
             (microcirculation concerns).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients being treated for sepsis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>28 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Weeks</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Oana Dr Anton, MBBS MRCPCH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brighton and Sussex University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jacqueline van Druten, BScMedHons</last_name>
    <phone>07407614698</phone>
    <email>jacqueline.vandruten@inspiration-healthcare.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>R, A</last_name>
    <email>CRR-WAVE@inspiration-healthcare.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.inspiration-healthcare.com</url>
    <description>Sponsor website</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kesavan K, Frank P, Cordero DM, Benharash P, Harper RM. Neuromodulation of Limb Proprioceptive Afferents Decreases Apnea of Prematurity and Accompanying Intermittent Hypoxia and Bradycardia. PLoS One. 2016 Jun 15;11(6):e0157349. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0157349. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>27304988</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martin RJ, Di Fiore JM, Macfarlane PM, Wilson CG. Physiologic basis for intermittent hypoxic episodes in preterm infants. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2012;758:351-8. doi: 10.1007/978-94-007-4584-1_47. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23080182</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>te Pas AB, Davis PG, Kamlin CO, Dawson J, O'Donnell CP, Morley CJ. Spontaneous breathing patterns of very preterm infants treated with continuous positive airway pressure at birth. Pediatr Res. 2008 Sep;64(3):281-5. doi: 10.1203/PDR.0b013e31817d9c35.</citation>
    <PMID>18458652</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Robertson CM, Watt MJ, Dinu IA. Outcomes for the extremely premature infant: what is new? And where are we going? Pediatr Neurol. 2009 Mar;40(3):189-96. doi: 10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2008.09.017. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19218032</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Henderson-Smart DJ, Steer PA. Caffeine versus theophylline for apnea in preterm infants. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2010 Jan 20;(1):CD000273. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD000273.pub2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20091506</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sweet DG, Carnielli V, Greisen G, Hallman M, Ozek E, Te Pas A, Plavka R, Roehr CC, Saugstad OD, Simeoni U, Speer CP, Vento M, Visser GHA, Halliday HL. European Consensus Guidelines on the Management of Respiratory Distress Syndrome - 2019 Update. Neonatology. 2019;115(4):432-450. doi: 10.1159/000499361. Epub 2019 Apr 11.</citation>
    <PMID>30974433</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hummel P, Puchalski M, Creech SD, Weiss MG. Clinical reliability and validity of the N-PASS: neonatal pain, agitation and sedation scale with prolonged pain. J Perinatol. 2008 Jan;28(1):55-60. doi: 10.1038/sj.jp.7211861. Epub 2007 Oct 25.</citation>
    <PMID>18165830</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Randerath W, Verbraecken J, Andreas S, Arzt M, Bloch KE, Brack T, Buyse B, De Backer W, Eckert DJ, Grote L, Hagmeyer L, Hedner J, Jennum P, La Rovere MT, Miltz C, McNicholas WT, Montserrat J, Naughton M, Pepin JL, Pevernagie D, Sanner B, Testelmans D, Tonia T, Vrijsen B, Wijkstra P, Levy P. Definition, discrimination, diagnosis and treatment of central breathing disturbances during sleep. Eur Respir J. 2017 Jan 18;49(1). pii: 1600959. doi: 10.1183/13993003.00959-2016. Print 2017 Jan.</citation>
    <PMID>27920092</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shevtsova NA, Marchenko V, Bezdudnaya T. Modulation of Respiratory System by Limb Muscle Afferents in Intact and Injured Spinal Cord. Front Neurosci. 2019 Mar 26;13:289. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2019.00289. eCollection 2019. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30971888</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Potts JT, Rybak IA, Paton JF. Respiratory rhythm entrainment by somatic afferent stimulation. J Neurosci. 2005 Feb 23;25(8):1965-78.</citation>
    <PMID>15728836</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dekker J, Martherus T, Cramer SJE, van Zanten HA, Hooper SB, Te Pas AB. Tactile Stimulation to Stimulate Spontaneous Breathing during Stabilization of Preterm Infants at Birth: A Retrospective Analysis. Front Pediatr. 2017 Apr 3;5:61. doi: 10.3389/fped.2017.00061. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>28421171</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Solkoff N, Matuszak D. Tactile stimulation and behavioral development among low-birthweight infants. Child Psychiatry Hum Dev. 1975 Fall;6(1):33-7.</citation>
    <PMID>1238237</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lovell JR, Eisenfeld L, Rosow E, Adam J, Lapin C, Bronzino JD. Vibrotactile stimulation for treatment of neonatal apnea: a preliminary study. Conn Med. 1999 Jun;63(6):323-5.</citation>
    <PMID>10432764</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pichardo R, Adam JS, Rosow E, Bronzino J, Eisenfeld L. Vibrotactile stimulation system to treat apnea of prematurity. Biomed Instrum Technol. 2003 Jan-Feb;37(1):34-40.</citation>
    <PMID>12613292</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pietravalle A, Cavallin F, Opocher A, Madella S, Cavicchiolo ME, Pizzol D, Putoto G, Trevisanuto D. Neonatal tactile stimulation at birth in a low-resource setting. BMC Pediatr. 2018 Sep 20;18(1):306. doi: 10.1186/s12887-018-1279-4.</citation>
    <PMID>30236090</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Frank UA, Bordiuk JM, Borromeo-McGrail V, Saltzman MB, Keitel HG. Treatment of apnea in neonates with an automated monitor-actuated apnea arrestor. Pediatrics. 1973 May;51(5):878-83.</citation>
    <PMID>4703399</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cramer SJE, Dekker J, Dankelman J, Pauws SC, Hooper SB, Te Pas AB. Effect of Tactile Stimulation on Termination and Prevention of Apnea of Prematurity: A Systematic Review. Front Pediatr. 2018 Mar 2;6:45. doi: 10.3389/fped.2018.00045. eCollection 2018.</citation>
    <PMID>29552548</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 22, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>cardio-respiratory stability</keyword>
  <keyword>neonate</keyword>
  <keyword>premature infant</keyword>
  <keyword>proprioceptive stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Apnoea of Prematurity</keyword>
  <keyword>Medical Device</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Premature Birth</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bradycardia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypoxia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Publication and conference presentation of results planned</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

