<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03190954</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>170114</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>17-AA-0114</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03190954</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Brain Dopaminergic Signaling in Opioid Use Disorders</brief_title>
  <official_title>Brain Dopaminergic Signaling in Opioid Use Disorders (OUD)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The chemical messenger dopamine carries signals between brain cells. It may affect addiction.&#xD;
      Heavy use of pain medicines called opioids may decrease the amount of dopamine available to&#xD;
      the brain. Researchers want to study if decreased dopamine decreases self-control and&#xD;
      increases impulsiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn more about how opiate use disorder affects dopamine in the brain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults 18-80 years old who are moderate or severe opiate users&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy volunteers the same age&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will first be screened under another protocol. They will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a physical exam&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Answer questions about their medical, psychiatric, and alcohol and drug use history&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Take an MRI screening questionnaire&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Give blood and urine samples&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have their breath tested for alcohol&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have up to 3 study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      They will have 2-3 positron emission tomography (PET) scans. A radioactive chemical will be&#xD;
      injected for the scans. Participants will lie on a bed that slides in and out of the&#xD;
      donut-shaped scanner. A cap or plastic mask may be placed on the head.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vital signs will be taken before and after the PET scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will get capsules of placebo or the study drug. They will rate how they feel&#xD;
      before, during and after.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have their breath and urine tested each day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scans. They will lie on a table that&#xD;
      slides into a cylinder in a strong magnetic field. They may do tasks on a computer screen&#xD;
      while inside the scanner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have tests of memory, attention, and thinking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will wear an activity monitor for one week....&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives: Primary objective is to assess whether the balance between dopamine D1 (D1R) and&#xD;
      D2 receptors (D2R) signaling in striatum is disrupted in participants with an opioid use&#xD;
      disorder (OUD) who are on opioid agonist medication (MAT+: methadone or buprenorphine)&#xD;
      relative to OUD participants treated with the opioid antagonist medication naltrexone and OUD&#xD;
      participants not being treated with medications (MAT-). Secondary objectives are to assess&#xD;
      how striatal D1R to D2R availability (assessed with PET) influences: (1) striatal dopamine&#xD;
      (DA) release; (2) the function of brain reward and self-control networks (assessed with task&#xD;
      fMRI activation and with resting functional connectivity, RFC) and (3) behavior (locomotor&#xD;
      activity and neuropsychological tests); (4) to assess if DA increases, as induced by oral&#xD;
      methylphenidate (MP), improve the function of brain reward and control networks in OUD; and&#xD;
      (5) to assess if there is recovery after protracted treatment (comparing treated and&#xD;
      non-treated) by repeating fMRI at 6 month follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: We will complete studies in 150 (n=150) subjects: N=60 healthy control&#xD;
      adults and N=90 OUD participants (30 MAT+, 30 naltrexone-treated and 30 MAT-) aged 18-65&#xD;
      (male/female) will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: Single-blind. Participants will undergo three scans with positron emission tomography&#xD;
      (PET): one with [11C]NNC-112 to assess baseline D1R, another with [11C]raclopride after&#xD;
      placebo to assess baseline D2R and a third one with [11C]raclopride after MP administration&#xD;
      (60mg oral) to assess striatal DA release (assessed as the difference in specific binding of&#xD;
      [11C]raclopride between baseline and MP). In addition, participants will undergo two imaging&#xD;
      sessions with MRI to assess functional reactivity to drug-cues and to a measure of&#xD;
      self-control (delayed discounting task), to assess RFC and to obtain structural brain&#xD;
      measures (including diffusion tensor imaging, DTI). One of the sessions will be done under&#xD;
      baseline conditions (no drug administered) and the other after MP (about one hour after the&#xD;
      [11C]raclopride MP scan is completed). Neuropsychological tests (NP) and accelerometers will&#xD;
      be used to assess cognitive performance and locomotor activity respectively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures: Main outcome: (1) Differences in D1R to D2R striatal ratio between&#xD;
      participants with an OUD and controls and between MAT+, naltrexone, and MAT- groups.&#xD;
      Secondary outcomes: Correlations between striatal D1R to D2R and (1) striatal DA release; (2)&#xD;
      fMRI activation in reward and controls networks (assessed with cue-reactivity and delay&#xD;
      discounting tasks, and with RFC) and (3) NP performance and locomotor activity. (4)&#xD;
      Differences in fMRI activation and RFC after MP when compared with baseline measures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences in D1R to D2R striatal ratio and in DA release between participants with an OUD and controls and between MAT+, naltrexone, and MAT- groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether the balance between D1R and D2R in striatum and in DA release is disrupted in participants with an opioid use disorder (OUD) who are being treated with an opioid agonist medication (MAT+), those treated with an opioid antagonist medication (naltrexone) and OUD participants who are not being treated with medications (MAT-).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3) To assess if there is recovery after protracted treatment (comparing treated and non-treated) by repeating fMRI at 6 month follow-up.</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study</time_frame>
    <description>Determine if the brain recovers with protracted abstinence as assessed by recovery of resting brain networks and brain activation responses to stimulation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>2) To assess if DA increases as achieved with oral MP influence the brain functional measures.</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study</time_frame>
    <description>Assess the association between striatal D1R to D2R availability and striatal DA release. Assess how D1R and D2R relate to behavior (locomotor activity and NP performance).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1) To assess the impact of disruptions on striatal D1R to D2R availability on: DA release; Function of brain reward and control networks; Behavior.2) To assess if DA increases as achieved with oral MP influence the brain functional measure...</measure>
    <time_frame>End of study</time_frame>
    <description>DA release (assessed with [11C]raclopride and the MP challenge strategy). Function of brain reward and control networks (assessed with fMRI with task activation and with RFC). Behavior (assessed with NP and actigraphy).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Normal Physiology</condition>
  <condition>Opiod Use Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]NNC-112</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>[11C]NNC-112 PET scan obtained without any drug intervention to measure dopamine D1 receptors. Blind N /A</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]raclopride plus drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Methylphenidate 60 mg. po will be given 60 minutes prior to [11C]raclopride scan to measure striatal dopamine release. MRI scan to follow end of PET scan. Subject blind as to drug administration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]raclopride plus placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo (po) will be given 60 minutes prior to [11C] raclopride scan to measure baseline dopamine D2 receptors. MRI scan to follow end of PET scan. Subject blind as to drug administration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[11C]raclopride plus placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo (po) will be given 60 minutes prior to [11C]raclopride scan to measure baseline dopamine D2 receptors. MRI scan to follow end of PET scan. Subject blind as to drug administration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]raclopride plus placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[11C]raclopride plus drug</intervention_name>
    <description>Methylphenidate 60 mg. po will be given 60 minutes prior to [11C]raclopride scan to measure striatal dopamine release. MRI scan to follow end of PET scan. Subject blind as to drug administration.</description>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]raclopride plus drug</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>[11C]NNC-112</intervention_name>
    <description>[11C]NNC-112 PET scan obtained without any drug intervention to measure dopamine D1 receptors. Blind N/A</description>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]NNC-112</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]raclopride plus drug</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>[11C]raclopride plus placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Healthy Volunteer Participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or females between 18 and 65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        MAT- Opiate Use Disorder (OUD) Participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or females between 18 and 65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. DSM-5 diagnosis of a moderate or severe OUD (established through history and clinical&#xD;
             exam).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active abuse of opiates (last use within one week of study as assessed by&#xD;
             self-reports).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Minimum 3 year history of opiate abuse - self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Must consume opiates at least 5 days per week as per self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Currently not receiving medications for OUD (methadone, buprenorphine or naltrexone).&#xD;
&#xD;
        MAT+ OUD Participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or females between 18 and 80 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. DSM-5 diagnosis of a moderate or severe OUD (established through history and clinical&#xD;
             exam).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active or non-active abuse of opiates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Minimum 3 year history of opiate abuse as per self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Must have consumed at least 5 days per week (prior opiate use) as per self report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Receiving opioid agonist therapy for OUD (e.g., methadone or buprenorphine) and must&#xD;
             have taken for at least one week before imaging study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Naltrexone OUD Participants&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Males or females between 18 and 65 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability to provide written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. DSM-5 diagnosis of a moderate or severe OUD (established through history and clinical&#xD;
             exam).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active or non-active abuse of opiates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Minimum 3 year history of opiate abuse as per self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Must have consumed at least 5 days per week (prior opiate use) as per self- report.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Receiving naltrexone treatment for their OUD and must have taken at least one week&#xD;
             before imaging study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For all groups of subjects regarding inclusion #1: OUD and HV subjects who are age 66-80&#xD;
        may be included in this study except they will not receive the methylphenidate and&#xD;
        subsequent PET and MRI scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All Subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Current DSM-5 diagnosis of a psychiatric disorder (other than OUD or severe&#xD;
                  alcohol/substance use disorders in OUD participants and nicotine/caffeine use in&#xD;
                  all participants) that requires/required daily psychoactive medications&#xD;
                  (antidepressant, antipsychotics, stimulants, benzodiazepines or barbiturates) in&#xD;
                  the past two months and that could impact brain function at the time of the study&#xD;
                  as determined by history and clinical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. The following current chronically used (2 months) medications are exclusionary:&#xD;
                  stimulant or stimulant-like medications (amphetamine, methylphenidate,&#xD;
                  modafinil); opioid analgesics (for controls only); antianginal agents;&#xD;
                  antiarrhythmics; systemic corticosteroids; anticholinergics; anticoagulants;&#xD;
                  anticonvulsants; antidepressants; antihistamines (sedating); beta-blocker&#xD;
                  antihypertensives; antineoplastics; antiobesity; antipsychotics; anxiolytics&#xD;
                  (benzodiazepine or barbiturates); lithium; muscle relaxants; psychotropic drugs&#xD;
                  not otherwise specified (nos); sedatives/hypnotics, systemic steroids. Note that&#xD;
                  nicotine and/or caffeine is not exclusionary and that opiate drugs will not&#xD;
                  exclude participants with OUD. Subjects on stable antihypertensive medications&#xD;
                  (except for beta blockers) may be included provided they are clinically stable&#xD;
                  dose for at least a month [BP less than or equal to 140/90]. OUD subjects who&#xD;
                  have hypertension may still be included in this study except they will not&#xD;
                  receive the methylphenidate and subsequent PET and MRI scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Current continuous treatment (&gt; 3 weeks) with methadone, buprenorphine or&#xD;
                  naltrexone for controls or MAT- OUD participants; or naltrexone for MAT+ OUD&#xD;
                  participants; or agonist treatment (methadone or buprenorphine) for OUD&#xD;
                  participants treated with Naltrexone.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Current major medical problems that can permanently impact brain function (e.g.,&#xD;
                  CNS: including seizures, psychosis, stroke, severe depression, Alzheimer s,&#xD;
                  Parkinson s disease, Traumatic brain injury; Cardiovascular: including&#xD;
                  uncontrolled hypertension [BP &gt; 140/90] and clinically significant arrhythmias&#xD;
                  except bradycardia; and HIV+) as determined by history. However, OUD subjects who&#xD;
                  have hypertension and/or certain EKG findings results may still be included in&#xD;
                  this study except they will not receive the methylphenidate and subsequent PET&#xD;
                  and/or MRI scans.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Clinically significant laboratory findings that could impact brain function or&#xD;
                  study procedures (e.g., active infections, arrhythmias, hepatic or renal failure)&#xD;
                  will be exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Have had previous radiation exposure (from X-rays, PET scans, or other exposure)&#xD;
                  that, with the exposure from this study, would exceed NIH annual research limits&#xD;
                  as determined by medical history and physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Head trauma with loss of consciousness for more than 30 minutes as determined by&#xD;
                  medical history and physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Pregnant and/or currently breast-feeding. Females of childbearing potential (age&#xD;
                  60 or less) will undergo a urine pregnancy test that must be negative to&#xD;
                  participate. Urine pregnancy tests will be repeated on subsequent days of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Presence of ferromagnetic objects in the body that are contraindicated for MRI&#xD;
                  (pacemakers or other implanted electrical devices, brain stimulators, some types&#xD;
                  of dental implants, aneurysm clips, metallic prostheses, permanent eyeliner,&#xD;
                  implanted delivery pump, or shrapnel fragments) or fear of enclosed spaces -&#xD;
                  self-report checklist. However, OUD subjects who are contraindicated for MRI&#xD;
                  participation, or the study team cannot access prior surgical records to confirm&#xD;
                  that a subject is cleared for MRI, may still participate in all aspects of the&#xD;
                  study except MRI. If it is discovered during the clinical brain MRI or after&#xD;
                  enrollment onto the study that the subject experiences anxiety or becomes&#xD;
                  claustrophobic, we will discontinue the MRI portion of the study and he/she can&#xD;
                  continue to participate in all other aspects of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Personal or family history (parents or siblings) for cerebral aneurysm.&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Past or present history of chest pain and trouble breathing with activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Glaucoma as assessed by medical history.&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Cannot lie comfortably flat on their backs for up to 2 hours in the PET and MRI&#xD;
                  scanners self-report.&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Weight &gt; 400 pounds, which is the maximum weight the PET scanner can hold.&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. Study investigators and staff, as well as their superiors, subordinates and&#xD;
                  immediate family members (adult children, spouses, parents, siblings).&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Additional exclusion criteria for MAT+ / MAT- / Naltrexone OUD participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Participation in a court ordered residential treatment program.&#xD;
&#xD;
                  Additional exclusion criteria for MAT- OUD participants only:&#xD;
&#xD;
              17. Currently seeking treatment for OUD, for the MAT- group.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note that subjects will not be excluded from enrollment onto this study if their urine test&#xD;
        is positive for drugs on initial screening. The following guidelines will be followed for&#xD;
        positive drug screens on study procedure days:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If a Healthy Volunteer subject s urine drug screen test is positive on days involving&#xD;
             imaging (MRI and/or PET) and NP testing, the procedures will be postponed and&#xD;
             rescheduled. We will allow for up to 3 rescheduled study days resulting from positive&#xD;
             urine drug screens. If urine drug screen is positive for THC-COOH, a saliva drug&#xD;
             screen will be performed and subject may proceed with study day testing procedures if&#xD;
             saliva results for THC are negative. If the urine/saliva drug test is positive on the&#xD;
             third rescheduled visit, the participant will be withdrawn from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If an OUD subject s urine drug screen test is positive for drugs (other than opiates),&#xD;
             the procedures will not be postponed. If urine drug screen is positive for THC-COOH, a&#xD;
             saliva drug screen will be performed to verify if THC is present. Positive results for&#xD;
             drugs other than opiates will be considered at the time of data analysis as a&#xD;
             co-variate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Also, note that at any time during participation in this study if any subject expresses&#xD;
        that he/she wants to get treatment for their OUD, we will immediately refer him/her to a&#xD;
        treatment program. The subject will be withdrawn from the study at that time. No&#xD;
        medications will be stopped or held for participation in this protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gene-Jack Wang, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism (NIAAA)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Gene-Jack Wang, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-5012</phone>
    <email>gene-jack.wang@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2017-AA-0114.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 27, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 16, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 16, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 19, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Raclopride</keyword>
  <keyword>NNC-112</keyword>
  <keyword>Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI)</keyword>
  <keyword>Dopamine D1 Receptor</keyword>
  <keyword>D2 Receptors</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Raclopride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

