<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03197623</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20161825</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>LLP2A-001</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03197623</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Tolerability of Intravenous LLP2A-Alendronate for Osteopenia Secondary to Glucocorticoids</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Single and Multiple Ascending Dose Study of the Safety and Tolerability of Intravenous LLP2A-Alendronate in Adult Men and Women With Osteopenia Secondary to Glucocorticoids</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nancy E. Lane, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>California Institute for Regenerative Medicine (CIRM)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Davis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Phase 1 Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Single and Multiple Ascending Dose&#xD;
      Study of the Safety and Tolerability of Intravenous LLP2A-Alendronate in Adult Men and Women&#xD;
      with Osteopenia Secondary to Corticosteroids&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed to evaluate safety and tolerability of LLP2A-Ale beginning with a&#xD;
      single ascending dose (SAD) cohort followed by multiple ascending dose (MAD) cohorts with&#xD;
      matching placebo in each cohort. The population in this study includes patients with low bone&#xD;
      density (osteopenia with a T score ≤ -1.0) in the femoral neck, total hip or lumbosacral&#xD;
      spine who are taking Corticosteroids. Up to 59 patients will be enrolled, 32 in the SAD and&#xD;
      27 in the MAD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      LLP2A-Ale is a novel anabolic agent. It appears that LLP2A-Ale may have utility in a variety&#xD;
      of conditions where new bone formation is required. Non-traumatic osteonecrosis (ON) has been&#xD;
      selected as the first indication for LLP2A-Ale because of the high unmet need, absence of&#xD;
      treatments besides surgical joint replacement, and the clear need to attract and stimulate&#xD;
      differentiation of stem cells into the region of necrotic bone. However, osteonecrosis is a&#xD;
      rare, sporadic disease. Therefore, the Phase 1 study is being performed in people at risk for&#xD;
      osteonecrosis, as a population representative of people with osteonecrosis, who will be the&#xD;
      participants in any subsequent Phase 2 and 3 studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-traumatic ON may also be caused by a variety of underlying medical conditions.&#xD;
      Glucocorticoid use, alcohol, and smoking contribute to up to 80% of cases of nontraumatic ON.&#xD;
      The relationship to GC is the strongest in people receiving relatively long term therapy,&#xD;
      with risk increasing with cumulative exposure over three or more months. Vasculitis from&#xD;
      autoimmune diseases predisposes to ON and ON is particularly associated with Systemic Lupus&#xD;
      Erythematous (SLE), possibly due to coexistence of vasculitis and chronic GC treatment. In&#xD;
      different series, symptomatic ON is reported in about 5-30% of SLE patients. Because many&#xD;
      foci of ON are asymptomatic, rates based on MRI surveillance are higher, in the range of 30 -&#xD;
      50%, and often are multifocal. Because of the particularly high incidence of ON in SLE we&#xD;
      anticipate that SLE patients will be a significant component of the population in later&#xD;
      trials. Therefore investigators in this Phase 1 trial include rheumatologists in order to&#xD;
      increase the likelihood of inclusion of lupus patients in this first study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 14, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled Single and Multiple Ascending Dose Study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose limiting Adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the Study, average of 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of dose limiting or intolerable treatment related adverse events (AEs) including A serious drug-related adverse event in ≥ 1 subject receiving LLP2A-Ale and/or Severe drug related adverse events in ≥ 2 subjects receiving LLP2A-Ale</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Severe infusion reactions</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the study, average of 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Fever, myalgia, nausea/vomit, headache, flu like symptoms in ≥ 2 subjects receiving LLP2A-Ale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Grade 2 elevated creatinine</measure>
    <time_frame>Duration of the study, average of 4 years</time_frame>
    <description>serum creatinine greater than 1.5 - 3.0 x baseline; greater than 1.5 - 3.0 x upper limit of normal (CTCAE v4.0) in ≥ 1 patient.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">58</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteopenia</condition>
  <condition>Osteoporosis</condition>
  <condition>Osteonecrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>LLP2A-ALENDRONATE</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>50, 150, 400, 750 or 1200 μg/kg or placebo given as a one time intravenous administration over 120 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo given as a one time intravenous administration over 120 minutes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>LLP2A-ALENDRONATE</intervention_name>
    <description>A small molecule, LLP2A-Ale that directs endogenous mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs), the cells that have the potential to grow bone tissue, to the bone surface to form new bone. Single administration of LLP2A-Ale given intravenously over 120 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>LLP2A-ALENDRONATE</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>LLP2A-Ale</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo, one time single administration given intravenously over 120 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects must meet all of the following criteria to be included in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 20 - 85 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Receiving 5 - 40 mg/day prednisone, or equivalent of another GC (methylprednisolone 4&#xD;
             mg/day, or prednisone 10 mg every other day) for a minimum of 4 consecutive weeks&#xD;
             prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Anticipated to continue to receive at least 5 mg/day prednisone or equivalent&#xD;
             throughout study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. T score ≤ -1.0 in the femoral neck or total hip or lumbosacral spine. Only one result&#xD;
             from one of these locations that is ≤ -1.0 is required. For screening DXA, a DXA&#xD;
             completed within 6 months of screening may be used; otherwise DXA must be completed&#xD;
             within 4 weeks of screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Must be ambulatory and able to attend all appointments&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women must agree to use one of the following methods of birth control for the duration&#xD;
             of the clinical trial: systemic hormonal contraceptive (oral, injected, transdermal),&#xD;
             intrauterine device, double barrier (e.g., cervical cap or diaphragm with condom or&#xD;
             spermicide). Men with female partners must agree to use double barrier contraception,&#xD;
             unless their partner is using systemic hormonal contraceptives or has an intrauterine&#xD;
             device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. In the opinion of the investigator, the concurrent medical conditions of the study&#xD;
             subject are stable&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject undergoing PET/CT scans must have the ability to lay motionless for up to&#xD;
             30-45 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Anticipated to continue to receive all chronic medications without dose changes&#xD;
             throughout study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects undergoing PET/CT scans must have the ability to lay motionless for up to&#xD;
             30-45 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who meet any of the following criteria will be excluded from the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Weight greater than the limit of the DXA table at the clinical site&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History or concurrent conditions that might place the subject at increased risk, such&#xD;
             as renal insufficiency (CKD 4 or 5), glomerulonephritis, atypical infections due to&#xD;
             impaired immunity, hypersensitivity to multiple IV medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of or concurrent presence of medical conditions which might interfere with&#xD;
             ability to participate for the duration of the study, such as clinically significant&#xD;
             cardiovascular disease, uncontrollable hypertension, uncontrolled asthma, symptomatic&#xD;
             pulmonary fibrosis, recent GI bleeding requiring transfusion, psychosis, substance&#xD;
             abuse or hospital admission within 6 months of enrollment (except for elective&#xD;
             procedures)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior use or current need for prohibited concomitant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Rheumatic disease with clinically significant renal or central nervous system&#xD;
             involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of deep vein thrombosis (DVT) along with taking any prophylaxis/treatment that&#xD;
             occurred within the last 5 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of clinically significant atrial fibrillation and/or taking medications for&#xD;
             its treatment and prevention&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Unable or unwilling to comply with restrictions on alcohol 9. Previous&#xD;
             hypersensitivity to alendronate&#xD;
&#xD;
        10. Any of the following on Screening laboratory tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Total calcium values outside the normal range (corrected if albumin &lt; lower limit of&#xD;
             normal (LLN))&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Phosphate level &lt; LLN&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. 25-hydroxyvitamin D (25-OH Vitamin D) below 10ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. TSH &gt; upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Hepatic enzymes (ALT, AST, GGT) &gt; 1.5 X ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Creatinine clearance (eGRF) &lt;35 mL/min/1.73 m2 using the Modification of Diet in Renal&#xD;
             Disease (MDRD) formula&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Hemoglobin &lt;10 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Positive serology for HIV, Hepatitis B or C&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Positive pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Prolonged QTc interval (QTcF (Fredericia) of &gt; 450 msec for men, &gt; 470 msec for women)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any other clinically significant laboratory value as judged by the investigator 11.&#xD;
             Subject cannot enroll in MAD part of study until after 60 days of completing SAD part&#xD;
             of study 12. Subjects undergoing PET/CT scans must not be breast-feeding 13. History&#xD;
             of hypersensitivity to fluoride&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nancy E Lane, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UC Davis Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nancy E Lane, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>UC Davis Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>West Coast Clinical Trials (WCCT)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cypress</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92626</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diablo Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Walnut Creek</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94598</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Altoona Center for Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duncansville</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>16635</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Metroplex Clinical Research Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75231</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 19, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 21, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Davis</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nancy E. Lane, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Glucocorticoids</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Diseases, Metabolic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteonecrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alendronate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

