<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03197181</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>FPC-17-AGING-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03197181</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Frontopolar Cortex and Motivation in Healthy Older Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>Causal Role of Frontopolar Cortex for Motivation in Healthy Older Adults: a Transcranial Direct Current Stimulation Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Zurich</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Zurich</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Motivation represents a core aspect of goal-directed behavior as it determines how much&#xD;
      effort individuals are willing to invest to reach their goals. While research on effort-based&#xD;
      decision-making focuses mainly on effort preferences in younger adults, loss of motivation&#xD;
      might be a key component of the apathetic tendencies frequently seen in older adults.&#xD;
      However, an open question refers to which brain mechanisms underlie motivational processes in&#xD;
      older adults. The investigators have recently shown that the frontopolar cortex plays a&#xD;
      crucial in motivating the exertion of rewarded effort in younger adults. The goal of the&#xD;
      current study is to determine whether frontopolar cortex plays a crucial role for motivation&#xD;
      also in older adults and may thus be a promising target for improving the motivation deficits&#xD;
      in healthy aging. Participants perform computer-based experimental tasks measuring the&#xD;
      propensity to exert cognitive or physical effort for monetary rewards. During task&#xD;
      performance, participants receive anodal or sham transcranial direct current stimulation&#xD;
      (tDCS) over their frontopolar cortex. The study tests whether tDCS over frontopolar cortex&#xD;
      allows modulating participants' motivation to engage in rewarded effort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Motivation represents a core aspect of goal-directed behavior as it determines how much&#xD;
      effort individuals are willing to invest to reach their goals. While research on effort-based&#xD;
      decision-making focuses mainly on effort preferences in younger adults, loss of motivation&#xD;
      might be a key component of the apathetic tendencies frequently seen in older adults.&#xD;
      However, an open question refers to which brain mechanisms underlie motivational processes in&#xD;
      older adults. The investigators have recently shown that the frontopolar cortex plays a&#xD;
      crucial in motivating the exertion of rewarded effort in younger adults (Soutschek et al.,&#xD;
      2018, Biological Psychiatry). The goal of the current study is to determine whether&#xD;
      frontopolar cortex plays a crucial role for motivation also in older adults and may thus be a&#xD;
      promising target for improving the motivation deficits in healthy aging. 30 older&#xD;
      participants (65-80 years) perform computer-based experimental tasks measuring the propensity&#xD;
      to exert cognitive or physical effort for monetary rewards. During task performance,&#xD;
      participants receive 1 mA anodal or sham transcranial direct current stimulation (tDCS) over&#xD;
      their frontopolar cortex. The study tests whether tDCS over frontopolar cortex allows&#xD;
      modulating participants' motivation to engage in rewarded effort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 16, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>In two separate sessions, participants receive either anodal or sham transcranial direct current stimulation while the participants are performing a decision-making task on the computer.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>The participants are blind to whether the participants receive anodal or sham stimulation in a session.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>participants' decisions to exert cognitive or physical effort for monetary rewards</measure>
    <time_frame>All participants perform this decision-making task in both experimental sessions (i.e., both the anodal and the sham stimulation session) for 20 min while receiving anodal or sham stimulation.</time_frame>
    <description>The project seeks to test the causal role of FPC in discounting of cognitive and physical effort in healthy older adults. For that purpose, participants perform a task on a computer which requires the participants to decide whether the participants are willing to exert cognitive or physical effort for a monetary reward. Participants perform this task both under anodal and under sham stimulation. It is tested whether anodal, relative to sham, stimulation increases participants' willingness to engage in rewarded cognitive or physical effort.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Motivation in Healthy Older Adults</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>anodal transcranial direct current stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>anodal transcranial direct current stimulation (current strength: 1 mA, duration: 20 min) over the frontopolar cortex</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>sham transcranial direct current stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>sham transcranial direct current stimulation (current strength: 1 mA, duration: 0.5 min) over the frontopolar cortex</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>transcranial direct current stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants receive anodal or sham transcranial direct current stimulation while performing effort-based decision tasks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>anodal transcranial direct current stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>sham transcranial direct current stimulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 65-80 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent as documented by signature&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal or corrected-to-normal vision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive and language ability to understand study content and procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal cognitive functioning (assessed by MMST)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BDI-II score &lt; 20&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative response to TMS/tDCS in past&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of seizure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of stroke or heart attack&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of head injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric or neurological disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Metal in body/head&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Implanted medical products like pacemaker, medical pumps, heart catheter&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Headache&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tinnitus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently taking medication affecting the central nervous system&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient sleep in preceding night&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excessive consumption of alcohol within last 24 hours&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Philippe N Tobler, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Zurich</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Zurich</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zürich</city>
        <zip>8006</zip>
        <country>Switzerland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Switzerland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 20, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 21, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

