<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03197467</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0316-ASG</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2016-002170-13</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>MISP 52887</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03197467</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neoadjuvant Anti PD-1 Immunotherapy in Resectable Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>NEOMUN</acronym>
  <official_title>Neoadjuvant Anti PD-1 Immunotherapy in Resectable Non-small Cell Lung Cancer [NEOMUN]</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AIO-Studien-gGmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Merck Sharp &amp; Dohme Corp.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AIO-Studien-gGmbH</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      NEOMUN is designed as an open-label, single arm, prospective, monocenter, phase II study of&#xD;
      pembrolizumab in a neoadjuvant setting in patients with non-small cell lung cancer of Stage&#xD;
      II/IIIA suitable for curative intent surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed as an open-label, single arm, prospective, monocenter, phase II study&#xD;
      of pembrolizumab in a neoadjuvant setting in patients with resectable NSCLC stage II/IIIA&#xD;
      suitable for curative intent surgery, taking place in Germany. Planned sample size is N=30.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigational drug is Pembrolizumab at fixed dose, given 200 mg q3w i.v. for 2 cycles.&#xD;
      After completion of immunotherapy lobectomy/ bilobectomy with curative intent is scheduled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objectives are to assess feasibility and safety of a neoadjuvant application of&#xD;
      pembrolizumab and to assess antitumor activity of pembrolizumab with regard to clinical and&#xD;
      pathologic tumor response. Secondary objective is to assess the impact of neoadjuvant&#xD;
      pembrolizumab on patient disease free and overall survival. Exploratory objective is o&#xD;
      explore potential predictive biomarkers for pembrolizumab efficacy (immune cell imaging).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 18, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>frequency and severity of adverse events including periand post-operative complications</measure>
    <time_frame>46 month</time_frame>
    <description>grade 2-4 AEs according to NCI-CTCAE V4.03</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>number of patients treated in compliance with protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>46 month</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor response evaluation - Clinical response</measure>
    <time_frame>46 month</time_frame>
    <description>response rates (Δ tumor size) according to RECIST 1.1 criteria&#xD;
response rates (Δ lymph node size) according to RECIST 1.1 criteria&#xD;
Δ PET-activity (standardized uptake value [SUV])</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tumor response evaluation - Pathologic response</measure>
    <time_frame>46 month</time_frame>
    <description>Pathologic regression grading according to Junker criteria</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>disease free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>46 month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>46 month</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-small Cell Lung Cancer (NSCLC)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pembrolizumab at fixed dose: 200 mg q3w i.v. for 2 cycles</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pembrolizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Pembrolizumab at fixed dose: 200 mg q3w i.v. for 2 cycles</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pembrolizumab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Cooperation and willingness to complete all aspects of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Signed and dated written informed consent must be given prior to study inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histological or cytological confirmed NSCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Clinical stage II-IIIA according to the TNM classification, 7th edition:&#xD;
&#xD;
             stage IIIa: T1/T2 N2 (IIIa1-3 Robinson classification)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Adequate disease staging by PET/CT and brain MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. At least 1 measurable lesion according to RECIST 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. ECOG performance status 0 - 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Female subjects of childbearing potential must be willing to use an adequate method of&#xD;
             contraception for the course of the study through 120 days after the last dose of&#xD;
             study medication. Note: Abstinence is acceptable if this is the usual lifestyle and&#xD;
             preferred contraception for the subject. Female subject of childbearing potential&#xD;
             should have a negative urine or serum pregnancy within 72 hours prior to receiving the&#xD;
             first dose of study medication. If the urine test is positive or cannot be confirmed&#xD;
             as negative, a serum pregnancy test will be required.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Male subjects of childbearing potential must agree to use an adequate method of&#xD;
             contraception, starting with the first dose of study therapy through 120 days after&#xD;
             the last dose of study therapy. Note: Abstinence is acceptable if this is the usual&#xD;
             lifestyle and preferred contraception for the subject&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Adequate bone marrow function, liver and renal function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Thrombocytes ≥ 100 x 109/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hemoglobin ≥ 9 g/dL without transfusion or EPO dependency (within 7 days of&#xD;
                  assessment)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. INR &lt; 1.4 ULN and PTT &lt; 40 seconds during the last 7 days before therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. AST (GOT) and ALT (GPT) &lt; 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Albumin &gt;2.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Serum creatinine OR Measured or calculated creatinine clearance (GFR can also be&#xD;
                  used in place of creatinine or CrCl): ≤1.5 X upper limit of normal (ULN) OR ≥60&#xD;
                  mL/min for subject with creatinine levels &gt; 1.5 X institutional ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Adequate lung and cardiac function for intended lung resection according to German S3&#xD;
             guideline&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Anticancer treatment during the last 30 days prior to start of treatment, including&#xD;
             systemic therapy, radiotherapy or major surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participation in a clinical trial within the last 30 days prior to study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of allogeneic tissue/solid organ transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Has a history of (non-infectious) pneumonitis that required steroids or current&#xD;
             pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Evidence of interstitial lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. cT4 tumor&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Symptomatic acute cardiovascular or cerebrovascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Known active HBV, HCV or HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Has any other active infection requiring systemic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with active tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Prior therapy with an anti-Programmed cell death protein 1 (anti-PD-1), anti-PD-L1,&#xD;
             anti-Programmed cell death-ligand 2 (anti-PD-L2), anti-CD137 (4-1BB ligand, a member&#xD;
             of the Tumor Necrosis Factor Receptor [TNFR] family), or anti-Cytotoxic&#xD;
             T-lymphocyte-associated antigen-4 (anti-CTLA-4) antibody (including ipilimumab or any&#xD;
             other antibody or drug specifically targeting T-cell co-stimulation or checkpoint&#xD;
             pathways)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. A diagnosis of immunodeficiency or patient is receiving chronic systemic steroid&#xD;
             therapy or any other form of immunosuppressive therapy within 7 days prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of trial treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient has had a prior monoclonal antibody within 4 weeks prior to study Day 1&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient has had prior chemotherapy, targeted small molecule therapy, or radiation&#xD;
             therapy in history.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Has an active autoimmune disease requiring systemic treatment within the past 3 months&#xD;
             or a documented history of clinically severe autoimmune disease, or a syndrome that&#xD;
             requires systemic steroids or immunosuppressive agents. Subjects with vitiligo or&#xD;
             resolved childhood asthma/atopy would be an exception to this rule. Subjects that&#xD;
             require intermittent use of bronchodilators or local steroid injections would not be&#xD;
             excluded from the study. Subjects with hypothyroidism stable on hormone replacement or&#xD;
             Sjorgen's syndrome will not be excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Has received a live vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of trial treatment.&#xD;
             [Seasonal influenza vaccines for injection are generally inactivated flu vaccines and&#xD;
             are allowed; however intranasal influenza vaccines are live attenuated vaccines, and&#xD;
             are not allowed.]&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Has known hypersensitivity to pembrolizumab or any of the constituents of the product.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Other active malignancy requiring treatment Exceptions include basal cell carcinoma of&#xD;
             the skin or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin that has undergone potentially&#xD;
             curative therapy or in situ cervical cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Lactating or pregnant women, women of child-bearing potential who do not agree to the&#xD;
             usage of highly effective contraception methods (allowed methods of contraception,&#xD;
             meaning methods with a rate of failure of less than 1% per year are implants,&#xD;
             injectable contraceptives, combined oral contraceptives, intrauterine pessars (only&#xD;
             hormonal devices), sexual abstinence or vasectomy of the partner). Women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test (serum β-hCG) at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Any psychiatric illness that would affect the patient's ability to understand the&#xD;
             demands of the clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Patient has already been recruited in this trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Patient who has been incarcerated or involuntarily institutionalized by court order or&#xD;
             by the authorities § 40 Abs. 1 S. 3 Nr. 4 AMG.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Patients who are unable to consent because they do not understand the nature,&#xD;
             significance and implications of the clinical trial and therefore cannot form a&#xD;
             rational intention in the light of the facts [§ 40 Abs. 1 S. 3 Nr. 3a AMG].&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martin E. Eichhorn, PD Dr. med.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital Heidelberg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Heidelberg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <zip>69126</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 21, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 22, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pembrolizumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

