<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01070706</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCCCTS-08-369</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01070706</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase Ib/II Study of Primary Chemotherapy With Paclitaxel, Gemcitabine, and Sunitinib</brief_title>
  <acronym>PGS</acronym>
  <official_title>Phase Ib/II Study of Primary Chemotherapy With Paclitaxel, Gemcitabine, and Sunitinib in Patients With HER2-negative Stage II/III Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jungsil Ro</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>HK inno.N Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Center, Korea</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Phase Ib part:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ▪ Primary objective: To demonstrate the recommended dose of the combination of paclitaxel,&#xD;
      gemcitabine, and sunitinib (sutene®) (PGS) as preoperative chemotherapy in patients with&#xD;
      HER2-negative operable breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Secondary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. To demonstrate the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) and dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) of&#xD;
                this regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. To determine the safety profile&#xD;
&#xD;
                Phase II part&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Primary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the pathologic complete response rate (pCR) to preoperative administration of PGS&#xD;
&#xD;
      ▪ Secondary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess breast conserving rate after preoperative PGS&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To evaluate clinical response rate, disease free survival (DFS), and overall survival&#xD;
           (OS)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To assess the safety profiles of PGS&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Unlike adjuvant chemotherapy, primary (preoperative) chemotherapy will shrink tumor and allow&#xD;
      more patients to become candidates for conservative surgery and avoid mastectomy. It also is&#xD;
      an in vivo chemosensitivity test and the result is a predictive marker for clinical outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Paclitaxel has been shown to be an effective agent in the treatment of breast cancer.&#xD;
      Gemcitabine is a cytosine arabinoside prodrug analog and shows response rates of 15% to 46%&#xD;
      as a single agent with very low toxicity. The combination of paclitaxel and gemcitabine (PG)&#xD;
      resulted in improvement in objective response rate, time to progression and overall survival&#xD;
      compared to paclitaxel monotherapy in patients with metastatic breast cancer. In addition,&#xD;
      primary chemotherapies with PG and PGH (PG + trastuzumab) showed significant activity and&#xD;
      very low toxicity in phase II studies performed at National Cancer Center, Korea (ASCO 2007&#xD;
      and SABCS 2008, respectively).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sunitinib is an oral small molecular tyrosine kinase inhibitor that exhibits potent&#xD;
      anti-angiogenic and antitumor activity. Sunitinib is a rationally designed small molecule&#xD;
      that inhibits members of the split-kinase domain family of receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs)&#xD;
      including the vascular endothelial growth factors (VEGFs) types 1, 2, and 3, platelet-derived&#xD;
      growth factor receptor (PDGFR)-α, and -β, stem cell factor receptor (KIT), colony stimulating&#xD;
      factor 1 receptor (CSF-1R), Fms-like tyrosine kinase (FLT-3), and glial cell line-derived&#xD;
      neurotrophic factor receptor (RET). Inhibition of these RTKs blocks signal transduction,&#xD;
      thereby affecting many of the process involved in tumor growth, progression, metastasis, and&#xD;
      angiogenesis. Angiogenesis plays a vital role in the growth and metastasis of solid tumors.&#xD;
      Preclinical and indirect clinical evidence has accumulated to support the role of&#xD;
      neo-angiogenesis in the pathogenesis and progression of breast cancer. Breast cancer&#xD;
      neo-vascularization, as measured by an increase in microvessel density, is correlated with&#xD;
      the extent of disease and is associated with vascular invasion of the tumor, a prerequisite&#xD;
      for blood-borne metastasis. VEGFR signaling is also implicated in the pathobiology of breast&#xD;
      cancer. Breast cancer patients exhibit high levels of circulating VEGF and other RTKs are&#xD;
      very likely implicated in breast cancer pathogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interestingly, a phase II study (Study A6181002) of single-agent sunitinib (50 mg/d on&#xD;
      schedule 4/2) in breast cancer patients with anthracycline- and taxane-refractory metastatic&#xD;
      disease revealed a response rate of approximately 14% in 51 assessable patients, leading to&#xD;
      additional accrual.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When sunitinib is combined with paclitaxel, significant activity was noticed with tolerable&#xD;
      toxicity profile in a phase I trial (SABCS 2007). Based on this trial, phase III trial of&#xD;
      paclitaxel and sunitinib is ongoing. In addition, phase I trials of gemcitabine and sunitinib&#xD;
      combination are ongoing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based both on the significant activity of PG combination regimens in the neoadjuvant and&#xD;
      metastatic setting and on the phase I trials of combination regimens with&#xD;
      sunitinib-paclitaxel and sunitinib-gemcitabine, we plan to conduct a phase IB/II study of&#xD;
      primary chemotherapy with sunitinib, paclitaxel and gemcitabine in patients with&#xD;
      HER2-negative stage II/III breast cancer. The goal of this phase IB/II study is to define the&#xD;
      recommended dose and maximum tolerable dose of paclitaxel and gemcitabine in combination with&#xD;
      sunitinib, and explore the activity of this combination as preoperative chemotherapy in&#xD;
      patients with HER2-negative operable breast cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>March 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase Ib part: To demonstrate the recommended dose of the combination of paclitaxel, gemcitabine, and sunitinib. Phase II part: To evaluate the pathologic complete response rate (pCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>17Mar2009~08Apr2010</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Paclitaxel, Gemcitabine, Sunitinib</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Paclitaxel, Gemcitabine, Sunitinib</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paclitaxel,Gemcitabine,Sunitinib</intervention_name>
    <description>To determine the MTD, only DLT occurring during the first cycle of treatment will be considered. And MTD is defined as the dose level at which at least one-third of patients experience a DLT during their first treatment course. The recommended dose level for the subsequent phase II study is defined as the preceding dose level before the MTD is attained.&#xD;
If MTD is not reached, the recommended initial dose of the phase II part will be at the dose of paclitaxel 80 mg/m2 and gemcitabine 1200 mg/m2 (days 1, 8) with sunitinib 37.5 mg qd D2-D15.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Paclitaxel, Gemcitabine, Sunitinib</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PGS</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ECOG performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histologically confirmed and newly diagnosed breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Documented HER2/neu non-overexpressing or non-amplified disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  0-1+ by HER2 IHC or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HER2 gene non-amplification by HER2 FISH&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinical stage II or III operable breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Axillary node positivity determined by cytology&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. No prior hormonal, chemotherapy or radiotherapy is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No breast operation other than biopsy to make diagnosis is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate hematologic, hepatic and renal function&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥ 1,500/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 10.0 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet ≥ 100,000/μL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST/ALT ≤ 2 X UNL (upper limit of normal)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline phosphatase ≤ 2 X UNL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤ 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Adequate cardiac function LVEF ≥ 50% and within the institutional range of normal as&#xD;
             measured by echocardiogram or MUGA scan within 4 weeks of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative urine pregnancy test within 7&#xD;
             days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Normal mental function to understand and sign the consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with metastatic breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who received hormonal, chemotherapy or radiotherapy for breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who underwent surgery for breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with T2N0, or inflammatory (T4d) breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who have history of cancer other than in situ uterine cervix cancer or&#xD;
             nonmelanotic skin cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with GI tract disease resulting in an inability to take oral medication,&#xD;
             malabsorption syndrome, a requirement for IV alimentation, prior surgical procedures&#xD;
             affecting absorption, uncontrolled inflammatory GI disease (e.g., Crohn's disease,&#xD;
             ulcerative colitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any of the following within the 12 months prior to starting study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  severe, unstable angina&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled or symptomatic congestive heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  coronary/peripheral artery bypass graft&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  cerebrovascular accident including transient ischemic attack&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  pulmonary embolism&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Ongoing cardiac dysrhythmias of grade ≥2, atrial fibrillation of any grade, or QTc&#xD;
             interval &gt;470 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Hypertension that cannot be controlled by medications (&gt;150/100 mmHg despite optimal&#xD;
             medical therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Current treatment with therapeutic doses of Coumadin (low dose Coumadin up to 2 mg po&#xD;
             daily for deep vein thrombosis prophylaxis is allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Known HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Pregnancy or breastfeeding. Female patients who are pregnant or nursing, female of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential who is unwilling to use adequate contraception to prevent&#xD;
             pregnancy during the program. All female patients with reproductive potential must&#xD;
             have a negative pregnancy test (serum or urine) prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Other severe acute or chronic medical or psychiatric condition, or laboratory&#xD;
             abnormality that would impart, in the judgment of the investigator, excess risk&#xD;
             associated with study participation or study drug during administration, or which, in&#xD;
             the judgment of the investigator, would make the patient inappropriate for entry into&#xD;
             this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jungsil Ro</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chief, Center for Breast Cancer, National Cancer Center, Korea</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center for breast cancer, National Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Goyang</city>
        <state>Kyeonggido</state>
        <zip>410-769</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 17, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 17, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 18, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 1, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 1, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 4, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Cancer Center, Korea</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jungsil Ro</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief, Center for Clinical Trials, National Cancer Center, Korea</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Patients with HER2- stage II/III breast cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sunitinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

