<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02909777</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>16-371</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02909777</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial of CUDC-907 in Children and Young Adults With Relapsed or Refractory Solid Tumors, CNS Tumors, or Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase 1 Trial of CUDC-907 in Children and Young Adults With Relapsed or Refractory Solid Tumors, CNS Tumors, or Lymphoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Curis, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study is evaluating a novel drug called CUDC-907 as a possible treatment for&#xD;
      resistant (refractory) pediatric solid tumors (including neuroblastoma), lymphoma, or brain&#xD;
      tumors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase I clinical trial. A Phase I clinical trial tests the safety of an&#xD;
      investigational intervention and also tries to find the best dose of the investigational&#xD;
      intervention to use for further studies. &quot;Investigational&quot; means that the intervention is&#xD;
      being studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The FDA (the U.S. Food and Drug Administration) has not approved CUDC-907 as a treatment&#xD;
      option for any disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is the first time that CUDC-907 will be given to children.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this research study, the investigators are evaluating a new drug, CUDC-907, as a potential&#xD;
      new treatment for children with solid tumors, lymphomas and brain tumors. CUDC-907 is an oral&#xD;
      drug that blocks certain proteins in tumor cells. These proteins may be important in the&#xD;
      growth of some cancers. Laboratory experiments and results from adult studies demonstrate&#xD;
      that CUDC-907 may stop tumor growth and, in some cases, cause tumor cells to die. CUDC-907&#xD;
      has been tested in adults with cancer to find out about side effects and dosing in adults.&#xD;
      The primary goal of this study is to evaluate side effects of CUDC-907 and find the best dose&#xD;
      of CUDC-907 when used in children. Other goals of this study are to determine whether this&#xD;
      drug may have benefits against the types of cancer seen in children and to measure the&#xD;
      effects of CUDC-907 in the blood.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dose Limiting Toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak plasma concentration of CUDC-907 in Pediatrics</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Determined using standard methods and reported descriptively in aggregate and by assigned dose level.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure (AUC) of CUDC-907 in Pediatrics</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Determined using standard methods and reported descriptively in aggregate and by assigned dose level.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of Response</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events per CTCAE Version 4</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective Response</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Neuroblastoma</condition>
  <condition>Brain Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Solid Tumor</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CUDC-907</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>CUDC-907 orally administered&#xD;
CUDC-907 once daily for 5 consecutive days per week followed by two days without dosing&#xD;
Dose level assigned at registration&#xD;
Pre-dose pharmacokinetic blood sample will be collected&#xD;
Dose escalation will follow a standard 3+3 design</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CUDC-907</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>CUDC-907</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &gt; 1 years and ≤ 21 years at time of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky performance status ≥ 50% for patients ≥16 years of age and Lansky ≥ 50% for&#xD;
             patients &lt;16 years of age (see Appendix A)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis requirement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Parts A and B, participants must have evaluable or measurable disease (see Section&#xD;
             11).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Part A, participants must have histologically confirmed solid tumors, CNS tumors,&#xD;
             or lymphoma based upon biopsy or surgery at initial diagnosis and/or&#xD;
             relapse/progression. The only exception to histologic confirmation is for pediatric&#xD;
             tumors that are routinely diagnosed exclusively by standard clinical imaging criteria:&#xD;
             diffuse intrinsic pontine glioma and optic pathway glioma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Part B, participants must have one of the following diagnoses histologically&#xD;
             confirmed:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neuroblastoma with evidence of Mycn/Myc positivity based on any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  MYCN amplification (&gt; 4 copy amplification) from COG reference laboratory or&#xD;
                       other CLIA-certified laboratory; or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Mycn protein expression &gt; 1+ according to validated assay in Children's&#xD;
                       Hospital Los Angeles (CHLA) Clinical Pathology Laboratory; or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Myc expression &gt; 1+ according to validated assay in CHLA Clinical Pathology&#xD;
                       Laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  One of the following mature B cell lymphoma diagnoses:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Diffuse large B cell lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Burkitt lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have disease that is relapsed or refractory and for which standard&#xD;
             curative or palliative measures do not exist or are no longer effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have fully recovered from the acute toxic effects of all prior&#xD;
             anti-cancer therapy except organ function as noted in Section 3.1.6). Patients must&#xD;
             meet the following minimum washout periods prior to enrollment:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myelosuppressive chemotherapy: At least 14 days after the last dose of&#xD;
             myelosuppressive chemotherapy (42 days for nitrosourea or mitomycin C).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 14 days after local palliative XRT (small port);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 90 days must have elapsed after prior TBI, craniospinal XRT or if &gt;50%&#xD;
                  radiation of pelvis;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 42 must have elapsed if other substantial BM radiation;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 42 days must have passed since last MIBG or other radionuclide therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Small molecule biologic therapy: At least 7 days following the last dose of a biologic&#xD;
             agent. For agents with known adverse events occurring beyond 7 days, this duration&#xD;
             must be extended beyond the time in which adverse events are known to occur. If&#xD;
             extended duration is required, this should be discussed and approved by the study&#xD;
             chair.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Monoclonal antibody: At least 21 days after the last dose of anitbody&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myeloid growth factors: At least 14 days following the last dose of long-acting growth&#xD;
             factor (e.g. Neulasta) or 7 days following short-acting growth factor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stem Cell Infusion or Cellular Therapies: The patient must have no evidence of graft&#xD;
             versus host disease and at least 42 days must have elapsed after transplant, stem cell&#xD;
             infusion, or cellular therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major Surgery: At least 3 weeks from prior major surgical procedure. Note: Biopsy and&#xD;
             central line placement/removal are not considered major.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PI3K and HDAC inhibitors: The patient must not have received prior CUDC-907 therapy.&#xD;
             Prior treatment with individual PI3K or HDAC inhibitors is allowed. Patients must not&#xD;
             have received therapy with the combination of PI3K and HDAC inhibitors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must have normal organ function as defined below.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bone Marrow Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥1,000/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥75,000/uL and transfusion independent, defined as not receiving a&#xD;
                  platelet transfusion for at least 5 days prior to CBC documenting eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hepatic Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal for age&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT (SGPT) ≤ 135 U/L For the purpose of this study, the ULN for ALT is 45 U/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin &gt; 2 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Renal Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
             --A serum creatinine based on age/gender as follows: Age Maximum Serum Creatinine&#xD;
             (mg/dL) Male Female&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. to &lt; 2 years 0.6 0.6&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. to &lt; 6 years 0.8 0.8&#xD;
&#xD;
             6 to &lt; 10 years 1 1 10 to &lt; 13 years 1.2 1.2 13 to &lt; 16 years 1.5 1.4&#xD;
&#xD;
             ≥ 16 years 1.7 1.4 OR&#xD;
&#xD;
             --Creatinine clearance ≥ 70 mL/min/1.73 m2 for participants with creatinine levels&#xD;
             above institutional normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate Cardiac Function: QTc &lt; 480 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate GI Function: Diarrhea &lt; grade 2 by CTCAE version 4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate Metabolic Function: Fasting glucose &lt; grade 2 (&lt; 160 mg/dL or &lt; 8.9 mmol/L)&#xD;
             without the use of antihyperglycemic agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Additional Agent-Specific Requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to swallow either intact capsules or mini-tabs without chewing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In order to limit dose deviations due to rounding, patients must have a body surface&#xD;
             area of at least 0.5 m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For patients with CNS tumors (primary or metastatic), any baseline neurologic deficits&#xD;
             (including seizure) must be stable for at least one week prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and/or the willingness of the patient (or parent or legally&#xD;
             authorized representative, if minor) to provide informed consent, using an&#xD;
             institutionally approved informed consent procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not be receiving any of the following concomitant medications:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pharmacologic doses of systemic corticosteroids unless for CNS metastatic or primary&#xD;
             disease. For patients with CNS metastatic or primary tumors receiving corticosteroids,&#xD;
             they should be on a stable or decreasing dose over the 7 days prior to registration&#xD;
             and meet criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For all patients, receipt of systemic physiologic replacement steroids, topical and/or&#xD;
             inhaled corticosteroids is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, oral anticoagulants, and therapeutic heparins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant participants will not be entered on this study given that the effects of&#xD;
             CUDC-907 on the developing human fetus are unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse events in nursing infants&#xD;
             secondary to treatment of the mother with CUDC-907, breastfeeding mothers are not&#xD;
             eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants of child-bearing or child-fathering potential must agree to use adequate&#xD;
             contraception (hormonal birth control; intrauterine device; double barrier method; or&#xD;
             total abstinence) throughout their participation, including up until 30 days after&#xD;
             last dose of CUDC-907.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to CUDC-907.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements. Note that patients who have had prior allogeneic transplantation&#xD;
             are required to have CMV PCR testing performed during screening. A positive screen&#xD;
             would be evidence of an active infection and would render the patient ineligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a known history of HIV, hepatitis B, and/or hepatitis C (testing not&#xD;
             required as part of screening).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a known history of type 1 or type 2 diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with gastrointestinal disease or disorder that could interfere with&#xD;
             absorption of CUDC-907, such as bowel obstruction or inflammatory bowel disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Year</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David S Shulman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>David S Shulman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>617-632-6670</phone>
    <email>david_shulman@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Francisco, Benioff Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94158</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kieuhoa Vo, MD</last_name>
      <phone>415-476-3831</phone>
      <email>kieuhoa.vo@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kieuhoa Vo, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David S Shulman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-632-6670</phone>
      <email>david_shulman@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>David S Shulman, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elizabeth Fox, MD</last_name>
      <phone>267-425-3010</phone>
      <email>foxe@email.chop.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elizabeth Fox, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Children's, Baylor College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jodi Muscal, MD</last_name>
      <phone>832-824-4632</phone>
      <email>jamuscal@txch.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jodi Muscal, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 13, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 19, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 21, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David S Shulman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Lymphoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Neuroblastoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Brain Tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>Solid Tumor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neuroblastoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

