<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00109018</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>050145</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>05-H-0145</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00109018</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Biomarkers for Cardiovascular Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Nitrite as a Marker of Cardiovascular Risk; Development of Novel Biomarkers in Patients With Coronary Artery Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Biomarkers for Cardiovascular Disease&#xD;
&#xD;
      Summary: This study will examine the function of the lining cells of blood vessels and&#xD;
      measure substances in the blood to see how they relate to various blood tests, including new&#xD;
      tests under development to determine cardiovascular disease risk. Nitric oxide is a molecule&#xD;
      produced by healthy blood vessels that helps keep them relaxed. Nitrate is a substance formed&#xD;
      from nitric oxide in the blood. The release of nitric oxide by blood vessels is reduced in&#xD;
      patients with coronary artery disease, compared with healthy people. Also, blood nitrite&#xD;
      levels rise in some of these patients. Other substances in the blood and urine also change&#xD;
      with risk for heart disease. This study will measure nitrite levels and other inflammatory&#xD;
      substances in the blood and urine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy volunteers, people with various risk factors for heart disease, and people with&#xD;
      blockage of one or more major heart arteries or a history of heart attack may be eligible for&#xD;
      this study. Candidates must be 21 years of age or older. People who have an irregular heart&#xD;
      rhythm or who cannot take oral nitrates are excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants undergo the following tests and procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood tests: Samples are drawn three times for routine tests and to look for certain&#xD;
           proteins that may affect the heart. Samples are collected once before any other tests,&#xD;
           once before starting the exercise stress test (see below) and again after the stress&#xD;
           test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Urine test: A sample may be tested for proteins in the urine and for other research&#xD;
           studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Brachial artery reactivity study: This ultrasound study tests how well a person's&#xD;
           arteries widen. The subject rests on a bed. An ultrasound measuring device is placed&#xD;
           over the artery just above the elbow. The size of the artery and blood flow through it&#xD;
           are measured before and after inflating a pressure cuff around the forearm. The pressure&#xD;
           cuff stops the flow of blood to the arm for 5 minutes and then is released while more&#xD;
           ultrasound pictures are taken. After the subject rests, a nitroglycerin tablet (medicine&#xD;
           that causes blood vessels to relax) is placed under the tongue. After the nitroglycerin&#xD;
           is given, the size of the artery and blood flow through it are measured again. After a&#xD;
           rest period, the study will be repeated in the healthy volunteers and first 20 patients&#xD;
           with heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Echocardiography (heart ultrasound): This test involves holding a small probe against&#xD;
           the chest to use sound waves for obtaining pictures of the heart. A small catheter&#xD;
           (plastic tube) may be placed in a vein to inject a contrast agent that enhances the&#xD;
           pictures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Metabolic stress testing: Subjects will be asked to breathe in and out of a mask while&#xD;
           baseline measurements are taken. Then they exercise on a treadmill while wearing a&#xD;
           breathing mask. This test shows how much oxygen the body uses at rest and with exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Genetic testing (optional): A blood sample is collected to examine DNA - genetic&#xD;
           material that determines inherited traits and contains information about body proteins.&#xD;
           Some parts of DNA may be used as markers of the level of damage produced by oxygen&#xD;
           by-products that may reflect the extent of heart disease in patients. Also, gene&#xD;
           variations may make an individual more likely to develop a heart problem. Such markers&#xD;
           may guide doctors in predicting how fast the disease will progress or may help find a&#xD;
           new type of drug to prevent disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Time requirements: This study is expected to take approximately 5-6 hours for completion&#xD;
           within one or two days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Follow-up: Patients are contacted by phone every 6 months for information on chest pain,&#xD;
           surgical procedures related to the heart, and hospitalizations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular events are a major cause of morbidity and mortality world-wide and traditional&#xD;
      risk factor assessment is limited in its ability to predict which patients will have an&#xD;
      event. The endothelium is known to play a central role in vascular homeostasis and nitric&#xD;
      oxide (NO) is believed to be the main component responsible for normal endothelial function.&#xD;
      Increasing evidence suggests that oxidative stress leading to reduced NO bioavailability and&#xD;
      subsequent endothelial dysfunction is an important factor in the progression of vascular&#xD;
      diseases. Further investigation of NO metabolites in blood may provide insight into the&#xD;
      mechanisms of endothelial dysfunction and disease progression. Preliminary data suggest that&#xD;
      although plasma nitrite levels are decreased in CAD patients and correlate with endothelial&#xD;
      dysfunction, the nitrite within red blood cells and whole blood is compensatorily increased.&#xD;
      Since this new measure is more reproducible and convenient to measure, it may serve as a&#xD;
      biomarker of endothelial dysfunction. A prospective study of nitrite and other novel NO-based&#xD;
      assays, proteomics, and current biomarkers linked to endothelial function phenotype will&#xD;
      allow further investigation into the pathophysiology of endothelial dysfunction and permit&#xD;
      development of future markers of atherothrombosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 19, 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date>April 15, 2009</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <enrollment>120</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adults older than 21, of both sexes:&#xD;
&#xD;
        The initial study group will consist of 120 subjects, which will consist of 100 subjects&#xD;
        with documented CAD (by cardiac catheterization showing greater than or equal to 70%&#xD;
        stenosis in an epicardial vessel), previously documented MI (based on ECG or cardiac&#xD;
        enzymes) or CAD risk equivalents (diabetes, peripheral vascular disease, abdominal aortic&#xD;
        aneurysm, symptomatic carotid disease, or multiple risk factors that confer a 10 year risk&#xD;
        of greater than 20% as defined by the Framingham Risk Score) and 20 healthy age- and&#xD;
        sex-matched controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
        Atrial fibrillation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any contraindications to oral nitrates&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hypotension, bradycardia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Myocardial infarction within the prior 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
        Symptoms of acute CHF&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
        Receiving active treatment for cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Any other condition that may interfere with the interpretation of the study results or not&#xD;
        be in the best interest of the subject in the opinion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Since oral nitrate therapy is known to affect serum and possibly whole blood nitrite&#xD;
        levels, we will exclude patients on long-acting nitrates for the initial group of 100&#xD;
        cardiac patients. Those patients on chronic nitrate therapy will subsequently be included&#xD;
        in the later portion of the study but will be analyzed separately.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Myerburg RJ, Interian A Jr, Mitrani RM, Kessler KM, Castellanos A. Frequency of sudden cardiac death and profiles of risk. Am J Cardiol. 1997 Sep 11;80(5B):10F-19F. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9291445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wilson PW, D'Agostino RB, Levy D, Belanger AM, Silbershatz H, Kannel WB. Prediction of coronary heart disease using risk factor categories. Circulation. 1998 May 12;97(18):1837-47.</citation>
    <PMID>9603539</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ridker PM, Rifai N, Rose L, Buring JE, Cook NR. Comparison of C-reactive protein and low-density lipoprotein cholesterol levels in the prediction of first cardiovascular events. N Engl J Med. 2002 Nov 14;347(20):1557-65.</citation>
    <PMID>12432042</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 15, 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 21, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 21, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 22, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Risk Assessment</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronary Heart Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Vascular Function</keyword>
  <keyword>Nitric Oxide Metabolites</keyword>
  <keyword>Blood Tests</keyword>
  <keyword>Nitrite</keyword>
  <keyword>Flow-Mediated Dilation</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarker</keyword>
  <keyword>Endothelial Dysfunction</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronary Artery Disease</keyword>
  <keyword>CAD</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronary Artery Disease At Risk</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

