<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00620438</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CPR 005</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00620438</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Drug Interaction Between Coartem® and Nevirapine, Efavirenz or Rifampicin in HIV Positive Ugandan Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pharmacokinetic Interaction Between Coartem® and Either Nevirapine, Efavirenz or Rifampicin in HIV Positive Ugandan Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Makerere University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Health Research Board, Ireland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Makerere University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There are increasing numbers of HIV-infected patients in sub-Saharan Africa receiving&#xD;
      antiretroviral drugs and/or rifampicin based antituberculous therapy. HIV infected patients&#xD;
      are at an increased risk of contracting malaria. Increasing resistance to anti-malarials such&#xD;
      as chloroquine, amodiaquine, fansidar, sulphadoxine-pyrimethamine in East and West Africa has&#xD;
      led the WHO to recommend artemether-lumefantrine (Coartem®- Novartis) as first line therapy&#xD;
      for malaria for adults and children. As early as 2004, fourteen countries in sub-Saharan&#xD;
      Africa had adopted this guideline as national policy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no data on the interaction between Coartem® and any of the antiretroviral agents.&#xD;
      Both components of Coartem® are substrates for the 3A4 isoform of cytochrome P450. Despite&#xD;
      the lack of data, antiretroviral drugs and/or antituberculous drugs in addition to Coartem®&#xD;
      are of necessity co-prescribed daily in the African setting. Nevirapine, efavirenz and&#xD;
      rifampicin are known inducers of cytochrome P450 3A4. A technical consultation convened by&#xD;
      WHO in June, 2004 concluded that additional research on interactions between antiretroviral&#xD;
      and antimalarial drugs is urgently needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We propose to perform a suite of pharmacokinetic studies to evaluate these interactions in&#xD;
      HIV infected Ugandan patients. The aim of these studies is to evaluate the pharmacokinetic&#xD;
      interaction between Coartem® and commonly co-prescribed inducers of 3A4 i.e. nevirapine,&#xD;
      efavirenz and rifampicin.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Comparison of steady state pharmacokinetics of Coartem® in HIV-infected patients prior&#xD;
           to commencement of nevirapine and at nevirapine steady state&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Comparison of steady state pharmacokinetics of Coartem® in HIV-infected patients prior&#xD;
           to commencement of efavirenz and at efavirenz steady state&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Comparison of steady state pharmacokinetics of Coartem® in Ugandan patients at&#xD;
           rifampicin steady state and without rifampicin&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coartem® is the combination of artemether and lumefantrine used for the treatment of&#xD;
      uncomplicated falciparum malaria 1. This oral combination seems to be well-tolerated and is&#xD;
      useful for treatment of multi-drug resistant Plasmodium falciparum. This unique anti-malarial&#xD;
      agent combines the fast, but short-acting artemether with a less potent, but longer-acting&#xD;
      lumefantrine. Original studies with the combination demonstrated safety and efficacy in&#xD;
      adults and children with uncomplicated falciparum malaria. 2,3 Additional studies showed&#xD;
      superiority with respect to parasite clearance time versus halofantrine,4 chloroquine5, and&#xD;
      mefloquine6. Coartem® also demonstrated a faster reduction in parasite burden after 24-hours&#xD;
      versus halofantrine4, chloroquine5 (in adults), chloroquine (in children) 7, and mefloquine6.&#xD;
      Various other studies have shown artemether-lumefantrine to have a superior 28-day cure rate,&#xD;
      as well as time to fever resolution compared to other antimalarial agents.1 Both components&#xD;
      of Coartem® were discovered in China. Artemether was isolated from sweet wormwood, Atemisia&#xD;
      annua, which has been used in traditional Chinese medicine for over 2000 years 1.&#xD;
      Lumefantrine is a synthetic compound, which has structural and physiochemical&#xD;
      characteristics; and a mode of action similar to other antimalarials, including quinine,&#xD;
      mefloquine, and halofantrine 8. In vitro, the two antimalarial agents show synergistic&#xD;
      activity against P.falciparum. Based on both in vitro and in vivo studies, a 1:6 ratio of&#xD;
      artemether to lumefantrine has been described as optimal. Thus, the tablets are manufactured&#xD;
      as 20mg artemether and 120mg lumefantrine. 8 Currently there are two recommended dosing&#xD;
      regimen for adults and children above 35 kg; or 12 years of age or older. In partially immune&#xD;
      patients, a 4-dose regimen is recommended. Four tablets as a single dose should be taken at&#xD;
      time of diagnosis and then again at 8, 24, and 48 hours post-initial dose. A different&#xD;
      regimen is recommended for either non-immune patients or patients in areas where multi-drug&#xD;
      resistance to falciparum malaria is a problem. This is a 3-day regimen consisting of 4&#xD;
      tablets as a single dose given at the time of diagnosis, 8 hours later and then twice daily&#xD;
      for the following two days. 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antimalarial Activity and Mechanism of Action: 1, 8 The antimalarial activity of artemether&#xD;
      and that of its active metabolite, dihydroartemisinin (DHA) have been extensively studied in&#xD;
      vitro. These are very potent antimalarial compounds. The IC50 of artemether ranges from 0.1&#xD;
      to 20 nmol/L and the IC50 for DHA ranges from 0.1 to 15 nmol/L. In vitro studies have shown&#xD;
      artemether to be 2 to 3 times less active than its metabolite, DHA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exact mechanisms of action of artemether and lumefantrine are unknown, but both agents&#xD;
      appear to act on the parasite's organelles. Artemether's action depends on its endoperoxide&#xD;
      bridge, which interacts with heme iron to cause free radical damage to the malaria parasite.&#xD;
      Lumefantrine most likely interferes with heme polymerization, which is a critical detoxifying&#xD;
      pathway for the malaria parasite. Both agents may have secondary actions that include&#xD;
      inhibition of parasite nucleic acid and protein synthesis; however, these actions have not&#xD;
      been well-described.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The varied pharmacokinetic profiles of the two antimalarial agents appear to create a&#xD;
      synergistic effect. Artemether works rapidly to decrease the parasite load and improve&#xD;
      patients' clinical symptoms. Lumefantrine is long-acting and appears to prevent recrudescence&#xD;
      (reappearance of the disease after inadequate or failed drug therapy). The different actions&#xD;
      of the two agents may also reduce the emergence of resistance. Artemether and DHA have been&#xD;
      shown to decrease parasite burden by about 104 per asexual life cycle in about 2 days. Thus,&#xD;
      the 3-day course of the combination therapy can potentially decrease the parasite burden by&#xD;
      about 108.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drug Interactions Pharmacokinetic and electrocardiographic interactions between&#xD;
      artemether-lumefantrine and the mefloquine were studied in 42 healthy volunteers. Like&#xD;
      artemether-lumefantrine, mefloquine is a substrate for CYP 3A4; however, it is also a&#xD;
      potential CYP 3A4 inhibitor. Pharmacokinetic parameters for artemether, DHA, and mefloquine&#xD;
      were unchanged; however, lumefantrine concentrations decreased by 30-40% when given with&#xD;
      mefloquine. The clinical significance of this interaction is not known. Co-administration of&#xD;
      the antimalarial agents resulted in no increased adverse effects. 13&#xD;
&#xD;
      An additional study evaluated the effects of concomitant administration with ketoconazole, a&#xD;
      potent CYP 3A4 inhibitor, and artemether-lumefantrine. The study was carried out in 16&#xD;
      healthy volunteers who received single doses of artemether-lumefantrine either alone or in&#xD;
      combination with multiple doses of ketoconazole. Artemether, DHA, and lumefantrine&#xD;
      pharmacokinetics were altered by ketoconazole. AUC and Cmax increased for all three compounds&#xD;
      and terminal half-life increased for artemether and DHA. None of the changes in PK parameters&#xD;
      were greater than those changes observed in healthy volunteers taking artemether-lumefantrine&#xD;
      with a high fat meal (i.e. a 16-fold increase in AUC). There was no increase in observed side&#xD;
      effects or electrocardiographic changes. Dosage adjustments do not appear to be necessary&#xD;
      with concomitant ketoconazole administration.14&#xD;
&#xD;
      A study of 42 healthy Caucasian volunteers was conducted to investigate pharmacokinetic or&#xD;
      electrocardiographic effects of concomitant administration of IV quinine and&#xD;
      artemether-lumefantrine. QTc prolongation was not associated with artemether-lumefantrine&#xD;
      administration alone; however transient increases in QTc interval were noted in the&#xD;
      combination groups. PK variables for lumefantrine and quinine were unchanged, but artemether&#xD;
      and DHA plasma concentrations decreased with concomitant quinine administration. The exact&#xD;
      mechanism for this decrease could not be explained for the results of this study.15&#xD;
&#xD;
      Artemether is metabolized via CYP 3A4 to dihydroartemisinin (although both compounds have&#xD;
      antimalarial activity, dihydroartemisinin has greater potency). Induction of CYP 3A4 would&#xD;
      increase dihydroartemisinin but decrease artemether.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study objectives General objective To evaluate the pharmacokinetic interaction between&#xD;
      Coartem® and commonly co-prescribed inducers of 3A4 i.e. nevirapine, efavirenz and rifampicin&#xD;
      in HIV positive patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To compare the steady state pharmacokinetics of Coartem® in HIV-infected patients prior&#xD;
           to commencement of nevirapine and at nevirapine steady state&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To compare the steady state pharmacokinetics of Coartem® in HIV-infected patients prior&#xD;
           to commencement of efavirenz and at efavirenz steady state&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To compare the steady state pharmacokinetics of Coartem® in Ugandan patients at&#xD;
           rifampicin steady state and without rifampicin therapy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of lumefantrine in patients receiving either nevirapine, efavirenz or rifampicin</measure>
    <time_frame>11 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <condition>Tuberculosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>nevirapine arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>efavirenz arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rifampicin arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lumefantrine-artemether and nevirapine</intervention_name>
    <description>Administration of lumefantrine 480mg co-formulated with artemether 80mg twice daily for three days to HIV positive patients receiving nevirapine 200mg twice daily as part of their antiretroviral treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Coartem</other_name>
    <other_name>Triomune</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>lumefantrine-artemether and efavirenz</intervention_name>
    <description>Administration of lumefantrine 480mg co-formulated with artemether 80mg twice daily for three days to HIV positive adults receiving efavirenz tablets 600mg once daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Coartem</other_name>
    <other_name>Sustiva</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lumefantrine-artemether and rifampicin</intervention_name>
    <description>Administration of lumefantrine 480mg co-formulated with artemether 80mg twice daily for three days to patients receiving rifampicin as part of fixed dose combination therapy for tuberculosis</description>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Coartem</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age over eighteen years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to provide full written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed diagnosis of HIV infection&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Haemoglobin &lt; 8g/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver and renal function tests &gt; 3 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of known inhibitors or inducers of cytochrome P450 or P-glycoprotein.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of herbal medications (information will be obtained from patients' medication&#xD;
             history through interview with the patient)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal EKG ie QTc (Rate adjusted QT interval) &gt;450ms (men) or &gt;470ms (women)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intercurrent Illness including malaria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to artemisinin-derivatives, halofantrine or lumefantrine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cardiac disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Concepta Merry, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Trinity Colleg Dublin</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Infectious Diseases Institute, Makerere University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kampala</city>
        <zip>22418</zip>
        <country>Uganda</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Uganda</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 7, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 19, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 21, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 3, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 3, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 6, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Concepta Merry</name_title>
    <organization>Infectious Diseases Institute, Makerere University</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Lumefantrine</keyword>
  <keyword>Efavirenz</keyword>
  <keyword>Nevirapine</keyword>
  <keyword>Rifampicin</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Tuberculosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Efavirenz</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nevirapine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rifampin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lumefantrine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Artemether</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Artemether, Lumefantrine Drug Combination</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

