<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03489109</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>180075</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>18-I-0075</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03489109</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>2-5 Intermittent Caloric Restriction for Weight Loss and Insulin Resistance in HIV-Infected Adults With Features of the Metabolic Syndrome</brief_title>
  <official_title>2-5 Intermittent Caloric Restriction for Weight Loss and Insulin Resistance in HIV-Infected Adults With Features of the Metabolic Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weight gain can lead to obesity and diabetes even in people living with human&#xD;
      immunodeficiency virus (HIV). Researchers want to see if the technique intermittent calorie&#xD;
      restriction can help overweight people with HIV as an alternative to traditional diets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To see if intermittent calorie restriction leads to weight loss and improved blood sugar in&#xD;
      obese people with HIV.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 18-65 with HIV who are obese and do not have diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with a medical history, physical exam, and blood and urine&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before starting treatment, participants will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a nutritional consultation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Get a pedometer to record daily steps&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Test a restricted diet for 1 day&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a body x-ray&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the baseline visit, participants will have:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood drawn after they drink a sugar drink&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Questions about their health and eating&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A nutritional consultation&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Resting energy expenditure measured. Participants will fast overnight. Then they will&#xD;
           lie down while a plastic bubble goes over the head and a plastic sheet covers the upper&#xD;
           body. Oxygen flows into the bubble.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Liver stiffness test. A wand on the stomach releases sound waves like an ultrasound.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For 12 weeks, some participants will be on a standard diet. Others will restrict how much&#xD;
      food they eat 2 days a week. On those days they will eat about 25% of their recommended&#xD;
      calories.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will keep a diary of their diet and steps.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have 4 visits during the 12-week diet and 1 visit 12 weeks after the diet&#xD;
      ends. They will repeat previous tests.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The high prevalence of obesity coupled with chronic inflammation and immune activation places&#xD;
      human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-infected individuals at increased risk for metabolic&#xD;
      complications emphasizing the need for more aggressive management of obesity and related&#xD;
      co-morbidities in the aging HIV-infected population. The most effective treatment for obesity&#xD;
      and metabolic syndrome is lifestyle modification, usually with a combination of caloric&#xD;
      restriction and increased exercise. Intermittent caloric restriction (ICR) or intermittent&#xD;
      fasting simplifies caloric restriction by severely limiting calories only a few days per week&#xD;
      and allowing ad lib diet on the other days. Weight loss benefits are similar to those seen&#xD;
      with conventional diets, however, data suggests possible added health benefits from&#xD;
      intermittent fasting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We propose to study the benefits of a 2-5 ICR strategy on weight, insulin resistance, and&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease markers in obese HIV-infected adults with features of the metabolic&#xD;
      syndrome. In a prospective pilot study, 50 HIVinfected adults will be randomized 1:1 to ICR&#xD;
      or standard-of-care instruction of healthy diet and lifestyle for a 12-week intervention&#xD;
      period. We hypothesize that ICR (2 days per week) will be an effective and acceptable diet&#xD;
      strategy that will result in significant weight reduction, improvements in insulin&#xD;
      sensitivity, and related metabolic parameters.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 9, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in weight and insulin sensitivity as measured by HOMA-IR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, week 12, week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Weight</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of ICR</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 12, Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Subject's tolerability to ICR and compliance as recorded on subject diary.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lipid levels, metabolic biomarkers, biomarkers of inflammation and immune activation, and mood.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 12, Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Change in lipids levels, metabolic biomarkers, biomarkers of inflammation and immune activation. Mood changes measured by subject questionnaires.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body composition, including visceral adiposity abd hepatic steatosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 12, Week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Change in body composition, including visceral adiposity and hepatic steatosis measured by fibroscan.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Human Immunodeficiency Virus</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent Fasting</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subject will consume approximately 25% of their daily calories for 2 days per week. The other 5 days they will eat their normal diet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care dietary and healthy lifestyle counseling</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intermittent fasting</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will consume approximately 25% of their daily calories for 2 days per week. The other 5 days they will eat their normal diet</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intermittent Fasting</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Subject will receive standard of care recommendations for healthy diet and lifestyle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18 to 65 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. HIV RNA level less than or equal to 200 copies/mL for greater than or equal to1 year&#xD;
             (1 measure greater than or equal to 200 allowed if also &lt;500 and preceded and followed&#xD;
             by one or more undetectable values)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. CD4 &gt;200 cells/mL and no active opportunistic infection or malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. BMI greater than or equal to 30 kg/m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. One or more components of the metabolic syndrome as defined below.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Risk Factor: Waist circumference&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Men: Defining Level: &gt;102 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Women: Defining Level: &gt;88 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Risk Factor: Triglycerides, greater than or equal to 150 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Risk Factor: High density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Men: Defining Level: &lt;40 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Women: Defining Level: &lt;50 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Risk Factor: Blood pressure, greater than or equal to 130 / greater than or equal&#xD;
                  to 85 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Risk Factor: Fasting glucose, greater than or equal to 110 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Fasting blood glucose &gt;60 mg/dL at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Willingness to allow sample storage for future research&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Able to provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Established diagnosis of diabetes mellitus use of anti-diabetes medications, or a Hgb&#xD;
             A1C of &gt;7.0%&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of eating disorder, uncontrolled mood or thought disorder, significant&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disorder or malabsorption, or significant hepatic or renal impairment&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current use of medical therapy for overweight/obesity including phentermine, orlistat,&#xD;
             lorcaserin, naltrexone/bupropion, and liraglutide or history of weight loss surgery.&#xD;
             Concomitant use of medications with side effects known to potentially influence&#xD;
             appetite are allowed if on a stable dose for at least 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of symptomatic hypoglycemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Use of systemic glucocorticoids (stable dose daily inhaled corticosteroid allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Chronic viral hepatitis C; subjects with a history of hepatitis C successfully treated&#xD;
             can enroll &gt;12 months after sustained virologic response&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Alcohol or substance use disorder in the past year as defined by DSM-V or positive&#xD;
             urine drug screen&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Current pregnancy, actively seeking to become pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Any serious health or other condition which, in the opinion of the PI or their&#xD;
             designee, could potentially interfere with the ability of a subject to comply with the&#xD;
             procedures and assessments of the protocol or to safely participate and complete the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Colleen M Hadigan, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Cheryl L. Chairez</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-3840</phone>
    <email>chairezc@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2018-I-0075.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 12, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 4, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 4, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Fasting</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin Resistance</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

