<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02687724</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UCDCRC/15/007</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02687724</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Golimumab (GLM) Dose Optimisation to Adequate Levels to Achieve Response in Colitis</brief_title>
  <acronym>GOAL-ARC</acronym>
  <official_title>GLM Dose Optimisation to Adequate Levels to Achieve Response in Colitis (GOAL-ARC). A Nationwide Multi-centred Randomised Controlled Trial (RCT) Investigating the Use of GLM Dose Adjustment in Ulcerative Colitis (UC).</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University College Dublin</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University College Dublin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      GLM dose Optimisation to Adequate Levels to Achieve Response in Colitis (GOAL-ARC). A&#xD;
      nationwide multi-centred randomised controlled trial (RCT) investigating the use of GLM dose&#xD;
      adjustment in ulcerative colitis (UC). The primary objective is to ascertain if dose&#xD;
      adjustment of GLM based on GLM drug levels and FCP levels results in higher response and&#xD;
      remission rates than standard SmPC dosing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      UC is a chronic inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) in which the lining of the large intestine&#xD;
      become inflamed. There is no official database which gives accurate figures but it is thought&#xD;
      that at least 20,000 people are living with IBD in Ireland. Males and females are affected&#xD;
      equally and patients can be diagnosed at any age, including babies and children. The peak age&#xD;
      of incidence is between the ages of 15 and 35, with a second (smaller) peak from the 50s to&#xD;
      70s.&#xD;
&#xD;
      GLM is a human IgG1κ monoclonal antibody produced by a murine hybridoma cell line with&#xD;
      recombinant DNA technology. It is part of the immunosuppressants pharmacotherapeutic group of&#xD;
      TNF-α inhibitors. It is licensed for use in several chronic inflammatory conditions including&#xD;
      UC, Psoriatic arthritis, axial spondylitis, rheumatoid arthritis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The design of GOAL-ARC aims to address the impact of dose escalation of GLM immediately&#xD;
      following induction and during the subsequent maintenance phase in response to suboptimal&#xD;
      drugs levels or persisting inflammatory burden as represented by raised faecal calprotectin&#xD;
      (FCP). FCP has been shown to correlate closely to endoscopic disease activity6.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>June 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Continuous Clinical Response (pCCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Wk 14 through to Wk 46</time_frame>
    <description>Absence of clinical flare, defined as an increase in modified partial Mayo score of 2 points value with accompanying requirement for treatment intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Mayo Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1, Week 46</time_frame>
    <description>The Total Mayo Score is a combined endoscopic and clinical scale used to assess the severity of UC. It is a composite of sub-scores from four categories, including stool frequency, rectal bleeding, findings at endoscopy and physician global assessment (PGA), with a total score ranging from 0 - 12.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Partial Mayo Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 14</time_frame>
    <description>Partial Mayo score consists of three subscores including stool frequency, rectal bleeding and PGA, a total score ranges from 0 - 9.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified Partial Mayo Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 1 to Week 46</time_frame>
    <description>A modified partial Mayo score comprises of the two PRO sub-scores, rectal bleeding and stool frequency</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Week 14 Clinical Response</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 14</time_frame>
    <description>A decrease from BL in partial Mayo score by ≥30% or a decrease of 3 points. or A decrease from BL in modified partial Mayo of 2 points or a decrease of ≥30% from baseline.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 46</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical remission is defined as a Mayo score ≤2 points, with no individual sub-score &gt;1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Flare</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 14 to Week 46</time_frame>
    <description>UC symptom recurrence as a defined by modified partial Mayo score increase of 2 points from week 14 value with accompanying requirement for treatment intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Corticosteroid Free Remission</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 46</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical remission at WK 46 with no concomitant steroids</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mucosal healing</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 46</time_frame>
    <description>A Mayo endoscopic subscore of 0 or 1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">136</enrollment>
  <condition>Colitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard treatment as per SmPC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive standard loading dose of GLM of 200/100 mgs at WKS 0 &amp; 2. They will then receive 100mgs/ 50mgs depending on their weight as per SmPC. Patients will report their modified partial mayo score and SHS score every 4 weeks (PRO) and provide it to the investigator site via a web based application.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive standard loading dose of GLM of 200/100 mgs at WKS 0 &amp; 2. As with Group 1, Patients will report their modified partial mayo and SHS score every four weeks ( the window for this will be +/- one week) and provide it to the investigator site via a web based application. In addition FCP, GLM DL and ADA shall be measured every four weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Golimumab (GLM)</intervention_name>
    <description>GLM is a human IgG1κ monoclonal antibody produced by a murine hybridoma cell line with recombinant DNA technology</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard treatment as per SmPC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients ≥ 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must be able and willing to give written informed consent and to comply with&#xD;
             the requirements of this study protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Established diagnosis of UC and moderate-to-severe disease activity, defined as a Mayo&#xD;
             score of 6-12, with an endoscopic subscore ≥2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients had an inadequate response to, or had failed to tolerate, 1 or more of the&#xD;
             following conventional therapies: oral 5-aminosalicylates, oral corticosteroids,&#xD;
             azathioprine (AZA), and/or 6-mercaptopurine (6MP); or corticosteroid dependent (ie, an&#xD;
             inability to taper corticosteroids without recurrence of UC symptoms).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients concurrently treated with oral 5-aminosalicylates or corticosteroids were to&#xD;
             receive a stable dose for at least 2 weeks before baseline, and patients receiving AZA&#xD;
             and/or 6MP were to receive a stable dose for at least 4 weeks before baseline.&#xD;
             Patients were required to maintain stable doses of their concomitant UC medications&#xD;
             during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects of child bearing potential must be willing to ensure that they or&#xD;
             their partner use effective contraception during the study and for 6 months thereafter&#xD;
             OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgical sterilized female patients with documentation of prior hysterectomy, tubal&#xD;
             ligation or complete bilateral oophorectomy OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postmenopausal women with postmenopausal defined as permanent cessation &gt;1 year of&#xD;
             previously occurring menses.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects' serum pregnancy test performed at the screening visit and urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test performed at the baseline visit must be negative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects have following investigations within 1 month prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Routine bloods including U&amp;E, FBC, LFTs, inflammatory markers (CRP) and albumin will&#xD;
             be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history, concomitant medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intradermal reaction to Tuberculin (PPD skin test) or Mycobacterium tuberculosis&#xD;
             antigenspecific interferon-gamma release assay (IGRA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TB screening: chest X-Ray unless performed in the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stool examination for enteric pathogens including Clostridium difficile&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion/exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mayo score (including sigmoidoscopy unless performed in previous 3 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's weight and height and abdominal circumference&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are pregnant or breast-feeding or considering becoming pregnant&#xD;
             during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged &lt;18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who cannot give informed consent,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients or those who are breastfeeding will be deemed ineligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with any anti-TNF agent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contra-indication to use of GLM (Hypersensitivity to the active substance or to any of&#xD;
             the excipients; Active tuberculosis (TB), acute or chronic Hepatitis B infection or&#xD;
             other severe infections such as sepsis and/or opportunistic infections including HIV&#xD;
             infection; Moderate or severe heart failure (NYHA class III/IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have symptoms or signs suggestive of current active or latent TB upon medical history,&#xD;
             physical examination and/or chest radiograph, or positive Mycobacterium tuberculosis&#xD;
             antigen-specific interferon-gamma release assay (IGRA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of, or at imminent risk for, colectomy; who required&#xD;
             gastrointestinal surgery within 2 months before screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of colonic mucosal dysplasia or adenomatous colonic polyps that were not&#xD;
             removed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Screening stool study positive for enteric pathogens or Clostridium difficile toxin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Oral corticosteroids at a dose &gt;40 mg prednisone or its equivalent per day; receipt of&#xD;
             cyclosporine, tacrolimus, sirolimus, or mycophenolate mofetil within 8 weeks before&#xD;
             the first study agent injection; or use of an investigational agent within 5&#xD;
             half-lives of that agent before the first study agent injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in recent receipt of live vaccinations within 4 weeks prior to enrolment&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Glen Doherty</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>g.doherty@st-vincents.ie</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peter Doran, PhD</last_name>
    <email>peter.doran@ucd.ie</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rabia Hussain</last_name>
    <email>rabia.hussain@ucd.ie</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Vincent's University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dublin</city>
        <country>Ireland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Glen Doherty</last_name>
      <email>g.doherty@st-vincents.ie</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Glen Doherty</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 16, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 19, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 22, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 18, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 18, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 19, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Golimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

