<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02689453</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>160062</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>16-C-0062</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02689453</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Subcutaneous Recombinant Human IL-15 (s.c. rhIL-15) and Alemtuzumab for People With Refractory or Relapsed Chronic and Acute Adult T-cell Leukemia (ATL)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Study of Subcutaneous Recombinant Human IL-15 (S.C. Rhil-15) and Alemtuzumab for Patients With Refractory or Relapsed Chronic and Acute Adult T-Cell Leukemia (ATL)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adult T-cell leukemia (ATL) is a rare blood cancer. Researchers want to see if a combination&#xD;
      of two drugs - recombinant human interleukin 15 (rhIL-15) and alemtuzumab - is a better&#xD;
      treatment for ATL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test if giving rhIL-15 combined with alemtuzumab improves the outcome of therapy for ATL.&#xD;
      Also, to determine the safe dose of this combination and identify side effects and effects on&#xD;
      the immune system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults 18 years and older with chronic or acute ATL who have not been helped by other&#xD;
      treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened with tests that are mostly part of their usual cancer care.&#xD;
      They will sign a separate consent form for this.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weeks 1 and 2: Participants will have a total of 10 visits. They will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Get rhIL-15 under the skin by needle.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a physical exam and vital signs measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Give blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Answer questions about their health and their medicines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Week 3: Participants will stay in the clinic. They will:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Get alemtuzumab infusions in a vein through a small catheter on days 1, 2, 3, and 5..&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Take medicines to decrease side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a computed tomography (CT) scan to evaluate the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Have a physical exam and vital signs measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Give blood samples.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Answer questions about their health and medicines.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weeks 4, 5, and 6 will repeat week 3, without the CT scan. Some patients will just have&#xD;
      outpatient visits these weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After treatment, participants will have follow-up visits every few months for up to 2 years.&#xD;
      At these visits, participants will give blood samples and have CT scans....&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A previous trial alemtuzumab (CAMPATH-1) in patients with chronic, acute and&#xD;
           lymphomatous subtype HTLV-1 associated ATL showed appreciable initial activity but no&#xD;
           clear long-term impact.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Antibody dependent cellular cytotoxicity (ADCC) with polymorphonuclear neutrophils&#xD;
           (PMNs), monocytes and natural killer (NK) cells acting as the effector cells is&#xD;
           alemtuzumab s primary in vivo mechanism of action for depleting malignant leukemic or&#xD;
           lymphomatous cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The immunologic effects of Interleukin-15 (IL-15), a stimulatory cytokine that promotes&#xD;
           the differentiation and activation of NK cells, monocytes and long-term CD8+ memory&#xD;
           Tcells, has been assessed in several phase I trials in cancer patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Administration of recombinant human (rh) IL-15 as an intravenous bolus (IVB), continuous&#xD;
           intravenous infusion (CIV) or subcutaneous injections (SC) into adult cancer patients&#xD;
           has produced 5 to 50 fold expansion in the number of circulating NK cells at well&#xD;
           tolerated doses in these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Preclinical murine lymphoid malignancy models have shown efficacy from the&#xD;
           administration of IL-15 and monoclonal antibodies, with improved survival compared to&#xD;
           controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      -To determine the safety, toxicity profile and the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) of s.c.&#xD;
      rhIL-15 in combination with standard three times per week IV alemtuzumab treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age greater than or equal to 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECOG Performance Status less than or equal to 1&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diagnosis of adult T-cell leukemia (HTLV-1 associated, chronic or acute), peripheral&#xD;
           T-cell lymphoma (angioimmunoblastic, hepatosplenic, or not otherwise specified),&#xD;
           cutaneous T-cell lymphoma (Stage III or IV, with leukemia involvement or erythrodemia),&#xD;
           or T-cell prolymphocytic leukemia (T-PLL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measurable or evaluable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adequate organ and bone marrow function as defined in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This is a single institution nonrandomized Phase I dose escalation study evaluating&#xD;
           increasing doses of SC rhIL-15 in combination with alemtuzumab using a standard 3 + 3&#xD;
           dose escalation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Treatment will include s.c. rhIL015 daily (M-F) weeks 1 and 2 (dose levels 0.5- 2&#xD;
           mcg/kg/dose), followed by IV alemtuzumab beginning in week 3 (escalating doses followed&#xD;
           by standard dosing in weeks 4-6).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Up to 30 patients will be enrolled in this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 19, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine MTD and DLTs of s.c. rhIL-15 administered with 3 times per week IV Alemtuzumab</measure>
    <time_frame>after 6 weeks of IL-15 and alemtuzumab</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events will be tabulated/reported by type, grade, and frequency.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical response rate and progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>after 6 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The response rate will be determined and reported along with a 95% confidence interval.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asses biological effects of rhIL-15 administered with alemtuzumab on the percentages and absolute numbers of circulating lymphocytes (T and NK cells) and the T-cell subsets naive, central and effector memory subsets</measure>
    <time_frame>after 6 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>characterize the biological effects of rhIL-15 administered with alemtuzumab by FACS analysis to define the percentages and absolute numbers of circulating lymphocytes (T and NK cells) and the T-cell subsets naive, central and effector memory subsets (based on expression of CD52, CD56, CD4, CD8, CD45RO, CD45RA, CD28, CD95, CD194, and CCR7) by flow cytometry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Define the effect of the combination on the plasma levels of pro-inflammatory cytokines</measure>
    <time_frame>after 6 weeks of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>define the effect of the combination on the plasma levels of proinflammatory cytokines using Mesoscale analysis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">11</enrollment>
  <condition>T-Cell Lymphoma Relapsed</condition>
  <condition>Adult T-Cell Leukemia (ATL)</condition>
  <condition>Peripheral T-Cell Lymphoma (PTCL)</condition>
  <condition>Cutaneous T Cell Lymphoma (CTCL)</condition>
  <condition>T-Cell Prolymphocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>IL-15 for 10 doses over two weeks followed byalemtuzumab for 4 weeks per dosing schema to determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>IL-15 for 10 doses over two weeks followed by alemtuzumab for 4 weeks at the maximum tolerateddose (MTD)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IL-15 plus alemtuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>rhIL-15 by s.c. injection Monday-Friday over two weeks; followed by alemtuzumab three times a week for a total of 4 weeks of alemtuzumab treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>1A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>1B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater than or equal to 18 years; no upper age limit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with a leukemia or lymphoma as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic or acute leukemia forms of HTLV-1 associated adult T-cell leukemia;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Peripheral T-cell lymphoma (angioimmunoblastic, hepatosplenic, or not otherwise&#xD;
                  specified); or,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cutaneous T-cell lymphoma stage III or IV with circulating monoclonal cells (B1&#xD;
                  or B2) and/or erythrodermia (T4)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  T-cell prolymphocytic leukemia (T-PLL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: Diagnosis must be validated by the Pathology Department, NCI.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Patients must have measurable or evaluable disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: All patients with greater than 10% abnormal CD4+ homogeneous CD3low strongly CD25+&#xD;
        expressing cells, or greater than 5% S(SqrRoot)(Copyright)zary cells/T-PLL, among the PBMCs&#xD;
        in the peripheral blood will be deemed to have evaluable disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal T cells must be CD52+ as assessed by flow cytometry or immunohistochemistry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a life expectancy of greater than or equal to 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have been refractory or relapsed following front line therapy for ATL;&#xD;
             those with CTCL or PTCL who have CD30+ disease must have progressed during or after&#xD;
             treatment with brentuximab vedotin, or are unable to receive treatment due to allergy&#xD;
             or intolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have recovered to less than grade 1 or to baseline from toxicity of&#xD;
             prior chemotherapy or biologic therapy and must not have had major surgery,&#xD;
             chemotherapy, radiation or biologic therapy within 2 weeks prior to beginning&#xD;
             treatment. NOTE: Exceptions to this include events not considered to place the subject&#xD;
             at unacceptable risk of participation in the opinion of the PI (e.g., alopecia).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DLCO/VA and FEV 1.0 &gt; 50% of predicted on pulmonary function tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate laboratory parameters, as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine of less than or equal to 1.5 x the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST and ALT &lt; 3 x the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count greater than or equal to 1,500/mm^3 and platelets greater&#xD;
             than or equal to 100,000/mm^3.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG less than or equal to 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be able to understand and sign an Informed Consent Form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients must use adequate contraception during participation in this trial and&#xD;
             for 4 months following completing therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received any systemic corticosteroid therapy within 4 weeks prior to&#xD;
             the start of therapy, or 12 weeks if given to treat graft versus host disease (GVHD),&#xD;
             with the exception of physiological replacement doses of cortisone acetate or&#xD;
             equivalent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have undergone allogeneic stem cell transplantation and have required&#xD;
             systemic treatment for GVHD (including but not limited to oral or parenteral&#xD;
             corticosteroids, ibrutinib, and extracorporeal phototherapy) within the last 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical evidence of (parenchymal or meningeal) CNS involvement or metastasis. In&#xD;
             subjects suspected of having CNS disease, a magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan of&#xD;
             the brain and lumbar puncture should be done to confirm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documented HIV, active bacterial infections, active or chronic hepatitis B, hepatitis&#xD;
             C.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Positive hepatitis B serology indicative of previous immunization (i.e., HBsAb&#xD;
                  positive and HBcAb negative) or a fully resolved acute hepatitis B infection is&#xD;
                  not an exclusion criterion.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  If hepatitis C antibody test is positive, then the patient must be tested for the&#xD;
                  presence of HCV by RT-PCR and be HCV RNA negative&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: HIV-positive patients are excluded from the study. Alemtuzumab may produce a&#xD;
        different pattern of toxicities in patients with HIV infection; in addition, the depletion&#xD;
        of T cells produced by alemtuzumab may have adverse effects on HIV-positive individuals.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent anticancer therapy (including other investigational agents).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe asthma or presently on chronic inhaled corticosteroid medications&#xD;
             (patients with a history of mild asthma not requiring corticosteroid therapy are&#xD;
             eligible).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with smoldering and lymphomatous ATL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have previously received alemtuzumab are ineligible. NOTE: Patients with&#xD;
             relapsed T-PLL who have achieved at least a partial response to prior alemtuzumab are&#xD;
             eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, moderate/severe graft versus host disease, cognitive impairment, active&#xD;
             substance abuse, or psychiatric illness/social situations that, in the view of the&#xD;
             Investigator, would preclude safe treatment or the ability to give informed consent&#xD;
             and limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Milos Miljkovic, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2016-C-0062.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 17, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 20, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 20, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 24, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>T-cell Lymphoproliferative Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>CD4/CD25 Expressing T-cells in Blood and Lymphoid Tissues</keyword>
  <keyword>Anti-CD52 Monoclonal Antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Antibody Dependent Cellular Cytotoxicity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia-Lymphoma, Adult T-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Peripheral</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, T-Cell, Cutaneous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Prolymphocytic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Prolymphocytic, T-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alemtuzumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

