<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01283789</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>12418</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01283789</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lapatinib and RAD-001 for HER2 Positive Metastatic Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Trial of Lapatinib and RAD-001 for HER2 Positive Metastatic Breast Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Kansas Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Novartis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>GlaxoSmithKline</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Kansas Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      By doing this study, researchers hope to learn the effectiveness of the combination of&#xD;
      Lapatinib and RAD-001 for treating patients who have progressed on previous therapies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Twenty to twenty five percent of Human Breast Cancers are HER2 positive. HER2 positivity&#xD;
      confers a poor prognosis in the absence of HER2 targeted therapies (trastuzumab and&#xD;
      lapatinib). With these targeted agents often combined with chemotherapy, the treatment of&#xD;
      HER2 positive breast cancer has improved greatly, both in metastatic and adjuvant settings.&#xD;
      However most patients with metastatic HER2 positive breast cancer will eventually develop&#xD;
      resistance to these agents and succumb to their disease. Therefore, there is a need to test&#xD;
      new agents and new combinations that can increase the efficacy of HER2 targeted therapy&#xD;
      and/or prevent resistance to HER2 targeted therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A unique feature of HER2 positive breast cancers is a rather high incidence of brain&#xD;
      metastasis in this population. Brain metastases develop in one third to one half of patients&#xD;
      with advanced HER2+ breast cancer and CNS is a frequent site of trastuzumab failure.&#xD;
      Effective therapy for patients with central nervous system (CNS) progression after cranial&#xD;
      radiation is extremely limited and represents a major clinical challenge. Compared to&#xD;
      trastuzumab, which has no CNS activity, lapatinib, an epidermal growth factor receptor/HER2&#xD;
      inhibitor, has modest CNS activity. In a study of more than 200 patients by Lin et al, 21% of&#xD;
      patients experienced a 20% volumetric reduction in their CNS lesions on lapatinib. An&#xD;
      association was observed between volumetric reduction and improvement in progression-free&#xD;
      survival and neurologic signs and symptoms. Of the 50 evaluable patients who entered the&#xD;
      lapatinib plus capecitabine extension, 20% experienced a CNS objective response and 40%&#xD;
      experienced a 20% volumetric reduction in their CNS lesions. Mammalian target of Rapamycin&#xD;
      (mTOR) is a serine/threonine kinase that regulates key functions associated with cell growth,&#xD;
      survival and angiogenesis. mTOR is activated by HER signaling, PI3K oncogenic mutation and&#xD;
      loss of PTEN function. In vitro data suggests that activation of mTOR by PTEN loss and PI3K&#xD;
      mutation induces trastuzumab resistance. Preclinical studies have shown that mTOR inhibition&#xD;
      enhances the efficacy of trastuzumab and reverses trastuzumab resistance caused by PTEN loss.&#xD;
      This preclinical finding was confirmed in 2 recent Phase 1 studies where addition of mTOR&#xD;
      inhibitor (RAD-001) to trastuzumab and chemotherapy reversed the resistance to Trastuzumab in&#xD;
      patients with heavily pretreated metastatic HER2 positive breast cancer. Thus, mTOR&#xD;
      inhibition would be an attractive modality to add to HER2 targeted therapy for improving&#xD;
      outcomes in women with HER2 positive breast cancer. Everolimus (RAD001), a rapamycin&#xD;
      analogue, is an orally administered inhibitor of mTOR. Everolimus has shown promising&#xD;
      activity in solid tumors. PK data in mouse models indicated that penetration of rapamycin and&#xD;
      Everolimus into the CNS is substantial. Everolimus brain levels are approximately one-third&#xD;
      that of systemic levels at 48 hours after a dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A small molecule inhibitor of HER2, lapatinib is clinically active in women with advanced&#xD;
      HER2-positive breast cancer who have progressed on trastuzumab treatment. However, the&#xD;
      effectiveness of this class of agents is limited by either primary resistance or acquired&#xD;
      resistance. Using an unbiased genetic approach, Eichhorn et al performed a genome wide&#xD;
      loss-of-function short hairpin RNA screen to identify novel modulators of resistance to&#xD;
      lapatinib. Tumor suppressor PTEN was identified as a modulator of lapatinib sensitivity in&#xD;
      vitro and in vivo. In addition, they show that two dominant activating mutations in PI3K&#xD;
      pathway which are prevalent in breast cancer, also confer resistance to lapatinib. They also&#xD;
      showed that PI3K-induced lapatinib resistance could be abrogated through the use of&#xD;
      NVP-BEZ235, a dual inhibitor of PI3K/mTOR. This suggests that deregulation of the PI3K&#xD;
      pathway leads to lapatinib resistance, which can be effectively reversed by inhibition of&#xD;
      PI3K/mTOR pathway.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, the combination of Everolimus and lapatinib needs to be studied in women with&#xD;
      metastatic breast cancer who have progressed on at least one prior anti-HER2 therapy. If&#xD;
      RAD-001 is able to overcome resistance to anti-HER2 therapies, a very desirable response rate&#xD;
      and prolongation in TTP can be expected. Moreover, both lapatinib and Everolimus appear to be&#xD;
      able to cross the blood brain barrier, and this combination may prove to be effective in&#xD;
      controling CNS metastases in this population. The investigators hypothesize that combining&#xD;
      mTOR inhibitor Everolimus with lapatinib will be an effective strategy for patients who have&#xD;
      progressed on a prior anti-HER2 therapy, both systemically and within the CNS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>February 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess the effectiveness of the combination of RAD-001 and lapatinib</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the effectiveness of the combination of RAD-001 and lapatinib as measured by the six-month Overall Response Rate in women with MBC who have progressed on trastuzumab and/or lapatinib based therapies.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall benefit of combination</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Six-month Progression Free Survival.&#xD;
Safety and Tolerability of the combination.&#xD;
Six-month Objective CNS response rate in patients with CNS metastases.&#xD;
Six-month Clinical benefit rate of systemic disease.&#xD;
Six-month Clinical benefit rate in the CNS.&#xD;
Rate of development of Brain Metastases on six months of therapy.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">23</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lapatinib and RAD-001</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>RAD-001 will be administered orally as a once-daily dose of 5 mg (one 5 mg tablet) continuously from study day 1 until progression of disease or unacceptable toxicity. Patients will be instructed to take RAD-001 in the morning, at the same time each day.&#xD;
Lapatinib will be administered orally as a once-daily dose of 1250 mg (five 250 mg tablets) continuously from study day 1 until progression of disease or unacceptable toxicity. Patients will be instructed to take lapatinib at bedtime, at the same time each day. Lapatinib should be taken by the patient in a fasting state.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lapatinib and RAD-001</intervention_name>
    <description>Lapatinib will be taken orally as a once-daily dose of 1250 mg (five 250 mg tablets) continuously from study day 1 until progression of disease. Patients will take the tablet at bedtime, at the same time each day, in a fasting state.&#xD;
Everolimus will be taken orally as a once-daily dose of 5 mg (one 5 mg tablet) from study day 1 until progression of disease. Patients will take the tablet at the same time each morning.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lapatinib and RAD-001</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>everolimus</other_name>
    <other_name>tykerb</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females &gt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically proven adenocarcinoma of breast in primary or metastatic setting.&#xD;
             Stage: Locally advanced (inoperable) or metastatic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HER2 positive breast cancer (IHC 3+ or FISH ratio of &gt; 2.0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance status 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Up to four prior chemotherapy regimens and anti-HER2 agents in metastatic setting&#xD;
             allowed. Must have progressed on at least one HER2 targeted therapy (lapatinib or&#xD;
             Herceptin) for metastatic breast cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential must have negative urine or serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 7 days prior to administration of Everolimus. If barrier contraceptives are&#xD;
             used, they must be continued throughout trial by both sexes. Hormonal contraceptives&#xD;
             not acceptable as a sole method of contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate kidney function: serum creatinine of &lt; 1.5 mg/dl and/or creatinine clearance&#xD;
             of &gt; 60 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate hepatic function: transaminases &lt; 2.5 x upper limit of normal (up to 5 x ULN&#xD;
             in patients with liver metastases) and total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL. Adequate&#xD;
             coagulation: INR ≤ 2.0 and PTT &lt; 1.5 X the upper limit of institution normal range.&#xD;
             Oral anticoagulants, eg, warfarin are CYP2C9 substrates and, as such, no interaction&#xD;
             with Everolimus is expected. Anticoagulation with Coumadin is allowed if target INR is&#xD;
             ≤ 2.0 and stable for &gt; 2weeks. Anticoagulation with LMW is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be informed of investigational nature of study, and must sign an informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pretreatment lab values (must be performed within 14 days of patient registration&#xD;
             unless otherwise specified. Other baseline studies must be performed within 30 days of&#xD;
             registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients will have baseline CT chest, abdomen and pelvis within 30 days of&#xD;
             registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate cardiac function (LVEF ≥ 50% as measured by echocardiogram or MUGA scan).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting serum cholesterol ≤ 300 mg/dL OR ≤ 7.75 mmol/L AND fasting triglycerides ≤ 2.5&#xD;
             x ULN. NOTE: In case one or both of these thresholds are exceeded, patient may be&#xD;
             included after initiation of appropriate lipid lowering medication with approval from&#xD;
             the principal investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have measurable or non-measurable disease by RECIST criteria (version 1.1), with&#xD;
             radiologic scans performed within 30 days of registration. Baseline scans can include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CT Scan or MRI and Bone Scan OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PET/CT provided it is performed with both IV and oral contrast and the CT is&#xD;
                  acquired with 5mm or less slice thickness. If IV contrast administration is&#xD;
                  contraindicated, patients should have CT scan without contrast and bone scan or&#xD;
                  MRI and bone scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MRI of brain will be used for baseline assessment and tumor response assessment&#xD;
                  for CNS lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with CNS progression without systemic progression will be allowed to&#xD;
                  remain on the protocol. Local treatment, radiation, surgery, and SRS will be&#xD;
                  allowed while on protocol as deemed necessary by the treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Baseline imaging method(s) should be used to determine tumor response throughout&#xD;
                  course of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Measurable disease: lesions with clearly defined margins that can be accurately&#xD;
                  measured in at least one diameter (longest diameter to be recorded) with a&#xD;
                  minimum size of:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  10mm by CT scan (CT scan slice thickness no greater than 5mm)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  10mm caliper measurement by clinical exam (lesions which cannot be&#xD;
                       accurately measured with calipers should be recorded as non-measurable)&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  20mm by chest xray&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Malignant lymph nodes: to be considered pathologically enlarged and&#xD;
                       measurable. Lymph node must be &gt; 15mm in short axis when assessed by CT&#xD;
                       scan. At baseline and in follow-up, only short axis will be measured and&#xD;
                       followed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Non-measurable disease: all other lesions including small lesions (longest&#xD;
                  diameter &lt; 10mm or pathological lymph nodes with &gt; to &lt;15 mm (short axis), and&#xD;
                  masses with margins not clearly defined. Lesions that are considered&#xD;
                  non-measurable include:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Bone lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Pleural/pericardial effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Inflammatory breast disease&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Abdominal masses that are not confirmed and followed by imaging techniques&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Cystic lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Lymphangitic involvement of skin or lung&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The following pre-study tests should be obtained within 14 days prior to registration&#xD;
             in accordance with good medical practice. Results of these tests do not determine&#xD;
             eligibility and minor deviations are acceptable if they do not impact patient safety&#xD;
             in the judgment of the treating physician:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ANC &gt; 1,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  platelet count &gt; 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  hemoglobin &gt; 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received prior lapatinib for metatastic breast cancer will be&#xD;
             excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection requiring parenteral antibiotics or psychiatric illness/social situations&#xD;
             that would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GI tract disease resulting in an inability to take oral medication, malabsorption&#xD;
             syndrome, a requirement for IV alimentation, prior surgical procedures affecting&#xD;
             absorption, uncontrolled inflammatory GI disease (eg, Crohn's, ulcerative colitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current active hepatic or biliary disease (exception of patients with Gilbert's&#xD;
             syndrome, asymptomatic gallstones, liver metastases or stable chronic liver disease&#xD;
             per investigator assessment)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and lactating women. Women of reproductive potential not using or unwilling&#xD;
             to use effective birth control methods throughout the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe and/or uncontrolled medical conditions or other conditions that could affect&#xD;
             participation in the study such as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptomatic congestive heart failure of NYHA Class III or IV&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  unstable angina pectoris, symptomatic congestive heart failure, myocardial&#xD;
                  infarction within 6 months of start of study drug, serious uncontrolled cardiac&#xD;
                  arrhythmia or any other clinically significant cardiac disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  liver disease such as cirrhosis or severe hepatic impairment (Child-Pugh class&#xD;
                  C). Note: A detailed assessment of Hepatitis B/C medical history and risk factors&#xD;
                  must be done at screening for all patients. HBV DNA and HCV RNA PCR testing&#xD;
                  required at screening for all patients with a positive medical history based on&#xD;
                  risk factors and/or confirmation of prior HBV/HCV infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with symptomatic brain metastases who have not completed radiation therapy&#xD;
             and/or are receiving systemic steroid therapy. Patients with leptomeningeal disease&#xD;
             will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with CNS progression during the trial will be allowed to receive local&#xD;
             treatment for CNS metastases and will remain on protocol. Trial medications will be&#xD;
             held during hte time patients are receiving radiation therapy as dictated by their&#xD;
             treating physicians.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving chronic, systemic treatment with corticosteroids (of more than&#xD;
             4mg/day or equivalent of dexamethasone. Doses of dexamethasone of up to 8mg/day may be&#xD;
             administered for less than 2 weeks) or another immunosuppressive agent. Topical or&#xD;
             inhaled corticosteroids are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should not receive immunization with attenuated live vaccines within one week&#xD;
             of study entry or during study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severely impaired lung function defined as spirometry and DLCO that is &lt; 50% of the&#xD;
             normal predicted value and/or 02 saturation that is 88% or less at rest on room air.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled diabetes as defined by fasting serum glucose &gt;1.5 x ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active (acute or chronic) or uncontrolled severe infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of HIV seropositivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active, bleeding diathesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received prior treatment with an mTOR inhibitor (eg, sirolimus,&#xD;
             temsirolimus, everolimus).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity to Everolimus or other rapamycins (eg, sirolimus, temsirolimus)&#xD;
             or to its excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active Hepatitis B or C infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of &lt; 2 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior anti-cancer therapy (eg, biologic or other targeted therapy, chemotherapy,&#xD;
             hormonal therapy) within 2 weeks prior to Day 1 if the patient has recovered from all&#xD;
             AEs to grade 1 except for alopecia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior investigational anti-cancer therapy within 4 weeks prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had a major surgery or significant traumatic injury within 4 weeks&#xD;
             of start of study drug, have not recovered from side effects of any major surgery&#xD;
             (defined as requiring general anesthesia) or may require major surgery during the&#xD;
             course of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other malignancies within past 3 years except for adequately treated carcinoma of&#xD;
             cervix or basal or squamous cell carcinomas of the skin.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Qamar Khan, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Kansas Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Kansas Medical Centner</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66160</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 10, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 25, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 26, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 6, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 6, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 8, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>breast</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>metastatic</keyword>
  <keyword>metastasis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lapatinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

