<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03733080</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999919012</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>19-N-N012</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03733080</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Large-Scale Online Studies of Early Motor Skill Learning</brief_title>
  <official_title>Large-scale Online Studies of Motor Responses and Cognition</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our goal is to gain insight into early human motor skill learning by carrying out online&#xD;
      substudies using online crowd-sourcing tools.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn more about motor behavior in a large group of people using motor tasks, and&#xD;
      questions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 18 and older based in the U.S. who speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be recruited from a crowd-sourcing website like Amazon Mechanical Turk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will do online tasks. They can use their own computers anywhere with Internet&#xD;
      access. They will not need to directly interact with researchers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be asked for general data, like their age and gender. No personally&#xD;
      identifiable data will be collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will see a list of tasks on their computer screen. They will be able to choose&#xD;
      tasks they wish to do. They will get a description of the experiment, how long it takes, and&#xD;
      how much compensation they will get.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete on their screen a motor behavioral task, a cognitive task, and/or&#xD;
      a questionnaire. For example, they may be asked to press sequences of numbers on the keyboard&#xD;
      or move the mouse when a stimulus appears on the screen. Experiments may last up to 1 hour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants can complete as many experiments as they wish. They can quit at any point.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our overall goal in this protocol has been to gain insight into early motor skill learning&#xD;
      (micro-learning) in large-scale healthy volunteer cohorts using online crowd-sourcing. We&#xD;
      have used a simple keyboard typing task to study micro-offline performance improvements&#xD;
      during early motor skill learning. This online approach limits the burden on participants&#xD;
      (who perform tasks in the comfort of their homes instead of traveling to NIH) and&#xD;
      substantially reduces burden on in-house human, financial and technical resources. Results&#xD;
      from this protocol contribute to a better understanding of factors relevant to human motor&#xD;
      skill learning, with important implications for the design of better motor learning and&#xD;
      neurorehabilitative strategies after brain lesions. We had completed data collection for four&#xD;
      aims under this protocol at the time we were informed by the NIH IRB that they determined&#xD;
      this to be a thematic protocol (September 23, 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The four specific aims addressed under this protocol are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Aim 1. To validate a motor skill learning task previously used by our group in lab-based&#xD;
           studies {Bonstrup, 2019 #36} within an online, crowd-sourcing platform.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Aim 2. To compare the influence of an interfering task applied during early (&quot;early&#xD;
           interference&quot;) vs late (&quot;late interference&quot;) rest periods on motor learning, thus&#xD;
           evaluating resistance to interference, a feature of consolidation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Aim 3. To evaluate the effects of a shorter practice period duration (i.e. - 5s vs.&#xD;
           previously studied 10s duration) on micro-offline motor learning to gain insight into&#xD;
           the impact of fatigue-related factors on learning.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Aim 4. To evaluate the effects of randomly variable practice period durations between&#xD;
           5-10s in length on micro-offline gains&#xD;
&#xD;
      As instructed, the purpose of this amendment is to request authorization to proceed with data&#xD;
      analysis and publication. No new experiments will be carried out under this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      U.S.-based English speakers aged 18 and above were recruited under this minimal risk&#xD;
      protocol. Participants completed an online task in the comfort of their own homes using the&#xD;
      internet, and did not need to directly interact with the investigators. All participants were&#xD;
      given an anonymized random ID by the on-line site. We did collect general demographic&#xD;
      information including age (needed to determine elegibility), and gender, race and ethnicity&#xD;
      (per IRB reporting requirements, i.e. - Cumulative Inclusion Enrollment Report). However, we&#xD;
      did not collect personally identifiable information (PII) about the participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Under this protocol, we have conducted experiments supporting four aims using Amazon&#xD;
      Mechanical Turk (AMT). All experiments consisted of a brief keyboard typing task where&#xD;
      participants were asked to repeatedly type a 5-key sequence (4-1-3-2-4) as fast and as&#xD;
      accurately as possible for several seconds (i.e. - practice trial). Each practice trial was&#xD;
      followed by a rest period lasting several seconds. Following the task, participants completed&#xD;
      a short questionnaire designed to query compliance with task instructions, and collect&#xD;
      general demographic data required for IRB reporting. The average total time for participation&#xD;
      across all experiments was approximately 20 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome measures for the keyboard typing task were correct sequence typing speed&#xD;
      and typing accuracy. Microlearning scores were derived by quantifying the speed change&#xD;
      between the end of a previous practice trial and the beginning of the subsequent one&#xD;
      (micro-offline learning) and the speed difference between the beginning and end of the same&#xD;
      practice trial (micro-online learning). Information from the questionaires related to task&#xD;
      instruction compliance was primarily used to exclude data from further analysis if needed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 9, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 17, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 17, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>data analysis</measure>
    <time_frame>in data analysis</time_frame>
    <description>Aim 1. To validate a motor skill learning task previously used by our group in lab-based studies {Bonstrup, 2019 #36} within an online, crowd-sourcing platform. Aim 2. To compare the influence of an interfering task applied during early ( early interference group) vs late ( late interference ) rest periods on stabilization of motor learning. Aim 3. To evaluate the effects of shorter practice period durations (i.e. - 5s vs. previously studied 10s duration) on micro-offline motor learning to gain insight into the impact of fatigue-relatedfactors on learning. Aim 4. To evaluate the effects of randomly variable practice period durations between 5-10s in length on micro-offline gains</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2529</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <description>ages 18 and older</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        A total of 2,529 volunteers have participated in this protocol. It is possible that some of&#xD;
        these participants may have been NIH or NINDS employees, since participant identities were&#xD;
        anonymous to the experimenters. Data aquired from 97 participants was used for testing and&#xD;
        debugging the typing task application during initial technical development. These data are&#xD;
        not useable for research purposes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        U.S.-based English speakers greater than 18 years of age are eligible to participate in the&#xD;
        study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects are excluded if they are less than 18 years of age. NIH and NINDS employees are&#xD;
        not excluded from the study, since participation is anonymous and personal identifiers&#xD;
        unknown to the experimenters.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Leonardo G Cohen, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 29, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 6, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 6, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 7, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>AMT</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

