<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03736473</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D6070C00006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03736473</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase I Study of MEDI9447 (Oleclumab) in Japanese Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I, Open-label Study to Assess the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Anti-tumor Activity of MEDI9447 (Oleclumab) in Japanese Patients With Advanced Solid Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase I, open-label study to assess the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and&#xD;
      preliminary anti-tumor activity of MEDI9447 in Japanese patients with advanced solid&#xD;
      malignancies.This study consists of 2 cohorts. Cohort 1 (dose level 1) and Cohort 2 (dose&#xD;
      level 2). At least 3 or up to 6 evaluable Japanese patients with advanced solid malignancies&#xD;
      will be enrolled in each cohort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the safety and tolerability, describe any dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) for MEDI9447&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To determine the pharmacokinetics (PK) characteristics of MEDI9447 To determine the&#xD;
      immunogenicity of MEDI9447 To evaluate candidate biomarker of MEDI9447 activity in archival&#xD;
      tumor biopsy specimens To describe the preliminary antitumor activity of MEDI9447&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To explore profile of biomarker status, with MEDI9447 treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a phase I, open-label study to assess the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and&#xD;
      preliminary anti-tumor activity of MEDI9447 in Japanese patients with advanced solid&#xD;
      malignancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study consists of 2 cohorts. Cohort (dose level 1) and Cohort 2 (dose level 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At least 3 or up to 6 evaluable Japanese patients with advanced solid malignancies will be&#xD;
      enrolled in each cohort. The total number of subjects will depend upon the available data in&#xD;
      each cohort and Safety Review Committee (SRC)'s decision.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Period:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is expected to start in October 2018 and end in July 2019.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of Subjects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maximum 12 evaluable patients will be enrolled in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatments and treatment duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will receive MEDI9447 on Day 1 and Day 15 in a 4-week cycle. Subjects participating&#xD;
      in the study may continue to receive study treatment(s) as long as they are continuing to&#xD;
      show clinical benefit, as judged by the Investigator, unless the subject has progressive&#xD;
      disease (PD) with either clinical deterioration and/or no further benefit from treatment,&#xD;
      experiences unacceptable toxicity, or should discontinue for any other reason. In such cases,&#xD;
      the Investigator needs to consult with the sponsor and they agree to continue study treatment&#xD;
      in advance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this study is to assess the safety and tolerability profile of&#xD;
      MEDI9447.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All safety data will be summarized using the safety analysis set (All subjects who received&#xD;
      at least 1 dose of MEDI9447). Evaluations of safety and tolerability will include, but not be&#xD;
      limited to, AEs, physical examinations, laboratory findings (including clinical chemistry,&#xD;
      hematology, and urinalysis), vital signs (including blood pressure and pulse), and&#xD;
      electrocardiograms using summary statistics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For secondary and exploratory efficacy endpoints, all analyses will be descriptive, and no&#xD;
      formal statistical testing will be performed. Data will be summarized and plotted&#xD;
      appropriately according to data type.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PK concentration data for MEDI9447 will be listed for each subject and each dosing day, and&#xD;
      summary statistics will be tabulated. Immunogenicity results will be listed by subject, and&#xD;
      summaries of the number and percentage of subjects who develop detectable antidrug antibodies&#xD;
      (ADAs) against MEDI9447 will be provided. The immunogenicity titre will be listed for samples&#xD;
      confirmed positive for the presence of ADAs. Neutralizing ADAs may be reported for samples&#xD;
      confirmed positive for the presence of ADAs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All analyses and reporting will be conducted for each cohort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 7, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 19, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 19, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>From the informed consent to 90 days after the last dose</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the safety and tolerability, describe any dose-limiting toxicity (DLT) for MEDI9447</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">6</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Solid Malignancies</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI9447 monotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Dose escalation of MEDI9447 monotherapy for patients with advanced solid malignancies</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MEDI9447 (oleclumab)</intervention_name>
    <description>MEDI9447 administered intravenously</description>
    <arm_group_label>MEDI9447 monotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Major Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult subjects; age ≥ 20 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a histologically confirmed solid malignancy that is refractory to standard therapy&#xD;
             or for which no standard of care regimen currently exists&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must have at least 1 lesion that is measureable using RECIST v1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All subjects must consent to provide archived tumor specimens for biomarker studies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG Performance Status of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy ≥12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ function&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight ≥ 35 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
        Major Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have completed any previous cancer-related treatments before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with CD73 antagonist, tumor necrosis factor receptor superfamily&#xD;
             agonists&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All CTLA-4, PD-1, or PD-L1 antagonists related-AEs must have resolved to ≤ NCI CTCAE&#xD;
             v4.03 Grade 1 or baseline prior to screening and not worsened before the first dose of&#xD;
             study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must not have required the use of additional immunosuppression other than&#xD;
             corticosteroids for the management of an CTLA-4, PD-1, or PD-L1 related AE, not have&#xD;
             experienced recurrence of an AE if re-challenged, and not currently require&#xD;
             maintenance doses of &gt; 10 mg prednisone or equivalent per day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or hypersensitivity to the study drug, its compounds, or agents similar&#xD;
             biologic composition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of more than one event of IRR requiring permanent discontinuation of IV drug&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of severe drug allergies or anaphylaxis to 2 or more food products or medicine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiac or peripheral vascular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NCI CTCAE v4.03 Grade 3 or greater edema&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled massive ascites or pleural effusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of NCI CTCAE v4.03 Grade 3 or greater thromboembolic events within 3 months&#xD;
             prior to the first dose of study drug or thromboembolic event of any grade with&#xD;
             ongoing symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active tuberculosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with history of, or current ILD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active or prior documented autoimmune within the past 3 years prior to the start of&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated or unstable CNS metastatic disease, leptomeningeal disease, or cord&#xD;
             compression&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent enrollment in another clinical study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any concurrent chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or biologic or hormonal therapy for cancer&#xD;
             treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Toxicities from prior anticancer therapy that have not resolved to ≤ NCI CTCAE v4.03&#xD;
             Grade 1 or baseline prior to the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of primary immunodeficiency or solid organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis B, hepatitis C, or HIV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females who are pregnant, lactating, or intend to become pregnant during their&#xD;
             participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other invasive malignancy within 2 years prior to the first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled concomitant illnes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Judgment by the Investigator that the patient is unsuitable to participate in the&#xD;
             study and the patient is unlikely to comply with study procedures, restrictions, and&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Involvement in the planning and/or conduct of the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chuo-ku</city>
        <zip>104-0045</zip>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 7, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 7, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 4, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 4, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

