<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00592449</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NA_00011802</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01AR054871</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00592449</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sleep in Osteoarthritis Project</brief_title>
  <acronym>SOAP</acronym>
  <official_title>Sleep Disturbance, Central Pain Modulation, and Clinical Pain in Osteoarthritis (The SOAP Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Johns Hopkins University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases (NIAMS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Johns Hopkins University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Osteoarthritis (OA) is one of the most common diseases and one of the leading causes of&#xD;
      disability in the world. People with OA frequently experience sleep disturbances, primarily&#xD;
      due to pain. Although insomnia is a known consequence of OA, recent studies have shown that&#xD;
      it may also worsen clinical pain by interfering with the body's responses to painful stimuli.&#xD;
      This study will evaluate the effectiveness of behavioral treatments for insomnia in reducing&#xD;
      sleep disturbances, thereby reducing clinical pain in people with knee OA. The study will&#xD;
      test whether improvement in clinical pain are mediated by changes in certain types of pain&#xD;
      processing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Sleep disturbance and pain are two of the most common and disabling symptoms of OA. Sleep&#xD;
      disturbances have been shown to worsen clinical pain by impairing some of the body's central&#xD;
      pain processing mechanisms. Sufficient research is lacking, however, on what treatments may&#xD;
      be effective for sleep disturbance in people with OA or whether normalization of sleep&#xD;
      patterns in people with OA will reduce their pain. This study will evaluate the effectiveness&#xD;
      of behavioral treatments for insomnia in reducing sleep disturbances, thereby reducing&#xD;
      clinical pain in people with knee OA.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in Phase 1 of this study will be separated into the following four groups:&#xD;
      people with OA and insomnia; people with OA, but without insomnia; people without OA, but&#xD;
      with insomnia; and people without OA or insomnia. All participants will attend two study&#xD;
      visits. During Visit 1, participants will complete questionnaires and an interview and will&#xD;
      provide a urine sample and a set of recent x-rays. A diary, which will be used to record&#xD;
      activity levels for 2 weeks, will also be given to all participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Optional Ancillary Sleep and Immunoreactivity Study Procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who pass the visit one screen will be provided the option of participating in&#xD;
      ancillary study procedures designed to assess inflammatory biomarkers present in plasma,&#xD;
      physical functioning capabilities, and pain and mood status during the pain testing&#xD;
      procedures. Subjects will be asked to give blood samples during the pain testing procedures,&#xD;
      followed by standardized tests of physical function. Subjects will be also asked to complete&#xD;
      additional questionnaire and diary items that ask them to rate their emotions during the pain&#xD;
      testing procedures and during the days that they keep their electronic diary for the parent&#xD;
      project. At Visit 2, participants will undergo pain testing, an in-home sleep study and&#xD;
      optional procedures outlined above. At Visit 3, participants with knee osteoarthritis will&#xD;
      have an exam by a rheumatologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in Phase 1 who have both knee OA and insomnia will be asked to continue into&#xD;
      Phase 2, which will last 8 months. These participants will be randomly assigned to receive&#xD;
      two different forms of behavioral treatment, cognitive behavior therapy (CBT) or a behavioral&#xD;
      desensitization treatment. Participants assigned to both treatments will meet with a&#xD;
      psychologist once a week for 8 weeks. Participants will learn new sleeping habits and mental&#xD;
      exercises designed to reduce arousal and alertness while trying to sleep. All participants&#xD;
      will attend four assessment visits over the course of Phase 2. The first visit will occur at&#xD;
      Week 4 and will include completing questionnaires and undergoing pain testing. The second&#xD;
      visit will occur at Week 8 and will include the same questionnaires, further pain testing&#xD;
      with optional blood draws and physical tests and an in-home sleep study. Two weeks before&#xD;
      assessment Visit 3, participants will receive a diary in the mail, which they will use to&#xD;
      keep track of their pain, sleep, medications, and symptoms until Visit 3. Assessment Visit 3&#xD;
      will take place at Month 5 and will include the same procedures followed during Visit 2.&#xD;
      Participants will complete a second diary 2 weeks before Visit 4. At Visit 4, which will&#xD;
      occur at Month 8, the same procedures completed at Visits 2 and 3 will be repeated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>April 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in sleep disturbances</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Weeks 4 and 8 and Months 5 and 8</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reduction in OA-related pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured at Weeks 4 and 8 and Months 5 and 8</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">209</enrollment>
  <condition>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Osteoarthritis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with knee OA who meet research diagnostic criteria for insomnia will partake in Phase 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants with knee OA who meet research diagnostic criteria for normal sleep will partake in Phase 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants without knee OA or a pain syndrome who meet research diagnostic criteria for primary insomnia will partake in Phase 1</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants without knee OA or a pain syndrome who meet research diagnostic criteria for normal sleep will enroll in Phase I</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>5</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phase 1 participants with knee OA who meet research diagnostic criteria for insomnia will enroll in Phase 2 of the study and are assigned to receive behavioral desensitization treatment for insomnia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>6</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phase 1 participants with knee OA who meet research diagnostic criteria for insomnia will enroll in Phase 2 of the study and are assigned to receive cognitive behavior therapy for insomnia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive behavioral therapy (CBT) for insomnia</intervention_name>
    <description>During CBT, participants will learn how to change their sleeping habits and reduce arousal and alertness while trying to sleep. Participants will attend 8 weekly CBT sessions with a psychologist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>6</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CBT-I</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Behavioral desensitization treatment for insomnia</intervention_name>
    <description>The behavioral desensitization treatment is designed to decondition states of arousal that interfere with sleep. Participants will attend 8 weekly behavioral desensitization treatment sessions with a psychologist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>5</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        For all participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 50 ; or 35 ≥ if KOA/Insomnia group&#xD;
&#xD;
        For participants with knee OA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets American College of Rheumatology (ACR) criteria for knee OA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shows radiographic evidence of Kellgren-Lawrence Grade OA greater than or equal to 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Experiences knee pain more than 5 days per week for more than 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reports at least typical arthritic pain (a score of at least 2 out of 10, with 0 being&#xD;
             no pain and 10 being the most extreme pain imaginable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients taking non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) or acetaminophen must&#xD;
             be on a stable dose for at least 1 month prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not scheduled for arthroplasty or surgery during projected period of study&#xD;
             participation&#xD;
&#xD;
        For participants with insomnia:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A sleep maintenance insomnia profile is evident both at study entry (based on&#xD;
             retrospective reports) and as an average profile from 2 weeks of sleep diaries&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets diagnostic criteria for insomnia due to knee OA only or for primary insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reports total sleep time less than 6.5 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Middle insomnia symptom frequency of more than 3 nights per week for more than 1 month&#xD;
&#xD;
        For participants without insomnia:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meets research diagnostic criteria for normal sleepers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insomnia Severity Index of less than 10&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Epworth Sleepiness score of less than 10&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index score of less than 5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Wake After Sleep Onset Time is under 30 minutes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sleep efficiency percentage is greater than 85%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total sleep time is greater than 6.5 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
        For participants without knee OA and without insomnia:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Free from any acute pain or injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No recent history of chronic pain within 3 years prior to study entry (pain severity&#xD;
             report greater than 2 out of 10 more than 2 days per week for 6 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reports good overall health, with no major medical or psychiatric illness known to&#xD;
             disturb sleep or cause pain&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sleep disorders other than insomnia (e.g., obstructive sleep apnea, periodic limb&#xD;
             movement disorder, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Apnea/Hypopnea Index (AHI) of greater than 15&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant rheumatologic or painful disorders other than knee OA (including&#xD;
             fibromyalgia, rheumatoid arthritis, neuralgia, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any major medical diseases known to impact sleep or cause pain (including chronic&#xD;
             obstructive pulmonary disease, diabetes, congestive heart failure, seizure disorder,&#xD;
             Raynaud's phenomenon, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia or cognitive impairment, defined as Mini Mental State Exam score of less than&#xD;
             24&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or recent history of major psychiatric disorders (within 3 months prior to&#xD;
             study entry)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of schizophrenia or bipolar I disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Center for Epidemiologic Studies of Depression Scale (CES-D) greater than or equal to&#xD;
             27 or suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or history of substance abuse (within 6 months prior to study entry)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of antidepressants, antipsychotics, or mood stabilizers more than 3 days per week&#xD;
             in the past 2 months- Note: only applies to groups other than KOA/Insomnia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of narcotics (opioids), myorelaxants, sedatives, or anticonvulsants more than 3&#xD;
             days per week within 1 month prior to study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to discontinue all use of certain medications by 1 week prior to&#xD;
             study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refuses to contact physician to obtain relevant medical record information&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or plans to become pregnant within 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive toxicology test (benzodiazepines and receptor agonists, barbiturates,&#xD;
             opioids, tetrahydrocannabinol, alcohol, and stimulants)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>35 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael T. Smith, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center 5510 Nathan Shock Dr, Ste 100</name>
      <address>
        <city>Baltimore</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>21224</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 28, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 28, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 14, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 22, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 22, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 23, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Insomnia</keyword>
  <keyword>Knee pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Osteoarthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>Arthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>Sleep</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Initiation and Maintenance Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

