<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00592618</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>346147SLEEP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00592618</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of NAC on Sleep Apnea</brief_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assaf-Harofeh Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assaf-Harofeh Medical Center</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sleep studies in ESRD patients have identified increased prevalence of Sleep Apnea. Based on&#xD;
      current knowledge, treatment aimed at reducing oxidative stress might improve Sleep Apnea in&#xD;
      HD patients. The aim of our study is to investigate the effect of N-acetylsysteine on Sleep&#xD;
      Apnea in HD patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background Cardiovascular disease is the commonest cause of morbidity and mortality in&#xD;
      chronic dialysis patients [1]. Sleep studies in ESRD patients have identified increased&#xD;
      prevalence of sleep apnea (SA), both obstructive (OSA) and central (CSA) in origin [2]. The&#xD;
      reported prevalence of SA in patients with ESRD ranges from 50% to 70% [3], which is&#xD;
      dramatically higher than the estimated prevalence of 2% to 4% in the general population [4].&#xD;
      SA has been recognized as a novel risk factor for cardiovascular disease in general&#xD;
      population [5]. Recent evidence showed that severity of SA in hemodialysis patients is&#xD;
      associated with severity of coronary artery calcifications [6]. Underlying mechanisms by&#xD;
      which SA adversely affects cardiovascular morbidity and mortality have not been fully&#xD;
      established yet. The presence of untreated SA may further impair fluid balance,&#xD;
      cardiovascular function and increase mortality through abnormal vagal or sympatomimetic&#xD;
      responces and hypoxia [7]. One intriguing possibility is oxidative stress, which has been&#xD;
      implicated in cardiovascular disease in patients with ESRD [8]. Recent study demonstrated&#xD;
      association between SA and decreased antioxidant status in hemodialysis patients [6].&#xD;
      Repeated apnea-related hypoxic events in patients with SA may trigger elevated oxidative&#xD;
      stress [9].&#xD;
&#xD;
      In general population, the treatment of SA with CPAP improves oxygenation during sleep and&#xD;
      quality of life [10]. In the ESRD population, CPAP was used in a very preliminary study on 8&#xD;
      patients with some improvement in nocturnal oxygenation and 5 of 6 patients reported improved&#xD;
      daytime alertness [11]. Unfortunately, CPAP application itself may be stressful, poorly&#xD;
      tolerated and so disturb night sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hanly and Pierratos suggested that SA in hemodialysis patients may be a consequence of&#xD;
      inadequate treatment of uremia by standard 4-hours thrice-weekly HD procedure [12]. This&#xD;
      group reported that intensive nocturnal HD for 8 hours 6-7 times per week reduced the&#xD;
      severity of SA, although their patients continued to suffer from frequent arousals,&#xD;
      diminished sleep time, REM sleep and sleep efficiency [12]. Restoration of normal kidney&#xD;
      function by transplantation may lead to reversal of SA [13, 14].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several experimental and clinical studies showed that increased oxidative stress in dialysis&#xD;
      patients may be due to inhibition of nitric oxide (NO) synthesis by ADMA (Asymmetric&#xD;
      Dimethylarginine ), known to be endogenous inhibitor of NO synthetase [15]. ADMA may be&#xD;
      significantly reduced by dialysis [16]. Metabolism of ADMA is primarily by the enzyme DDAH ,&#xD;
      which activity is decreased by inflammation, oxidative stress, diabetes mellitus and&#xD;
      hypercholesterolemia [17 ]. It was proposed that circulating ADMA may be one mechanism&#xD;
      accounting for the resistant hypertension and overfluid in dialysis patients [17 ].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on current knowledge, treatment aimed at reducing oxidative stress should decrease ADMA&#xD;
      levels [17 ], and it is logical to suggest that such a therapy might improve SA in HD&#xD;
      patients. One preliminary study on effect of antioxidant Vitamin E showed a small beneficial&#xD;
      effect on ADMA in chronic kidney disease [19 ].&#xD;
&#xD;
      In our opinion, it is worth to check an ability of antioxidant therapy to produce a favorable&#xD;
      effect on parameters of SA in dialysis patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      N-Acetylcysteine (NAC) is an active antioxidant proved to be safe and beneficial in&#xD;
      hemodialysis patents [19]. In our recent study, NAC effectively reduced the ototoxic effect&#xD;
      of gentamicin in chronic hemodialysis patients [20, 21]. Cheap and safe drug therapy may&#xD;
      appear more cost effective than such resource consuming therapies as CPAP and not readily&#xD;
      available treatments as prolong every night hemodialysis or kidney transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of our study is to investigate the effect of N-acetylsysteine on SA in HD patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods. Study population. The study will include 20 patients with ESRD, treated with chronic&#xD;
      hemodialysis in Assaf Harofeh Medical Center and suffering from sleep disturbances, such as&#xD;
      frequent arousals, snoring, daytime sleepiness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be excluded from the study if they are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Recently started treated with chronic dialysis: less than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Survived recent major illness, requiring hospitalisation in the last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients with acute renal failure&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Currently treated with antioxidants ( NAC, vitamin E ets.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Current use of sleep pills Study protocol. We planned this study as a prospective&#xD;
           cross-sectional study where every patient will serve as his/her own control. Al the&#xD;
           patients will continue their previous dialysis and drugs regimen. The presence and&#xD;
           severity of SA will be accessed using the overnight polysomnography in the Sleep&#xD;
           Laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After performance of baseline overnight polysomnography the patients will receive orally NAC&#xD;
      1200 mg x 2/day for 4 weeks. At the end of this therapy, a follow up overnight&#xD;
      polysomnography examination will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical monitoring of all the patients will include:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Blood Pressure and Heart Rate - at each dialysis session 3 times a week. .&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Review of medications and doses.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Body weight - at each dialysis session 3 times a week&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Dialysis adequacy: Kt/V at study start and end.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Biochemical studies: full chemistry, bicarbonate, ADMA, DDAH, NO - both at baseline and&#xD;
           follow up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis The statistical analysis will be performed using the statistical&#xD;
      software SPSS-version 10. Parametric data will be expressed as means ± standard deviation and&#xD;
      compared by the standard t-test. Non-parametric data will be compared using chi square test.&#xD;
      p value of 0.05 or less will be considered significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      References&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. United States Renal Data System. Patient mortality and survival. USRDS Annual Report. Am&#xD;
           J Kidney Dis 1997; 30 [Suppl. 1]: s91-s101&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Chakravorty I, Shastry M, Farrington K. Sleep apnoea in end-stage renal disease: a short&#xD;
           review of mechanisms and potential benefit from its treatment. Nephrol Dial Transplant&#xD;
           2007; 22:28-31&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Kraus M, Hamburger R. Sleep apnea in renal failure. Adv Perit Dial 1997; 13:88-92&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Young T, Palta M, Dempsey J, Skatrud J, Weber S, Badr S. The occurrence of&#xD;
           sleep-disordered breathing among middle-aged adults.&#xD;
&#xD;
           NEJM 1993; 328:1230-35&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Wolk R, Kara T, Somers V. Sleep-disordered breathing and cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Circulation 2003;108:9-12&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Jung H, Han H, Lee J. Sleep apnea, coronary artery disease, and antioxidant status in&#xD;
           hemodialysis patients. AJKD 2005;45:875-882&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Zoccali C. Sleep apnoea and nocturnal hypoxaemia in dialysis patients: mere&#xD;
           risk-indicators or causal factors for cardiovascular disease? Nephrol Dial Transplant&#xD;
           2000, 15:1919-21&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Boaz M, Matas Z, Biro A, Katzir Z, Green M, Fainaru M, Smetana S. Serum malondialdehyde&#xD;
           and prevalent cardiovascular disease in hemodialysis. Kidney Int 1999;56:1078-83&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Lavie L. Obstructive sleep apnoea syndrome--an oxidative stress disorder. Sleep Med Rev&#xD;
           2003;7:35-51&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. D'Ambrosio C, Bowman T, Mohsenin V. Quality of life in patients with obstructive sleep&#xD;
           apnea: effect of nasal continuous positive airway pressure--a prospective study.Chest&#xD;
           1999;115:123-29&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Pressman M, Benz R, Schleifer C, Peterson D. Sleep disordered breathing in ESRD: acute&#xD;
           beneficial effects of treatment with nasal continuous positive airway pressure. Kidney&#xD;
           Int 1993; 43:1134-39.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Hanly P, Pierratos A. Improvement of sleep apnea in patients with chronic renal failure&#xD;
           who undergo nocturnal hemodialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
           N Engl J Med 2001; 344:102-7&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Auckley D, Schmidt-Nowara W, Brown L. Reversal of sleep apnea hypopnea syndrome in&#xD;
           end-stage renal disease after kidney transplantation. Am J Kidney Dis 1999;34:739-744&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. Langevin B, Fougue D, Leger P, Robert D. Sleep apnea syndrome and end-stage renal&#xD;
           disease. Cure after renal transplantation. Chest 1993;103:1330-1335&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Vallance P, Leone A, Calver A, Collier J, Moncada S. Accumulation of an endogenous&#xD;
           inhibitor of nitric oxide synthesis in chronic renal failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Lancet. 1992 Mar 7;339(8793):572-5.&#xD;
&#xD;
       16. Kielstein J, Boger R, Bode-Boger S et al. Asymmetric Dimethylarginine Plasma&#xD;
           Concentrations Differ in Patients with End-Stage Renal Disease. J Am Soc Nephrol 1999;&#xD;
           10:594-600&#xD;
&#xD;
       17. Kielstein J, Zoccali C. Asymmetric dimethylarginine: a cardiovascular risk factor and a&#xD;
           uremic toxin coming of age? Am J Kidney Dis. 2005;46(2):186-202.&#xD;
&#xD;
       18. Saran R, Novak J, Desai A et al. Impact of vitamin E on plasma asymmetric&#xD;
           dimethylarginine (ADMA) in chronic kidney disease (CKD): a pilot study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2003 Nov;18(11):2415-20.&#xD;
&#xD;
       19. Tepel M, van der Giet M, Statz M et al. The antioxidant acetylcysteine reduces&#xD;
           cardiovascular events in patients with end-stage renal failure: a randomized, controlled&#xD;
           trial. Circulation. 2003 Feb 25;107(7):992-5.&#xD;
&#xD;
       20. Feldman L, Efrati S, Abramsohn R, Yarovoy I, Gersch E, Eviatar E, Averbukh Z,&#xD;
           Weissgarten J. N-Acetylcysteine for prevention of gentamicin-induced ototoxicity in&#xD;
           hemodialysis patients. J Am Soc Nephrol 2006; 17 (Suppl): 22A&#xD;
&#xD;
       21. Feldman L, Efrati S, Eviatar E, Abramsohn R, Yarovoy I, Gersch E, Averbukh Z,&#xD;
           Weissgarten J. N-Acetylcysteine ameliorates gentamicin-induced ototoxicity in&#xD;
           hemodialysis patients. Kidney Int 2007 ( in press)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <condition>ESRD</condition>
  <condition>Sleep Apnea</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oral N-Acetylcysteine 1200 mg x 2/day for 4 weeks</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The study will include 20 patients with ESRD, treated with chronic hemodialysis in&#xD;
             Assaf Harofeh Medical Center and suffering from sleep disturbances, such as frequent&#xD;
             arousals, snoring, daytime sleepiness.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients will be excluded from the study if they are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recently started treated with chronic dialysis: less than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Survived recent major illness, requiring hospitalisation in the last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with acute renal failure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently treated with antioxidants ( NAC, vitamin E ets.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of sleep pills&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Leonid S Feldman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assaf Harofeh MC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Leonid S Feldman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972-8-9779383</phone>
    <email>leonidf@asaf.health.gov.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nephrology Division, Assaf Harofeh Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zerifin</city>
        <zip>70300</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Leonid S Feldman</last_name>
      <phone>+972-8-9779383</phone>
      <email>leonidf@asaf.health.gov.il</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2007</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 1, 2008</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 11, 2008</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 14, 2008</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 11, 2008</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 11, 2008</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 14, 2008</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>ESRD</keyword>
  <keyword>Hemodialysis</keyword>
  <keyword>Sleep Apnea</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Apnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetylcysteine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>N-monoacetylcystine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

