<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02925507</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00044374</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02925507</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Computerized Acoustic Swallowing Evaluation</brief_title>
  <acronym>CASE</acronym>
  <official_title>Computerized Acoustic Swallowing Evaluation in Patients With Stroke</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is the purpose of this study to determine if a commercially available electronic&#xD;
      stethoscope synchronized with an smart phone or iPad application can be used as an accurate&#xD;
      and objective screening tool for measuring dysphagia. The investigators plan to do so in two&#xD;
      phases; in Phase I the investigators will recruit normal subjects to establish normal&#xD;
      swallowing patterns, as well as optimal sensor placement; and in Phase II the investigators&#xD;
      will compare the recordings obtained by the electronic stethoscope with those obtained using&#xD;
      videofluoroscopy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In this study, the investigators will use commercially available electronic stethoscope to&#xD;
      assess dysphagia in patients who have recently experienced a stroke. The Eko Core electronic&#xD;
      stethoscope is approved by the Food and Drug Agency (FDA) is currently available for use in&#xD;
      the health care context.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase I&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the first phase of this study the investigators will try to establish the electronic&#xD;
      stethoscope's measurements for normal swallowing patterns. The investigators will recruit&#xD;
      healthy controls and auscultate for swallowing sounds at three locations: in the&#xD;
      anterolateral section of the neck, in the posterior section of the neck, and in the superior&#xD;
      sternum as illustrated in Figure 1. After the sensors are placed, participants will be asked&#xD;
      to perform the following tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dry Swallow - ask participant to swallow their saliva&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask participant to swallow 1 teaspoon of water&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask participant to swallow 3 ounces of water (continuous)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask participant to swallow one teaspoon of applesauce&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask participant to chew one cracker Healthy subjects will be recruited by advertisement&#xD;
           using a flyer. Interested individuals will be able contact the study coordinator by&#xD;
           email or phone. Subsequently, the participants will present for consenting and testing&#xD;
           at the CSMC rehabilitation gym (North Tower 7215) or Pacific Theaters Building (116 N.&#xD;
           Robertson) at a mutually agreed time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of these tests will be used to determine the electronic stethoscope's&#xD;
      measurements for a normal swallowing pattern.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additionally, the investigators will determine optimal sensor location by measuring the&#xD;
      quality of the recordings obtained in each location, and getting participant input with&#xD;
      regarding their preferred sensor location. Signal quality will be determined by observing the&#xD;
      loudness of the swallowing signal relative to the loudness of background noises (heartbeat,&#xD;
      pulse, etc.) in each of the three locations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase II As part of their standard of care, all stroke patients at CSMC undergo a swallowing&#xD;
      screen by the nursing staff at bedside. If a patient fails the bedside screen, a referral is&#xD;
      made to the physician for a clinical swallowing evaluation by a swallowing therapist. If the&#xD;
      patient fails the clinical swallowing evaluation, the referral is made to the physician for&#xD;
      an instrumental swallowing evaluation which is often the videofluoroscopy swallowing study.&#xD;
      At bedside, the electronic stethoscope will be used to monitor the patients' pharyngeal&#xD;
      acoustic signals while they undergo swallowing evaluations monitored by members of the&#xD;
      research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Phase II all subjects will undergo evaluation by the electronic stethoscope. Regarding&#xD;
      VSS, it is entirely dependent upon the managing medical team and the physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators anticipate that a number of patients will undergo VSS. If VSS is required,&#xD;
      the order and timing will be determined by the medical team. Given the dynamic nature of the&#xD;
      acute inpatient setting, details such as timing of VSS cannot be anticipated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential participants will be identified through the daily stroke list on CS-Link, which is&#xD;
      reviewed by the investigators who have access to this list as part of routine daily&#xD;
      operations. The investigator has access to the patient list as part of quality oversight. Per&#xD;
      request for waiver of consent/authorization, patients will be selected from this list based&#xD;
      on inclusion/exclusion criteria. Subsequently, the treating physician will be contacted for&#xD;
      approval to recruit the patient. Once approval is given, the investigator will then visit the&#xD;
      patient and ask if he or she is willing to participate. The investigator will only consent&#xD;
      patients that are able to communicate clear understanding of the study, by demonstrating that&#xD;
      they understand purpose, procedure, risks and benefits of the study. If the patient cannot&#xD;
      understand the purpose of the study, risks, and benefits they will not be consented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible patients will be approached by a member of the research team who will discuss the&#xD;
      study in detail with them and obtain consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once consent is obtained, the electronic stethoscope will be placed on the location found in&#xD;
      Phase I to be optimal, and the patient will be asked to perform the following tests at&#xD;
      bedside and during the videofluoroscopy swallowing study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Dry Swallow-Ask patient to swallow their saliva&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask patient to swallow 1 teaspoon of water&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask patient to swallow 3 ounces of water (continuous)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask patient to swallow one teaspoon of applesauce&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ask patient to chew one cracker&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following outcomes will be measured in both evaluations:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Timing of swallow onset (timing of hyoid elevation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Duration of pharyngeal phase of swallow&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Timing of esophageal phase onset&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Duration of esophageal phase of swallow&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Coughing (Yes/No)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Throat clearing (Yes/No)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pharyngeal pooling (Yes/No)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Spontaneous multiple swallows (more than one) to clear bolus (Yes/No)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator will compare the data obtained using videofluoroscopy swallowing study with&#xD;
      the signals recorded with the electronic stethoscope to determine whether the patterns&#xD;
      detected by electronic stethoscope concur with those obtained via the videofluoroscopy&#xD;
      swallowing study. Additionally, the investigator will compare the results to similar tests&#xD;
      performed by nurses and swallowing therapists.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lastly, the investigators will compare the data obtained by the electronic stethoscope from&#xD;
      the healthy controls in Phase I with the data obtained from the stroke patients in Phase II,&#xD;
      and the investigators will try to determine whether the signals recorded can differentiate&#xD;
      normal from abnormal swallowing patterns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will not be compensated for their participation in this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Problems with biosensor not working properly and not functional for study&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 19, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 19, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acoustic Signal of Normal Swallowing Pattern</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute</time_frame>
    <description>To establish the acoustic signals associated wtih a normal pattern of swallowing using an electronic stethoscope</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acoustic Signal of Swallowing in the Stroke Population</measure>
    <time_frame>1 minute</time_frame>
    <description>To establish the acoustic signals associated with neurologic pattern of swallowing using an electronic stethoscope</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Deglutition Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy patients with no neurologic impairments or disease</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stroke Subjects</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with new onset stroke for ischemic, hemorrhagic or TIA</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Swallowing Screen</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient will be ask to undergo a swallowing screen by study staff</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy Controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Stroke Subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Phase 1: Normal Controls&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase 2: Patients with new onset Ischemic, hemorrhagic or transient ischemic attack&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Admitted to CSMC for acute ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke, or TIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No history of head and/or neck cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No tracheostomy or ventilator&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to follow simple one step commands&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Not admitted to CSMC for acute ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke or TIA&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of head and/or neck cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Tracheostomy or ventilator&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unable to follow simple one step commands&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Less than 18 years of age.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <reference>
    <citation>Armstrong JR, Mosher BD. Aspiration pneumonia after stroke: intervention and prevention. Neurohospitalist. 2011 Apr;1(2):85-93. doi: 10.1177/1941875210395775.</citation>
    <PMID>23983842</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bhattacharyya N. The prevalence of dysphagia among adults in the United States. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2014 Nov;151(5):765-9. doi: 10.1177/0194599814549156. Epub 2014 Sep 5.</citation>
    <PMID>25193514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brogan E, Langdon C, Brookes K, Budgeon C, Blacker D. Dysphagia and factors associated with respiratory infections in the first week post stroke. Neuroepidemiology. 2014;43(2):140-4. doi: 10.1159/000366423. Epub 2014 Nov 5.</citation>
    <PMID>25402187</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Daniels SK, Brailey K, Priestly DH, Herrington LR, Weisberg LA, Foundas AL. Aspiration in patients with acute stroke. Arch Phys Med Rehabil. 1998 Jan;79(1):14-9.</citation>
    <PMID>9440410</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Edmiaston J, Connor LT, Steger-May K, Ford AL. A simple bedside stroke dysphagia screen, validated against videofluoroscopy, detects dysphagia and aspiration with high sensitivity. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dis. 2014 Apr;23(4):712-6. doi: 10.1016/j.jstrokecerebrovasdis.2013.06.030. Epub 2013 Jul 30.</citation>
    <PMID>23910514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kendall KA, McKenzie S, Leonard RJ, Gonçalves MI, Walker A. Timing of events in normal swallowing: a videofluoroscopic study. Dysphagia. 2000 Spring;15(2):74-83.</citation>
    <PMID>10758189</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Leder SB, Bayar S, Sasaki CT, Salem RR. Fiberoptic endoscopic evaluation of swallowing in assessing aspiration after transhiatal esophagectomy. J Am Coll Surg. 2007 Oct;205(4):581-5.</citation>
    <PMID>17903733</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Trapl M, Enderle P, Nowotny M, Teuschl Y, Matz K, Dachenhausen A, Brainin M. Dysphagia bedside screening for acute-stroke patients: the Gugging Swallowing Screen. Stroke. 2007 Nov;38(11):2948-52. Epub 2007 Sep 20.</citation>
    <PMID>17885261</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 4, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 4, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 6, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 21, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 21, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 25, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Pamela Roberts</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will only be shared in the aggregate</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

