<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02923193</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CP 60892</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02923193</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Shockwave Medical Peripheral Lithoplasty System Study for PAD (Disrupt PAD III)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Study of the Shockwave Medical Peripheral Lithoplasty® System Used in Combination With DCB Versus Standard Balloon Angioplasty Used in Combination With DCB to Treat Moderate and Severely Calcified Femoropopliteal Arteries</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Shockwave Medical, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Shockwave Medical, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Shockwave Medical Inc. intends to conduct a prospective, multi-center, single blind,&#xD;
      randomized (1:1) study of Lithoplasty treatment used in combination with DCB versus standard&#xD;
      balloon angioplasty used in combination with DCB to treat moderate and severely calcified&#xD;
      femoropopliteal arteries. Assuming that roughly 15% of the subjects will be&#xD;
      lost-to-follow-up, a total of up to 400 subjects (200 per treatment arm) will be enrolled in&#xD;
      the study at up to 60 sites in Europe, the United States and New Zealand.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the randomized study, an observational study of subjects who do not meet the&#xD;
      inclusion/exclusion criteria for the randomized study will be conducted. The objective of the&#xD;
      observational study is to assess the real-world acute performance of the Shockwave Medical&#xD;
      Peripheral Lithoplasty System in the treatment of calcified, stenotic, peripheral arteries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The observational study is a prospective, multi-center, single arm observational study for&#xD;
      subjects who do not meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria of the randomized study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A maximum of 1000 subjects at the same 60 sites will be enrolled in the observational study.&#xD;
      Once enrollment in the randomized portion of the study is complete, subjects may continue to&#xD;
      be enrolled in the observational study provided they meet OS eligibility criteria.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Shockwave Medical Inc. intends to conduct a prospective, multi-center, single blind,&#xD;
      randomized (1:1) study of Lithoplasty treatment used in combination with DCB versus standard&#xD;
      balloon angioplasty used in combination with DCB to treat moderate and severely calcified&#xD;
      femoropopliteal arteries. The Shockwave Medical Peripheral Lithoplasty System is indicated&#xD;
      for lithotripsy-enhanced, low-pressure balloon dilatation of calcified, stenotic peripheral&#xD;
      arteries in patients who are candidates for percutaneous therapy. Up to 400 subjects at 60&#xD;
      sites in Europe, the United States and New Zealand.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be followed through discharge, 30 days, and 6, 12 and 24 months. DUS&#xD;
      assessments will be completed at 12 and 24 months. Procedural success is defined as residual&#xD;
      stenosis ≤30% without flow-limiting dissection (≥ grade D) prior to DCB or stenting by&#xD;
      angiographic core lab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who do not meet the randomized study inclusion and exclusion criteria, but meet the&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria for the observational study may be enrolled in the&#xD;
      observational study. The objective of the observational study is to assess the real-world&#xD;
      acute performance of the Shockwave Medical Lithoplasty System in the treatment of calcified,&#xD;
      stenotic, peripheral arteries.The observational study is a prospective, multi-center, single&#xD;
      arm observational study for subjects who do not meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria of the&#xD;
      randomized study. A maximum of 1000 subjects at the same 60 sites will be enrolled in the&#xD;
      observational study. Procedural success is defined as residual stenosis ≤30% without&#xD;
      flow-limiting dissection (≥ grade D) prior to DCB or stenting by angiographic core lab.&#xD;
      Enrollment in the observational study is anticipated to last approximately 22 months.&#xD;
      Subjects in the observational study will be followed through hospital discharge. Once&#xD;
      enrollment in the randomized portion of the study is complete, subjects may continue to be&#xD;
      enrolled in the observational study provided they meet OS eligibility criteria.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 22, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Procedural success is defined as residual stenosis ≤30% without flow-limiting dissection (≥ grade D) prior to DCB or stenting by angiographic core lab.</measure>
    <time_frame>Peri-Procedural</time_frame>
    <description>Procedural success is defined as residual stenosis ≤30% without flow-limiting dissection (≥ grade D) prior to DCB or stenting by angiographic core lab.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary patency defined as freedom from clinically-driven target lesion revascularization (TLR) and freedom from restenosis determined by duplex ultrasound or angiogram greater than or equal to 50% stenosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>Peri-Procedural</time_frame>
    <description>Acute PTA failure requiring a stent at any time during the index procedure will be counted as a loss of primary patency.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Composite of new-onset Major Adverse Events (MAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 30 days, 6, 12 and 24 months post procedure</time_frame>
    <description>Need for emergency surgical revascularization of target limb&#xD;
Unplanned target limb major amputation (above the ankle)&#xD;
Symptomatic thrombus or distal emboli that require surgical, mechanical or pharmacologic means to improve flow and extend hospitalization&#xD;
Perforations that require an intervention, including bail-out stenting</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Primary patency</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6, 12 and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as freedom from clinically-driven target lesion revascularization (TLR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Success ABI</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6, 12 and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as ankle-brachial index ABI reported as change from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Success Rutherford Category</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6, 12 and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as Rutherford Category reported as change from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Success Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days, 6, 12 and 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined by Quality of Life assessed by EQ5D questionnaire reported as change from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">306</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Arterial Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lithoplasty System followed by DCB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Shockwave Lithoplasty® Peripheral Lithoplasty System is a lithotripsy-enhanced, low-pressure balloon dilatation of calcified, stenotic peripheral arteries in patients who are candidates for percutaneous therapy. lithoplasty</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medtronic IN.PACT (DCB)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Medronic IN.PACT Drug Coated Balloon (DBS) is indicated for percutaneous transluminal angioplasty (PTA) in patients with obstructive disease of peripheral arteries, including patients with in-stent restenosis (ISR) and arteriovenous (AV) access to help maintain hemodialysis access in patients with end-stage renal disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Shockwave Lithoplasty® Peripheral Lithoplasty System</intervention_name>
    <description>The Shockwave Lithoplasty® System is a proprietary lithotripsy-enhanced balloon catheter that is designed to be delivered through the peripheral arterial system of the lower extremities to the site of calcified stenosis. Activating the lithotripsy within the device will generate pulsatile mechanical energy within the target treatment site, disrupt calcium within the lesion and allow subsequent dilation of a peripheral artery stenosis using low balloon pressure. The system consists of a balloon catheter with multiple integrated lithotripsy electrodes, and a generator.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lithoplasty System followed by DCB</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Medtronic IN.PACT (DCB)</intervention_name>
    <description>The IN.PACT Admiral DCB is an over-the-wire (OTW) balloon catheter with a drug-coated balloon at the distal tip. The drug component, referred to as the FreePac™ drug coating, consists of the drug paclitaxel and the excipient urea. The device component physically dilates the vessel lumen by PTA, and the drug is intended to reduce the proliferative response that is associated with restenosis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lithoplasty System followed by DCB</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Medtronic IN.PACT (DCB)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>drug coated balloon</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Randomized Study Arm Eligibility Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        General Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject is able and willing to comply with all assessments in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject or subject's legal representative have been informed of the nature of the&#xD;
             study, agrees to participate and has signed the approved consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age of subject is greater than or equal to 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Rutherford Clinical Category 2, 3, or 4 of the target limb.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Estimated life expectancy &gt;1 year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject is a suitable candidate for angiography and endovascular intervention in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator or per hospital guideline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject is intended to undergo treatment with Lithoplasty followed by DCB, or DCB with&#xD;
             standard balloon pre-dilatation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Angiographic Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Target lesion that is located in a native, de novo superficial femoral artery (SFA) or&#xD;
             popliteal artery (popliteal artery extends to and ends proximal to the ostium of the&#xD;
             anterior tibial artery).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Target lesion reference vessel diameter is between 4.0mm and 7.0mm by visual estimate.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Target lesion is ≥70% stenosis by investigator via visual estimate.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Target lesion length is ≤180mm for lesions 70-99% stenosed. Target lesion can be all&#xD;
             or part of the 180mm treated zone.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Chronic total occlusion, lesion length is ≤100mm of the total ≤180 mm target lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject has at least one patent tibial vessel on the target leg with runoff to the&#xD;
             foot, defined as no stenosis &gt;50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Calcification is at least moderate defined as presence of fluoroscopic evidence of&#xD;
             calcification: 1) on parallel sides of the vessel and 2) extending &gt; 50% the length of&#xD;
             the lesion if lesion is ≥50mm in length; or extending for minimum of 20mm if lesion is&#xD;
             &lt;50mm in length.&#xD;
&#xD;
        General Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Rutherford Clinical Category 0, 1, 5 and 6.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has active infection requiring antibiotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Planned target limb major amputation (above the ankle).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of prior endovascular or surgical procedure on the index limb within the past&#xD;
             30 days or planned within 30 days of the index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject has a known coagulopathy or has bleeding diatheses, thrombocytopenia with&#xD;
             platelet count less than 100,000/microliter.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject in whom antiplatelet or anticoagulant therapy is contraindicated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subject has known allergy to contrast agents or medications used to perform&#xD;
             endovascular intervention that cannot be adequately pre-treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subject has known allergy to urethane, nylon, or silicone.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Myocardial infarction within 60 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of stroke within 60 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of thrombolytic therapy within two weeks of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subject has acute or chronic renal disease defined as serum creatinine of &gt;2.5 mg/dL&#xD;
             or &gt;220 umol/L, or on dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Subject is pregnant or nursing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subject is participating in another research study involving an investigational agent&#xD;
             (pharmaceutical, biologic, or medical device) that has not reached the primary&#xD;
             endpoint.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject has other medical, social or psychological problems that, in the opinion of&#xD;
             the investigator, preclude them from receiving this treatment, and the procedures and&#xD;
             evaluations pre- and post-treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. The use of specialty balloons, re-entry or atherectomy devices.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Angiographic Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. In-stent restenosis within 10mm of the target zone.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Lesions within 10mm of the ostium of the SFA or within 10mm of the ostium of the&#xD;
             anterior tibial artery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Evidence of aneurysm or thrombus in target vessel.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. No calcium or mild calcium in the target lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Target lesion within native or synthetic vessel grafts.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Subject has significant stenosis (&gt;50% stenosis) or occlusion of inflow tract before&#xD;
             target treatment zone (e.g. iliac or common femoral) not successfully treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Subject requires treatment of a peripheral lesion on the ipsilateral limb distal to&#xD;
             target site at the time of the index procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Failure to successfully cross the guidewire across the target lesion; successful&#xD;
             crossing defined as tip of the guidewire distal to the target lesion in the absence of&#xD;
             flow limiting dissections or perforations.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subjects who do not meet the inclusion/exclusion criteria for the randomized study may&#xD;
        satisfy the eligibility criteria for the observational study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Observational Study Eligibility Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects intended to be treated with the Shockwave Medical Peripheral Lithoplasty®&#xD;
             System for de-novo or restenotic lesions of the femoral, ilio-femoral, popliteal, and&#xD;
             infra-popliteal arteries.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subjects presenting with claudication or CLI by Rutherford Clinical Category 2,3,4,5,&#xD;
             or 6 of the target limb.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age of subject is &gt; 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject or subject's legal representative have been informed of the nature of the&#xD;
             study, agrees to participate, and has signed the approved study consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Calcification is at least moderate, defined as presence of fluoroscopic evidence of&#xD;
             calcification: 1) on parallel sides of the vessel and 2) extending &gt; 50% the length of&#xD;
             the lesion if lesion is ≥50mm in length; or extending for minimum of 20mm if lesion is&#xD;
             &lt;50mm in length.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects with any medical condition that would make him/her an inappropriate candidate&#xD;
             for treatment with Shockwave Medical Peripheral Lithoplasty® System as per&#xD;
             Instructions for Use (IFU) or investigator's opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject is already enrolled in other investigational (interventional) studies that&#xD;
             would interfere with study endpoints.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gunnar Tepe, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>RoMed Klinikum Rosenheim</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>William A Gray, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Main Line Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Arkansas Heart Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Little Rock</city>
        <state>Arkansas</state>
        <zip>72211</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cedars-Sinai Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Los Angeles</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90048</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Stanford Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rocky Mountain Regional VA Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCHealth Northern Colorado</name>
      <address>
        <city>Loveland</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80538</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale New Haven Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06510</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MedStar Cardiovascular Research Network @ Medstar Washington Hospital Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tallahassee Research Institute, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tallahassee</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>32308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Piedmont Heart Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30309</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northeast Georgia Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gainesville</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30501</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alexian Brothers Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Elk Grove Village</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60007</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Advocate Health and Hospitals Corporation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Naperville</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60540</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Prairie Education &amp; Research Cooperative</name>
      <address>
        <city>Springfield</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>62769</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Midwest Cardiovascular Research Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Davenport</city>
        <state>Iowa</state>
        <zip>52803</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Steward St. Elizabeth's Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brighton</city>
        <state>Maine</state>
        <zip>02135</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Joseph Mercy Oakland</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pontiac</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48431</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ascension / St. John Providence</name>
      <address>
        <city>Southfield</city>
        <state>Michigan</state>
        <zip>48075</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>North Mississippi Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tupelo</city>
        <state>Mississippi</state>
        <zip>38801</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Saint Luke's Cardiovascular Consultants</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kansas City</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64111</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Luke's East Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lee's Summit</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>64086</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Deborah Heart and Lung Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Browns Mills</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>08015</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>New Mexico Heart Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Albuquerque</city>
        <state>New Mexico</state>
        <zip>87102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mount Sinai West</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10019</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Columbia University Medical Center/New York Presbyterian Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10032</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NC Heart &amp; Vascular Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Raleigh</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27607</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>WakeMed Health &amp; Hospitals</name>
      <address>
        <city>Raleigh</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27610</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ohio Health Research Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43214</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. John Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bartlesville</city>
        <state>Oklahoma</state>
        <zip>74006</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence Portland Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Providence Heart &amp; Vascular Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Portland</city>
        <state>Oregon</state>
        <zip>97225</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bryn Mawr Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bryn Mawr</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>PinnacleHealth Harrisburg Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Harrisburg</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>17101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>PENN Presbyterian Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Einstein Medical Center Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19141</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lankenau Institute for Medical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wynnewood</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19096</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Miriam Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Providence</city>
        <state>Rhode Island</state>
        <zip>02906</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wellmont CVA Heart Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kingsport</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37660</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tennova Healthcare - Turkey Creek Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Knoxville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37934</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baptist Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38120</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. David's Heart and Vascular dba Austin Heart</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78756</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Baylor College of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charleston Area Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charleston</city>
        <state>West Virginia</state>
        <zip>25304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medizinische Universitaet Graz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Graz</city>
        <zip>8036</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gefäßsambulanz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vienna</city>
        <zip>1140</zip>
        <country>Austria</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Karolinen-Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Arnsberg</city>
        <zip>59759</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitäts-Herzzentrum Freiburg &amp; Bad Krozingen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bad Krozingen</city>
        <zip>79189</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sankt Gertrauden-Krankenhaus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>10713</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Leiter Sektion Angiologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonn</city>
        <zip>53127</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medizinische Klinik II</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bruchsal</city>
        <zip>76646</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Klinik für Gefäßmedizin</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>21075</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Leipzig AoR Leipzig</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leipzig</city>
        <zip>04103</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Katholisches Klinikum Mainz</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mainz</city>
        <zip>55131</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Franziskus Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Munster</city>
        <zip>48145</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Evangelisches Krankenhaus Mühlheim an der Ruhr</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mülheim</city>
        <zip>45468</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>RoMed Klinikum Rosenheim</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rosenheim</city>
        <zip>83022</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Auckland City Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Auckland</city>
        <zip>1023</zip>
        <country>New Zealand</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Austria</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>New Zealand</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/32147133/</url>
    <description>Intravascular lithotripsy for treatment of calcified, stenotic iliac arteries: A cohort analysis from the Disrupt PAD III Study</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 28, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 4, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

