<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04469972</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>not have</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04469972</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Breathing Exercise on Certain Physiological Parameters, Sleep Quality and Vitality in Elderly</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Breathing Exercise on Certain Physiological Parameters, Sleep Quality and Vitality in Elderly</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aysun Erdal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Gazi University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Gazi University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objective: To determine the effect of breathing exercises on certain physiological&#xD;
      parameters, sleep quality and vitality in the elderly. Method: In this randomized controlled,&#xD;
      experimental study, pre and post tests were applied to 26 elderly participants in the&#xD;
      intervention group and to 25 elderly patients in the control group. The intervention group&#xD;
      underwent breathing exercises for 30 minutes at the same time of the day, three days a week&#xD;
      for three months (pursed-lip breathing exercise, deep breathing exercise, coughing exercise),&#xD;
      while no such exercise was carried out by the control group. Pittsburg Sleep Quality Index,&#xD;
      the Subjective Vitality Scale, spirometer, sphygmomanometer and pulse oximetry device&#xD;
      measurements were used for the collection of data. The data was evaluated with an independent&#xD;
      sample t-test, a paired-sample t-test and a two-way repeated measures ANOVA.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study design The study was conducted in a pre-test- post-test, randomised controlled&#xD;
      (parallel) and experimental design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population and sample The sample size was determined based on the variable under study&#xD;
      (i.e. lung function) using the GPower 3.1.9.4 program. The pretest and post-test &quot;FVC (L)&quot;&#xD;
      variable values obtained by Jun et al.18 were taken into account in the effect size&#xD;
      calculations, being 3.26 and 3.46, with standard deviations of 0.33 and 0.61, respectively.&#xD;
      The calculations identified a sample size that provides α = 0.05, and the power of the test&#xD;
      (1-β) = 0.80 indicated a sample size of 26 subjects in each group. Considering the potential&#xD;
      for losses over the course of such studies,12,15 20% of the minimum sample size (11&#xD;
      individuals) was added to the study so as not to reduce the statistical power of the study.&#xD;
      It was planned in the study to include 32 elderly participants in the intervention group and&#xD;
      31 in the control group.The study was completed with 26 individuals in the intervention group&#xD;
      and 25 individuals in the control group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sampling After the study protocol was approved by the Institutional Ethics Committee of Gazi&#xD;
      University and the Ministry of Family and Social Policies, a nursing home selected previously&#xD;
      according to the number of elderly people in residence was selected for the study and&#xD;
      approached. Of the 294 elderly residents of the nursing home, 158 were excluded for not&#xD;
      satisfying the inclusion criteria, while 60 were unwilling to take part. Consequently, 63&#xD;
      elderly people were entered into the study and were randomly assigned to the intervention or&#xD;
      control groups. While assessing the residents in terms of the inclusion criteria in the&#xD;
      study, their health status was obtained from the health unit files of the nursing home, and&#xD;
      the Mini Mental test was applied by the researcher.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation Age and gender are significant factors affecting lung and cardiac function, and&#xD;
      so a stratified randomization was performed to ensure the similarity of the intervention and&#xD;
      control groups. The study participants were stratified by age (65-74 years, and ≥75 years)&#xD;
      and gender (female/male) by the researcher, and were then assigned to the intervention and&#xD;
      control groups using a simple randomization application within the computer-based SPSS&#xD;
      program, with each stratum group divided equally. In this way, a balanced distribution of the&#xD;
      groups was achieved without being affected by age and gender. Neither the study participants&#xD;
      nor the breathing exercise trainers were blinded in the study, although the respiratory&#xD;
      function tests were evaluated by an independent physiotherapist. The participants were called&#xD;
      in alphabetical name order, and the measurements were made by an independent physiotherapist.&#xD;
      The statistical analyses and reporting were performed by an independent statistician. The&#xD;
      data were sent to the statistician with the groups coded as &quot;Group 1&quot; and &quot;Group 2&quot;, without&#xD;
      distinguishing between the intervention and control groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Implementation steps Pre-test: The pre-test measurements were performed by the researcher and&#xD;
      a physiotherapy specialist in the physical therapy unit of the nursing home. The participants&#xD;
      in both groups were called up for pretest evaluation in alphabetical name order. To begin&#xD;
      with, the PSQI and SVS were applied by the researcher, after which the height and body weight&#xD;
      of the participant were measured and recorded, along with their age. All these measurements&#xD;
      take around 15 minutes. In this way, the elderly were rested and prevented from imbibing&#xD;
      anything that could affect lung and heart function, such as cigarettes, tea or coffee, before&#xD;
      measurement. The cardiological findings were then evaluated by the researcher. A manual&#xD;
      sphygmomanometer and a pulse oximeter were used to assess cardiac function (blood pressure,&#xD;
      heart rate, oxygen saturation). Prior to the oxygen saturation measurement, any blue, black,&#xD;
      green, brown or red nail polish was removed, along with any artificial nails. Finally,&#xD;
      pulmonary function was assessed, for which dentures were removed. The pulmonary function test&#xD;
      procedure had been explained and shown previously by the physiotherapist to the elderly&#xD;
      participant, and a spirometer was used for the pulmonary function (FVC, FEV1, FEV1/FVC ratio&#xD;
      and percentages) measurement. The results were all delivered to the researcher by the&#xD;
      authorized representative of the spirometer manufacturer in pdf format within 15 days. All&#xD;
      other data were recorded by the researcher after measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Implementation in the intervention group: A review of literature was made prior to the&#xD;
      determination of the breathing exercise protocol to be applied to the elderly participants in&#xD;
      the intervention group. In Jun et al., elderly smokers were given breathing exercises three&#xD;
      times a week.18 In the study conducted by El Kader, a breathing exercise program was&#xD;
      developed for the elderly participants involving activities three times a week for 20 minutes&#xD;
      for a period of three months.21 Jansang et al. devised a three-month breathing exercise&#xD;
      program for the elderly comprising a diaphragmatic breathing exercise and a pursed lip&#xD;
      breathing exercise.12 The breathing exercises in the present study were planned taking into&#xD;
      account the methods and recommendations made in the above and similar studies. The&#xD;
      intervention group was subjected to a pursed-lip breathing exercise (using a windmill toy), a&#xD;
      diaphragmatic breathing exercise and a coughing exercise, three times a week (Mondays,&#xD;
      Tuesdays and Thursdays) for 12 weeks in groups of 5-6 (2 groups of 6 persons, and 4 groups of&#xD;
      5 persons: 6 groups in total) between 10:00 and 15:30, at the same time of the day for each&#xD;
      group in 30-minute sessions. The exercises were performed in the group activity hall of the&#xD;
      physical therapy unit, which was determined as the most suitable area for the participants&#xD;
      and for the exercise application, based on a joint decision of the nursing home management&#xD;
      and the researcher. No special clothing or equipment was identified for the breathing&#xD;
      exercise. The wind rose to be used during the exercise was provided by the researcher. All of&#xD;
      the breathing exercises were taught to the participants on the first day of implementation,&#xD;
      and were demonstrated again by the researcher prior to exercising throughout the&#xD;
      implementation phase. The participants were informed about the possible symptoms that could&#xD;
      occur during the breathing exercise, such as dizziness, and they were told to take a short&#xD;
      break in such cases, and to wait until the dizziness was over before continuing. If the&#xD;
      elderly person could not participate in the exercise session for any reason, the missing&#xD;
      exercise time was compensated for the week and day, determined jointly by the elderly&#xD;
      individual and the researcher. The breathing exercise program was as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Taking the appropriate position for the exercise, as demonstrated by the practitioner (5&#xD;
      minutes) II. Pursed-lip breathing exercise (using a windmill toy) (10 minutes) III. Take a&#xD;
      break for 1 minute IV. Diaphragmatic breathing exercise (10 minutes) V. Take a break for 1&#xD;
      minute VI. Coughing exercise (10 minutes)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Implementation in the control group: None of the participants in the control group were&#xD;
      subjected to breathing exercises, and continued their daily lives as normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-test: On the day following the breathing exercises, the PSQI, SVS and physiological&#xD;
      parameters were applied following the same steps as in the pre-test implementation, and&#xD;
      conducted by the same physiotherapist and researcher in the physical therapy unit. All data&#xD;
      were recorded by the researcher in the same manner.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data assessment The study data were evaluated using the SPSS (Statistical Package for Social&#xD;
      Sciences) 16.0 software package. The normal distribution of the quantitative data was&#xD;
      assessed with a Kolmogorov-Smirnov test. Numbers, percentages, means, and standard deviation&#xD;
      and t-test values were used for the analysis of the dependent groups, and a paired samples&#xD;
      t-test, and two-way analysis of variance was used for repeated measures. The level of&#xD;
      significance was accepted as p&lt;0.05. The effect size was determined based on Cohen's d value,&#xD;
      and a partial eta square (pη2) was used as the effect size when assessing the two-way&#xD;
      analysis of variance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 21, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 5, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 9, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FVC (Forced vital capacity ),%FVC</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>FVC was evaluated using a spirometer. The spirometer measurement results are compared FVC values with the expected values (predicted values) pre-calculated in healthy individuals of the same age, height and gender by the software found in the spirometer device and expressed as a percentage of these values.The results are delivered to the researcher by the authorised representative of the spirometer in pdf format within 15 days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FEV1 (air volume after 1 second of forced expiration),%FEV1</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>FEV1 was evaluated using a spirometer. The spirometer measurement results are compared FEV1 values with the expected values (predicted values) pre-calculated in healthy individuals of the same age, height and gender by the software found in the spirometer device and expressed as a percentage of these values. The results are delivered to the researcher by the authorised representative of the spirometer in pdf format within 15 days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>FEV1/FVC, %FEV1/FVC</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>FEV1/FVC was evaluated using a spirometer. The spirometer measurement results are compared FEV1/FVC with the expected values (predicted values) pre-calculated in healthy individuals of the same age, height and gender by the software found in the spirometer device and expressed as a percentage of these values.The results are delivered to the researcher by the authorised representative of the spirometer in pdf format within 15 days.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Systolic blood pressure was evaluated using a manual sphygmomanometer. Measurement results before and after the intervention are recorded by the researcher.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Diastolic blood pressure was evaluated using a manual sphygmomanometer. Measurement results before and after the intervention are recorded by the researcher.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Heart rate was evaluated using a pulse oximeter, Measurement results before and after the intervention are recorded by the researcher.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygen saturation was was evaluated using a pulse oximeter, Measurement results before and after the intervention are recorded by the researcher.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The PSQI contains 18 self-rated questions and measures the quality of sleep over the last 4 weeks. The total score ranges from 0 to 21. An overall score higher than 5 indicates poor quality of sleep. The Cronbach α internal consistency coefficient of the scale is 0.80.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective Vitality Scale (SVS)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The SVS is a 7-point Likert-type instrument with 7 self-rated items. The total score of the scale ranges from 7 to 49. A higher score indicates a higher level of subjective vitality. The Cronbach α internal consistency coefficient of the scale is 0.87.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">51</enrollment>
  <condition>Breathing</condition>
  <condition>Sleep Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Implementation in the intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This group of elderly were subjected to a pursed-lip breathing exercise (using a windmill toy), a diaphragmatic breathing exercise and a coughing exercise three times a week (Mondays, Tuesdays and Thursdays) for 12 weeks in groups of 5-6 individuals (2 groups of 6 persons, and 4 groups of 5 persons: 6 groups in total) between 10:00 and 15:30, at the same time of the day for each group in 30-minute sessions. All breathing exercises were taught to the elderly individuals on the first day of implementation and demonstrated again prior to practice by the researcher throughout the implementation phase.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Implementation in the control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>None of the elderly in the control group were subjected to breathing exercises. They continued their daily lives as normal.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Breathing Exercises</intervention_name>
    <description>Breathing exercise is defined as therapeutic intervention to create a particular form of breathing.The application of the breathing exercise program is as follows; I. Pursed Lip Breathing Exercise (Total 10 minutes) II. Diaphragmatic breathing exercise (10 minutes in total), III. Cough exercise (Total 10 minutes)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Implementation in the intervention group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residing individuals at a nursing home in Ankara included the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  aged 65 years and older&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  had a Mini Mental Test score of ≥24,15&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  had no acute or chronic lung diseases,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  had no physical/mental disabilities or limitations and conditions that might&#xD;
                  present any obstacle to participate in breathing exercises.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria. Physical / mental disability or limitation and disease that will&#xD;
        prevent them from participating in breathing exercise (previous ear, brain, spinal cord&#xD;
        surgery, acute retinal hemorrhage vertebral fracture and diaphragmatic rupture, hiatus or&#xD;
        abdominal hernia, acute myocardial infarction, unstable angina pectoris, severe coronary&#xD;
        artery disease, congestive heart failure, severe heart valve disease, acute myocarditis,&#xD;
        acute and unstable musculoskeletal injuries, uncontrollable systemic hypertension, severe&#xD;
        dementia and behavioral disorders)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Naile Bilgili</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Gazi University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gazi University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ankara</city>
        <state>Yenimahalle</state>
        <zip>06560</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Jansang S, Mickleborough T, Suksom D. Effects of Pursed-Lip Breathing Exercise Using Windmill Toy on Lung Function and Respiratory Muscle Strength in the Elderly. J Med Assoc Thai. 2016 Sep;99(9):1046-51.</citation>
    <PMID>29927211</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Gazi University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aysun Erdal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>reseach assistant</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Elderly</keyword>
  <keyword>Breath exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Physiological changes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Aspiration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Wake Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Study method can be explained. Results will be shared after the study is published</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 1, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/72/NCT04469972/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 1, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/72/NCT04469972/SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>January 1, 2019</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/72/NCT04469972/ICF_002.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

