<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04460768</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D0817R00028</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04460768</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An INternational Frontline Ovarian Cancer Real World Management Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>INFORM</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multicountry, Multicenter, Retrospective Study Evaluating the Patient Characteristics, Disease Burden, Treatment Patterns, and Patient Journey of Advanced Epithelial Ovarian Cancer Patients: A Korean, Taiwanese, and Australian Secondary Database Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>AstraZeneca</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>AstraZeneca</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The current study aims to analyze the existing secondary databases from Korea (Sungkyunkwan&#xD;
      University, Samsung Medical Center, Seoul), Taiwan (National Taiwan University, Chang-Gung&#xD;
      Medical Foundation Linkou Branch and Mackay Memorial Hospital), and Australia (Australian&#xD;
      Ovarian Cancer Study [AOCS]) to leverage the already available data in the real-world setting&#xD;
      to review the current standard of care in advanced epithelial ovarian cancer cases. The&#xD;
      collected data will help provide the required information for assessing the unmet treatment&#xD;
      needs in this patient group. The data will also provide the needed information to support any&#xD;
      reimbursement activity needed for future novel therapies in this patient group&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ovarian cancer is the eighth most commonly diagnosed cancer (295,414 cases reported in 2018)&#xD;
      and the seventh leading cause of cancer-associated mortality (184,799 deaths reported in&#xD;
      2018) in women, worldwide. The increasing trends in the burden of ovarian cancer, coupled&#xD;
      with other challenges, such as lack of awareness of ovarian cancer risk factors, lack of&#xD;
      adequate screening tools, lack of access to diagnostics, and lack of trained clinicians,&#xD;
      contribute to delays in diagnosis, resulting in a high proportion of patients presenting with&#xD;
      advanced-stage ovarian cancer associated with high mortality. Over 75% of women with ovarian&#xD;
      cancer have been reported to be diagnosed at a late stage with high relapse rates, despite&#xD;
      first-line therapy. Studies in Asia have highlighted that about 65%-70% of women with ovarian&#xD;
      cancer are diagnosed at an advanced stage. Further, the five-year net survival rate of&#xD;
      advanced-stage ovarian cancer in Asia has been found to range from 14% to 41%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among the various ovarian cancer subtypes based on histology, epithelial ovarian cancer is&#xD;
      the most common type, reported in about 90% of cases. Specifically, type II epithelial&#xD;
      ovarian cancer (that includes serous carcinoma, mixed epithelial and stromal carcinoma,&#xD;
      undifferentiated carcinomas, and other epithelial carcinoma) accounts for about 66%-73%, 56%,&#xD;
      73%, and 73% in the US, Asia, Europe, and Oceania, respectively. The corresponding rates for&#xD;
      type I epithelial ovarian tumors (that include endometrioid, clear cell, mucinous, squamous,&#xD;
      and transitional cell carcinomas) have been noted to be 19%-21%, 32.5%, 20.5%, and 20%,&#xD;
      respectively. Regarding prognosis, the five-year net survival rate of type II epithelial&#xD;
      ovarian cancer that includes serous carcinoma has been found to be low when compared to other&#xD;
      subtypes across all regions. Of note, type II epithelial ovarian tumors have been reported to&#xD;
      be highly aggressive and usually present at an advanced stage, with poor survival rates. The&#xD;
      recurrence or relapse rates have also been noted to be high with epithelial serous ovarian&#xD;
      cancer. Furthermore, a strong association has been noted between family history of ovarian&#xD;
      cancer, a very strong risk factor, and the risk of developing aggressive serous carcinomas.&#xD;
      Genetic (both germline and somatic) mutations in BRCA1/2 have been noted in about 22% of&#xD;
      high-grade, serous, ovarian carcinomas, and the majority of hereditary cases (~44%). Also,&#xD;
      mutations in homologous recombination response genes have been noted in about 50% of&#xD;
      high-grade serous epithelial ovarian cancer cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering the high incidence, poor prognosis, and high morbidity and mortality from&#xD;
      advanced epithelial ovarian cancer, it is important to have well-organized databases on the&#xD;
      clinical characteristics, treatment patterns, and outcomes of these patients, to help&#xD;
      identify the unmet needs and gaps and further optimize the survival outcomes in these&#xD;
      patients. With exception of the UK, France, Germany, Italy, and Spain and the USA, there is&#xD;
      paucity of databases, registries, or published literature on patient level data pertaining to&#xD;
      treatment patterns, clinical characteristics, and outcomes of advanced ovarian cancer&#xD;
      patients. Therefore, the current study aims to analyze the existing secondary databases from&#xD;
      Korea (Sungkyunkwan University, Samsung Medical Center, Seoul), Taiwan (National Taiwan&#xD;
      University, Chang-Gung Medical Foundation Linkou Branch and Mackay Memorial Hospital), and&#xD;
      Australia (Australian Ovarian Cancer Study) to leverage the already available data in the&#xD;
      real-world setting to review the current standard of care in advanced epithelial ovarian&#xD;
      cancer cases. The collected data will help provide the required information for assessing the&#xD;
      unmet treatment needs in this patient group. The data will also provide the needed&#xD;
      information to support any reimbursement activity needed for future novel therapies in this&#xD;
      patient group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 27, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 10, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 10, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Retrospective study of patients diagnosed between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018</time_frame>
    <description>In first line setting - length of time from diagnosis to first progression, death, or last follow-up. In second line setting, length of time from start of second line therapy until patient has disease progression, death, or last follow-up.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Platinum free interval</measure>
    <time_frame>Retrospective study of patients diagnosed between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The number of months elapsed from the last day of platinum chemotherapy for first line of treatment to the date of diagnosis of disease recurrence or date of last follow-up if the patient did not recur during the study period</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression</measure>
    <time_frame>Retrospective study of patients diagnosed between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The length of time from the date of cancer diagnosis or the start of anti-cancer treatment until the cancer starts to get worse or spread to other parts of the body.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Retrospective study of patients diagnosed between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The length of time from the start of anti-cancer treatment to end of anti-cancer treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first subsequent treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Retrospective study of patients diagnosed between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018</time_frame>
    <description>The length of time from the date of cancer diagnosis to the start of cancer treatment after cancer progression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Retrospective study of patients diagnosed between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018</time_frame>
    <description>Duration from the index date to the date of death (if available)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">989</enrollment>
  <condition>Ovarian Neoplasms</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a non-interventional study that involves retrospective collection of data from&#xD;
        medical records of all patients who have been newly diagnosed with advanced-stage&#xD;
        epithelial ovarian cancer (high grade serous type epithelial ovarian cancer for Taiwan)&#xD;
        between the period Jan 2014-Dec 2018.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects above the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a confirmed diagnosis of advanced-stage (FIGO III/IV) epithelial (Serous&#xD;
             [high or low grade], mucinous, endometrioid, clear cell, mixed, and others) ovarian&#xD;
             cancer between the period Jan 2014 and Dec 2018, provided at least 12 months data is&#xD;
             available (not mandatory to be ovarian cancer related) as a proxy of healthcare use&#xD;
             prior to the diagnosis of advanced-stage epithelial ovarian cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients being included in interventional clinical trials with PARPi for the treatment&#xD;
             of advanced-stage high-grade epithelial ovarian cancer treatment during the study&#xD;
             period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with early stage disease (FIGO Stage I, IIA, IIB, or IIC)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other malignancies within the past five years, except adequately treated non-melanoma&#xD;
             skin cancer; curatively treated in situ cancer of the cervix; ductal carcinoma in&#xD;
             situ; stage 1, grade 1 endometrial carcinoma; or other solid tumors including&#xD;
             lymphomas (without bone marrow involvement) curatively treated with no evidence of&#xD;
             disease for ≥5 years. Patients with a history of localized breast cancer may have been&#xD;
             eligible, provided they completed their adjuvant chemotherapy more than three years&#xD;
             prior to registration, and remained free of recurrent or metastatic disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <state>Victoria</state>
        <zip>D0817R00028</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <zip>D0817R00028</zip>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Taipei City</city>
        <zip>D0817R00028</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Research Site</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei City</city>
        <zip>D0817R00028</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://filehosting-v2.pharmacm.com/api/Attachment/Download?tenantId=80217111&amp;amp;parentIdentifier=D0817R00028&amp;amp;attachmentIdentifier=30b554f7-0338-4254-9a8f-a528fc2c1e33&amp;amp;fileName=D0817R00028_CSR_v1.0_clean_0823_r_Redacted.pdf&amp;amp;versionIdentifier=</url>
    <description>D0817R00028_CSR_v1.0_clean_0823</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 3, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 3, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No IPD will be shared.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

