<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00001971</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>910214</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>91-DK-0214</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00001971</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Patients With Liver Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Patients With Liver Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study aims to evaluate, investigate, and follow-up patients suffering from acute&#xD;
      and chronic liver disease. The study will focus on understanding diseases affecting the&#xD;
      liver.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients participating in the study will first undergo a routine check-up as an outpatient.&#xD;
      They will be asked to provide blood and urine samples for laboratory testing and will undergo&#xD;
      an ultrasound of the liver. Ultrasound examinations use sound waves to determine the size and&#xD;
      texture of the liver. After the initial visit subjects will be requested to follow-up once a&#xD;
      year at the outpatient department for a similar check-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Additional tests may be requested throughout the study to provide information for other&#xD;
      research studies and individual consent will be requested. These tests may include liver&#xD;
      biopsies, skin biopsies, and / or specialized blood, plasma, and lymphocyte examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects that qualify for medications presently being studied may be offered the opportunity&#xD;
      to benefit from experimental therapy....&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a general clinical research protocol to allow for evaluation, investigation and&#xD;
      long-term follow up of patients who have an acute or chronic liver disease. The protocol is&#xD;
      designed to study the natural history and pathogenesis of various liver diseases such as&#xD;
      acute and chronic hepatitis B, C, D and E, primary biliary cirrhosis, primary sclerosing&#xD;
      cholangitis, Wilson's disease, hemochromatosis, nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH),&#xD;
      noncirrhotic portal hypertension, hepatocellular carcinoma, and cryptogenic or poorly defined&#xD;
      forms of chronic liver disease. Patients will initially be seen in the outpatient department&#xD;
      and undergo a medical history and physical examination. They will have a series of of&#xD;
      clinical evaluation and the collection of research samples. Patients will then be followed in&#xD;
      the outpatient department at intervals appropriate for their clinical status. At which&#xD;
      patients will undergo an interim medical history and brief examination, with research samples&#xD;
      collected. Collection of additional tissue biopsy may be obtained during a clinically&#xD;
      indicated procedure such as liver biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects may be asked to undergo leukapheresis or plasmapheresis, and genetic analysis for&#xD;
      research purposes, and separate consent forms are provided. In addition, a control group of&#xD;
      healthy volunteers will be recruited for genetic analysis, leukapheresis and plasmapheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects who qualify for other studies of their liver disease will be offered participation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 27, 1992</start_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Predisposition and outcomes related to liver disease susceptibility, progression, and treatment response</measure>
    <time_frame>Annual visits</time_frame>
    <description>Predisposition and outcomes related to liver disease susceptibility, progression, and treatment response</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">8000</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatitis D</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis C</condition>
  <condition>Hepatitis B</condition>
  <condition>Liver Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy individuals</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy individuals who have recovered from liver diseases or who are healthy volunteers</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Liver disease patients</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        This is a general clinical research protocol to allow for evaluation, investigation and&#xD;
        long-term follow up of patients who have an acute or chronic liver disease. The protocol is&#xD;
        designed to study the natural history and pathogenesis of various liver diseases such as&#xD;
        acute and chronic hepatitis B, C, D and E, primary biliary cirrhosis, primary sclerosing&#xD;
        cholangitis, Wilson's disease, hemochromatosis, nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH),&#xD;
        noncirrhotic portal hypertension, hepatocellular carcinoma, and cryptogenic or poorly&#xD;
        defined forms of chronic liver disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Stated willingness to comply with all study procedures and availability for the&#xD;
             duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female, &gt;=2 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Suspected or evidence of acute or chronic liver disease on evaluation by a referring&#xD;
             licensed independent practitioner (LIP), healthcare organization or study subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Absence of other significant medical illnesses that might interfere with prolonged&#xD;
             follow up evaluation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ability of subject, parent/guardian or Legally Authorized Representative to understand&#xD;
             and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        There are no specific reasons to exclude any patients from this protocol as it does not&#xD;
        entail sig- nificant risk to the patient or excessive clinical burden to the Liver Diseases&#xD;
        Branch. Patients who resolve their chronic liver disease, such as patients with chronic&#xD;
        hepatitis B who become negative for HBsAg or patients with chronic hepatitis C who become&#xD;
        negative for HCV RNA will continue to be followed despite lack of apparent disease or&#xD;
        disability. This is to document that clearance of these hepatitis viruses is, indeed,&#xD;
        associated with resolution of the liver disease and lack of long-term adverse effects.&#xD;
        Because there are data suggesting that chronic HBsAg carriers who become HBsAg-negative and&#xD;
        patients with chronic hepatitis C whose liver disease becomes inactive can still develop&#xD;
        long-term consequences of these diseases (especially hepatocellular carcinoma), following&#xD;
        such patients is important.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adults only may have the following research tests but must meet certain criteria to have&#xD;
        these research procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Genetic Analysis of Serum Samples:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult subjects with clinically significant anemia will be excluded for phlebotomy that&#xD;
             is necessary for isolation of DNA material from the blood cells.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to understand or sign informed consent will also exclude patients from this&#xD;
             aspect of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Apheresis:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult subjects will have to fulfill the criteria of the NIH Department of Transfusion&#xD;
             Medicine regarding leukapheresis and plasmapheresis donors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Because this is a research procedure to obtain reagents and assay materials, only&#xD;
             patients who are active and relatively fit (i.e. not disabled from their liver&#xD;
             disease) and do not exhibit any contraindications for the procedure will be asked to&#xD;
             undergo this procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject s &lt;18 years old are excluded from apheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Decisionally impaired adults are excluded from apheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from apheresis procedures.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>T. Jake Liang, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patricia E Alcivar</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 435-6121</phone>
    <email>patricia.alcivar@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>T. Jake Liang, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 496-1721</phone>
    <email>jakel@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_1991-DK-0214.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 18, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 18, 2000</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 19, 2000</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hepatitis B</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatitis C</keyword>
  <keyword>Hepatitis D</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Hepatitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Liver Disease</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis A</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis C</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis B</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis D</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hepatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

