<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03017144</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>T70/2012</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03017144</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Association Between Technical and Non-technical Skills in Real-life ALS Situations. Impact of Pit Crew Model on the Resuscitation Skills.</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Association Between Technical and Non-technical Skills in Real-life ALS Situations. Impact of Pit Crew Model on the Resuscitation Skills.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Turku University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Turku University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cardiac arrest is handled by cardiopulmonary resuscitation which is a time critical emergency&#xD;
      situation. The actions during resuscitation are lead by international guidelines.&#xD;
      Traditionally, the main focus of the training has been on medical knowledge and technical&#xD;
      skills (TS). Nowadays non-technical skills (NTS), such as communication, teamwork behaviour,&#xD;
      and leadership, are considered at least equally important.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to evaluate both TS and NTS of the resuscitation team during&#xD;
      real-life resuscitation situations using a validated assessment tool. The association between&#xD;
      TS and NTS will be analyzed. Findings from this study may help to recognize the possible&#xD;
      weaknesses and issues which could be improved by training. Hypothesis is that that TS are&#xD;
      probably in a high level, but some improvement points of NTS are ought to be known better.&#xD;
      Investigators hypothesis that the good NTS performance in resuscitation is accompanied by&#xD;
      good TS performance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiac arrest is a time-critical emergency situation, which is treated by cardiopulmonary&#xD;
      resuscitation (CPR). The actions during resuscitation are lead by international guidelines&#xD;
      (Nolan et al 2010). Because of the relatively rare nature of cardiac arrests in many wards&#xD;
      and clinics, regular resuscitation training is necessary.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During cardiopulmonary resuscitation and other sudden medical crisis situations, in addition&#xD;
      to medical knowledge and technical skills (TS), also non-technical skills (NTS) are needed&#xD;
      (Castelao et al 2011, Fletcher et al 2002, Helmreich et al 1999, Gaba et al 1998). NTS are&#xD;
      behavioural elements which are ought to improve team performance. The importance of NTS has&#xD;
      been demonstrated only in a simulated settings, not in a real life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drawbacks in team organization and communication are frequent problems within advanced life&#xD;
      support (ALS) events (Risaliti et al, Colquitt et al). As unclear team member roles can cause&#xD;
      errors during ALS (Weng et al, Ornato et al) more emphasis should be placed on educating&#xD;
      specific roles and responsibilities to resuscitation team members (Soar et al, Maney et al).&#xD;
      Pit crew models for resuscitation, where all resuscitation team members have their&#xD;
      pre-assigned positions and pre-arranged roles and tasks to perform ALS have been developed to&#xD;
      respond these problems. (Gonzales et al, Pearson et al, Glendenning et al, Ong et al, Hopkins&#xD;
      et al, Spitzer et al)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective, purpose, and hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first part of this study (ID T70/2012) aims to evaluate the technical and especially&#xD;
      non-technical skills of the resuscitation team during real-life resuscitation situations.&#xD;
      Investigators hypothesis that good non-technical performance is related on good technical&#xD;
      performance. Findings from this study may help to recognize the possible weaknesses and&#xD;
      issues which could be improved by training. The hypothesis is that technical skills are&#xD;
      probably on a high level, but some improvement points of non-technical skills are ought to be&#xD;
      known better.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second part of the study aims to evaluate the impact of a pit crew model on ALS skills.&#xD;
      (ID: T70/2012)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design and Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Turku University Central Hospital lies in a Southwestern part of Finland, and provides&#xD;
      medical services for 865 000 inhabitants. The target group of this study is the resuscitation&#xD;
      team of the adult ICU of Turku University Central Hospital. This team consists of an ICU&#xD;
      doctor (most commonly an anaesthesiologist specialized for intensive care), two ICU nurses,&#xD;
      and one medical technician. These people are treating approximately 90 cardiac arrests per&#xD;
      year, but this group also gets other alarms (like shortness of breath, unconscious patients&#xD;
      and other acute situations). This ICU resuscitation team takes care of all resuscitation&#xD;
      calls in the newer part of the Turku University Hospital, when the older parts of the&#xD;
      hospital are taken care either by a resuscitation team from pediatric ICU or by prehospital&#xD;
      emergency medical service system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data from 20 video-recorded real-life resuscitation situations treated by resuscitation&#xD;
      team in Turku University Hospital will be collected and the overall NTS and TS score will be&#xD;
      measured using a validated assessment tool (Peltonen et al 2017). The association between the&#xD;
      TS and NTS will be analyzed by statistical methods. In addition, after each recorded&#xD;
      resuscitation situation, every member of the resuscitation team will be called by a phone.&#xD;
      During the calls team members are asked to tell examples, what went well during the&#xD;
      resuscitation, and what could have been done better. Based on these answers, inductive&#xD;
      analysis will be made.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pit crew model for resuscitation will be implemented in our organizations' resuscitation&#xD;
      team responding cardiac arrest alarms. We will continue to video-recording after the&#xD;
      intervention, and similarly, NTS and TS will be measured using the validated assessment tool&#xD;
      (Peltonen et al 2017). In the second part of the study, we will compare the pre- and&#xD;
      post-intervention ALS-performance in the videos.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethics&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study protocol was approved by the Ethics Committee of Turku University. All&#xD;
      ALS-situations in Turku University newer hospital building area are considered eligible to&#xD;
      the study regardless of the initial rhythm or presumed aetiology. Written information consent&#xD;
      of patients is not needed, because the study is directed at resuscitation team performance,&#xD;
      not the patients. The patients are not identified at any phase of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To measure the association of the NTS and TS on one-another using validated assessment tool.</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the association between NTS and TS subgategories.</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the impact of the pit crew model.</measure>
    <time_frame>two years</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">37</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac Arrest</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Resuscitation team</arm_group_label>
    <description>Resuscitation pit crew model is educated to the resuscitation team.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pit crew model education</intervention_name>
    <description>A pit crew model for resuscitation is educated to all resuscitation team members.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Resuscitation team</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The target group of this study is the resuscitation team of the adult ICU of Turku&#xD;
        University Central Hospital. This team consists of an ICU doctor (most commonly an&#xD;
        anaesthesiologist specialized for intensive care), two ICU nurses and one medical&#xD;
        technician.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. a doctor, a nurse, a paramedic or a medical technician working on adult ICU&#xD;
             resuscitation team&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. all the members of the ICU resuscitation team in the CPR-situation are volunteer to&#xD;
             take part in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1) if any member of the ICU resuscitation team in the CPR-situation refuse to be video&#xD;
        recoded&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Miretta Tommila, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Turku University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sanna Salanterä, PhD, RN</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Vice Head of the Department of Nursing Science and Nurse Director at Turku University Hospital, Finland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ville Peltonen, Lic.Med</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Turku University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura-Maria Peltonen, M.Sc. RN</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Turku, Finland, Nursing Science</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Teemu Elomaa, Lic.Med</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Turku University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jaana Elomaa, RN</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Turku University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tomi Pappila, RN</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Vakka-Suomi Hospital Tyks, Finland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sanna Hoppu, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Tampere University Hospital, Finland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eeva Hevonoja, RN</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Turku, Finland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Saija Hurme</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Turku, Finland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Katariina Perkonoja</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>University of Turku, Finland</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nolan JP, Soar J, Zideman DA, Biarent D, Bossaert LL, Deakin C, Koster RW, Wyllie J, Böttiger B; ERC Guidelines Writing Group. European Resuscitation Council Guidelines for Resuscitation 2010 Section 1. Executive summary. Resuscitation. 2010 Oct;81(10):1219-76. doi: 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2010.08.021.</citation>
    <PMID>20956052</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fernandez Castelao E, Russo SG, Cremer S, Strack M, Kaminski L, Eich C, Timmermann A, Boos M. Positive impact of crisis resource management training on no-flow time and team member verbalisations during simulated cardiopulmonary resuscitation: a randomised controlled trial. Resuscitation. 2011 Oct;82(10):1338-43. doi: 10.1016/j.resuscitation.2011.05.009. Epub 2011 May 25.</citation>
    <PMID>21664757</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fletcher GC, McGeorge P, Flin RH, Glavin RJ, Maran NJ. The role of non-technical skills in anaesthesia: a review of current literature. Br J Anaesth. 2002 Mar;88(3):418-29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11990277</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Helmreich RL, Merritt AC, Wilhelm JA. The evolution of Crew Resource Management training in commercial aviation. Int J Aviat Psychol. 1999;9(1):19-32.</citation>
    <PMID>11541445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gaba DM, Howard SK, Flanagan B, Smith BE, Fish KJ, Botney R. Assessment of clinical performance during simulated crises using both technical and behavioral ratings. Anesthesiology. 1998 Jul;89(1):8-18.</citation>
    <PMID>9667288</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 17, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 9, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 11, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>non-technical skills (NTS)</keyword>
  <keyword>human factors</keyword>
  <keyword>team work</keyword>
  <keyword>Crew Resource Management / Crisis Resource Management (CRM)</keyword>
  <keyword>technical skills (TS)</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiopulmonary resuscitation</keyword>
  <keyword>Advanced cardiac life support</keyword>
  <keyword>Pit Crew Model</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Arrest</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Patients treated by cardiopulmonary resuscitation (CPR) in the videos can be recognized. Video material can not be shared due to patient privacy. Other data is possible to share.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

