<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03014466</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-37577</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03014466</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Screen-Based Distraction Tool for Preoperative Preparation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Screen-Based Distraction Tool for Preoperative Preparation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Preoperative anxiety in pediatric patients undergoing surgical procedures has been previously&#xD;
      shown to increase the likelihood of family stressors, post- operative pain, agitation, sleep&#xD;
      disturbances, and negative behavioral changes. The purpose of this study is to determine&#xD;
      whether the use of a bed mounted Video Projection unit (i.e. BERT, Bedside EnterRtainment&#xD;
      Theater) is more effective than the use of a standard of care tablet (i.e., iPad) for&#xD;
      preventing anxiety before surgery among children undergoing anesthesia and surgery. The&#xD;
      anticipated primary outcome will be reduction of child's anxiety in the preoperative and&#xD;
      operating room setting and compliance with mask induction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients will initially be approached about the study during a pre-surgical phone call that&#xD;
      every patient receives prior to their procedure by a Nurse Practitioner (NP). During this&#xD;
      phone call, the NP will ask if the family would be interested in participating in a research&#xD;
      study and if they may be contacted by the research team. If the family expresses interest,&#xD;
      the NP will follow-up with the research team and a eligibility screening phone call will be&#xD;
      given. If families decline interest, we will respect their decision and will not pursue the&#xD;
      family any further for this study. Not all families will be available during the initial pre-&#xD;
      surgical phone call, and in this case, the medical staff member and research assistant will&#xD;
      approach the family in the pre-operative holding area day of surgery. Interested families&#xD;
      will be given a brochure with information about the study and screened for eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Upon arrival for preoperative preparations, the research assistant will go over the consent&#xD;
      and assent forms with the parent and child and answer any questions they may have about the&#xD;
      study. While child is being prepped to be transported to the preoperative holding area, a&#xD;
      research staff member will determine whether the participant will receive the standard care&#xD;
      (i.e. entertainment via tablet) or the (i.e. BERT, Bedside EnteRtainment System; Video&#xD;
      Projection) via random assignment. Once determined, the research staff will set up the system&#xD;
      for the patient and will be asked to fill out questionnaires, on REDCap or by paper, about&#xD;
      how they are feeling at that time before their surgery. Parents will also be asked to fill&#xD;
      out questionnaires about their feelings of their child's preoperative emotions. The child&#xD;
      will continue to view their preoperative entertainment through to induction. A video camera&#xD;
      mounted to the BERT screen or tablet will be used for retrospective coding by blinded&#xD;
      research assistants. When possible, a blinded research assistant will also live-code the&#xD;
      observer-rated surveys. We aim for this to occur for around 20-30% of participants. care) The&#xD;
      research assistants will complete the mYPAS (modified Yale Preoperative Anxiety Scale) and&#xD;
      ICC (Induction Compliance Checklist) when coding in vivo. Vitals (i.e. blood pressure, heart&#xD;
      rate, oxygen saturation, end tidal CO2, and temperature) will also be recorded as they&#xD;
      undergo preoperative preparations. The parent will be asked to remain with their child from&#xD;
      the preoperative holding area until the child has undergone induction. Once child enters&#xD;
      induction phase in the OR, the patient will undergo surgery as scheduled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post-operation, the research assistant will further examine the child's behaviors as they&#xD;
      wake from anesthesia. They will also give the the parent, child, and child's anesthesiologist&#xD;
      a survey about their experiences with the screen-based device. 1 week after the surgery, the&#xD;
      research assistant will follow up with the parent/guardian with questions about their and&#xD;
      their child's preoperative and perioperative via phone. The call will also be audio recorded.&#xD;
      After the one-week follow-up survey, the study will be concluded for the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      b) Explain how the above research procedures are the least risky that can be performed&#xD;
      consistent with sound research design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All survey questions are meant to answer questions pertaining to the study aims. Set up of&#xD;
      the Video Projection unit will be performed by trained members of the research team and will&#xD;
      be of minimal risk to patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The risks associated with this study include the possibility of participation being&#xD;
      discovered by others outside of the study team. This is highly unlikely given the precautions&#xD;
      that will be described later in this application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      c) State if deception will be used. If so, provide the rationale and describe debriefing&#xD;
      procedures. Since you will not be fully informing the participant in your consent process and&#xD;
      form, complete an alteration of consent (in section 13). Submit a debriefing script (in&#xD;
      section 16).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Deception will not be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      d) State if audio or video recording will occur. Describe what will become of the recording&#xD;
      after use, e.g., shown at scientific meetings, erased. Describe the final disposition of the&#xD;
      recordings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be video taped to capture the patient's full experience with the Video&#xD;
      Projection unit and its effect during preoperative and perioperative procedure. The video&#xD;
      camera will be mounted on the tablet or BERT system. Videos will be coded by the research&#xD;
      team, and will not contain PHI. Audio will be recorded from the follow-up phone calls so that&#xD;
      the parents' responses will be fully captured in our measures. These videos and audio files&#xD;
      will be stored on a secured, password protected, and encrypted computer, which only&#xD;
      authorized members of the study will have access to. The videos and audio files will be&#xD;
      destroyed 6 years after the publication of the study. These videos and audio files may be&#xD;
      presented at scientific meetings and this will be included in the consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      e) Describe alternative procedures or courses of treatment, if any, that might be&#xD;
      advantageous to the participant. Describe potential risks and benefits associated with these.&#xD;
      Any standard treatment that is being withheld must be disclosed in the consent process and&#xD;
      form. (i.e. standard-of-care drug, different interventional procedure, no procedure or&#xD;
      treatment, palliative care, other research studies).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a randomized trial to validate the effectiveness of using a Video Projection unit,&#xD;
      therefore there will be subjects that undergo standard treatment as a result of the&#xD;
      randomization. The randomization will be performed by the research assistant following&#xD;
      consent. Parents must be with their child from the pre-operative area until induction. They&#xD;
      will have the option to opt-out of the study if the parent or child does not want the parent&#xD;
      present or there is a strong patient or parent preference for pharmacological anxiolytic or a&#xD;
      specific anxiety-reduction technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      f) Will it be possible to continue the more (most) appropriate therapy for the participant(s)&#xD;
      after the conclusion of the study?&#xD;
&#xD;
      N/A. The interventional technologies will only be implemented to allay preoperative anxiety,&#xD;
      therefore will not be continued after the surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      g) Study Endpoint. What are the guidelines or end points by which you can evaluate the&#xD;
      different treatments (i.e. study drug, device, procedure) during the study? If one proves to&#xD;
      be clearly more effective than another (or others) during the course of a study, will the&#xD;
      study be terminated before the projected total participant population has been enrolled? When&#xD;
      will the study end if no important differences are detected?&#xD;
&#xD;
      The endpoint of the study will be determined by the completion of the target number of&#xD;
      participants. The target number of participants for the study is 30 participants in each&#xD;
      randomized group (i.e. standard care tablet and Video Projection unit group) for a total of&#xD;
      60 patients who complete the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety at Induction of Anesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Modified Yale Perioperative Anxiety Score at induction of anesthesia. This is a validated scale used to assess patient periprocedural anxiety</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Induction Compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Validated score for assessing patient compliance with anesthesia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Tablet</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Preoperative patients will utilize a video tablet for addressing pre anesthesia anxiety</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Video Projector</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Preoperative patients will utilize a video projection unit for addressing pre anesthesia anxiety</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Use of Video Projector</intervention_name>
    <description>Bed mounted video projector that is used to play videos of the patient's choosing prior to induction of anesthesia</description>
    <arm_group_label>Video Projector</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Bedside Entertainment Theater</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Use of Video Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>7 inch video tablet that is used for displaying videos of the patient's choosing prior to induction of anesthesia</description>
    <arm_group_label>Tablet</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants must:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. be between ages of 4-10 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. have comprehension of instructions in the English language&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. have parental consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pediatric patient must be undergoing non-emergent outpatient surgery at Lucile Packard&#xD;
             Children's Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Children who are normally healthy (ASA I) or have a mild systemic disease (ASA II) -&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        General Exclusion Criteria are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Significant cognitive impairment/developmental delays per parental report or H&amp;P.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Children with ASA III, ASA IV (severe systemic disease that is a constant threat to&#xD;
             life) or ASA V (unstable patients not expected to survive &gt;24hours or without the&#xD;
             operation)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Children currently taking psychotropic mediations will be excluded from this study due&#xD;
             to the affect emotion modulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Strong parental or patient preference for pharmacological anxiolytic&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Strong parental or patient preference for specific anxiety-reducing technique&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Children born before 32 week gestation&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any indication that the patient may be admitted post-operatively&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Child has had previous surgery or has undergone general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Parent does not want to be present during transport to the OR or during induction -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Samuel T Rodriguez, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Stanford School of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>September 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 5, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 5, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Stanford University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Samuel Rodriguez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

