<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04096989</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08-X-026</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04096989</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Traditional Chinese Medicine Regimen-based Lifestyle Mobile Health APP in Prediabetes</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Development and Effectiveness of Traditional Chinese Medicine Regimen-based Lifestyle and Mobile Health Application Intervention for People With Prediabetes</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital, Buddhist Tzu Chi Medical Foundation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prediabetes is a major risk factor for diabetes. The Lifestyle Modification Mobile Health&#xD;
      Application (APP) could not only help to decrease blood sugar among individuals with&#xD;
      prediabetes but it could also prevent a later occurrence of diabetes. While many people use&#xD;
      traditional Chinese medicine (TCM) to improve the participants body constitution in Chinese&#xD;
      culture, it rarely if ever obtained through a mobile device. There are very few apps that&#xD;
      provide effective TCM regimen-based lifestyle advice for prediabetes. Therefore, the&#xD;
      investigators want to develop and evaluate the effectiveness of receiving TCM regimen-based&#xD;
      lifestyle advice from a mobile device designed to improve the applicant's health status.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background: People with prediabetes have an increased risk of Type 2 diabetes. Traditional&#xD;
      Chinese medicine (TCM) lifestyle modification has been shown to be effective in achieving a&#xD;
      balanced status and decreasing the risk of prediabetes progressing to diabetes. TCM theories&#xD;
      note that Body constitution (BC) lays the foundation for diagnosis, treatment and disease&#xD;
      prevention. The measurement and regulation of an individual's body constitution might prevent&#xD;
      disease. TCM practitioners give individualized interventions according to each person's body&#xD;
      constitution. Qi (energy) also is a core concept in TCM. Both body constitution and meridian&#xD;
      energy (ME) can be used to determine deviated and abnormal body function. The Lifestyle&#xD;
      Modification Mobile Health Application (APP) could help to decrease blood sugar among&#xD;
      individuals with prediabetes, it could also prevent a later occurrence of diabetes. But, a&#xD;
      few studies to development a TCM regimen-based lifestyle APP, and evaluate the effectiveness&#xD;
      of receiving TCM regimen-based lifestyle APP in prediabetes. In this study, the objective was&#xD;
      to development a TCM regimen-based lifestyle APP, and evaluate the effectiveness of receiving&#xD;
      TCM regimen-based lifestyle APP in prediabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims of the study: To development a TCM regimen-based lifestyle APP, and evaluate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of receiving TCM regimen-based lifestyle APP in prediabetes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and Methods: A three-arm randomized controlled trail. The study was carried out&#xD;
      involving 100 participants, who were recruited at a teaching hospital in northern Taiwan. The&#xD;
      study variables include socio-demographics, disease history, and lifestyle, the physiological&#xD;
      indicators from the blood-test will be obtained from the oneline medical charts. Physical&#xD;
      activity was measured by International Physical Activity Questionnaire Self-Administered&#xD;
      Short Version (IPAQ-SS). Health related quality of life was assessed by the SF-36, which&#xD;
      yielded physical component score (PCS) and mental component scores (MCS) covering 8&#xD;
      subscales: physical functioning (PF), role physical (RP), body pain (BP), general health&#xD;
      (GH), vitality (VT), role emotional (RE), social function (SF), and mental health (MH), with&#xD;
      higher score indicating better quality of life. The Body Constitution questionnaire (BCQ) was&#xD;
      used to measure neutral, Yang-deficiency, Ying-deficiency, and Phlegm-stasis, with higher&#xD;
      scores indicating larger deficiencies. Meridian energy was examined by using the Meridian&#xD;
      energy device, which included individual point and balance of meridian energy measurements&#xD;
      (metabolism, musculoskeletal &amp; circulation, mental health, and autonomic nervous system&#xD;
      status).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Possible effect: There is no TCM regimen-based lifestyle mobile health APP among people with&#xD;
      prediabetes. Through the study, The investigators hope to develop a TCM regimen-based&#xD;
      lifestyle mobile health APP, and evaluation it. By TCM regimen-based lifestyle using and use&#xD;
      of APP, health management of the could be improved. The results could serve as a reference&#xD;
      for promotion of traditional Chinese preventive medicine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 20, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Meridian energy of Meridian energy device</measure>
    <time_frame>Change before, through intervention completion (average of 6 months)and after 1 month intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The meridian energy device captures data regarding the individual's balance of meridian energy. Balance was measured by the values of physical, metabolism, musculoskeletal and circulation, mental health, and autonomic nervous system status ratios. To achieve the appropriate balance for the energy results, a ratio of close to one was preferred.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Body constitution of body constitution questionnaire (BCQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change before, through intervention completion (average of 6 months)and after 1 month intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The scale range from 44 to 220, with higher scores indicating larger deficiencies</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical activity of international physical activity questionnaire self-administered short version (IPAQ-SS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change before, through intervention completion (average of 6 months)and after 1 month intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The unit of measurement is metabolic equivalent (METs), with higher METs indicating more physical activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related quality of life of short form 36 (SF-36)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change before, through intervention completion (average of 6 months)and after 1 month intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The scale range from 0 to 100, with higher scores indicating better quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">121</enrollment>
  <condition>PreDiabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Routine care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants accept TCM regimen-based lifestyle mobile health application intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham comparator group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The participants accept mobile health application intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Traditional Chinese medicine regimen-based lifestyle mobile health APP</intervention_name>
    <description>The Experimental group receives TCM regimen-based lifestyle mobile health application intervention.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lifestyle mobile health APP</intervention_name>
    <description>Sham comparator group receives mobile health application, but there is no traditional Chinese medicine information.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sham comparator group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Previously diagnosed with prediabetes with an HbA1c of 5.7% to 6.4% and an FPG level&#xD;
             of 100 mg/dl to &lt; 126 mg/dl (ADA, 2011, 2014).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged 20 and above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Provided informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Use of hypoglycemic agent,βblocker, thiazide diuretics, nicotinic acid or steroids&#xD;
             within the past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Self-reported catastrophic illness in the last 6 months (e.g. stroke, cardiovascular&#xD;
             disease, renal and liver insufficiency, heart failure, chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
             disease and cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Endocrine diseases like hyperthyroidism or autoimmune disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Psychosis or other major neurocognitive disorder; (e) pregnancy and/or lactation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        (f) Individuals with pacemakers.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taipei Tzu Chi Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Taipei City</city>
        <zip>231</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 10, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 19, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>prediabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>TCM</keyword>
  <keyword>body constitution</keyword>
  <keyword>meridian energy</keyword>
  <keyword>APP</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prediabetic State</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

