<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04096417</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ACCRU-GI-1701</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2019-05877</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>ACCRU-GI-1701</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA015083</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04096417</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pemigatinib for the Treatment of Metastatic or Unresectable Colorectal Cancer Harboring FGFR Alterations</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II, Multicenter, Single-Arm Study of Pemigatinib in Patients With Metastatic or Unresectable Colorectal Cancer Harboring FGFR Alterations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Academic and Community Cancer Research United</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Academic and Community Cancer Research United</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase II trial studies how well pemigatinib works in treating patients with colorectal&#xD;
      cancer with mutations (alterations) in a FGFR gene and that has spread to other places in the&#xD;
      body (metastatic) or cannot be removed by surgery (unresectable). Pemigatinib may stop the&#xD;
      growth of tumor cells by blocking FGFR, which is needed for cell growth.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess overall response rate (ORR) of pemigatinib in patients with metastatic or&#xD;
      unresectable colorectal cancer harboring activating FGFR alterations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess the clinical benefit rate (complete response + partial response + stable&#xD;
      disease) with pemigatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess progression free survival (PFS) and overall survival (OS) with pemigatinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. Assess changes in patient quality of life (QOL) as measured by the linear analogue&#xD;
      self-assessment (LASA) questionnaire.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Assess the frequency and severity of adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CORRELATIVE RESEARCH OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess plasma pharmacodynamic biomarkers of response and resistance to therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To explore any correlation between tissue and blood based biomarkers and clinical&#xD;
      outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive pemigatinib orally (PO) once daily (QD) on days 1-21. Treatment repeats&#xD;
      every 21 days for up to 35 cycles in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable&#xD;
      toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up every 3 months for 3 years&#xD;
      after registration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 31, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 36 weeks after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the percentage of patients, among evaluable patients, who experience an objective response per RECIST 1.1. The proportion of successes will be estimated by the number of successes divided by the total number of evaluable patients. Confidence intervals for the true success proportion will be calculated according to the approach of Clopper and Pearson.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical benefit rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical Benefit Rate is defined as the number of patients that experience a complete or partial response within 36 weeks post registration, or have stable disease for at least 36 weeks post registration, divided by the number of evaluable patients. Analysis of this endpoint will mirror that of the primary objective.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From study entry to the first of either disease progression or death from any cause, assessed up to 3 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival (PFS) is defined as the time from study entry to the first of either disease progression or death from any cause, where disease progression is determined based on RECIST 1.1 criteria. PFS will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. The median PFS and corresponding 95% confidence interval will be reported. Patients who do not experience disease progression or death while on protocol will be censored at the last disease assessment date.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From study entry to death from any cause, assessed up to 3 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Overall survival (OS) is defined as the time from study entry to death from any cause. Will be estimated using the Kaplan-Meier method. The median OS and corresponding 95% confidence interval will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life (QOL) as measured by the LASA [item 1: Overall QOL]</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Life (QOL) was measured using item 1: Overall QOL of the Linear Analogue Self-Assessment (LASA) Questionnaire on a 0-10 scale, with 0=as bad as it can be and 10=as good as it can be. The QOL scores was converted to a 100-point scale, with 0=Low QOL and 100=Best QOL. Change from baseline to Week 36 will be calculated by subtracting the baseline scores from the scores at Week 36. Negative change indicates the QOL decrease and positive change indicates the QOL improvement.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years after registration</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events will be summarized by frequency and severity using Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">24</enrollment>
  <condition>FGFR1 Gene Amplification</condition>
  <condition>FGFR1 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>FGFR1 Gene Translocation</condition>
  <condition>FGFR2 Gene Amplification</condition>
  <condition>FGFR2 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>FGFR2 Gene Translocation</condition>
  <condition>FGFR3 Gene Amplification</condition>
  <condition>FGFR3 Gene Mutation</condition>
  <condition>FGFR3 Gene Translocation</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Colorectal Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Stage III Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIA Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIB Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IIIC Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IV Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVA Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVB Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Stage IVC Colorectal Cancer AJCC v8</condition>
  <condition>Unresectable Colorectal Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (pemigatinib)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive pemigatinib PO QD on days 1-21. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 35 cycles in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pemigatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (pemigatinib)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>INCB054828</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Quality-of-Life Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (pemigatinib)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Quality of Life Assessment</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Registered to Colorectal and Liquid Biopsy Molecularly Assigned Therapy (COLOMATE)&#xD;
             Academic and Community Cancer Research United (ACCRU)-GI-1611 and:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  COLOMATE Companion Trial Recommendation Form indicates patient qualifies to be&#xD;
                  screened for a COLOMATE companion trial&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  COLOMATE Companion Trial Recommendation Form date of completion is =&lt; 30 days&#xD;
                  prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of metastatic or unresectable&#xD;
             colorectal cancer (mCRC), based on documentation from local or outside review of&#xD;
             pathology according to each site?s established institutional procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Documentation of an activating genomic alteration(s) in FGFR1-3 (gain of function&#xD;
             mutations, translocations, and amplifications allowed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide informed written consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must have received and progressed on, or be intolerant to, each of the&#xD;
             following treatments for mCRC (or have contraindication to these treatments):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fluoropyrimidine&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Oxaliplatin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Irinotecan&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Anti-VEGF (vascular endothelial growth factor) monoclonal antibody, if eligible&#xD;
                  for this therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Anti-EGFR (epidermal growth factor receptor) monoclonal antibody, if eligible for&#xD;
                  this therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of 0, 1, or 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt;= 1500/mm^3 (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to&#xD;
             registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &gt;= 100,000/mm^3 (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9.0 g/dL (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 1.5x upper limit of normal (ULN), or =&lt; 2.5x ULN if patient has&#xD;
             Gilbert syndrome or disease involving the liver (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to&#xD;
             registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) =&lt; 2.5x ULN (or =&lt;&#xD;
             5x ULN in presence of suspected liver metastases) (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to&#xD;
             registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum phosphate &lt; institutional ULN (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum calcium within institutional normal range, or serum albumin-corrected calcium&#xD;
             within institutional normal range (if serum albumin is outside of the institutional&#xD;
             normal range) (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Potassium levels &gt; institutional lower limit of normal (supplementation can be used to&#xD;
             correct potassium level during screening) (obtained =&lt; 28 days prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine =&lt; 1.5x ULN, or calculated creatinine clearance &gt; 30 mL/min using the&#xD;
             Cockcroft-Gault formula or 24-hours urine collection analysis (obtained =&lt; 28 days&#xD;
             prior to registration)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corrected QT interval (QTc) by Fridericia?s method (QTcF) assessed by&#xD;
             electrocardiogram (ECG) completed =&lt; 28 days prior to registration, and resulted as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QTcF =&lt; 450 msec in men, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QTcF =&lt; 470 msec in women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serum pregnancy test completed =&lt; 7 days prior to registration, for women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential only&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide tissue and blood samples for correlative research purposes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to allow transfer of tissue and blood samples, clinical information, and&#xD;
             outcome data collected from this trial for future research&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with pemigatinib&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with a selective FGFR inhibitor =&lt; 180 days (6 months) prior to&#xD;
             registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known hypersensitivity or severe reaction to an FGFR inhibitor, or to the excipients&#xD;
             of pemigatinib (i.e. microcrystalline cellulose, sodium starch glycolate, and&#xD;
             magnesium stearate)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current evidence of clinically significant corneal or retinal disorder confirmed by&#xD;
             ophthalmologic examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with other investigational study drug for any indication for any reason, or&#xD;
             receipt of anticancer medications =&lt; 14 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery =&lt; 28 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  External beam radiation therapy =&lt; 28 days prior to registration, or palliative&#xD;
             radiation for non-central nervous system (CNS) disease =&lt; 14 days prior to&#xD;
             registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Brain metastases, central nervous system (CNS) metastases, leptomeningeal disease, or&#xD;
             spinal cord compression&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Patients who are asymptomatic or previously treated and stable, without&#xD;
                  evidence of progression for &gt;= 28 days prior to registration are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Patients taking concomitant corticosteroids and/or anticonvulsants are&#xD;
                  allowed if patient is on a stable or decreasing dose of such treatment for &gt;= 28&#xD;
                  days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History or presence of significant cardiovascular disease or condition including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled angina pectoris (Canadian Cardiovascular Society grade II-IV despite&#xD;
                  medical therapy)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congestive heart failure (New York Heart Association class III or IV)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled arrhythmia requiring therapy. Note: Patients with a pacemaker and&#xD;
                  well-controlled rhythm for &gt;= 28 days prior to registration are not excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any of the following occurring =&lt; 6 months prior to registration: myocardial&#xD;
                  infarction, angioplasty, cardiac stenting, coronary/peripheral artery bypass&#xD;
                  graft, cerebrovascular accident or transient ischemic attack&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to adequately recover (i.e. to =&lt; grade 1 [according to Common Terminology&#xD;
             Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version (v.)5] or to pre-treatment baseline) from&#xD;
             adverse events (AEs) deemed by the investigator as clinically significant and&#xD;
             attributed to prior therapy. Exception: alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prohibited medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any potent CYP3A4 inhibitors or inducers or moderate CYP3A4 inducers =&lt; 14 days&#xD;
             or 5 half-lives (whichever is shorter) prior to registration. Note: topical&#xD;
             ketoconazole will be allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypovitaminosis D requiring supraphysiologic doses to replenish the&#xD;
             deficiency. Note: patients receiving vitamin D food supplements are allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History and/or current evidence of ectopic mineralization/calcification, including but&#xD;
             not limited to soft tissue, kidneys, intestine, myocardia, or lung; with the exception&#xD;
             of calcified lymph nodes and asymptomatic arterial or cartilage/tendon calcification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable or unwilling to swallow pemigatinib and keep a medication diary, or significant&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disorder(s) that could interfere with absorption, metabolism or&#xD;
             excretion of pemigatinib per the discretion of the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following because this study involves an investigational agent whose&#xD;
             genotoxic, mutagenic and teratogenic effects on the developing fetus and newborn are&#xD;
             unknown:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Nursing women&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of childbearing potential or men able to father children who have a female&#xD;
                  partner of childbearing potential, who are unwilling to employ acceptable&#xD;
                  contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of human immunodeficiency (HIV) infection or positivity on immunoassay&#xD;
             confirmed per local standards&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: HIV test is not required for screening, but patients with a known history&#xD;
                  of HIV infection will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of active hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV) infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other known active malignancy =&lt; 5 years prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  EXCEPTIONS: Non-melanotic skin cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix,&#xD;
                  provided there is no known active disease and no additional therapy for the&#xD;
                  condition is ongoing or required during the trial period&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: anti-estrogen/androgen therapy or bisphosphonates allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-morbid systemic illness, other severe concurrent disease, or psychiatric&#xD;
             illness/social situation which, in the judgment of the investigator, would make the&#xD;
             patient inappropriate for entry into this study, limit compliance with study&#xD;
             requirements, or interfere significantly with the proper assessment of safety and&#xD;
             toxicity of the prescribed regimen&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kristen K Ciombor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Academic and Community Cancer Research United</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Arizona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Scottsdale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85259</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referrals Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocliniccancerstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tanios S. Bekaii-Saab</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>MedStar Georgetown University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20007</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Brenton Foretich</last_name>
      <phone>202-687-4346</phone>
      <email>bjf53@georgetown.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Benjamin A. Weinberg</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory University Hospital/Winship Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>KJ Lee</last_name>
      <phone>404-778-3173</phone>
      <email>kyungjong.lee@emory.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Walid Shaib</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic in Rochester</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Clinical Trials Referrals Office</last_name>
      <phone>855-776-0015</phone>
      <email>mayocliniccancerstudies@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Joleen M. Hubbard</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Terrance Lawrence</last_name>
      <phone>919-668-1861</phone>
      <email>terrance.lawrence@duke.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jingquan Jia</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vanderbilt University/Ingram Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nashville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kristen Ciombor</last_name>
      <phone>877-936-8422</phone>
      <email>kristen.k.ciombor@vumc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kristen K. Ciombor</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Aurora Cancer Care-Milwaukee West</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wauwatosa</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53226</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Mathieu</last_name>
      <phone>414-302-2312</phone>
      <email>jennifer.mathieu@aurora.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Federico Augusto H. Sanchez</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 12, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 18, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 19, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

