<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01911884</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P110124</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>ID RCB : 2011-A01517-34</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01911884</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment of Quality of Global and Sexual Life and Impact of Surgical and Non Surgical Vaginal Aplasia in Patients With a Rokitansky Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>MRKH</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment of Quality of Global and Sexual Life and Impact of Surgical and Non Surgical Vaginal Aplasia in Patients With a Rokitansky Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The principal objective is to assess the general health status and the sexual health status&#xD;
      of women with Rokitansky syndrome having received a surgical or non surgical treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary purpose is to assess the anatomical aspect and the quality of sexual life. To&#xD;
      search a correlation between the anatomical result, the general and sexual quality of life.&#xD;
      To compare the different techniques of medical follow-up in terms of anatomic results,&#xD;
      general quality of life, sexual quality of life, complications and morbidities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate social inclusion of these women with their family situation, social and&#xD;
      professional category and their job.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the same time, we propose an evaluation with a psychologist to study the impact of the&#xD;
      announcement of the diagnosis. This impact study is conducted at a distance from diagnosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The MRKH syndrome is a congenital disorder characterized by absence of uterus and at least&#xD;
      the two thirds of the vagina, a female phenotype and a normal karyotype XX.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These patients have normal ovaries and fallopian tubes. The external genitalia are normal.&#xD;
      This syndrome was described by Mayer (1829), Rokitansky ( 1838), Kuster ( 1910) and Hauser (&#xD;
      1961). About one in every 4500 female babies has this condition. This syndrome represents 85%&#xD;
      of congenital vagina aplasia and is the second cause of primary amenorrhea after disorders of&#xD;
      sexual development. These women are unfertile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The malformation can be isolated or associated with other malformations called MURCS&#xD;
      (Müllerian duct aplasia, renal aplasia, and cervicothoracic somite dysplasia), as kidney (&#xD;
      30%), bone ( 10%) or cardiac malformations ( 1%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The most common age for MRKH to be diagnosed is when the woman hasn't started her period (&#xD;
      85%).Some girls may find out at an earlier age when there is a severe malformation , during a&#xD;
      systematic gynaecological examination or during an pelvic ultrasound. When the women are&#xD;
      older, the syndrome can be diagnosed during studies for infertility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pelvic ultrasound is usually the first test performed to assess presence of uterus. A&#xD;
      magnetic resonance imaging may be used to complete the investigations. These tests can also&#xD;
      confirm if there are two ovaries and two kidneys. Sometimes, a very small uterus can be seen,&#xD;
      it's a uterine horn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The psychological management is essential to take care of the women affected.It seeks to&#xD;
      understand the impact of the diagnosis announcement and the various treatments offered. The&#xD;
      follow-up can be different for each girl and her parents during several appointments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therapeutic management can be proposed when the girl is ready because the therapeutic is long&#xD;
      and difficult. Two therapeutic approaches can be proposed: to create a vagina using dilators&#xD;
      or having a surgical procedure. In France, vaginal reconstruction with dilators is the most&#xD;
      used. This method consists in dilating the vagina progressively with different sizes of&#xD;
      dilators in order to obtain a vaginal opening of 8 cm around 6 months after treatment&#xD;
      initiation. This method is successful in about 75% of cases. Complications are exceptional.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery is an option for patients who are unsuccessful with dilatators or patients who prefer&#xD;
      surgery. A number of operations are appropriate for the correction of vaginal agenesis.&#xD;
      Vecchietti procedure and sigmoid vaginoplasty are the most commonly used techniques in&#xD;
      France.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In national and international publications, it is impossible to compare scientifically the&#xD;
      results of the different technique because of the small effective in each studies and because&#xD;
      of the the lack of standardized assessment. Studies report the functional result for each&#xD;
      technique but none compare the techniques used. No studies compared the result in terms of&#xD;
      anatomical and function results, complications and quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The demonstration of a positive correlation between the anatomic criteria and the functional&#xD;
      results would help to guide the surgical technique. The lack of correlation would suggest&#xD;
      that a perfect anatomical reconstruction is not essential. If it is demonstrated, the&#xD;
      management should focus on other criteria like psychological management. Several factors seem&#xD;
      to influence the general and sexual quality of life of women affected by the Rokitansky&#xD;
      syndrome. Our objective is to evaluate the importance of these factors to improve the&#xD;
      treatment of these women.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 11, 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 10, 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 10, 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of quality of global life</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>To fill a self-administered questionnaire: the World Health Organization Quality Of Life (general scale WHOQOL)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of quality of sexual life</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>To fill 2 self-administered questionnaires : Female Sexual Function Index and Female Sexual Dysfunction Scale-Revised (FSFI and FSDS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of anatomic results</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>Gynaecological examination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of social integration</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>To fill a self-administered questionnaire (marital status, occupational group, education level, employment status)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">138</enrollment>
  <condition>Rokitansky Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Surgical or Vaginal Dilatation of Vaginal Aplasia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with a Rokitansky Syndrome</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with a Rokitansky Syndrome</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>evaluate quality of life of surgical and non surgical vaginal aplasia</intervention_name>
    <description>protocol designed to evaluate quality of life of surgical and non surgical vaginal aplasia</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with a Rokitansky Syndrome</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient affected with Rokitansky syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient over 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient care with dilatations or by surgery since 1995&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient having started dilatations or having had surgery since at least one year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who signed the consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  French patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with social welfare&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a serious chronic disease interfering with analysis to be performed in&#xD;
             this project.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient can't reading or writing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with legal protection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michel POLAK, PUPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Service d'Endocrinologie et Gynécologie Pédiatriques Hôpital Necker Enfants Malades</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <zip>75015</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cheikhelard A, Bidet M, Baptiste A, Viaud M, Fagot C, Khen-Dunlop N, Louis-Sylvestre C, Sarnacki S, Touraine P, Elie C, Aigrain Y, Polak M; French MRKH Study Group. Surgery is not superior to dilation for the management of vaginal agenesis in Mayer-Rokitansky-Küster-Hauser syndrome: a multicenter comparative observational study in 131 patients. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2018 Sep;219(3):281.e1-281.e9. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2018.07.015. Epub 2018 Jul 21.</citation>
    <PMID>30036500</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 26, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 30, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Rokitansky syndrome</keyword>
  <keyword>surgical or vaginal dilatation of vaginal aplasia</keyword>
  <keyword>quality of global and sexual life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Dilatation, Pathologic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

