<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01910545</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OTS167-FR02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01910545</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase 1 Study of OTS167 in Patients With Solid Tumors</brief_title>
  <official_title>PhaseI, Single-Center, Cohort Dose Escalation Trial to Determine the Safety, Tolerance, and Preliminary Antineoplastic Activity of OTS167, a MELK Inhibitor, in Patients With Refractory Locally Advanced or Metastatic Solid Tumor Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>OncoTherapy Science, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>OncoTherapy Science, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to test the safety and tolerability of an investigational drug&#xD;
      called OTS167. OTS167 is a maternal embryonic leucine zipper kinase (MELK) inhibitor which&#xD;
      demonstrated antitumor properties in laboratory tests. It is being developed as an&#xD;
      anti-cancer drug. In this first-in-human study OTS167 will be administered to patients with&#xD;
      solid tumors which have not responded to treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 23, 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 4, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 11, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with adverse events and/or dose-limiting toxicities as a measure of safety and tolerability of OTS167 IV infusion.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days after last dose of study drug</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <condition>Metastatic Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OTS167IV</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>single arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OTS167IV</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>OTS167IV</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female patients, &gt;= 18 years of age at the time of obtaining informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with a documented (histologically- or cytologically-proven) solid tumor&#xD;
             malignancy that is locally advanced or metastatic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with a malignancy that is either refractory to standard therapy or for which&#xD;
             no standard therapy is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with a malignancy that is currently not amenable to surgical intervention due&#xD;
             to either medical contraindications or non-resectability of the tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with measurable or non-measurable disease according to the response&#xD;
             evaluation criteria in solid tumors (RECIST , v1.1)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with an Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status (PS) of&#xD;
             0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients, both male and female, who are either not of childbearing potential or who&#xD;
             agree to use a medically effective method of contraception during the study and for 3&#xD;
             months after the last dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with the ability to understand and give written informed consent for&#xD;
             participation in this trial, including all evaluations and procedures as specified by&#xD;
             this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Women who are pregnant or lactating. Women of child-bearing potential (WOCBP), and&#xD;
             fertile men with a WOCBP-partner not using adequate birth control.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with known central nervous system (CNS) or leptomeningeal metastases not&#xD;
             controlled by prior surgery or radiotherapy, or patients with symptoms suggesting CNS&#xD;
             involvement for which treatment is required.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with any hematologic malignancy. This includes leukemia (any form), lymphoma,&#xD;
             and multiple myeloma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with any of the following hematologic abnormalities at baseline:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &lt; 1,500 per mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &lt; 100,000 per mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with any of the following serum chemistry abnormalities at baseline:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &gt;= 1.5 × the ULN for the institution&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;= 3 × the&#xD;
                  upper limit normal (ULN) for the institution (&gt;= 5 × if due to hepatic&#xD;
                  involvement by tumor)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum albumin &lt; 2.5 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine &gt;= 1.5 × ULN for the institution (or a calculated creatinine clearance&#xD;
                  &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73 m2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with a significant cardiovascular disease or condition, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congestive heart failure (CHF) currently requiring therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Need for antiarrhythmic medical therapy for a ventricular arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Severe conduction disturbance&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Angina pectoris requiring therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corrected QT (QTc) interval &gt; 450 msec (males) or &gt; 470 msec (females)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QTc interval &lt;= 300 msec&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of congenital long QT syndrome or congenital short QT syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt; 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled hypertension (per the Investigator's discretion)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Class III or IV cardiovascular disease according to the New York Heart&#xD;
                  Association's (NYHA) Functional Criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction (MI) within 6 months prior to first study drug&#xD;
                  administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with a known or suspected hypersensitivity to any of the components of&#xD;
             OTS167.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with a known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or active&#xD;
             infection with hepatitis B virus (HBV) or hepatitis C virus (HCV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with any other serious/active/uncontrolled infection, any infection requiring&#xD;
             parenteral antibiotics, or unexplained fever &gt; 38ºC within 1 week prior to first study&#xD;
             drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with inadequate recovery from acute toxicity associated with any prior&#xD;
             antineoplastic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients with inadequate recovery from any prior surgical procedure, or patients&#xD;
             having undergone any major surgical procedure within 4 weeks prior to first study drug&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients with any other life-threatening illness, significant organ system&#xD;
             dysfunction, or clinically significant laboratory abnormality, which, in the opinion&#xD;
             of the Investigator, would either compromise the patient's safety or interfere with&#xD;
             evaluation of the safety of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients with a psychiatric disorder or altered mental status that would preclude&#xD;
             understanding of the informed consent process and/or completion of the necessary&#xD;
             studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients with the inability or with foreseeable incapacity, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             Investigator, to comply with the protocol requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 23, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 25, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 29, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 31, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 31, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 1, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>OTS167</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

