<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02377765</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LWH0991</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02377765</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Use of Transcutaneous Posterior Tibial Nerve Stimulation (TPTNS) in Maintaining OAB Symptoms Improvement.</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Single Blind, Randomised, Controlled Trial to Evaluate the Effectiveness of Transcutaneous Posterior Tibial Nerve Stimulation (TPTNS) in Overactive Bladder (OAB) Symptoms in Women Responders to Posterior Tibial Nerve Stimulation (PTNS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Liverpool Women's NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Manchester Metropolitan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Liverpool Women's NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will help to determine the effectiveness of a self-supervised, home-based&#xD;
      Transcutaneous Posterior Tibial Nerve Stimulation treatment protocol in maintaining&#xD;
      Overactive Bladder (OAB) symptoms improvement in women responders to Posterior Tibial Nerve&#xD;
      Stimulation (PTNS)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Conservative management of OAB includes (NICE, 2006): behavioural therapy (bladder training&#xD;
      techniques, prompted voiding, timed voiding…); physical therapy (PFM exercises, Biofeedback,&#xD;
      Neuro Muscular Electrical Stimulation…); lifestyle interventions (weight loss, smoking&#xD;
      cessation…) and fluid advice (fluid balance, reduction of caffeine intake…). Antimuscarinic&#xD;
      agents are recommended if non-pharmacological treatment proves ineffective (NICE, 2006).&#xD;
      However, results of behavioural and physical therapy have been shown to fall off by three&#xD;
      months after treatment (Burgio et al, 1998). Furthermore, less than one third of patients are&#xD;
      compliant with anticholinergic medication after 6 months, mostly due to intolerable side&#xD;
      effects, but also to lack of efficacy (Hampel, 2007; Kelleher et al, 1997).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients refractory to conservative regimens are candidates in our Physiotherapy Department&#xD;
      for peripheral Neuromodulation therapy in the form of Percutaneus Tibial Nerve Stimulation&#xD;
      (PTNS). Although its mechanism of action is still poorly understood, its efficacy has been&#xD;
      reported to be comparable to that of the antimuscarinic agents, with an objective success&#xD;
      rate of 60% (Burton, Sajja &amp; Latthe, 2012), but with a better side effect profile.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TPTNS is a non-invasive technique, easily manageable by patients, which lacks some adverse&#xD;
      side effects reported with the use of PTNS, such as bleeding and/or pain at the site of&#xD;
      needle insertion. As the technique is self-administered, the associated costs might be&#xD;
      substantially lower when compared to PTNS, which involves repeated Hospital appointments for&#xD;
      maintenance therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will help to determine the effectiveness of a self-supervised, home-based&#xD;
      Transcutaneous Posterior Tibial Nerve Stimulation treatment protocol in maintaining&#xD;
      Overactive Bladder (OAB) symptoms improvement in women responders to Posterior Tibial Nerve&#xD;
      Stimulation (PTNS)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be assigned to one of the two treatments arms using a computer generated&#xD;
      random number table, with assignments drawn from sealed, opaque, serially numbered envelopes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be recruited from the Physiotherapy Department at the Liverpool Women's&#xD;
      Hospital. Our primary outcome variable will be changes in 24-hour voiding frequency, number&#xD;
      of episodes of urgency, as well as number of episodes of urge urinary incontinence. These&#xD;
      variables can be reliably measured in self-completed 3-day bladder diaries (Gormley et al,&#xD;
      2012).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As OAB is a symptom-based diagnosis, the quality of life (QoL) impact of the symptoms is a&#xD;
      crucial aspect of the condition. We will therefore use as secondary end point the score in&#xD;
      the OAB-q questionnaire, a patient-reported outcome measure (PROM) of symptom severity as&#xD;
      well as Health Related Quality of Life (HRQOL). The OAB-q has shown good content and&#xD;
      construct validity, as well as high internal consistency and good test-retest reliability&#xD;
      (Coyne et al, 2006).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bladder diaries and the OAB-q questionnaire are routinely used in our Department for all&#xD;
      patients starting on PTNS (T1). Collection of data will be carried out again at the end of&#xD;
      the 12-week course of PTNS. Data obtained at this point (T2) will determine those subjects&#xD;
      who are objective responders and who will be invited to enter the trial and be randomized&#xD;
      into one of the two treatment arms. During the study period, further assessments will be&#xD;
      carried out by the main investigator, who will be blinded to the treatment group allocation,&#xD;
      at 6 weeks (T3), 3 months (T4) and 6 months (T5).&#xD;
&#xD;
      PTNS will be performed bilaterally, inserting a 40 mm x 0.25 mm acupuncture needle (Classic&#xD;
      Plus Sterile Needle, HMD Europe), three finger breaths cephalad to medial malleolus and&#xD;
      posterior to the medial border of the tibia (SP6 acupuncture point). A self-adhesive&#xD;
      electrode will be placed on the medial aspect of the calcaneus. The needle and the electrode&#xD;
      will be attached to a low voltage electrostimulator (AS SUPER 4 digital, Pierenkemper GmbH,&#xD;
      Germany), set up with a pulse duration of 200 μsecs and a frequency of 20 Hz. The amplitude&#xD;
      (0-20 mA, adjustable in steps of 0.1 mA) will be increased until flexion of the first toe or&#xD;
      fanning of all toes is seen, or tingling sensation in the sole of the foot is reported,&#xD;
      always at a tolerable level. Elevation of the Intensity will be allowed whenever the patient&#xD;
      describes fading of the above sensation due to accommodation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TPTNS will be also applied bilaterally, using two surface self-adhesive electrodes in each&#xD;
      leg, one placed at SP6 and the other placed on the ankle skin behind the medial malleolus.&#xD;
      Electrical stimulation will be applied through a TENS unit (NeuroTrac PelviTone, Verity&#xD;
      Medical Ltd, Hampshire, UK) using the same parameters as in the PTNS group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An experienced Women's Health physiotherapist will conduct the PTNS sessions in the control&#xD;
      group and will instruct subjects in the TPTNS group in the stimulation technique.&#xD;
      Participants will be provided with a telephone number to contact the research team in case&#xD;
      they have any queries or any difficulty with the use of the TENS unit.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in 24-hour micturition frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>Bladder diaries completed at recruitment and 6 weeks, 12 weeks and 6 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Mean number of micturition episodes recorded in 3-day bladder chart.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom severity</measure>
    <time_frame>OAB-q completed at recruitment and 6 weeks, 12 weeks and 6 months.</time_frame>
    <description>Severity score on validated OAB-q questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Related Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>OAB-q completed at recruitment and 6 weeks, 12 weeks and 6 months.</time_frame>
    <description>HRQoL score as recorded on OAB-q</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Overactive Bladder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Percutaneus Stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>PTNS performed bilaterally every 4 weeks within the Physiotherapy Department.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transcutaneous Stimulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TPTNS applied bilaterally, using two surface, self-adhesive, round electrodes (3 cm in diameter) in each leg at least 3 times per week.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transcutaneous Stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>TPTNS through a TENS unit is a non-invasive technique, easily manageable by patients, which lacks some adverse side effects reported with the use of PTNS, such as bleeding and/or pain at the site of needle insertion. As the technique is self-administered, the associated costs might be substantially lower when compared to PTNS, which involves repeated Hospital appointments for maintenance therapy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcutaneous Stimulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Percutaneus Stimulation</intervention_name>
    <description>PTNS aims to stimulate the sacral nerve plexus (origin to the parasympathetic innervations to the bladder) through the afferent fibres of the posterior tibial nerve, a mixed nerve containing L5-S3 fibres (Slovak, Chapple and Barker, 2014). This is achieved by a needle electrode inserted above the medial malleolus. Interestingly, this anatomical area is known as acupuncture point Spleen6 (Sp6).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Percutaneus Stimulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically diagnosed of idiopathic OAB according to the definition by the&#xD;
             International Continence Society (Haylen et al, 2012) given above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good response to PTNS. For the purpose of this study, responders will be considered&#xD;
             those subjects who have achieved a reduction in the number of micturitions per 24&#xD;
             hours by &gt; 30%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who do not comprehend the physiotherapist's instructions or who are unable to&#xD;
             co-operate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, or plans of becoming pregnant during the course of the study. The main&#xD;
             acupuncture point that will be used (SP6) has been reported to induce uterine activity&#xD;
             (Hecker et al, 2001).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of a relevant neurological condition (causing neurogenic detrusor&#xD;
             overactivity or peripheral neuropathy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of continence surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with a pace-maker fitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with uncorrectable coagulopathies or on anticoagulant medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of dermatological lesions (e.g. dermatitis, eczema...) in the medial aspect&#xD;
             of lower leg and/or feet.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No anticholinergic medication will be allowed during the study period with minimum&#xD;
             wash-out period of 15 days before randomization.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Miguel Martin-Garcia, MSc</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Liverpool Women's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Liverpool Women's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Liverpool</city>
        <zip>L8 7SS</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 26, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 3, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">March 4, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 19, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 19, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 20, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Neuromodulation</keyword>
  <keyword>Detrusor overactivity</keyword>
  <keyword>Urinary urgency</keyword>
  <keyword>Urgency urinary incontinence</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

