<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02372279</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>InstitutoBernabeu</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02372279</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prospective Randomized Study to Evaluate the Effect of Embryonic Observation on the Gestation (PROdE)</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROdE</acronym>
  <official_title>Prospective Randomized Study to Evaluate the Effect of Embryonic Observation on the Live Birth Rate (LBR)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Instituto Bernabeu</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Instituto Bernabeu</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In a conventional in vitro fertilization (IVF) cycle, daily microscopic observation of&#xD;
      embryos outside the incubator to assess their morphology and establish a selection process is&#xD;
      performed. In this way it is possible to know which embryo or embryos have greater&#xD;
      implantantion capacity and will be transferred to the uterus to obtain a viable pregnancy.&#xD;
      However, these observations can produce deleterious effects on embryo development due to&#xD;
      changes in temperature, pH and osmolarity of the culture media, as well as a negative effect&#xD;
      of direct light microscope for observation. This project aims to test the hypothesis that&#xD;
      non-embryonic observation produces a beneficial effect on embryo quality until day 5 of&#xD;
      development (blastocyst stage) and, therefore, on rates of implantation and ongoing&#xD;
      gestation, compared with the conventional protocol of observations under the inverted&#xD;
      microscope on days two, three and five of development.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The present study is a prospective double-blind randomised controlled trial (RCT) approved by&#xD;
      a local Ethics Committe. Summarily, in the control group we did three embryo observations&#xD;
      outside the incubator as we usually do in our conventional protocol: day 2, day 3 and day 5,&#xD;
      just before ET; in the study group we performed a unique embryo observation on day 5 before&#xD;
      ET. All the subjects that participated in the study were informed and gave us their consent&#xD;
      to take part on it.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria of the study were: first cycle of ART treatment with conventional IVF&#xD;
      or ICSI with donated eggs, normal uterine cavity and a single or double embryo transfer,&#xD;
      always performed on day 5 at blastocyst stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exclusion criteria were the following: patients above 50 years old, patients that were&#xD;
      diagnosed with recurrent implantation failure (RIF) and/or recurrent pregnancy loss (RPL) or&#xD;
      uterine pathologies, body mass index &gt;30 kg/m2, the use of seminal samples coming from donors&#xD;
      or testicular origin and cycles that included preimplantational genetic testing (PGT).&#xD;
&#xD;
      LBR was the main outcome of our study, defined as the number of deliveries that resulted in a&#xD;
      live born neonate, expressed per 100 embryo transfers (Zegers- Hochschild et al., 2009).&#xD;
      Secondary efficacy endpoints were positive hCG rate (&gt;5 mUI/mL, assessed in serum 14 days&#xD;
      after oocyte retrieval), implantation rate (number of gestational sacs observed divided by&#xD;
      the number of embryos transferred, expressed as a percentage, %), ongoing pregnancy rate,&#xD;
      defined as a pregnancy with a detectable heart rate at 12 weeks of gestation or beyond and&#xD;
      miscarriage (loss of a pregnancy after 12 weeks of gestation).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, we assessed the next IVF laboratory parameters: fertilization rate, blastocyst&#xD;
      formation rate on day 5, blastocyst quality, number of transferred embryos and number of&#xD;
      usable blastocysts (number of blastocysts transferred and frozen).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size calculation was based on the primary outcome. We assumed a live birth rate of&#xD;
      40% in the control group, compared to 50% in the non-observational group deduced from&#xD;
      previous studies. By applicating the sample size calculation program, 776 patients (388 per&#xD;
      group) were required in order to detect a risk difference (RD) of 10% between the two groups&#xD;
      in the final analysis, with a power of 80% at a two-sided, adjusted alpha-level of 0.05. A&#xD;
      follow-up loss rate of 10% was estimated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The forecast regarding the number of patients that could enter the study were not met in the&#xD;
    designated period&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Live Birth Rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Nine months after treatment.</time_frame>
    <description>The number of deliveries that resulted in a live born neonate, expressed per 100 embryos</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive hCG rate</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days after oocyte retrieval.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of treatments with a level of BhCG &gt;5 mUI/mL, assessed in serum.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Implantation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6-7 weeks after oocyte retrieval.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of gestational sacs observed divided by the number of embryos transferred. expressed as a percentage, %.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ongoing pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks after B-hCG positive test</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as a pregnancy with a detectable heart rate at 12 weeks of gestation or beyond.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Miscarriage rate</measure>
    <time_frame>From 12 weeks after gestation to delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Loss of a pregnancy after 12 weeks of gestation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fertilization rate</measure>
    <time_frame>16-18 hours after microinjection or insemination</time_frame>
    <description>Number of fertilized oocytes out of the total microinjected or inseminated.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blastocyst formation rate on day 5</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days after microinjection or insemination.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of embryos that reach the blastocyst stage at day 5</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blastocyst quality</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days after microinjection or insemination.</time_frame>
    <description>The assessment of blastocyst morphology in several grades</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of usable blastocysts</measure>
    <time_frame>5 days after microinjection or insemination.</time_frame>
    <description>Number of blastocysts transferred and frozen.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">193</enrollment>
  <condition>Placenta; Implantation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No embryo observation (NEO)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Study group. No embryonic observation from day one to day five of embryo development.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Embryo observation (EO)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group. Conventional embryonic observations performed in day two, three and five of embryo development.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Embryo observation</intervention_name>
    <description>In EO group, conventional observations will be made.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Embryo observation (EO)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First cycle of ART treatment with conventional IVF or ICSI with donated eggs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal uterine cavity and a single or double embryo transfer, always performed on day&#xD;
             5 at blastocyst stage.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients above 50 years old, patients that were diagnosed with recurrent implantation&#xD;
             failure (RIF) and/or recurrent pregnancy loss (RPL) or uterine pathologies,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body mass index &gt;30 kg/m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The use of seminal samples coming from donors or testicular origin.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cycles that included preimplantational genetic testing (PGT).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jorge Ten Morro, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Instituto Bernabeu</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Bernabeu</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alicante</city>
        <zip>03016</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alpha Scientists in Reproductive Medicine and ESHRE Special Interest Group of Embryology. The Istanbul consensus workshop on embryo assessment: proceedings of an expert meeting. Hum Reprod. 2011 Jun;26(6):1270-83. doi: 10.1093/humrep/der037. Epub 2011 Apr 18.</citation>
    <PMID>21502182</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fujiwara M, Takahashi K, Izuno M, Duan YR, Kazono M, Kimura F, Noda Y. Effect of micro-environment maintenance on embryo culture after in-vitro fertilization: comparison of top-load mini incubator and conventional front-load incubator. J Assist Reprod Genet. 2007 Jan;24(1):5-9. Epub 2006 Dec 13.</citation>
    <PMID>17160731</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gardner DK, Lane M, Stevens J, Schlenker T, Schoolcraft WB. Blastocyst score affects implantation and pregnancy outcome: towards a single blastocyst transfer. Fertil Steril. 2000 Jun;73(6):1155-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10856474</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bernabeu R, Roca M, Torres A, Ten J. Indomethacin effect on implantation rates in oocyte recipients. Hum Reprod. 2006 Feb;21(2):364-9. Epub 2005 Nov 10.</citation>
    <PMID>16284067</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Herrero J, Tejera A, Albert C, Vidal C, de los Santos MJ, Meseguer M. A time to look back: analysis of morphokinetic characteristics of human embryo development. Fertil Steril. 2013 Dec;100(6):1602-9.e1-4. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2013.08.033. Epub 2013 Sep 29.</citation>
    <PMID>24083877</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhang JQ, Li XL, Peng Y, Guo X, Heng BC, Tong GQ. Reduction in exposure of human embryos outside the incubator enhances embryo quality and blastulation rate. Reprod Biomed Online. 2010 Apr;20(4):510-5. doi: 10.1016/j.rbmo.2009.12.027. Epub 2009 Dec 28.</citation>
    <PMID>20129824</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kirkegaard K, Kesmodel US, Hindkjær JJ, Ingerslev HJ. Time-lapse parameters as predictors of blastocyst development and pregnancy outcome in embryos from good prognosis patients: a prospective cohort study. Hum Reprod. 2013 Oct;28(10):2643-51. doi: 10.1093/humrep/det300. Epub 2013 Jul 30.</citation>
    <PMID>23900207</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Steptoe PC, Edwards RG. Birth after the reimplantation of a human embryo. Lancet. 1978 Aug 12;2(8085):366.</citation>
    <PMID>79723</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bognar Z, Csabai TJ, Pallinger E, Balassa T, Farkas N, Schmidt J, Görgey E, Berta G, Szekeres-Bartho J, Bodis J. The effect of light exposure on the cleavage rate and implantation capacity of preimplantation murine embryos. J Reprod Immunol. 2019 Apr;132:21-28. doi: 10.1016/j.jri.2019.02.003. Epub 2019 Mar 4.</citation>
    <PMID>30852462</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Barberet J, Chammas J, Bruno C, Valot E, Vuillemin C, Jonval L, Choux C, Sagot P, Soudry A, Fauque P. Randomized controlled trial comparing embryo culture in two incubator systems: G185 K-System versus EmbryoScope. Fertil Steril. 2018 Feb;109(2):302-309.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2017.10.008. Epub 2017 Nov 23.</citation>
    <PMID>29175066</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Armstrong S, Bhide P, Jordan V, Pacey A, Marjoribanks J, Farquhar C. Time-lapse systems for embryo incubation and assessment in assisted reproduction. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2019 May 29;5:CD011320. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD011320.pub4.</citation>
    <PMID>31140578</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kalleas D, McEvoy K, Horne G, Roberts SA, Brison DR. Live birth rate following undisturbed embryo culture at low oxygen in a time-lapse incubator compared to a high-quality benchtop incubator. Hum Fertil (Camb). 2020 Feb 26:1-7. doi: 10.1080/14647273.2020.1729423. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32098536</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 20, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 20, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 26, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Instituto Bernabeu</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jorge Ten Morro</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Ph.D. Embryologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Embryo development</keyword>
  <keyword>Implantation</keyword>
  <keyword>In vitro fertilization</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

