<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02370069</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RP-232-08262014</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02370069</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Previous Pneumococcal Immunization on the Immune Response of Patients With Severe CKD to Prevnar 13</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Previous Pneumococcal Immunization on the Immune Response of Adult Patients With Severe Chronic Kidney Disease to Prevnar 13</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lakehead University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lakehead University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with severe chronic kidney disease (CKD) are at a great risk for infection due to&#xD;
      their immune system being suppressed. Pneumococcal infection is particularly common and often&#xD;
      results in death due to inflammation of lung (pneumonia) or the whole body (sepsis). This&#xD;
      infection can be prevented using vaccines which help build protective immunity. The currently&#xD;
      recommended pneumococcal vaccine (Pneumovax), however, is often inefficient in this group of&#xD;
      patients. There is thus an urgent need to improve the existing vaccination policy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this research is to optimize pneumococcal vaccination of patients with severe&#xD;
      CKD. Many patients suffering from CKD have already been vaccinated with Pneumovax. Because&#xD;
      this vaccine has low immunogenicity in immunocompromised individuals, they may still develop&#xD;
      infection. A new vaccine, Prevnar13, has superior immunogenicity and has been recently&#xD;
      approved for immunization. There is, however, no specific policy regarding immunization of&#xD;
      adult CKD patients, and it is furthermore unknown whether previous Pneumovax immunization&#xD;
      negatively affects immune response to Prevnar13.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to test whether previous immunization with Pneumovax affects the immune response of&#xD;
      severe CKD patients to Prevnar 13, the investigators will immunize two groups of adult stage&#xD;
      4 and 5 CKD patients with one dose of Prevnar 13 and will assess their initial immunological&#xD;
      response, its longevity, and vaccine safety. The first group will consist of patients who had&#xD;
      been previously immunized with Pneumovax, and the second group will include participants with&#xD;
      no history of pneumococcal vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Antibody levels and opsonophagocytic activity (OPA) will be quantified. The longevity of the&#xD;
      immune response will be assessed. As a secondary objective, the immune response will be&#xD;
      analyzed in the context of demographic and clinical characteristics of the vaccinated&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Adult patients with severe chronic kidney disease (CKD) are immunocompromised and known to&#xD;
      have an increased risk of pneumococcal infection. To prevent the infection, immunization with&#xD;
      pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccine (PPV23) is currently recommended in Canada; however, the&#xD;
      vaccine effect in these patients is suboptimal because of their immune dysfunction. The&#xD;
      second-generation pneumococcal vaccines (polysaccharide-protein conjugate) have superior&#xD;
      immunogenicity in some immunocompromised adult individuals. In Canada, Prevnar 13 has&#xD;
      recently been recommended by the NACI for certain categories of immunocompromised adults,&#xD;
      such as HSCT recipients and HIV-positive patients. However, the NACI has concluded that there&#xD;
      is currently insufficient evidence to recommend the use of Prevnar 13 in patients with&#xD;
      chronic kidney disease. No published data on the use of pneumococcal conjugate vaccines in&#xD;
      adults with CKD are available. Moreover, it is unknown whether a previous immunization with&#xD;
      PPV23 may have a negative effect on the immune response to Prevnar 13 in these patients. Such&#xD;
      a possibility exists due to the memory B-cells' depletion following immunization with pure&#xD;
      polysaccharide antigens. In this case, additional doses of Prevnar 13 may be required to&#xD;
      achieve the optimal protection. The conjugate vaccine will then expand the B-cell pool&#xD;
      available to respond to subsequent antigen challenge. To test whether previous immunization&#xD;
      with PPV23 affects the immune response of severe CKD patients to Prevnar 13, we will immunize&#xD;
      two groups of adult stage 4 and 5 CKD patients attending the Thunder Bay Regional Health&#xD;
      Sciences Centre with one dose of Prevnar 13 and will assess their initial immunological&#xD;
      response, its longevity, and vaccine safety. The first group will consist of patients who had&#xD;
      been immunized with PPV23 more than one year prior to the enrollment in this study and the&#xD;
      second group will include patients without history of pneumococcal vaccination. Fold increase&#xD;
      in antibody levels and OPA, as well as longevity of the immune response over a one-year&#xD;
      period will be assessed as the surrogate for protection against pneumococcal infection. The&#xD;
      immune response will be analyzed in the context of demographic and clinical characteristics&#xD;
      of the vaccinated patients. All infectious episodes in the study participants will be&#xD;
      recorded throughout one year of observation. We will also record all vaccine adverse effects&#xD;
      following immunization and compare their frequency and severity between the two groups. The&#xD;
      anticipated results of this trial will provide essential evidence to justify the use of&#xD;
      Prevnar 13 for immunization of adult CKD patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>immunogenicity (Fold increase in serotype-specific antibody levels 28 days post-immunization as compared to baseline)</measure>
    <time_frame>0 days, 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Fold increase in serotype-specific antibody levels 28 days post-immunization as compared to baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>immunogenicity (Increase in OPA titres 28 days post-immunization)</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>Increase in OPA titres 28 days post-immunization</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Longevity of the immune response (Persistence of antibody one year post-immunization)</measure>
    <time_frame>365 days</time_frame>
    <description>Persistence of antibody one year post-immunization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Longevity of the immune response (Persistence of OPA titres one year post-immunization)</measure>
    <time_frame>365 days</time_frame>
    <description>Persistence of OPA titres one year post-immunization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical effect (Number of all infectious episodes during one year post-immunization)</measure>
    <time_frame>365 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of all infectious episodes during one year post-immunization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">138</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Kidney Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Previous immunization with PPV23</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who have received a previous vaccination with 1 or more dose of PPV23 at least 12 months previously will receive one dose of 0.5 mL Prevnar 13 study vaccine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Naive to PPV23</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants who have never received a previous vaccination with PPV23 will receive one dose of 0.5 mL Prevnar 13 study vaccine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prevnar 13</intervention_name>
    <description>One dose of 0.5 mL Prevnar 13 injected intramuscularly into the deltoid muscle on Day 0.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Naive to PPV23</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Previous immunization with PPV23</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females of 18 years of age or older at the time of the vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe chronic kidney disease (Stage 4 and 5)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  immunization with PPV23 within the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any confirmed or suspected immunodeficiency condition, including human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection, haematological malignancy, or a congenital&#xD;
             immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of allergic disease or reactions likely to be exacerbated by any component of&#xD;
             the vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of allergic disease likely to be stimulated by the vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history or records of immunosuppressive therapy (with the exception of topical&#xD;
             corticosteroids) for more than 14 days and within 6 months of vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history or evidence of administration of immunoglobulins and/or any blood products&#xD;
             during the study period or within the three months preceding the study vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  use of any other investigational or non-registered drug or vaccine during the study&#xD;
             period or within 30 days preceding the study vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  administration of a vaccine during the period starting one month before the dose of&#xD;
             vaccine and ending one month after&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marina Ulanova, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Lakehead University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Thunder Bay Regional Health Sciences Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Thunder Bay</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>P7B 6V4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ulanova M, Huska B, Desbiens A, Gaultier GN, Domonkos V, McCready WG. Immunogenicity and safety of the 13-valent pneumococcal conjugate vaccine in 23-valent pneumococcal polysaccharide vaccine-naïve and previously immunized adult patients with severe chronic kidney disease. Vaccine. 2021 Jan 22;39(4):699-710. doi: 10.1016/j.vaccine.2020.12.035. Epub 2020 Dec 24.</citation>
    <PMID>33358702</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 18, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 23, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 24, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Lakehead University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marina Ulanova</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor, Division of Medical Sciences</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Kidney Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Renal Insufficiency, Chronic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heptavalent Pneumococcal Conjugate Vaccine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

