<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02371005</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>6026</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02371005</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oral Manifestations of Systemic Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Oral Manifestations of Systemic Sclerosis: Toward the Identification of New Prognostic Markers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Strasbourg, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Strasbourg, France</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Systemic sclerosis (SSc) is a rare multisystem connective-tissue disorder characterized by&#xD;
      three major pathological hallmarks: widespread fibrosis, vasculopathy and immunological&#xD;
      abnormalities. As all connective tissues can be affected, this condition has multiple effects&#xD;
      on the orofacial region. Indeed, the latter is involved in approximately 80% of SSc patients.&#xD;
      Oral manifestations have a major impact on quality of life and require specific treatments&#xD;
      that should be performed as early as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Widening of the periodontal ligament space, that seems to be linked to an increased collagen&#xD;
      synthesis, is one of the most common dental radiographic finding. However, this radiologic&#xD;
      sign has been mostly studied on two-dimensional radiographs. The investigators have recently&#xD;
      described in a patient suffering from SSc the existence of calcifications within the&#xD;
      periodontal ligament space using Cone Beam Computed Tomography (CBCT) approach (Jung et al.,&#xD;
      Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol 2013). Such calcifications, that have never been&#xD;
      observed before, could be part of the phenotypic spectrum of the disease, in particular when&#xD;
      dystrophic calcinosis is associated. They could furthermore constitute a specific feature of&#xD;
      SSc. However, this radiographic sign requires to be investigated in a largest number of&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several cytokines have been implicated in SSc pathogenesis. A recent study has revealed that&#xD;
      elevated CXCL4 serum levels correlate with disease complications, suggesting that this&#xD;
      molecule could be used as a prognostic biomarker. Increased IL-6 serum levels also correlate&#xD;
      with SSc severity. Gingival crevicular fluid can be easily collected from the gingival&#xD;
      crevice surrounding the teeth and constitute an indicator of local but also systemic&#xD;
      inflammation. Analysis of gingival crevicular fluid cytokine profile could contribute to the&#xD;
      identification of specific SSc biomarkers and allow a better comprehension of oral&#xD;
      manifestations pathogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this case-control study is to characterize precisely the oral manifestations&#xD;
      associated with SSc within the National Referral Center for Rare Autoimmune Diseases&#xD;
      (Strasbourg, France) patient cohort in order to identify specific radiological, clinical&#xD;
      and/or biological signs. Some of them could be correlated to the severity or to the prognosis&#xD;
      of the disease. To the investigators knowledge it is the first study using tridimensional&#xD;
      CBCT approach.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    scleroderma patients were difficult to recruit&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of the periodontal ligament space width at mid-root level on Cone Beam Computed Tomography (CBCT) axial views</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic analysis of oro-facial manifestations associated with systemic sclerosis using high-resolution volumetric Cone Beam Computed Tomography (CBCT) exploration</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">85</enrollment>
  <condition>Scleroderma, Systemic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Measurement of the periodontal ligament space</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Evaluation of the width of the ligament in patients with SSc and comparison to the width found in control.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Radiographic analysis of oro-facial manifestations</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Establishment of a complete clinical phenotypic description of oral manifestations associated with SSc and comparison with the control group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cone Beam Computed Tomography (CBCT)</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Measurement of the periodontal ligament space</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Radiographic analysis of oro-facial manifestations</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Common inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and females ≥ 18 years (18th birthday completed)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliation to a social security scheme&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent form prior to inclusion in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than 12 natural teeth suitable for evaluation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion criteria for systemic sclerosis patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic sclerosis Inclusion criteria for control&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjet that underwent or must undergo an upper and a lower jaw bone Cone Beam Computed&#xD;
             Tomography examination (impacted teeth assessment, implant treatment planning)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Common exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Overt acute or chronic infection (HIV, viral hepatitis…) known at the time of the oral&#xD;
             examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive neoplasia or neoplasia diagnosed within 2 years prior to the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing antibiotic treatment or within 3 months before oral examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals at risk of infective endocarditis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Oral antiseptics within the week before oral examination (chlorhexidine mouthwashes…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periodontal specialized treatments, root scaling/root planning or periodontal surgical&#xD;
             treatment within the year before oral examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing medical treatment inducing a significant modification of the gingival state&#xD;
             (anti-epileptic drugs…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smoking (≥ 10 cigarettes per day)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy female subjects (positive urine pregnancy test)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lactating female subjects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impossibility to provide accurate informations (emergency situation, comprehension&#xD;
             difficulties…)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for systemic sclerosis patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient currently involved in an other clinical trial (drug) or in an exclusion period&#xD;
             following participation in another clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other associated systemic auto-immune disease (Sjögren syndrome with positive serum&#xD;
             anti-SSA and/or anti-SSB auto-antibodies, systemic lupus erythematosus…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive chronic illness other than systemic sclerosis (diabetes…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Immunosuppressive therapy during the last month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Corticosteroid ≥10 mg/day during the last month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hematopoietic stem cell transplant recipient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Another cause of skin sclerosis (radiotherapy on the oro-facial region…)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria for control&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic chronic or evolutive illness at the time of the inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Progressive pathology involving the maxilla or the mandible at the time of the&#xD;
             inclusion (tumor…)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing treatment with corticsteroids or non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sophie JUNG, Dental surgeon</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Les Hôpitaux Universitaires de Strasbourg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Service de parodontologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Strasbourg</city>
        <zip>67000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 18, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 24, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 25, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Oral Manifestations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Systemic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scleroderma, Diffuse</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

