<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02496442</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CIS-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02496442</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Aqueduct Irrigation System Clinical Protocol: Medical Device Investigational Plan</brief_title>
  <official_title>Aqueduct Irrigation System Clinical Protocol: Medical Device Investigational Plan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Flowmed</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Flowmed</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A. Synopsis&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. This protocol comes to direct the experiment to be performed on the Aqueduct Automatic&#xD;
           Continuous Irrigation system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The Aquaduct System is aimed at reducing risks to the patient by decreasing the&#xD;
           irrigation fluid pressure he may be exposed to, reducing the procedure time and&#xD;
           therefore the anesthesia time, reducing the manual handling of the sterile bags and the&#xD;
           risk of contamination and more.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. In general since there is no new procedure suggested and the equipment does not actually&#xD;
           come into contact with the human body in any direct way, there is no need to have a&#xD;
           clinical study for the regulation purpose. The reason for performing this experiment is&#xD;
           to demonstrate the new system and to find out the best way to operate it in order to&#xD;
           improve the process and reduce risks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. This information will serve the development of most suitable automation solution for&#xD;
           achieving the long desired continuous irrigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The experiment will be performed in the OR in MIS procedures, and will replace the&#xD;
           standard gravitational manual method of performing the irrigation. The surgeons and the&#xD;
           medical staff of the OR will be directed with the set up and operation of the system&#xD;
           prior to using it. The experiment will be accompanied at all times with a knowledgeable&#xD;
           representative of the research originator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. A maximum of 30 procedures will be analyzed during a period of approximately one month.&#xD;
           The surgeons and the medical staff will report their impression of using the system&#xD;
           during the procedures and will recommend the best settings achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This information will be used to improve the system performance and design.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1.0 Purpose of the Investigation&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.1 Name of investigational device:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aqueduct model CIS-01&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.2 Intended use of the investigational device:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Automatic Continuous Irrigation in Endoscopic procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.3 Objectives of the clinical investigation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.3.1 Primary objective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Demonstrating the efficacy of the use of the Aqueduct system in:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Continuity of flow&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ease of operation&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.3.2 Secondary objective(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluation of potential safety issues associated with the use of the device;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evaluation of device design;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assessing certain human factors (e.g., patient or operator) associated with the use of&#xD;
           the device; or&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Other specified device characteristic or device application consideration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1.4 Anticipated duration of the clinical investigation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 Month&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.0 Clinical Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.1 Title of clinical protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Operation of automatic irrigation controller in endoscopic procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.1.1 Protocol number. Version 01&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.1.2 Version number and date. Version 1, March 4, 2015&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2 Study design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2.1 General study design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During this study the system will be used by surgeons after teaching of the system&#xD;
      capabilities, as they feel correct.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgeons will setup the system to supply solution flow with limiting pressure. Increase of&#xD;
      flow during operation as they require limited by the set pressure and by safety valve to 180&#xD;
      cmH2O.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following each procedure a case report form (attached in chapter 11 below) will be filled,&#xD;
      reporting single experiment results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both cases using the system or standard procedures not using it will be reported and&#xD;
      summarized in a table.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results will serve to analyze the equipment performance and efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3 Subject selection:&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3.1 General characteristics of the proposed subject population(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regular endoscopic procedures patient(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no difference between standard procedure and using the Aqueduct. Only improvements&#xD;
      without risks are expected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3.2 Anticipated number of research subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 30 patients will be enrolled to the experiment. They will have to sign the consent form&#xD;
      explaining the experiment&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3.3 Inclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any adult over the age of 18 who is candidate to endoscopic procedure is suitable for the&#xD;
      experiment&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3.4 Exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Only adults over the age of 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4 Study procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4.1 Screening procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The surgeon performing the operation will suggest the use of the Aqueduct to relevant&#xD;
      patients. He will explain the principles of the system the advantages and risks and their&#xD;
      mitigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If patient agrees and will sign the consent form he will be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4.2 Study treatment or diagnostic product procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will include series of procedures in which the surgeons will utilize the Aqueduct&#xD;
      for the irrigation instead of the use of the current bags pole.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The surgeons will inspect the parameters and settings of the Aqueduct, experiment any values&#xD;
      that may ease the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In general they will try the minimal flow and minimal pressure to be used efficiently. If&#xD;
      needed they will be able to increase or decrease the flow and the limiting pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In subsequent procedures the surgeons will use the settings achieved in the previous&#xD;
      procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After 10 procedures we will collect the best settings for future default setup of the&#xD;
      Aqueduct for each procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4.3 Follow-up procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4.3.1 Procedures to assess efficacy:&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the standard procedures calls for gravitational flow from 60 Cm above the patient, which&#xD;
      creates free flow of between 350 to 270 milliliter per minute and nominal pressure which is&#xD;
      above 60 cm H2O, the efficacy will be proved by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Nominal flow below 300ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Nominal pressure below 60cm H2O As lower the results will be lesser is the risk to the&#xD;
           patient .&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4.3.2 Procedures to assess safety:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Closing the input tap of the resectoscope will lead to operation of the pressure relief valve&#xD;
      at 180 cm H2O showing the protection achieved from overpressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4.4 Schedule of activities (Study Table).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Incorporated as a referenced attachment is a table that summarizes the protocol procedures&#xD;
      that will be performed at screening, for treatment or diagnosis, and at follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5 Study outcome evaluations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.1 Study endpoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After each procedure the surgeon will fill the protocol summary (per attachment in chapter 11&#xD;
      below): with his observations&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. If continuous flow was maintained during the procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. If the ease of use of the equipment was acceptable&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Any ideas for improvements in next system generations The study endpoint will be after&#xD;
           at least 10 procedures using the Aqueduct.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives will be satisfied by the ideas for improvements in next system&#xD;
      generations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.2 Sample size determination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no need to perform any clinical trial. The justification for the sample size&#xD;
      selected is just by the estimated time needed to evaluate the system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.5.3 Outcome data and data analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Average of the observations and/or measurements that result from using the system efficiently&#xD;
      will be the primary results of the experiment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The, secondary results or outcomes of the clinical study are the suggestions for improvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results will be used to reach a production model of the Aqueduct. 3.0 Risk Analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
      3.1 Anticipated risks:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks to patients are limited to the system extracting overpressure to the organs being&#xD;
      operated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The steps taken to reduce this risks are triple&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Set up of the system is to lower parameters of pressure than the values used in current&#xD;
           procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A pressure sensor is incorporated within the Y-Set providing the pressure readings and&#xD;
           preventing overpressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. In case of the system failure to control a low pressure a mechanical safety valve is set&#xD;
           to 180 cm H2O and prevents any risk of larger pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. During the operation pressure reading appears on the screen and a warning message&#xD;
           appears to the surgeon who can decide to stop the use of the Aqueduct and move to the&#xD;
           standard procedure. The system is designed to ease of transferring the solution bags and&#xD;
           the Y-Set to a standard gravitational activated pole.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Since the overpressure is immediately detected and acted upon there is no real risk but&#xD;
           just benefit to the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The benefit can be assessed by the % of flow from the average 330ml/min without the&#xD;
           system and the % of pressure from the minimal 60 cmH2O used in the standard procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2 Adverse event recording/reporting&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.1 Adverse event definitions.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Adverse effect. Any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study of an&#xD;
           investigational device; regardless of the causal relationship of the problem with the&#xD;
           device or, if applicable, other study treatment or diagnostic product(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Associated with the investigational device or, if applicable, other study treatment or&#xD;
           diagnostic product(s). There is a reasonable possibility that the adverse effect may&#xD;
           have been caused by the investigational device or, if applicable, the other study&#xD;
           treatment or diagnostic product(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Disability. A substantial disruption of a person's ability to conduct normal life&#xD;
           functions.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Life-threatening adverse effect. Any adverse effect that places the subject, in the view&#xD;
           of the investigator-sponsor, at immediate risk of death from the effect as it occurred&#xD;
           (i.e., does not include an adverse effect that, had it actually occurred in a more&#xD;
           severe form, might have caused death).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Serious adverse effect. Any adverse effect that results in any of the following&#xD;
           outcomes: death, a life-threatening adverse effect, inpatient hospitalization or&#xD;
           prolongation of existing hospitalization, a persistent or significant&#xD;
           disability/incapacity, or a congenital anomaly/birth defect.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Hospitalization shall include any initial admission (even if less than 24 hours) to&#xD;
                a healthcare facility as a result of a precipitating clinical adverse effect; to&#xD;
                include transfer within the hospital to an intensive care unit. Hospitalization or&#xD;
                prolongation of hospitalization in the absence of a precipitating, clinical adverse&#xD;
                effect (e.g., for a preexisting condition not associated with a new adverse effect&#xD;
                or with a worsening of the preexisting condition; admission for a&#xD;
                protocol-specified procedure) is not, in itself, a serious adverse effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Unexpected adverse effect. Any adverse effect, the frequency, specificity or severity of&#xD;
           which is not consistent with the risk information described in the clinical study&#xD;
           protocol(s) or elsewhere in the current IDE application, as amended.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Unanticipated adverse device effect. Any serious adverse effect on health or safety or&#xD;
           any life-threatening problem or death caused by, or associated with, a device, if that&#xD;
           effect, problem, or death was not previously identified in nature, severity, or degree&#xD;
           of incidence in the investigational plan or IDE application (including a supplementary&#xD;
           plan or application), or any other unanticipated serious problem associated with a&#xD;
           device that relates to the rights, safety, or welfare of subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.2 Eliciting adverse effect information.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Clinical study subjects will be routinely questioned about adverse effects at study&#xD;
           visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.3 Recording and assessment of adverse effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
           All observed or volunteered adverse effects (serious or non-serious) and abnormal test&#xD;
           findings, regardless of treatment group, if applicable, or suspected causal relationship&#xD;
           to the investigational device or, if applicable, other study treatment or diagnostic&#xD;
           product(s) will be recorded in the subjects' case histories. For all adverse effects,&#xD;
           sufficient information will be pursued and/or obtained so as to permit 1) an adequate&#xD;
           determination of the outcome of the effect (i.e., whether the effect should be&#xD;
           classified as a serious adverse effect) and; 2) an assessment of the casual relationship&#xD;
           between the adverse effect and the investigational device or, if applicable, the other&#xD;
           study treatment or diagnostic product(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Adverse effects or abnormal test findings felt to be associated with the investigational&#xD;
           device or, if applicable, other study treatment or diagnostic product(s) will be&#xD;
           followed until the effect (or its sequelae) or the abnormal test finding resolves or&#xD;
           stabilizes at a level acceptable to the investigator-sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.3.1 Abnormal test findings:&#xD;
&#xD;
           An abnormal test finding will be classified as an adverse effect if one or more of the&#xD;
           following criteria are met:&#xD;
&#xD;
           • The test finding is accompanied by clinical symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The test finding necessitates additional diagnostic evaluation(s) or&#xD;
                medical/surgical intervention; including significant additional concomitant drug or&#xD;
                other therapy. (Note: simply repeating a test finding, in the absence of any of the&#xD;
                other listed criteria, does not constitute an adverse effect.)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The test finding leads to a change in study dosing or exposure or discontinuation&#xD;
                of subject participation in the clinical study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  The test finding is considered an adverse effect by the investigator-sponsor.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.3.2 Causality and severity assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
           The investigator-sponsor will promptly review documented adverse effects and abnormal&#xD;
           test findings to determine 1) if the abnormal test finding should be classified as an&#xD;
           adverse effect; 2) if there is a reasonable possibility that the adverse effect was&#xD;
           caused by the investigational device or, if applicable, other study treatment or&#xD;
           diagnostic product(s); and 3) if the adverse effect meets the criteria for a serious&#xD;
           adverse effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
           If the investigator-sponsor's final determination of causality is &quot;unknown and of&#xD;
           questionable relationship to the investigational device or, if applicable, other study&#xD;
           treatment or diagnostic product(s)&quot;, the adverse effect will be classified as associated&#xD;
           with the use of the investigational device or study treatment or diagnostic drug&#xD;
           product(s) for reporting purposes. If the investigator-sponsor's final determination of&#xD;
           causality is &quot;unknown but not related to the investigational device or, if applicable,&#xD;
           other study treatment or diagnostic product(s)&quot;, this determination and the rationale&#xD;
           for the determination will be documented in the respective subject's case history.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.4 Reporting of adverse effects to the FDA. )&#xD;
&#xD;
           The investigator-sponsor will submit a completed Form FDA 3500 A to the FDA's Center for&#xD;
           Devices and Radiological Health for any observed or volunteered adverse effect that is&#xD;
           determined to be an unanticipated adverse device effect. A copy of this completed form&#xD;
           will be provided to all participating sub-investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The completed Form FDA 3500 A will be submitted to the FDA as soon as possible and, in&#xD;
           no event, later than 10 working days after the investigator-sponsor first receives&#xD;
           notice of the adverse effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
           If the results of the sponsor-investigator's follow-up evaluation show that an adverse&#xD;
           effect that was initially determined to not constitute an unanticipated adverse device&#xD;
           effect does, in fact, meet the requirements for reporting; the investigator-sponsor will&#xD;
           submit a completed Form FDA 3500 A as soon as possible, but in no event later than 10&#xD;
           working days, after the determination was made.&#xD;
&#xD;
           For each submitted Form FDA 3500 A, the sponsor-investigator will identify all&#xD;
           previously submitted reports that that addressed a similar adverse effect experience and&#xD;
           will provide an analysis of the significance of newly reported adverse effect in light&#xD;
           of the previous, similar report(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
           Subsequent to the initial submission of a completed Form FDA 3500 A, the&#xD;
           investigator-sponsor will submit additional information concerning the reported adverse&#xD;
           effect as requested by the FDA.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.2.5 Reporting of adverse effects to the responsible IRB.&#xD;
&#xD;
           In accordance with applicable policies of the medical centre Institutional Review Board&#xD;
           (IRB), the investigator-sponsor will report, to the IRB, any observed or volunteered&#xD;
           adverse effect that is determined to meet all of the following criteria: 1) associated&#xD;
           with the investigational device or, if applicable, other study treatment or diagnostic&#xD;
           product(s); 2) a serious adverse effect; and 3) an unexpected adverse effect. Adverse&#xD;
           event reports will be submitted to the IRB in accordance with the respective IRB&#xD;
           procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Applicable adverse effects will be reported to the IRB as soon as possible and, in no&#xD;
           event, later than 10 calendar days following the investigator-sponsor's receipt of the&#xD;
           respective information. Adverse effects which are 1) associated with the investigational&#xD;
           drug or, if applicable, other study treatment or diagnostic product(s); 2) fatal or&#xD;
           life-threatening; and 3) unexpected will be reported to the IRB within 24 hours of the&#xD;
           investigator-sponsor's receipt of the respective information.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Follow-up information to reported adverse effects will be submitted to the IRB as soon&#xD;
           as the relevant information is available. If the results of the sponsor-investigator's&#xD;
           follow-up investigation show that an adverse effect that was initially determined to not&#xD;
           require reporting to the IRB does, in fact, meet the requirements for reporting; the&#xD;
           investigator-sponsor will report the adverse effect to the IRB as soon as possible, but&#xD;
           in no event later than 10 calendar days, after the determination was made.&#xD;
&#xD;
           3.3 Withdrawal of subjects due to adverse effects:&#xD;
&#xD;
           In any case that the researcher decides that the subject is unsuitable for the&#xD;
           experiment the subject will be withdrawn from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
           There will be no replacement and the endpoint may include less than planned subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
           4.0 Description of the Investigational Device&#xD;
&#xD;
           The robotic technology is based on using the same solution bags. This electro-mechanic&#xD;
           system will replace the manual bag-switching procedure with an automatic one.&#xD;
&#xD;
           The system consists of several-sub mechanisms that identify when the bag solution is&#xD;
           about to end, opens a flow from a buffer bag, pulls the spike of the Y-set from the&#xD;
           empty bag, moves the spike to a new bag, removes its protective cover, spikes it and&#xD;
           switches the flow from the buffer bag to the current bag - thus enabling a continuous&#xD;
           irrigation. The system builds flow and pressure according to the procedure needs and&#xD;
           enables the surgeon for the first time, to directly control it by a switch or a foot&#xD;
           pedal allowing him to clear the visibility of the surgical site whenever it drops, as&#xD;
           often happens during surgery due to excessive bleeding..&#xD;
&#xD;
           The problems we solve:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Stoppage of fluid flow (no timely fluid bag replacement by nurse) 2. Physician control of&#xD;
      the flow to prevent vision block by excess bleeding 3. Prolonged operation time 4 Glycinemia&#xD;
      risk to the patient 5. Urethra injuries when entering the endoscope 6. Post operation blood&#xD;
      clots The design was created to ensure a &quot;user-friendly fool-proof &quot; system. Flow Med offers&#xD;
      for purchase the electro-mechanic system along with the disposable Y-sets designed&#xD;
      exclusively for the Flow Med system&#xD;
&#xD;
      A microcontroller is supervising the operation of the system and sets the correct control&#xD;
      algorithm to provide continuous flow.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2 Heads are incorporated. One in a fixed position and one rotating under the hanging bags on&#xD;
      the carousel. Each of the heads include 3 stepper motors one to remove the caps of the bags,&#xD;
      one to move the spike in and ut of the bag and one to open or close the flow.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A peristaltic pump is used to create the required flow.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following sensors are included in the system:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Weight sensor - measuring the weight of the bags helping to decide on the time to switch&#xD;
           bags&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Pressure sensor in the system main body with a sterile pressure capin the Y-Set helping&#xD;
           to prevent overpressure&#xD;
&#xD;
      A Safety relief valve at 180 cmH2O is incorporated in the Y-Set to prevent overpressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A safety switch prevents movement of the motors when the front door is opened.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The covers are secured with screws to prevent their removal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5.0 Monitoring Procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sponsor-investigator will permit direct access to the study monitors and appropriate&#xD;
      regulatory authorities to the study data and to the corresponding source data and documents&#xD;
      to verify the accuracy of these data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The system was designed according to ISO14385 standard. Electrical safety testing has been&#xD;
      performed to IEC 60601-1 and Electromagnetic Compatibility (EMC) testing has been tested&#xD;
      according to IEC 60601-1-2 in ITL (Israel Test Laboratories) and has their certificate to&#xD;
      show it passed the standards tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Appendix:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Case Report Form - reporting standard procedure results&#xD;
&#xD;
      Date:_________ Place:_________ Procedure type:______________ Number of bags used:&#xD;
      _________________ Procedure time:_______________ Height of bags above patient:_____________&#xD;
      Times extra pressure applied to the bags:_________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Observations on flow continuity during the procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Was continuous flow maintained during the procedure?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Would the offered system ease the procedure?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Any ideas for improvements in next system generations&#xD;
           ________________________________________________________________________________________&#xD;
           ____________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other difficulties during the procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ______________________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      ______________________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Name:__________ Signature:__________&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. Case Report Form - reporting single experiment results&#xD;
&#xD;
      Date:_________ Place:_________ Procedure type:______________ Number of bags hanged before&#xD;
      starting: ______&#xD;
&#xD;
      Changes in parameters set up prior to starting:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ____________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Changes for optimal parameters after the experiment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ______________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of the operation during the procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Parameter Value Procedure Time Bags used Foot pedal used Number of times foot pedal operated&#xD;
      Number of steps used each time Closing the surgeons input tap result Closing the surgeon exit&#xD;
      tap result Pressure protection performance Nominal Flow Nominal Pressure Maximal flow Maximal&#xD;
      Pressure Min operating Flow Min operating Pressure Difficulties&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suggestions&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researcher name Researcher signature&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Was continuous flow maintained during the procedure?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Is the ease of use of the equipment acceptable?&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Any ideas for improvements in next system generations&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>July 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>continuous flow was maintained during the procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>evaluation of the continuous nature of the treatment using the Aqueduct</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ease of use</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>get qualitative assesment of the ease compared to standard procedure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ideas for improvements</measure>
    <time_frame>3 Months</time_frame>
    <description>ideas for improvements in next system generations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostatic Hyperplasia</condition>
  <condition>Kidney Calculi</condition>
  <condition>Bladder Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>using Aqueduct</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients passing procedures with Aqueduct</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Not using Aqueduct</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients passing the standard procedures</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aqueduct</intervention_name>
    <description>Using Aqueduct in procedures to continuously supply the irrigation solutions</description>
    <arm_group_label>using Aqueduct</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients passing the specific procedures set on the Aqueduct&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Boaz Moskovitz, Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bnei-Zion</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Amir Gilead, MSc</last_name>
    <phone>+972508370241</phone>
    <email>amir@flowmed.co</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Boaz Moskovitz, Prof. MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972506267299</phone>
    <email>Boaz.moskovitz@b-zion.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>i.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 9, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 13, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">July 14, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 13, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 13, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 14, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Transurethral Resection of Prostate</keyword>
  <keyword>Cystoscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>PCNL</keyword>
  <keyword>RERAS</keyword>
  <keyword>Urethroscopy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Calculi</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nephrolithiasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Calculi</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

