<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03812562</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NU 18I03</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NU 18I03</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2018-03602</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA060553</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03812562</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Nivolumab and Yttrium-90 in Treating Patients With Liver Cancer Undergoing Surgical Resection</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pilot Study of Nivolumab in Combination With Therasphere (Yttrium-90) for Treatment of Hepatocellular Carcinoma (HCC) With Intent for Resection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Northwestern University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Northwestern University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This early phase I trial studies how well nivolumab and yttrium-90 work in treating patients&#xD;
      with liver cancer who are undergoing surgical resection. Immunotherapy with monoclonal&#xD;
      antibodies, such as nivolumab, may help the body?s immune system attack the cancer, and may&#xD;
      interfere with the ability of tumor cells to grow and spread. Radioactive drugs, such as&#xD;
      yttrium-90, may carry radiation directly to tumor cells and not harm normal cells. Giving&#xD;
      nivolumab and yttrium-90 may work better in treating patients with liver cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess the hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) recurrence rate post-resection in patients&#xD;
      intended to undergo resection post yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres (yttrium-90 [Y-90]) +&#xD;
      nivolumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To investigate the safety and feasibility of radioembolization and nivolumab in patients&#xD;
      with HCC with intent for resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To assess the pattern of recurrence post-resection (time frame and location of&#xD;
      recurrence).&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To evaluate efficacy in patients with HCC treated with Y90 + nivolumab using overall&#xD;
      survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. To evaluate the drop-out rate and incremental changes in future liver remnant (FLR).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To assess immune-related biomarkers from original tumor biopsy if available. II. To&#xD;
      identify differences in immunological profiles among patients who go undergo resection versus&#xD;
      those who do not undergo resection due to progression or failure to grow FLR to sufficient&#xD;
      level. III. In patients with hepatitis C virus (HCV), will explore changes in immunological&#xD;
      profile associated with direct acting anti-viral agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive standard of care yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres intravenously (IV). Within&#xD;
      1-2 weeks of completing of yttrium-90 treatment, patients receive nivolumab IV over 30&#xD;
      minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 2 weeks for up to 4 doses in the absence of disease&#xD;
      progression or unacceptable toxicity. If imaging shows adequate FLR and at least stable&#xD;
      disease, patients will undergo resection within 2 weeks after the last dose of nivolumab.&#xD;
      Patients who do not complete resection due to feasibility and have progressed or have&#xD;
      evidence of high-risk explant may continue to receive nivolumab IV every 2 weeks for up to 1&#xD;
      year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up at 30 days and then&#xD;
      periodically for up to 3 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 7, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>This primary dichotomous endpoint will be summarized at each time point using a table of frequencies and counts.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of adverse events will be graded according to Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 5.0. Will be tabulated and reviewed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>OS distributions will be estimated using the Kaplan Meier method, with estimates for the 25th percentile, median and 75th percentile for each time-to-event outcome. In addition, specific Kaplan-Meier estimates for survival at 1-year will be calculated, with Greenwood?s formula for variance used to calculate a 95% confidence interval (CI).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall increase in future liver remnant (FLR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 years post-treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres, nivolumab)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive standard of care yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres IV. Within 1-2 weeks of completing of yttrium-90 treatment, patients receive nivolumab IV over 30 minutes on day 1. Treatment repeats every 2 weeks for up to 4 doses in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity. If imaging shows adequate FLR and at least stable disease, patients will undergo resection within 2 weeks after the last dose of nivolumab. Patients who do not complete resection due to feasibility and have progressed or have evidence of high-risk explant may continue to receive nivolumab IV every 2 weeks for up to 1 year.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres, nivolumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>BMS-936558</other_name>
    <other_name>MDX-1106</other_name>
    <other_name>NIVO</other_name>
    <other_name>ONO-4538</other_name>
    <other_name>Opdivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Yttrium Y 90 Glass Microspheres</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (yttrium Y 90 glass microspheres, nivolumab)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TheraSphere</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a diagnosis of hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) confirmed by American&#xD;
             Association for Study of Liver Diseases (AASLD) guidelines with a Childs-Pugh score of&#xD;
             A or B (but, =&lt; Childs score B8)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be eligible for resection based on preserved hepatic function and lack&#xD;
             of clinically significant portal hypertension (HTN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Patients with branch or lobar portal vein thrombosis (PVT) who are&#xD;
                  otherwise a candidate for resection will be included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a pre-established need for Y90 therapy prior to resection for FLR&#xD;
             growth and/or retraction of tumor away from major vessel to improve margins&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable disease according to the standard Response Evaluation&#xD;
             Criteria in Solid Tumors (RECIST) version 1.1&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic hepatitis B are eligible as long as they have evidence of&#xD;
             ongoing viral replication (detectable hepatitis B surface antigen [HBsAg], hepatitis B&#xD;
             e-antigen [HBeAg], or hepatitis B virus [HBV] deoxyribonucleic acid [DNA]). They must&#xD;
             have HBV DNA viral load &lt; 100 IU/mL at screening. In addition, they must be on&#xD;
             antiviral therapy per regional standard of care guidelines prior to initiation of&#xD;
             study therapy. If not on antiviral therapy at screening, then the subject must&#xD;
             initiate treatment per regional standard of care guidelines at the time of consent.&#xD;
             Both HBeAg positive and negative patients will be included&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients positive for hepatitis C are permitted at physician discretion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate organ and bone marrow functions:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 2,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin &gt;= 9 g/dL; transfusion is permitted for eligibility, but should be &gt;= 7&#xD;
             days from registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 50,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 2.5 x institutional upper limit of normal (ULN) (except patients&#xD;
             with Gilbert syndrome, who can have total bilirubin &lt; 3.0 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic-oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamate pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])&#xD;
             =&lt; 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine of =&lt; 2.0 x ULN (upper limit of normal) or creatinine clearance &gt;= 30&#xD;
             mL/minute (using Cockcroft/Gault formula below):&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Female creatinine clearance (CrCl) = (140 - age in years) x weight in kg x 0.85/&#xD;
                  72 x serum creatinine in mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Male CrCl = (140 - age in years) x weight in kg x 1.00/ 72 x serum creatinine in&#xD;
                  mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females of childbearing potential (FOCBP) must have a negative serum or urine&#xD;
             pregnancy test (minimum sensitivity 25 IU/L or equivalent units of human chorionic&#xD;
             gonadotropin [HCG]) =&lt; 7 days prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: A FOCBP is any woman (regardless of sexual orientation, having undergone a&#xD;
                  tubal ligation, or remaining celibate by choice) who meets the following&#xD;
                  criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Has not undergone a hysterectomy or bilateral oophorectomy&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  Has had menses at any time in the preceding 12 consecutive months (and&#xD;
                       therefore has not been naturally postmenopausal for &gt; 12 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Abstinence is acceptable if this is the usual lifestyle and preferred&#xD;
                  contraception for the subject&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  FOCBP and men who are sexually active with FOCBP must agree to follow instructions for&#xD;
             method(s) of contraception for the duration of treatment and the designated&#xD;
             post-treatment period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent prior to&#xD;
             registration on study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had chemotherapy or radiotherapy =&lt; 28 days prior to registration&#xD;
             are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had prior immunotherapy including interleukin-2 and immune&#xD;
             checkpoint antagonist and/or agonists are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have not recovered to their baseline, =&lt; grade 1, or tolerable grade 2&#xD;
             (as documented by the treating physician) from adverse events due to agents&#xD;
             administered &gt;= 28 days earlier are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received any other investigational agents =&lt; 28 days prior to&#xD;
             registration are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar&#xD;
             chemical or biologic composition to nivolumab or Y90 are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had prior treatment with an anti-PD1, anti-PD-L1, antiPD-L2,&#xD;
             anti-CTLA-4 antibody, or any other antibody or drug specifically targeting T-cell&#xD;
             co-stimulation or immune checkpoint pathways are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active autoimmune disease or history of autoimmune disease that might&#xD;
             recur, which may affect vital organ function or require immune suppressive treatment&#xD;
             including chronic prolonged systemic corticosteroids (defined as corticosteroid use of&#xD;
             duration one month or greater), should be excluded. These include but are not limited&#xD;
             to patients with a history of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immune related neurologic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Multiple sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Autoimmune (demyelinating) neuropathy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pure red cell aplasia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Guillain-Barre syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myasthenia gravis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic autoimmune disease such as systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Connective tissue diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Scleroderma&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Crohn?s&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ulcerative colitis&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with a history of toxic epidermal necrolysis (TEN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stevens-Johnson syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Anti-phospholipid syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  NOTE: Subjects with vitiligo, alopecia, type I diabetes mellitus, residual&#xD;
                       hypothyroidism due to autoimmune condition only requiring hormone&#xD;
                       replacement, psoriasis not requiring systemic treatment, or conditions not&#xD;
                       expected to recur in the absence of an external trigger are permitted to&#xD;
                       enroll&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any condition requiring systemic treatment with corticosteroids (&gt; 10 mg&#xD;
             daily prednisone equivalents) or other immunosuppressive medications =&lt; 14 days prior&#xD;
             to registration are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Inhaled steroids and adrenal replacement steroid doses &gt; 10 mg daily&#xD;
                  prednisone equivalents are permitted in the absence of active autoimmune disease.&#xD;
                  A brief (less than 3 weeks) course of corticosteroids for prophylaxis (e.g.,&#xD;
                  contrast dye allergy) or for treatment of non-autoimmune conditions (e.g.,&#xD;
                  delayed-type hypersensitivity reaction caused by a contact allergen) is permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have received live vaccine =&lt; 28 days from registration are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: Examples of live vaccines include, but are not limited to, the following:&#xD;
                  measles, mumps, rubella, chicken pox, yellow fever, rabies, Bacillus&#xD;
                  Calmette-Guerin (BCG), and typhoid (oral) vaccine. Seasonal influenza vaccines&#xD;
                  for injection are generally killed virus vaccines and are allowed; however&#xD;
                  intranasal influenza vaccines (e.g. Flu-Mist) are live attenuated vaccines, and&#xD;
                  are not allowed at any time during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to any of&#xD;
             the following, are not eligible:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hypertension that is not controlled on medication&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ongoing or active infection requiring systemic treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptomatic congestive heart failure&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina pectoris&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cardiac arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with study&#xD;
                  requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any other illness or condition that the treating investigator feels would&#xD;
                  interfere with study compliance or would compromise the patient?s safety or study&#xD;
                  endpoints&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant or nursing are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with new brain metastases are not eligible unless they have had treatment of&#xD;
             lesions and are neurologically stable off steroids prior to registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with another primary malignancy within 2 years of registration are not&#xD;
             eligible with the following exceptions: adequately treated basal cell carcinoma,&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma or other non-melanomatous skin cancer, or in-situ carcinoma of&#xD;
             the uterine cervix, or any localized cancers that are deemed to be cured from&#xD;
             investigator?s point of view&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) or known acquired&#xD;
             immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners or participants who are involuntarily incarcerated are not eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NOTE: under certain specific circumstances a person who has been imprisoned may&#xD;
                  be included as a participant. Strict conditions apply and Bristol-Myers Squibb&#xD;
                  approval is required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants must not be compulsorily detained for treatment of either a psychiatric&#xD;
             or physical (e.g., infectious disease) illness&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura Kulik, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Northwestern University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Northwestern University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 16, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 17, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">January 23, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

