<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04079179</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H-43475 NACHO COBI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04079179</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cobimetinib in Refractory Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis (LCH), and Other Histiocytic Disorders</brief_title>
  <acronym>NACHO-COBI</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2 Study to Assess the Safety and Efficacy of Cobimetinib in Refractory Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis, LCH-Associated Neurodegenerative Disease, and Other Histiocytic Disorders.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Carl Allen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Baylor College of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>North American Consortium for Histiocytosis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Baylor College of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a research study of a drug called cobimetinib in children and adults diagnosed with&#xD;
      Langerhans cell histiocytosis (LCH), and other histiocytic disorders that has returned or&#xD;
      does not respond to treatment. Cobimetinib blocks activation of a protein called&#xD;
      Mitogen-activated protein kinase (MEK) that is part of incorrect growth signals in&#xD;
      histiocytosis cells. Four different groups of patients will be enrolled.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Histiocytic disorders are diseases caused by misfunctioning or buildup of particular immune&#xD;
      cells called histiocytes. Many histiocytic disorders (LCH, juvenile xanthogranuloma (JXG),&#xD;
      Erdheim-Chester disease (ECD), and Rosai-Dorfman Disease (RDD)) arises from blood cells that&#xD;
      receive incorrect growth signals. These incorrect signals are caused by changes in genes&#xD;
      (mutations) that lead to tissue damage (lesions) which causes disease. Some patients with LCH&#xD;
      can develop neurodegeneration (LCH-ND) which is damage to neurons that results in reduced&#xD;
      brain function, from LCH cells that go to the brain and activate inflammation. LCH arises&#xD;
      from blood cells that receive incorrect growth signals. These incorrect signals are caused by&#xD;
      mutations (changes in genes). The LCH blood cells can create changes in the structure of&#xD;
      almost any organ, and can cause damage to normal organ function.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of this research study is to learn whether cobimetinib is safe and effective in&#xD;
      subjects diagnosed with LCH, LCH-ND, RDD, JXG and ECD which may have a specfic mutation&#xD;
      called BRAF-V600E. In healthy cells, certain proteins (called BRAF and MEK) are thought to&#xD;
      help control normal cell growth. BRAF-V600E is a specific change in a gene that may cause&#xD;
      cancer cells to grow and spread by sending constant signals to the MEK protein. Cobimetinib&#xD;
      is designed to attach to and block the activity of MEK.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2029</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants are assigned to one of 4 groups in parallel for the duration of the study. All 4 groups receive the same intervention.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rates using modified RECiST criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of participants with (complete response, partial response, stable disease, progressive disease) by 1 year of therapy with Cobimetinib.&#xD;
It is assumed that at each protocol-specified timepoint, a response assessment occurs. Status calculation will occur at each timepoint for patients who have measurable disease at baseline per the criteria defined in the protocol.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Progression Free Survival defined as the length of time during and after the treatment of a disease, that a patient lives with the disease but it does not get worse.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nature and Severity of Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of the nature and severity of adverse events in patients treated with Cobimetinib for histiocytic disorders.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Response assessment (Modified RECIST) of histiocytic lesions with specific mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Response assessment using modified RECIST criteria for target lesions with specific mutations (e.g. BRAF-V600E) . Best response rate by 1 year of therapy.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Langerhan's Cell Histiocytosis</condition>
  <condition>Juvenile Xanthogranuloma</condition>
  <condition>Erdheim-Chester Disease</condition>
  <condition>Rosai Dorfman Disease</condition>
  <condition>Neuro-Degenerative Disease</condition>
  <condition>Histiocytic Sarcoma</condition>
  <condition>Histiocytic Disorders, Malignant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &lt; 30 years with recurrent LCH (Grp1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Children and young adults (&lt;30 years) with recurrent active LCH lesions (may also have LCH-ND).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients of any age with LCH-ND (Grp2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients of any age with progressive LCH Neurodegenerative Disease (LCH-ND) without other sites of active LCH.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &lt;30 years with other histiocytic disorders (Grp3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Newly diagnosed or relapsed/refractory children and young adults (&lt;30 years) with other histiocytic disorders including juvenile xanthogranuloma, Erdheim-Chester disease, histiocytic sarcoma and Rosai-Dorfman disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients ≥ 30 years with LCH/histiocytic disorders (Grp4)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adults (≥30 years) with LCH or other histiocytic disorder with recurrent active lesions (may also have LCH-ND).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cobimetinib</intervention_name>
    <description>All groups will receive the same intervention. Cobimetinib will be given orally at a maximum dose of 60mg daily for 21 days on, then 7 days off, in a 28-day treatment cycle for a total of 12 cycles (approximately 12 months).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &lt; 30 years with recurrent LCH (Grp1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients &lt;30 years with other histiocytic disorders (Grp3)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients of any age with LCH-ND (Grp2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients ≥ 30 years with LCH/histiocytic disorders (Grp4)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>COTELLIC</other_name>
    <other_name>RO5514041</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Group 1: Participant must be less than 30 years of age at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Group 2: Participant may be any age at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Group 3: Participant must be less than 30 years of age at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For Group 4: Participant must be 30 years of age or older at the time of enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must be able to take an enteral dose and formulation of medication. Study&#xD;
             medication is only available as an oral suspension or tablet which may be taken by&#xD;
             mouth or other enteral route such as nasogastric or gastric tube.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy proven LCH -AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure of at least front-line therapy for high-risk LCH with evaluable disease. -OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure of at least second-line therapy for low-risk LCH with evaluable disease. -OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of LCH-associated neurodegenerative disease with radiologic or clinical&#xD;
             progression within the past 3 months. -OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy proven JXG, ECD, RDD, histiocytic sarcoma, or other histiocytic lesion (newly&#xD;
             diagnosed or relapsed/refractory disease) with evaluable active disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Performance Level:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Karnofsky ≥ 50% for patients &gt; 16 years of age and Lansky ≥ 50% for patients ≤ 16 years of&#xD;
        age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate Hematologic Function Defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ANC ≥ 0.75 x 10^9/L (unsupported/without growth factor stimulant)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count ≥ 75 x 10^9/L (unsupported/without transfusion within the past 7 days).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with marrow disease must have platelet count of &gt;/= 75 x 10^9/L (transfusion&#xD;
             support allowed) and must not be refractory to platelet transfusions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin ≥ 8 g/dL (unsupported/without transfusion within the past 7 days)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with marrow disease must have hemoglobin ≥ 8 g/dL (transfusion support&#xD;
             allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate Renal Function Defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Calculated creatinine clearance (or radioisotope GFR) ≥ 70 mL/min/1.73m^2 or serum&#xD;
        creatinine based on age/gender as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Maximum Serum Creatinine (mg/dL) Age 2 to &lt; 6 years: Male 0.8 mg/d, Female 0.8; 6 to &lt; 10&#xD;
        years: Male 1 mg/dL,Female 1; 10 to &lt; 13 years: Male 1.2 mg/dL; Female 1.2; 13 to &lt; 16&#xD;
        years: Male 1.5 mg/dL ; Female 1.4;&#xD;
&#xD;
        ≥ 16 years: Male 1.7 mg/dL; Female 1.4;&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate Liver Function Defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bilirubin (sum of conjugated + unconjugated) ≤ 1.5 x upper limit of normal (ULN) for&#xD;
             age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  AST and ALT ≤ 2.5x ULN for age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum albumin ≤ 2 g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
        For patients with liver disease caused by histiocytic disorder:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Patients may be enrolled with abnormal bilirubin, AST, ALT and albumin with documentation&#xD;
        of histiocytic liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Adequate Cardiac Function Defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fractional shortening (FS) of ≥ 30% or ejection fraction of ≥ 50% by echocardiogram at&#xD;
             baseline, as determined by echocardiography or multigated acquisition scan (MUGA)&#xD;
             within 21 days prior to study database registration. Depending on institutional&#xD;
             standard, either FS or LVEF is adequate for enrollment if only one value is measured;&#xD;
             if both values are measured, then both values must meet criteria above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential require a negative urine or serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test for eligibility and again at database registration, if more than 2 weeks has&#xD;
             elapsed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of childbearing potential must agree to follow the contraceptive&#xD;
             requirements using two forms of effective contraceptive methods for the duration of&#xD;
             the study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Prior and Concomitant Use of Drugs with CYP3A4 inducing/inhibiting activity: Patient&#xD;
        taking strong inducers or inhibitors of CYP3A4 within 14 days prior to study enrollment,&#xD;
        including but not limited to the following: erythromycin, clarithromycin, ketoconazole,&#xD;
        azithromycin, itraconazole, grapefruit juice or St. John's wort.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior Therapy Restrictions Completion of previous chemotherapy, immunotherapy,&#xD;
             radiotherapy, or targeted therapy for LCH (or other histiocytic disorder) at least 28&#xD;
             days (except where specified below) prior to study database registration, with&#xD;
             resolution of all associated toxicity to ≤ Grade 1 prior to study enrollment&#xD;
             (exception for alopecia and ototoxicity which do not need to be resolved ≤ Grade 1).&#xD;
             Patients must have fully recovered from the acute toxic effects of all prior&#xD;
             anti-cancer therapy and must meet the following minimum duration from prior&#xD;
             anti-cancer directed therapy prior to enrollment. If after the required timeframe, the&#xD;
             laboratory eligibility criteria are met, the patient is considered to have recovered&#xD;
             adequately.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiation therapy within the last 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any prior treatment with Cobimetinib.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Treatment with a long-acting hematopoietic growth factor within 14 days prior to&#xD;
                  initiation of study drug or a short-acting hematopoietic growth factor within 7&#xD;
                  days prior to database registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Treatment with hormonal therapy (except hormone replacement therapy or oral&#xD;
                  contraceptives), immunotherapy, biologic therapy, investigational therapy, or&#xD;
                  herbal cancer therapy within 28 days or &lt; 5 half-lives, whichever is longer,&#xD;
                  prior to database registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Treatment with high-dose chemotherapy and stem-cell rescue (autologous stem cell&#xD;
                  transplant) or allogeneic stem cell transplant within 90 days prior to study&#xD;
                  database registration. Anti-GVHD agents post-transplant: Patients who are&#xD;
                  receiving cyclosporine, tacrolimus or other agents to prevent graft-versus-host&#xD;
                  disease post bone marrow transplant are not eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For patients with brain tumors (intracranial masses), use of anticoagulants&#xD;
                  within 7 days prior to study database registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corticosteroid therapy &lt;0.5 mg/kg/day averaged during the month prior to study&#xD;
                  database registration is permissible but must be discontinued fourteen (14) days&#xD;
                  prior to prior to study database registration. Patients with documented brain&#xD;
                  lesions receiving corticosteroids for management of cerebral edema must be on a&#xD;
                  stable dose for fourteen (14) days prior to study database registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient has received treatment with investigational therapy within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
                  to initiation of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusions for other illness&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other active malignancy or history of secondary malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Refractory nausea and vomiting, malabsorption, external biliary shunt&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Infection: Patients who have a known active infection (excluding documented&#xD;
                  fungal infection of the nail beds) within 28 days prior to study database&#xD;
                  registration that has not completely resolved.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Major surgical procedure or significant traumatic injury within 28 days prior to&#xD;
                  study database registration, or anticipation of need for major surgical procedure&#xD;
                  during the course of the study. Placement of a vascular access device or minor&#xD;
                  surgery is permitted within fourteen (14) days of study enrollment (provided that&#xD;
                  the wound has healed).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of significant bowel resection that would preclude adequate absorption or&#xD;
                  other significant malabsorptive disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ophthalmologic considerations: Patients with known significant ophthalmologic&#xD;
                  conditions or known risk factors for retinal vein occlusion are not eligible.&#xD;
                  Specifically, patients with a history of retinal vein occlusion (RVO), retinal&#xD;
                  detachment, retinal pathology on ophthalmologic exam, retinopathy of prematurity,&#xD;
                  central serous chorioretinopathy (CSSCR), neovascular retinopathy, intraocular&#xD;
                  pressure &gt; 21 mmHg, and predisposing factors to RVO (e.g., uncontrolled&#xD;
                  hypertension, diabetes, or hyperlipidemia, coagulopathy) will be excluded.&#xD;
                  Patients with longstanding and stable ophthalmologic findings secondary to&#xD;
                  existing conditions are eligible with appropriate documentation and approval from&#xD;
                  Study (Co)Chair and Coordinating Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of solid organ transplantation: Patients who have received a prior solid&#xD;
                  organ transplantation are not eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any other disease, metabolic or psychological dysfunction, physical examination&#xD;
                  finding, or clinical laboratory finding giving reasonable suspicion of a disease&#xD;
                  or condition that in the opinion of the investigator contraindicates use of an&#xD;
                  investigational drug or places the patient at unacceptable risk from treatment&#xD;
                  complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinically significant cardiac dysfunction, including the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant cardiac arrhythmias including brady-arrhythmias and/or&#xD;
                  patients who require anti-arrhythmic therapy (with the exception of beta blockers&#xD;
                  or digoxin). Patients with controlled atrial fibrillation are not excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable arrhythmia&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable angina, or new-onset angina within 3 months prior to initiation of study&#xD;
                  treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Symptomatic congestive heart failure, defined as New York Heart Association Class&#xD;
                  II or higher&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Myocardial infarction within 3 months prior to initiation of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known chronic human immunodeficiency virus (HIV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Grade ≥ 2 CNS hemorrhage or history of any CNS hemorrhage within 28 days of&#xD;
             study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients who are pregnant or lactating. Pregnant or lactating women will not be&#xD;
             entered on this study because there is no available information regarding human fetal&#xD;
             or teratogenic toxicities.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carl E Allen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carl E Allen, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>832-822-4242</phone>
    <email>ceallen@texaschildrens.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Olive Eckstein, MD</last_name>
    <phone>832-822-4242</phone>
    <email>Eckstein@bcm.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NACHO Consortium</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sara Clyburn</last_name>
      <phone>901-595-6042</phone>
      <email>Sara.Clyburn@STJUDE.ORG</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Heidi Clough</last_name>
      <phone>901-595-0362</phone>
      <email>Heidi.Clough@STJUDE.ORG</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Texas Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carl E. Allen, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>832-826-0860</phone>
      <email>ceallen@txch.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 10, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 4, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 6, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Baylor College of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carl Allen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cobimetinib</keyword>
  <keyword>Langerhans Cell Histiocytosis (LCH)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Histiocytic Sarcoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Histiocytic Disorders, Malignant</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Histiocytosis, Langerhans-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neurodegenerative Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Histiocytosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Erdheim-Chester Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Histiocytosis, Sinus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Xanthogranuloma, Juvenile</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

