<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04078334</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CER VN 19-20-15</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04078334</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Personalized Exercises Program Prescription to Prevent Functional Decline Throughout Older Adults Hospitalization</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prevention of the Functional Decline Throughout Hospitalization Among Older Adults by Using a Systematic Process for Prescribing Personalized, Evidence-based Exercises Via the Implementation of the Tool PATH 2.0</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Université du Québec a Montréal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Université du Québec a Montréal</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Bed rest related to hospitalization contributes to the physical decline in capacities of the&#xD;
      elderly, the loss of autonomy accelerated in post-hospitalization and the prevalence of the&#xD;
      iatrogenic functional decline is about 20 to 50% for the elderly after an hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mobilization through physical activity (PA) programs is strongly suggested to counter this&#xD;
      phenomenon, but it is not part of the routine clinical hospital practices.The consequences&#xD;
      are the functional incapacities, the mobility loss, the re-hospitalization falls and the&#xD;
      important use of the health care and health services. In this regard, the Ministry of Health&#xD;
      and Social Services adopted in 2011 a framework making mandatory the set up of interventions&#xD;
      to prevent the functional decline of hospitalized elderly in every hospital centres in&#xD;
      Quebec. The Geriatric Units (GU) admit elderly around 80 years old that present complex&#xD;
      health problems. The scientific literature presents effective mobilisation programs to ensure&#xD;
      the maintenance of functional capacities and the mobility of frail elderly. However, even&#xD;
      with this knowledge, the prescription of physical exercises by the GU does not seem to be&#xD;
      integrated in a natural and systematic way by in the professional practices.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our research team would like to implant the clinical tools : MATCH, PATH and PATH 2.0 that is&#xD;
      a unique process of systematic prescriptions of physical activity during hospitalization&#xD;
      (MATCH), at discharge (PATH) and during hospitalization and at discharge (PATH 2.0) in the&#xD;
      GU, adapted to the profile of these patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this project is to evaluate the implementation of the clinical tools MATCH,&#xD;
      PATH and PATH 2.0 in different GU and to evaluate the tools efficiency and estimate the&#xD;
      benefits-cost ratio on the use of post-hospitalization health services. Finally, the&#xD;
      conclusions would help us refine the procedures to use in the short and medium term which&#xD;
      clinical tool is likely a standard practice our GU and to improve the health continuum of&#xD;
      elderly.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aging of the population and the increase in longevity are associated with societal&#xD;
      issues, both in terms of costs, and the health resources needed to meet the needs of seniors.&#xD;
      Moreover, it is recognized that frail elderly people (defined as at risk of developing or&#xD;
      aggravating functional limitations or disabilities) are the largest users of health care&#xD;
      services. In Canada, as in other industrialized countries, more than a third of&#xD;
      hospitalizations annually are among people aged 65 and over, even though they account for&#xD;
      only 18% of the population .&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, hospitalizations exacerbate the deterioration of fitness, muscle weakness, loss of&#xD;
      balance, and physical inactivity that typically occur during aging and are precursors to&#xD;
      functional decline and frailty. One explanation for this deterioration in the health of&#xD;
      elderly people during hospital stays is bed rest and general immobility. Thus, the prevention&#xD;
      of immobilization syndrome in elderly people in hospitals being a priority issue for both&#xD;
      national and international health networks, a project was carried out between 2014 and 2016&#xD;
      within the geriatric unit (GU) of a Canadian university-affiliated geriatric hospital (IUGM).&#xD;
      This project aimed to implement in a pragmatic way (adjusted to the human and material&#xD;
      resources in place) a physical activity (PA) program for hospitalization according to the&#xD;
      functional capacities of the hospitalized patients. This project showed that the&#xD;
      implementation of this program was feasible (at least 1 session of PA / day) and acceptable&#xD;
      by health professionals, patients and their caregivers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the same time, it is recognized that, following hospitalization, 22 to 50% of older people&#xD;
      will experience a functional decline that will decrease their ability to perform activities&#xD;
      of daily living and, consequently, their quality. of life. These tangible losses lead to a&#xD;
      vicious circle as they contribute to readmission for 33% of those affected and additional use&#xD;
      of health services in the majority of cases. Prescription of PA is one of the recognized&#xD;
      solutions to prevent or reduce these deteriorations. PA, whether practiced in the community&#xD;
      or at home, improves the mobility and functional level of pre-frail and frail seniors to&#xD;
      moderate effect sizes (mobility).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The post-hospitalization prescription of an PA program, however, does not appear to be&#xD;
      integrated into standard care delivery practices, unlike the management of medications or&#xD;
      assistance with the performance of activities of daily living, and this, despite the&#xD;
      priorities established in this regard by governments and the World Health Organization (WHO).&#xD;
      On average, 35% of GU patients at discharge receive a prescription to maintain or improve the&#xD;
      strength and balance (internal data of the Regroupement des Unités de courte durée&#xD;
      gériatrique et des services hospitaliers de gériatrie-RUSHGQ), even if these communities have&#xD;
      rehabilitation services. As part of a project (2016-2018), the research team has created an&#xD;
      easy-to-implement decisional tree that can be used to prescribe appropriate programs for GU&#xD;
      at discharge, while inducing beneficial effects for patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, these two innovative projects, which aim to prevent functional decline through&#xD;
      hospitalization and which meet the policy of the Ministry of Health and Social Services, are&#xD;
      the&quot;Adapted Health Care Approach for Older Adults in Quebec Hospital Centres&quot; through&#xD;
      systematic, specific and specialized interventions, have not been implemented in a combined&#xD;
      and complementary way. However, the implementation of a proactive and adapted approach to&#xD;
      prescribing PA per and post-hospitalization, through a simple tool based on the clinical&#xD;
      measures available in practice settings, represents a real organizational innovation and&#xD;
      should add value to current practices. Thus, the study of the cost-benefit of implementing&#xD;
      such a practice is important to validate the scope of such a tool on the use of post-hospital&#xD;
      health care services compared to an isolated intervention of PA per or post-hospitalization&#xD;
      or usual care. In this sense, a study showed a savings of 22,000 $ / person in health&#xD;
      services costs for seniors who improved their mobility via PA in post-hospitalization. Thus,&#xD;
      the investigators can sense that preventing the loss of muscle function and mobility as well&#xD;
      as falls, the quality of life of patients and their caregivers. In addition, from a&#xD;
      collective point of view, this should lead to savings because of the reduction in the costs&#xD;
      of care related to injuries caused by a fall or fall after hospitalization that may result in&#xD;
      re-hospitalization or even a death.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Considering 1) the importance of the negative impacts of sedentarity / immobilization on&#xD;
      seniors, particularly per and post-hospitalization, as well as its potential economic and&#xD;
      societal impact; 2) the recognized importance of PA prescription in the prevention of the&#xD;
      functional decline of seniors per and post-hospitalization and 3) the absence of&#xD;
      organizational processes favoring the implementation of systematic prescribing of PA per and&#xD;
      post-hospitalization, The implementation of a systematic process of prescribing adapted,&#xD;
      validated and integrated physical exercises in the usual per and or post-hospitalization&#xD;
      practices appears crucial to the preservation of the autonomy and quality of life of the&#xD;
      elderly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the present study, an interventional pragmatic study design with randomization by cluster&#xD;
      was selected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTERVENTIONS :&#xD;
&#xD;
      MATCH : PA program per hospitalization PATH : PA program post hospitalization PATH 2.0 :&#xD;
      Combination of the PA program Per (MATCH) and Post hospitalization (PATH).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control : usual care by clinical teams&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in short physical performance battery (SPPB) after intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>SPPB is comprised of 3 tasks: a standing balance test (side by side, semi-tandem and tandem), 4-m habitual gait speed and 5 sit to stand from a chair. Each task is scored (based on time) from 0-4 points.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in muscle strength after intervention (upper muscle strength : handgrip strength, lower limb strength: sit to stand-30sec)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Handgrip strengh, sit to stand test (30sec)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in walking after intervention (Walking speed :4 m habitual gait speed and walking parameter : 3 meter timed up and go)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4 m habitual gait speed test and 3 m timed up and go test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the clinical tools : MATCH, PATH, PATH 2.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>will be measured using a score (expressed in %) taking into account the ratio of the number of patients who have received an PA program on the number of patients hospitalized and eligible for treatment study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usability of the clinical tools : MATCH, PATH, PATH 2.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Usability will be measured using the valided SUS questionnaire (10 items/score ranged from 0 to 100).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of the clinical tools: MATCH, PATH, PATH 2.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Will be evaluated by the administration of a questionnaire with 4 Likert level/question. This questionnaire will presented 3 sub-sections examining :1) its clinical relevance, 2) its applicability in ecological environment; 3) its implementation burden.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimate the benefits-cost ratio on the use of post-hospitalization health services</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>QALY analysis estimating cost reduction related to health service utilization, number of falls / falls with injuries, and benefits through improved quality of life; cost-effectiveness analysis; and confirmatory economic analysis of the &quot;difference-in-differences&quot; type, the following variables will be necessary: the socio-economic portrait of the participants, the quality of life, the cost of care and use of health services : 1) visits to doctors or health professionals, 2) home visiting DAS professionals or 3) emergency room / hospital stays via medical records)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the length of stay after intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospitalization days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in the quality of life after intervention (SF-12)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>SF-12</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Use of health resources</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of admissions before and after hospitalization, visit to general practitioner before and after hospitalization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in caregiver burden after intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 36 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Mini-zarit</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of pandemic period</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Differences on feasibility, acceptability and effects of MATCH, PATH and PATH 2.0 during and after COVID-19</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact of healthcare area</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Differences on feasibility, acceptability and effects of MATCH, PATH and PATH 2.0 between university and non-university hospitals or between urban vs non urban area</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">720</enrollment>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <condition>Hospitalization</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PATH Tool : Prescription of exercise programs at discharge</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>PATH 2.0 Tool : Prescription of exercise programs during hospitalization and discharge</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MATCH tool: Prescription of physical exercise programs during hospitalization</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group: Usual care by the clinical teams</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MATCH</intervention_name>
    <description>In the first days of hospitalization, the physiotherapist determines the score linked to the patient's mobility profile using of a decisional tree. The PA program has 2 or 3 exercises to be done with or without supervision 3 times per week day during hospitalization. These daily exercises are prescribed by the doctor and taught by the physiotherapist.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PATH</intervention_name>
    <description>In the days prior to discharge, the physiotherapist determines the patient's mobility profile using the decisional tree. When returning home after hospitalization, each PA program includes a daily walk as well as 3 or 4 exercises that can be completed in a 12 to 20 minutes timeframe. These daily exercises are prescribed by the doctor and taught by the physiotherapist in 2 sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PATH 2.0</intervention_name>
    <description>In the first days of hospitalization, the physiotherapist determines the score linked to the patient's mobility profile using of a decisional tree. The PA program has 2 or 3 exercises to be done with or without supervision 3 times per week day during hospitalization. These daily exercises are prescribed by the doctor and taught by the physiotherapist.&#xD;
In the days prior to discharge, the physiotherapist determines the patient's mobility profile using the decisional tree. When returning home after hospitalization, each PA program includes a daily walk as well as 3 or 4 exercises that can completed in a 12 to 20 minutes timeframe. These daily exercises are prescribed by the doctor and taught by the physiotherapist in 2 sessions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        There is no eligibility criteria but the doctor will have to consider these criteria :&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  be aged 65 and over,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  planned discharge to home&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of self-criticism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No PA contraindication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  And ability to speak and understand French and/or English&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mylene Aubertin-Leheudre, Ph. D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Université du Québec a Montréal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marie-Jeanne Kergoat, M.D., FRCPC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre de recherche de l'institut Universitaire de Gériatrie de Montreal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Fonseca Raquel, Ph. D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Université du Québec a Montréal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Veillette Nathalie, Ph.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Université de Montréal</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mylene Aubertin-Leheudre, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>514-987-3000</phone>
    <phone_ext>5018</phone_ext>
    <email>aubertin-leheudre.mylene@uqam.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Caroline Law</last_name>
    <phone>514-340-2800</phone>
    <phone_ext>2811</phone_ext>
    <email>caroline.law@criugm.qc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Geriatric Units</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 6, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Centre de Recherche de l'Institut Universitaire de Geriatrie de Montreal</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mylène Aubertin-Leheudre</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principale Investigator-Researcher</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Frail older adults</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>exercise</keyword>
  <keyword>Hospitalization</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

