<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04079868</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IIR 17-202</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04079868</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Models of Primary Osteoporosis Screening in Male Veterans</brief_title>
  <acronym>MOPS</acronym>
  <official_title>Models of Primary Osteoporosis Screening in Male Veterans</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Models of Osteoporosis Screening in Male Veterans aims to test 1 distinct care model of&#xD;
      primary osteoporosis screening in men within the VA healthcare setting. All care models&#xD;
      deliver VA recommended osteoporosis screening and treatment to high-risk Veterans by&#xD;
      appropriate Durham VA clinical staff. The MOPS project will evaluate patient, provider and&#xD;
      facility outcomes to determine the effectiveness of each intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background/Purpose:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Osteoporosis is under-recognized in older men. At age 50 years, 1 in 5 men can expect to&#xD;
      suffer a major osteoporotic fracture in their remaining lifetime, comparable to the risk of&#xD;
      prostate cancer. Men are more than twice as likely as women to experience complications after&#xD;
      a fracture, and have greater excess mortality after hip fracture. Because risk factors are&#xD;
      common in Veterans, osteoporosis is particularly prevalent in the Veterans Health&#xD;
      Administration (VA) system. More than half of male Veterans over age 50 years have osteopenia&#xD;
      or osteoporosis, a rate nearly double the non-Veteran population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fractures resulting from osteoporosis have negative consequences on functional status,&#xD;
      mortality, and quality of life, with high rates of pain, depression, and loss of&#xD;
      independence. After a hip fracture, nearly 75% of patients spend time in a nursing facility,&#xD;
      and only 20% regain their prior level of ambulation. Many fractures are associated with&#xD;
      substantial excess mortality; men with a hip fracture have excess annual mortality of 20%&#xD;
      that persists up to 10 years. Osteoporotic fractures also have an important economic impact.&#xD;
      It is estimated that hip fractures result in 43 million dollars of excess cost to the VHA&#xD;
      annually.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Osteoporosis screening and treatment services within VA are ineffective overall. Overall,&#xD;
      screening rates were 8% for men over age 65; far lower than expected based on the prevalence&#xD;
      of osteoporosis risk factors in the population. Moreover, even among men in whom screening&#xD;
      was completed, it was not associated with lower overall fracture rates because osteoporosis&#xD;
      treatment and adherence following screening were extremely low.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Attempts to improve osteoporosis screening using traditional quality improvement programs&#xD;
      have been minimally effective. Electronic health record (EHR) alerts alone do not improve&#xD;
      osteoporosis screening rates and do nothing to address adherence. However, one distinct&#xD;
      osteoporosis screening paradigm has been suggested, and form the scientific premise for the&#xD;
      models proposed in this application. A fracture Liaison Service (referred to here as &quot;Bone&#xD;
      Health Service&quot;, BHS) represents a centralized model that has been successful in improving&#xD;
      secondary osteoporosis screening and treatment adherence after a fracture has already&#xD;
      occurred. In this model, a team of nurses led by a bone specialist identify patients with&#xD;
      fracture within the entire health system, and arrange for evaluation and treatment. Such&#xD;
      models have reduced 2-year fracture rates by 56% and are cost saving or highly&#xD;
      cost-effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators propose a pragmatic group randomized trial of PACT teams from both Durham&#xD;
      and Richmond VAMC's. A PACT's will be randomized into 2 groups: a control group (no&#xD;
      additional support), and a centralized Bone Health Service (BHS) model where teams will&#xD;
      manage the screening and treatment of high-risk for fracture male Veterans.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes for all patients eligible for osteoporosis screening within the randomized PACTs&#xD;
      will be assessed by investigators masked to group assignment. Outcomes for PACT providers&#xD;
      will be assessed using qualitative methods (nominal group technique).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient-level outcomes:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Eligible proportion screened&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Medication adherence&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PACT fracture rates&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Harms&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bone mineral density&#xD;
&#xD;
      Provider and facility level outcomes:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Change in Dual-energy X-ray absorptiometry (DXA) volume&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Bone mineral density (sub-sample of patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Change in metabolic bone disease clinic volume&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PACT provider time and satisfaction (qualitative analyses)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Health system and policy level outcomes&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Program cost effectiveness&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will compare the 1 screening models by enrolling, screening and randomizing&#xD;
      PACT teams. 39 teams will be randomized, an estimated 24 teams at the Durham VA health care&#xD;
      system and 15 at the Richmond VA medical center. Teams will be randomized to 1 of 2 arms:&#xD;
      Bone Health Service or usual care (no additional support). A sub-set of providers will be&#xD;
      recruited to complete a nominal group qualitative interview during year 3. Also a random&#xD;
      sub-set of patients (900) will be recruited to complete a DXA scan to measure bone density&#xD;
      beginning in year 4. Outcomes will be assessed at year 1, 2, 3, and 4.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 30, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Stratified, block randomization will be used. A statistician unaware of team identity will randomize PACTs in blocks of 2 within strata to ensure similar distributions. If insufficient numbers of PACTs are recruited within small CBOCs, they will be combined with other similar CBOCs (rural vs. urban) for randomization.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Outcome assessors will be masked to the group assignment</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Screening Rates (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>Datapull at year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of men eligible men screened in last 12 months. Numerator is men receiving screening DXA, denominator is all patients meeting current osteoporosis screening criteria in the randomized PACT team</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication Discontinuation (days)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Obtained from pharmacy dispensing records, the mean number of days until a gap in medication prescription of &gt;=90 days among men prescribed osteoporosis medication</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication Initiation (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>Intervention period year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Obtained from pharmacy dispensing records, numerator is number of patients prescribed osteoporosis medications, denominator is number of patients eligible for osteoporosis medications within each of the 39 randomized PACT teams</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication Implementation (% of days covered with medication)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Obtained from pharmacy dispensing records, for patients started on osteoporosis medications within prior year within the 39 PACT teams. Numerator is days covered by dispensed tablets, denominator is total number of days since the first medication prescription, censoring for death.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone Mineral Density (gram/sq centimeter)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 5</time_frame>
    <description>Chart abstraction of completed DXA of a random sample of n=900 patients within the 39 enrolled PACT teams</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Harms (%)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 3</time_frame>
    <description>Data pull of ICD10 codes, numerator is number of men with new prescription for proton pump inhibitor or H2 blocker, denominator is all men eligible for osteoporosis screening within each of the 39 PACT teams.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PACT Provider Time</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Collected during nominal group qualitative interview</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fractures (% with fracture in last 2 years)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 4</time_frame>
    <description>Data pull, confirmed by chart abstraction for all patients within the 39 PACTs. Numerator is number of men with fracture in last 2 years, denominator is all men eligible for osteoporosis screening within each of the 39 PACT teams.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>DXA volume (DEXA rate per year)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Data collected at the facility level measuring change in DXA referrals</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bone Disease Clinic Volume (Consults per year)</measure>
    <time_frame>Year 2</time_frame>
    <description>Data collected at the facility level measuring change in bone clinic referral.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">39</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteoporosis</condition>
  <condition>Osteopenia</condition>
  <condition>Osteoporotic Fracture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bone Health Service arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Interventional arm</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care (control) arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm represents a &quot;no practice management support&quot; control group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bone Health Service Model</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients in PACTs randomized to the BHS model will have osteoporosis screening, education, and follow-up handled centrally by the bone health team.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Bone Health Service arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        PACT Team inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provider with at least 0.75 FTE&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provider has completed training (i.e., PACT teams led by residents and fellows are&#xD;
             excluded)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Care for male Veterans &gt;65 years (i.e., Women's Health PACTs are excluded)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patient Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior fracture or osteoporosis diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 1 VA Undersecretary Guideline risk factor (weight loss &gt;20% in 5 years; BMI&#xD;
             &lt;25 kg/m2; diabetes; pernicious anemia; gastrectomy; anticonvulsants; glucocorticoids;&#xD;
             androgen deprivation therapy; hyperthyroidism; hyperparathyroidism; rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis; alcohol dependence; chronic lung disease; chronic liver disease; stroke;&#xD;
             Parkinsonism; prostate cancer; and current smoking).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients (enrolled in year 4/5 sub-sample) inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men aged 65-85 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in eligible PACT team for at least 2 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meet 1 or more criteria for osteoporosis screening as the protocol at PACT enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cathleen S Colon-Emeric, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Durham VA Medical Center, Durham, NC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Durham VA Medical Center, Durham, NC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27705</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Salt Lake City Health Care System, Salt Lake City, UT</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84148</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hunter Holmes McGuire VA Medical Center, Richmond, VA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Richmond</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>23249</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 4, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 6, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Osteoporosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Osteopenia</keyword>
  <keyword>Osteoporotic fracture</keyword>
  <keyword>Age-Related Osteoporosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Bone Loss, Age-Related</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Osteoporosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Diseases, Metabolic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Osteoporotic Fractures</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

