<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04075214</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SBM-OWP-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04075214</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Transcutaneous Auricular Neurostimulation (tAN) for Symptoms of Opioid Withdrawal</brief_title>
  <official_title>Delivering Transcutaneous Auricular Neurostimulation (tAN) to Improve Symptoms Associated With Opioid Withdrawal</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Spark Biomedical, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Spark Biomedical, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Clinical performance data for transcutaneous auricular neurostimulation (tAN) as a method to&#xD;
      aid in the reduction of symptoms associated with opioid withdrawal in order to support&#xD;
      clinical substantial equivalence to a predicate device.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Prior evidence has demonstrated that non-invasive neurostimulation can modulate specific&#xD;
      brains regions associated with opioid use disorder and reduce opioid withdrawal symptoms.&#xD;
      This is a double blind, randomized, controlled, multi-center study in which subjects will be&#xD;
      randomized in a 1:1 ratio to one of two groups: 1) active transcutaneous auricular&#xD;
      neurostimulation (tAN) or 2) delayed-active tAN to determine reduction of symptoms related to&#xD;
      opioid withdrawal. Subjects in the active tAN group will receive tAN immediately whereas&#xD;
      those in the delayed-active tAN will have their therapy turned on after a 30 minute delay&#xD;
      (inactive period). All subjects will be informed of their group assignment at the conclusion&#xD;
      of the randomized, double blind period (following initial 30 minutes of active or inactive&#xD;
      therapy) and all will continue to receive active tAN throughout the five-day study. Each&#xD;
      clinical site will have pre-determined and qualified clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS)&#xD;
      accessor(s) that will be blind to the subjects group designation during the randomized,&#xD;
      double blind period and will not be informed that all subjects receive active therapy&#xD;
      throughout the remainder of the study. This will ensure a non-biased assessment of the COWS&#xD;
      score and maintain single blinding throughout the duration of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 19, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 14, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 14, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>60 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Mean percent change in clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) score from baseline to 60 minutes after start of active tAN therapy. The COWS is an 11-item scale with a score range between 0 and 48. Total score is the sum of all the items and a higher score indicates more severe withdrawal symptoms. Scores between 5 and 12 indicate mild withdrawal, scores between 13 and 24 indicate moderate withdrawal, scores between 25 and 36 indicate moderately severe withdrawal and scores greater than 36 indicate severe withdrawal. A COWS score reduction of 15% or greater for a given individual is considered clinically significant.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of mean percent change in COWS score in delayed active tAN versus active tAN groups at 30 minutes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) responder rate</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the proportion of participants with a clinically significant reduction in COWS score (defined as a 15% or greater reduction) in delayed-active tAN versus active tAN groups at 30 minutes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>30 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Mean percent change in COWS score from baseline to 30 minutes after start of active tAN therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>120 minutes</time_frame>
    <description>Mean percent change in COWS score from baseline to 120 minutes after start of active tAN therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical opiate withdrawal scale (COWS) score</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 2-5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean percent change in COWS score from baseline to Days 2 through 5 after start of active tAN therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate variability measured by R to R interval</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 2-5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change from baseline to Days 2-5 in heart rate variability measured by R to R interval</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>C-reactive protein (CRP) levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in C-reactive protein (CRP) levels from baseline to Day 5</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cortisol levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in cortisol levels from baseline to Day 5</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cytokine levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in cytokine levels from baseline to Day 5</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in depression symptoms measured by Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9) total score from baseline to Day 5. The PHQ-9 is a nine-item depression scale based directly on the nine diagnostic criteria for major depressive disorder in the DSM-IV. Each of the nine items is rated on a 0 (not at all) to 3 (nearly every day) scale. A total score is calculated by summing the nine items. Scores range from 0 to 27 and higher scores indicate a higher degree of depression.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD) Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in PTSD symptoms measured by the PTSD Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5) total symptom severity score from baseline to Day 5. The PCL-5 is a 20-item self-report measure that assesses the 20 DSM-5 symptoms of PTSD. Each of the 20 items is rated on a 0 (not at all) to 4 (extremely) scale. A total symptom severity score is calculated by summing the 20 items. Scores range from 0 and 80 and higher scores indicating a higher degree of PTSD symptomology. Evidence suggests that a10-20 point reduction in score represents a clinically significant change in PTSD symptoms.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>World Health Organization Quality of Life - BREF (WHOQOL-BREF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 5</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change in WHOQOL-BREF domain scores (physical health, psychological health, social relationships, environment, and overall QoL/general health) from baseline to Day 5. The World Health Organization Quality of Life - BREF (WHOQOL-BREF) is a 26-item, self-report questionnaire which assesses 4 quality of life domains: physical health, psychological health, social relationships, and environment. In addition, there are 2 items that measure overall quality of life and general health. Subjects rate how much they have experienced each item in the preceding 2 weeks on a 5-point Likert scale ranging from 1 (not at all) to 5 (completely). Domain scores are scaled in a positive direction with higher scores denoting higher quality of life. Raw domain scores will be converted to a 0 to 100 scale.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Opioid-use Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Opioid Withdrawal</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>delayed-active tAN</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>active tAN</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>transcutaneous auricular neurostimulation (tAN)</intervention_name>
    <description>Phoenix tAN system</description>
    <arm_group_label>active tAN</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>delayed-active tAN</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current opioid dependence; prescriptive or non-prescriptive&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. COWS score is ≥ 13 or in the opinion of the investigator the subject is in moderate to&#xD;
             severe withdrawal&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. 18-65 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. English Proficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants must be able to provide informed con-sent and function at an intellectual&#xD;
             level sufficient for study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current evidence of an uncontrolled and/or clinically significant medical condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of seizures or epilepsy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of neurological diseases or traumatic brain injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants using long-acting opioids such as methadone or buprenorphine for a period&#xD;
             of five or more consecutive days prior to enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Recent suicide attempt leading to current hospital admission or continued expressed&#xD;
             suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Presence of devices, e.g. pace-makers, cochlear prosthesis, neuro-stimulators&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Abnormal ear anatomy or ear infection present&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing potential, not using adequate contraception as per investigator&#xD;
             judgment or not willing to comply with contraception for the duration of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Females who are pregnant or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Any other significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the Investigator,&#xD;
             may either put the participants at risk because of participation in the trial, or may&#xD;
             influence the result of the trial, or the participant's ability to participate in the&#xD;
             trial&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Navid Khodaparast, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Spark Biomedical, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Recovery Unplugged</name>
      <address>
        <city>Austin</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>78745</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>auricular neurostimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>vagus nerve stimulation</keyword>
  <keyword>transcutaneous</keyword>
  <keyword>withdrawal symptoms</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Opioid-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance Withdrawal Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

