<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04079166</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCIB1-002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04079166</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase 2, Multicenter, Open-Label Study of SCIB1 in Patients With Advanced Unresectable Melanoma Receiving Pembrolizumab</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Multicenter, Open-Label Study of SCIB1 in Patients With Advanced Unresectable Melanoma Receiving Pembrolizumab</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Scancell Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Scancell Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find out if a new treatment called SCIB1 can be used safely&#xD;
      when added to pembrolizumab (Keytruda), a standard therapy approved for the treatment of&#xD;
      advanced melanoma (skin cancer). Pembrolizumab is an antibody treatment for cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will also look to see if SCIB1 can increase the likelihood that melanoma patients&#xD;
      will respond to pembrolizumab, and also if SCIB1 can help to make those responses last&#xD;
      longer. Pembrolizumab is considered a standard treatment for patients with advanced melanoma.&#xD;
      SCIB1 is considered experimental. SCIB1 has been given to melanoma patients in an earlier&#xD;
      study. It was generally well-tolerated, and researchers saw some signs that it may help to&#xD;
      stimulate the immune system, which is a way in which the body can fight the cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is expected to enroll up to 44 melanoma patients worldwide.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open label, single arm Phase 2 study to determine the safety and tolerability of&#xD;
      SCIB1 administered to patients with advanced melanoma using an electroporation device (the&#xD;
      TDS-IM v2.0 device) when added to pembrolizumab (Keytruda), a standard treatment already&#xD;
      approved for the treatment of advanced melanoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The plan for this study is for SCIB1 to be given for up to 85 weeks, in combination with&#xD;
      pembrolizumab according to the current label.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After receiving the first dose of SCIB1, the patient will receive SCIB1 at 4, 7, 13 and 25&#xD;
      weeks, then every 12 weeks until Week 85. Pembrolizumab treatment will be started 1 week&#xD;
      after the first dose of SCIB1 and given every 6 weeks up to Week 85.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pembrolizumab will be given by an injection into the patient's vein. The injection, known as&#xD;
      an infusion, usually takes about 30 minutes to complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On each occasion, SCIB1 will be given by two injections into a muscle in a different limb,&#xD;
      e.g., one into the upper arm and the other into the thigh. Instead of a normal needle and&#xD;
      syringe, a small, hand-held device, TDS-IM v2.0, will be used to inject SCIB1 into the&#xD;
      muscles. The site of SCIB1 administration will alternate on each occasion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The injection device is designed to increase the amount of SCIB1 that is delivered to the&#xD;
      muscle cells. The liquid containing SCIB1 will be delivered through the injection needle.&#xD;
      Immediately after the injection, the device will give an electrical impulse to the muscle&#xD;
      through the four thin wires at the site of the injection. The impulse will last for less than&#xD;
      one tenth of a second. A short video will be shown to the patient before the first injection&#xD;
      is given to show the patient what will happen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before treatment starts and after consent has been given, all patients will undergo screening&#xD;
      tests (to be completed within 28 days of treatment initiation) to ensure the patient is&#xD;
      eligible to take part. For screening, the patient will need to undergo tissue typing, a&#xD;
      melanoma tumor biopsy will be required if an adequate sample for testing was not previously&#xD;
      performed, an eye examination, blood and urine samples taken for clinical laboratory tests,&#xD;
      pregnancy status (for female patients only), tests of their immune functions, a physical&#xD;
      examination including their vital signs, performance status and an electrocardiogram (ECG), a&#xD;
      computerized tomography (CT) or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) scan plus a visual&#xD;
      inspection and photographing of any skin lesions, skin fold thickness measurement, and&#xD;
      medical history collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Over the 85-week treatment period, the patient will visit the hospital 25 times and have two&#xD;
      telephone/video calls. They will then have an end of treatment (EOT) visit approximately 4&#xD;
      weeks after the last dose of SCIB1 or pembrolizumab (whichever occurs last) and a final&#xD;
      post-treatment follow-up visit 12 weeks after the last dose of study treatment (SCIB1 or&#xD;
      pembrolizumab, whichever occurs last). The evaluations and procedures that will be carried&#xD;
      out at each visit are all detailed in the study information sheets given to the patient&#xD;
      before consent is taken. At some of these visits, blood samples will be taken for&#xD;
      immunological tests. Female participants of childbearing potential will undergo pregnancy&#xD;
      testing during screening, at the start of treatment, 7 weeks after the first dose of SCIB1,&#xD;
      every 6 weeks until the end of the treatment period and at the EOT visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At certain visits, all patients will have physical examinations and have their skin lesions&#xD;
      assessed and photographed. At all visits, patients will be asked about other medications they&#xD;
      are taking and about any adverse effects they might have experienced since their previous&#xD;
      clinic visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In response to the COVID-19 pandemic, the treatment burden for patients has also been reduced&#xD;
      where possible by conducting remote assessments via telephone or video conference.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After receiving their last dose of SCIB1 or pembrolizumab (whichever occurs last), all&#xD;
      surviving participants will be followed up by attending clinic visits for tumor assessments&#xD;
      (including CT/MRI scans) every 12 weeks for a period of 97 weeks (~2 years) from the first&#xD;
      dose of SCIB1, unless disease progression occurs or a new anticancer treatment is initiated.&#xD;
      If disease progression does occur or a new anticancer treatment is initiated, follow-up every&#xD;
      12 weeks (up to Week 97) may be conducted by a healthcare professional by telephone/video&#xD;
      conference call or during a routine clinic visit. At each assessment questions will be asked&#xD;
      about the following: survival, development of infection, immunological reactions,&#xD;
      participation in any other clinical trials and subsequent exposure to highly potent&#xD;
      treatments.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 19, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Open label, uncontrolled study.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of adverse events (AEs) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through last recorded assessment of safety, 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>National Cancer Institute [NCI] Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events; CTCAE v5.0.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (temperature) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Temperature (°C).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (pulse) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Pulse (beats per minute).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (respiratory rate) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory rate (breaths per minute).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (blood pressure) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Systolic and diastolic blood pressure (mm Hg).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by a physical examination of the participant (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Physical examination of eyes, neurological and cardiovascular systems, lungs, abdomen, head, neck, ears, nose, mouth, throat, thyroid, lymph nodes, extremities, and other areas with signs and symptoms of disease (binary classification: normal or abnormal).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (creatinine, bilirubin, uric acid) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Creatinine, bilirubin - total, bilirubin - direct (if clinically indicated), uric acid (urate) (μmol/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (including blood urea nitrogen) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood urea nitrogen, bicarbonate (or carbon dioxide), calcium, chloride, potassium, sodium, non-fasting glucose, phosphorus (measured as phosphate), uric acid (urate) (mmol/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (including alanine aminotransferase) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Alanine aminotransferase, alkaline phosphatase, aspartate aminotransferase, gamma glutamyl transferase, lactate dehydrogenase (LDH; international units/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (Albumin) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment).</time_frame>
    <description>Albumin, total protein (g/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (Thyroid-stimulating hormone) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Thyroid-stimulating hormone (mIU/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (Free thyroxine, triiodothyronine) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Free thyroxine, triiodothyronine (pmol/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (red blood cell count) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Red blood cell count (10⌃12/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (including hematocrit) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Hematocrit (%).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute neutrophils, absolute lymphocytes, absolute monocytes, absolute eosinophils, absolute basophils, absolute platelets (10⌃9/L).&#xD;
Differential neutrophils, differential lymphocytes, differential monocytes, differential eosinophils, differential basophils, differential platelets (%).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (corpuscular volume) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Mean corpuscular volume (fL).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (corpuscular hemoglobin) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Mean corpuscular hemoglobin (pg).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (hemoglobin, corpuscular hemoglobin) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Hemoglobin, mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (g/L).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by coagulation testing (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>International normalised ratio, activated partial prothrombin time (s).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (protein, glucose) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Protein, glucose (negative/trace/1+/2+/3+/4+).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (ketones, blood, nitrites, leukocytes, bilirubin) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Ketones, blood, nitrites, leukocytes, bilirubin (negative/trace/1+/2+/3+).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (pH) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>pH (pH units).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (specific gravity) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Specific gravity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (white blood cells, red blood cells) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>If clinically indicated: white blood cells and red blood cells (cells per high power field).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (bacteria, casts and crystals) (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>If clinically indicated: microscopic examination for bacteria, casts and crystals (binary classification: positive or negative).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by 12-lead ECG. (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 and 7 weeks after the first dose of study drug, and at end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of standard components of the 12-lead ECG. Information regarding standard components of the ECG will not be collected systematically; however, in cases where an ECG abnormality is identified, the abnormality will be reported as an AE, and all details of the identified abnormality will be provided.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by performance status (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Grading of performance status as defined by the European Cooperative Group (ECOG) Performance Status score on a 6-point scale, where 0 = 'fully active, able to carry on all pre-disease performance without restriction' and 5 = 'dead'.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the injection site reaction (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug to last post-study drug assessment (3 weeks after the last dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician assessment of the injection site reaction using a 3-point scale where 1 = 'mild' and 3 = 'severe'.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the use of concomitant medications (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug through last recorded assessment of safety, approximately 2 years (Week 97)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by a tolerability questionnaire (Run-In Cohort: first 6 participants enrolled)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug to last post-study drug assessment (3 weeks after the last dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Patient assessment of the tolerability of the injection using a 5-point scale where 1 = 'no sensation' and 5 = 'extreme pain'.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR) of SCIB1 in patients receiving pembrolizumab relative to historical data for pembrolizumab alone in this patient population (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through last recorded assessment of response, up to 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Objective response as assessed by Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors version 1.1 (RECIST 1.1) criteria.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect on duration of response of SCIB1 in patients receiving pembrolizumab relative to historical data for pembrolizumab alone in this patient population (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through last recorded assessment of response, up to 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of response, measured from the point of first response (complete response or partial response) to the date of disease progression (per RECIST 1.1) or death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab relative to historical data for pembrolizumab alone in this patient population, based on the modified RECIST 1.1 for immune-based therapeutics (iRECIST) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through last recorded assessment of response, up to 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>ORR as determined by iRECIST criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival (PFS) rate.</measure>
    <time_frame>At 1 year (Week 49) and 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>PFS rate is defined as the proportion of participants who have not progressed (per RECIST 1.1 and iRECIST), or started new anticancer therapy, or died.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS) rate.</measure>
    <time_frame>At 1 year (Week 49) and 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>OS rate is defined as the proportion of participants who remain alive.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of AEs (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through last recorded assessment of safety, 2 years (Week 97) from the first dose of study drug</time_frame>
    <description>[NCI] CTCAE v5.0.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (temperature) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Temperature (°C).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (pulse) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Pulse (beats per minute).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (respiratory rate) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory rate (breaths per minute).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the recording of vital signs (blood pressure) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Systolic and diastolic blood pressure (mm Hg).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by a physical examination of the participant (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Physical examination of eyes, neurological and cardiovascular systems, lungs, abdomen, head, neck, ears, nose, mouth, throat, thyroid, lymph nodes, extremities, and other areas with signs and symptoms of disease (binary classification: normal or abnormal).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (creatinine, bilirubin, uric acid) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Creatinine, bilirubin - total, bilirubin - direct (if clinically indicated), uric acid (urate) (μmol/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (including blood urea nitrogen) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Blood urea nitrogen, bicarbonate (or carbon dioxide), calcium, chloride, potassium, sodium, non-fasting glucose, phosphorus (measured as phosphate), uric acid (urate) (mmol/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (including Alanine aminotransferase) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Alanine aminotransferase, alkaline phosphatase, aspartate aminotransferase, gamma glutamyl transferase, LDH (international units/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (Albumin) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Albumin, total protein (g/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (Thyroid-stimulating hormone) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Thyroid-stimulating hormone (mIU/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by serum chemistry (Free thyroxine, triiodothyronine) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Free thyroxine, triiodothyronine (pmol/L). Free thyroxine, triiodothyronine (pmol/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (red blood cell count) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Red blood cell count (10⌃12/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (including hematocrit) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Hematocrit (%).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute neutrophils, absolute lymphocytes, absolute monocytes, absolute eosinophils, absolute basophils, absolute platelets (10⌃9/L).&#xD;
Differential neutrophils, differential lymphocytes, differential monocytes, differential eosinophils, differential basophils, differential platelets (%).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (corpuscular volume) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment).</time_frame>
    <description>Mean corpuscular volume (fL).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (corpuscular hemoglobin) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Mean corpuscular hemoglobin (pg).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by hematology (hemoglobin, corpuscular hemoglobin) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Hemoglobin, mean corpuscular hemoglobin concentration (g/L).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by coagulation testing (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>International normalised ratio, activated partial prothrombin time (s).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (protein, glucose) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Protein, glucose (negative/trace/1+/2+/3+/4+).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (ketones, blood, nitrites, leukocytes, bilirubin) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Ketones, blood, nitrites, leukocytes, bilirubin (negative/trace/1+/2+/3+).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (pH) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>pH (pH units).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (specific gravity) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Specific gravity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (white blood cells, red blood cells) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>If clinically indicated: white blood cells and red blood cells (cells per high power field).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by urinalysis (bacteria, casts and crystals) (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>If clinically indicated: microscopic examination for bacteria, casts and crystals (binary classification: positive or negative).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by 12-lead ECG (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 and 7 weeks after the first dose of study drug, and at end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of standard components of the 12-lead ECG. Information regarding standard components of the ECG will not be collected systematically; however, in cases where an ECG abnormality is identified, the abnormality will be reported as an AE, and all details of the identified abnormality will be provided.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by performance status (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Grading of performance status as defined by ECOG Performance Status score on a 6-point scale, where 0 = 'fully active, able to carry on all pre-disease performance without restriction' and 5 = 'dead'.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the injection site reaction (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug to last post-study drug assessment (3 weeks after the last dose of study drug)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician assessment of the injection site reaction using a 3-point scale where 1 = 'mild' and 3 = 'severe'.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety and tolerability of SCIB1 in participants receiving pembrolizumab as assessed by the use of concomitant medications (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug through last recorded assessment of safety, approximately 2 years (Week 97)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of SCIB1 in participants as assessed by a tolerability questionnaire (Main Study)</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first dose of study drug to last post-study drug assessment (3 weeks after the last dose of study drug)</time_frame>
    <description>Patient assessment of the tolerability of the injection using a 5-point scale where 1 = 'no sensation' and 5 = 'extreme pain'.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Exploratory: Immune response.</measure>
    <time_frame>From enrollment through end of treatment (28 days after the final dose of study treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Immune response to TRP-2 and gp100 peptides as measured using ELISpot and other assays on peripheral blood samples from patients at a limited number of sites.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">44</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SCIB1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SCIB1 administered using the TDS-IM v2.0 device</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SCIB1 administered with a small, hand-held electroporation device (TriGrid™ delivery system version 2.0 [TDS-IM v2.0]).</intervention_name>
    <description>The plan for this research study is for SCIB1 to be given for up to 85 weeks, in combination with pembrolizumab according to the current label.&#xD;
After receiving the first dose of SCIB1, the patient will receive SCIB1 at 4, 7, 13 and 25 weeks, then every 12 weeks up to Week 85. Pembrolizumab treatment will be started 1 week after the first dose of SCIB1 and given every 6 weeks.&#xD;
Pembrolizumab will be given by an infusion into the patient's vein. This normally takes about 30 minutes to complete.&#xD;
On each occasion, SCIB1 will be given by two injections into a muscle in a different limb, e.g. one into the upper arm and the other into the thigh. Instead of a normal needle and syringe, a small, hand-held electroporation device (TDS-IM v2.0) will be used to inject SCIB1 into the muscles.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCIB1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Electroporation device (TDS-IM v2.0).</intervention_name>
    <description>The small, hand-held electroporation device (TDS-IM v2.0) that will be used to administer SCIB1 for up to 85 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCIB1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has histologically confirmed, unresectable Stage III or Stage IV melanoma as&#xD;
             defined by the American Joint Committee on Cancer (8th Edition; Gershenwald et al&#xD;
             2017).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has not received prior systemic treatment for advanced disease. Prior adjuvant&#xD;
             treatment, defined as treatment following resection of all detectable disease, is&#xD;
             permitted; last dose must be at least 4 weeks before the first dose of SCIB1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has been clinically evaluated and pembrolizumab has been determined to be an&#xD;
             appropriate treatment for their advanced disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's BRAF status must be known; patients with BRAF mutation positive disease may&#xD;
             be enrolled without BRAF inhibitor treatment at the discretion of the Investigator,&#xD;
             provided that they have no evidence of rapidly progressing disease (LDH above normal&#xD;
             range, clinically significant tumor-related symptoms).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has at least one measurable lesion per RECIST 1.1 criteria by CT scan or MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has an archival (&lt; 5 years of age) or fresh biopsy sample of tumor available&#xD;
             for analysis of programmed death-ligand 1 (PD-L1) expression.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is human leukocyte antigen (HLA)-A2 positive.[*]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is positive for HLA-DR4, HLA-DR7, HLA-DR53 or HLA-DQ6.[*]&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is at least 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a life expectancy of more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has an ECOG performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has adequate organ function as determined by protocol laboratory values.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be able and willing to provide written Institutional Review&#xD;
             Board/Research Ethics Committee (IRB/REC) approved informed consent prior to any study&#xD;
             related procedure. (In the event that the patient is re-screened for study&#xD;
             participation or if a protocol amendment alters the care of an ongoing patient, a new&#xD;
             IRB/REC-approved informed consent form must be signed.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential (including women ≤ 12 months from last menstrual&#xD;
             period) must have a negative serum pregnancy test during Screening (within the 72&#xD;
             hours before planned administration of the first dose of study drug on Day 1) and be&#xD;
             neither breastfeeding nor intending to become pregnant during study participation, and&#xD;
             shall be warned of potential fetal harm from pembrolizumab. Women of child-bearing&#xD;
             potential must agree to use highly effective contraceptive methods prior to study&#xD;
             entry, for the whole duration of study treatment, and for 120 days after&#xD;
             discontinuation of SCIB1 or pembrolizumab, whichever is last.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men who are potentially fertile with partners of childbearing potential must agree to&#xD;
             use highly effective contraceptive methods for the whole duration of study treatment&#xD;
             and for 120 days after discontinuation of SCIB1 or pembrolizumab, whichever is last.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be willing and able to comply with scheduled visits, treatment plan,&#xD;
             laboratory tests and other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        [*] HLA testing will be conducted at accredited laboratories by molecular (DNA) typing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a diagnosis of uveal or ocular melanoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has active central nervous system metastases or carcinomatous meningitis&#xD;
             (patients with a response to previous treatment for brain metastases are eligible&#xD;
             provided that they are stable without MRI evidence of progression for at least 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to the first dose of study treatment, and systemic steroids have been withdrawn&#xD;
             for at least 2 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has previously received a treatment to block cytotoxic T lymphocyte associated&#xD;
             protein 4, programmed cell death protein 1, PD-L1, or programmed death-ligand 2 with&#xD;
             the following exception: patients who have received adjuvant treatment with these&#xD;
             treatments are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is expected to require any other form of systemic or localized antineoplastic&#xD;
             therapy while on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is taking any systemic steroid therapy within 1 week of the first dose of&#xD;
             study drug or is receiving any other form of immune suppressant medication.&#xD;
             Physiological doses of systemic steroids such as those for the management of adrenal&#xD;
             insufficiency, and topical and inhaled steroids, such as those for the management of&#xD;
             asthma, are permitted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is receiving treatment with any investigational product within 28 days (or 5&#xD;
             half-lives of the treatment concerned) prior to the first dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a previous (within 5 years) or current malignancy with the exception of&#xD;
             melanoma, and curatively treated local tumors such as carcinoma-in-situ of the breast,&#xD;
             cervix, basal or squamous cell carcinoma of the skin, prostate cancer with Gleason&#xD;
             grade &lt; 6 and prostate-specific antigen within normal range.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a concurrent illness which would preclude study conduct and assessment,&#xD;
             including, but not limited to uncontrolled medical conditions, uncontrolled and active&#xD;
             infection (considered opportunistic, life threatening, or clinically significant),&#xD;
             uncontrolled risk of bleeding, or uncontrolled diabetes mellitus, or pulmonary disease&#xD;
             (including obstructive pulmonary disease, pulmonary fibrosis, and history of&#xD;
             symptomatic bronchospasm), or alcoholic liver disease, or primary biliary cirrhosis.&#xD;
             Caution should be used for patients with suspected or diagnosed epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has any electronic stimulation device that cannot be removed during the&#xD;
             administration procedure, such as cardiac demand pacemaker, automatic implantable&#xD;
             cardiac defibrillator, nerve stimulator or deep brain stimulator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a skin-fold measurement of the cutaneous and subcutaneous tissue for all&#xD;
             eligible injection sites (deltoid or quadriceps muscles with intact lymph drainage)&#xD;
             that is &gt; 50 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has New York Heart Association class III or IV heart disease, myocardial&#xD;
             infarction within previous 6 months, a heart rate of ≤ 50 beats per minute, a history&#xD;
             of significant cardiac abnormality and/or clinically significant abnormal baseline ECG&#xD;
             reading, active ischemia, or any other uncontrolled cardiac condition such as angina&#xD;
             pectoris, clinically significant arrhythmia requiring therapy including&#xD;
             anticoagulants, uncontrolled hypertension (&gt; 140/90 mm Hg), significant&#xD;
             cerebrovascular disease, or congestive heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a history of severe hypersensitivity reaction to treatment with a&#xD;
             monoclonal antibody.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has an active autoimmune disease or a documented history of autoimmune disease&#xD;
             or syndrome that requires systemic steroids or immunosuppressive agents (patients with&#xD;
             vitiligo or resolved childhood asthma/atopy are an exception and are not excluded for&#xD;
             these conditions). The following patients are not excluded from the study: patients&#xD;
             who require intermittent use of bronchodilators or local steroid injections, patients&#xD;
             with hypothyroidism stable on hormone replacement, and patients who receive&#xD;
             physiological doses of steroids as replacement therapy, such as those for the&#xD;
             management of adrenal insufficiency. In such cases the recruiting investigator should&#xD;
             discuss the patients' eligibility with the study Medical Monitor prior to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received a vaccine within the 28 days prior to first dose of study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a known history of human immunodeficiency virus or has any positive test&#xD;
             for hepatitis B virus or hepatitis C virus indicating active acute or chronic&#xD;
             infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a known current or recent history (within the last year) of substance&#xD;
             abuse including illicit drugs or alcohol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Poulam Patel</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Nottingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robert Miller</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0)1865 582 690</phone>
    <email>info@scancell.co.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Velindre University NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cardiff</city>
        <zip>CF14 2TL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Satish Kumar, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Satish Kumar, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>East and North Hertfordshire NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Northwood</city>
        <zip>HA6 2RN</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Heather Shaw, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Heather Shaw, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nottingham University Hospitals NHS Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nottingham</city>
        <zip>NG5 1PB</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Poulam M Patel, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+44 115 8231850</phone>
      <email>poulam.patel@nottingham.ac.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Poulam M Patel, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Oxford University Hospital NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Oxford</city>
        <zip>OX3 7LE</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Miranda Payne, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Miranda Payne, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 16, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 2, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 6, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is not a plan to make IPD available.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

