<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02454751</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CTA/2014/002</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02454751</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Use of Intranasal Fentanyl for the Treatment of Incident Dyspnea in Congestive Heart Failure: A Prospective Trial</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Use of Intranasal Fentanyl for the Treatment of Incident Dyspnea in Congestive Heart Failure: A Prospective Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Boniface Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Boniface Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study Objective The primary object of this study is to investigate the safety and&#xD;
      effectiveness of fentanyl on the management of incident dyspnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design The study design will be a cross over study with a minimum of a one hour wash&#xD;
      out period.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Clinical question and hypothesis In patients with congestive heart failure who experience&#xD;
      episodic activity-induced dyspnea (incident dyspnea), will the administration of intranasal&#xD;
      fentanyl pre-activity result in subjective improvement in dyspnea and objective improvement&#xD;
      in functional capacity? Will there be side effects from this treatment?&#xD;
&#xD;
      We expect that pre-activity treatment with intranasal fentanyl will result in both subjective&#xD;
      improvements in dyspnea ratings as well as an increased measurement of functional capacity.&#xD;
      We also suspect that this treatment will not increase the patient's experienced side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Objective The primary object of this study is to investigate the safety and&#xD;
      effectiveness of fentanyl on the management of incident dyspnea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design The study design will be a cross over study with a minimum of a one hour wash&#xD;
      out period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in this study will be for 2 hours over 1-2 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Endpoints&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Walking distance from the 6MWT&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Endpoints&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subjective rating of dyspnea and side effects&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Heart rate, respiratory rate, oxygen saturation and participants' general appearance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size We hope to study 20 patients. Given the paucity of data so far, it is not&#xD;
      possible to statistically calculate the appropriate power for this study and 20 patients is&#xD;
      an approximation based on clinical experience.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is not enough data available currently for our statistician to find a power calculation&#xD;
      that eliminates type 1 and 2 error. Based on anecdotal evidence and experience with this&#xD;
      medication in the clinical setting, we have estimated that the number needed to determine a&#xD;
      clinically relevant difference is likely around 20.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient Population We will study the application of fentanyl in patients ages 18 or older, of&#xD;
      either gender, with either a diagnosis of NYHA Class 3 or 4 heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients must be experiencing activity-induced incident dyspnea without reversible&#xD;
           causes. They would have controlled background dyspnea without opioids.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients must be physically able to safely ambulate in order to complete the 6MWT (may&#xD;
           have mobility devices and may use supplement oxygen prescribed pre-study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients who are unable to perform the 6MWT for any reason or have contraindications to&#xD;
           performing the 6MWT&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients that have anatomical pathologies that would make intranasal administration&#xD;
           impossible&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with known allergies/sensitivities to fentanyl/sufentanil&#xD;
&#xD;
      Withdrawal Criteria Participants may voluntarily withdraw from the study at any time they&#xD;
      feel uncomfortable with the protocol. They will also be withdrawn if they experience chest&#xD;
      pain, palpitations, syncope, presyncope, or worsening dyspnea. Objectively, they will be&#xD;
      withdrawn if blood pressure drops below 90/50, heart rate drops below 60 or rises above 100,&#xD;
      if oxygen saturation drops below 90%, or if respiratory rate drops below 8 or rises above 20.&#xD;
      If any of: oxygen saturation, blood pressure, or respiratory rate drop below the cut off&#xD;
      point and do not recover within 5 min of rest, the antidote, Naloxone will be administered&#xD;
      with a subcutaneous injection. The trial may be stopped early if the treatment arm&#xD;
      statistically demonstrates superiority or increased harm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment of Subjects All patients will do the walk test with and without and fentanyl. They&#xD;
      will be instructed to continue any current medications that have been previously prescribed&#xD;
      and to not make any changes to their medications. Should they be on any medications for&#xD;
      dyspnea such as diuretics, bronchodilators, inhaled steroids, continuous oxygen, opioids&#xD;
      etc., they are to be continued.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before the first walk test, the patient will be asked to rate their baseline dyspnea,&#xD;
      somnolence, anxiety, pain and nausea using the ESAS VAS scale. The research team will record&#xD;
      baseline heart rate, respiratory rate, oxygen saturation and describe the patient's general&#xD;
      appearance. The patient will complete the 6MWT under appropriate supervision from our&#xD;
      research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research team will re-measure the study patient's heart rate, respiratory rate, oxygen&#xD;
      saturation and describe their general appearance for comparison to baseline. Any other&#xD;
      adverse effects or symptoms will be recorded. These measures will be repeated at 10 minutes&#xD;
      and 20 minutes post-6MWT to document any resolution of symptoms post activity. Following the&#xD;
      6MWT, treatment for dyspnea will be provided if required. The patient will also rerate their&#xD;
      dyspnea, somnolence, anxiety, pain and nausea using the ESAS VAS scale for an objective&#xD;
      measure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After a minimum of 1 hour (wash out period), they will proceed to the second phase of the&#xD;
      test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the second phase, the patient will once again be asked to rate their baseline dyspnea,&#xD;
      somnolence, anxiety pain and nausea using the ESAS VAS scale. This is to ensure consistency&#xD;
      among their baseline measures. The research team will record their objective measures as&#xD;
      stated above. The patients will then be given the fentanyl treatment and the 6MWT will be&#xD;
      repeated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients would be administered a spray of 50mcg of fentanyl intranasally as suggested as the&#xD;
      first titration step outlined in the Incident Pain and Dyspnea protocol, developed by the&#xD;
      Winnipeg Regional Health Authority Palliative Care Program&#xD;
      (http://palliative.info/IncidentPain.htm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following the 6MWT, the patient will again be asked to rate their baseline dyspnea,&#xD;
      somnolence, anxiety and nausea using the ESAS VAS scale. The research team will complete and&#xD;
      record objective measurements. As in phase 1 these measures will be repeated at 10 minutes&#xD;
      and 20 minutes post-6MWT to document any resolution of symptoms post activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of Efficacy By collecting data at the time points described above, we will be able&#xD;
      to compare the averaged baseline symptoms with exertion induced symptoms. Most importantly,&#xD;
      the data will allow us to compare the difference in subjective symptoms between&#xD;
      pre-exertional treatment with intranasal fentanyl with symptoms without pre-exertional&#xD;
      treatment. Using the 6MWT, we would be able to objectively assess any change in the study&#xD;
      patient's walking distance, which would represent a change in their functional capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of Safety Patients will be monitored with a subjective symptom assessment scale&#xD;
      (ESAS) and also with vital sign monitoring. If adverse events occur, the patients will be&#xD;
      monitored by the research nurse with vitals signs taken every 5 minutes until the patient&#xD;
      settles. If the patient does not settle within 5 minutes, as evidenced by an improvement in&#xD;
      vital signs and/or subjective report, the research nurse will determine whether naloxone&#xD;
      should be administered. If naloxone is not indicated, or the patient does not improve with&#xD;
      the administration of naloxone, the research nurse will report the patient's condition to the&#xD;
      patients primary nurse in charge of his/her care on the ward. The research nurse will further&#xD;
      assist the primary nurse in providing standard medical care to the participant as necessary.&#xD;
      If naloxone is administered, the research nurse will inform the primary ward nurse and will&#xD;
      continue to monitor the patient with vital signs every 5 min for an hour. After an hour has&#xD;
      elapsed, it is anticipated the study medication will have cleared from the participants body,&#xD;
      and any unresolved adverse effects will be managed according to standard medical practice by&#xD;
      the ward doctors and nurses. All adverse events will be documented. All serious adverse&#xD;
      events (representing a significant health hazard to the participant) will be reviewed by the&#xD;
      medical monitor and reported to the sponsor and the University of Manitoba Research Ethics&#xD;
      Board and Health Canada accordingly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis Comparison of subjective rank data (non-parametric) between phase 1 and&#xD;
      phase 2 will be analyzed using the Wilcoxin rank sum test. Comparison of objective numerical&#xD;
      data (parametric) between phase 1 and 2 will be analyzed using paired t-tests. The 6MWT&#xD;
      interpretation will include both absolute differences and percentage differences.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 15, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 30, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Walking distance from the 6MWT</measure>
    <time_frame>6 min</time_frame>
    <description>meters walked</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective rating of dyspnea and side effects (Edmonton Symptom Assessment Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min Day 2 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min</time_frame>
    <description>Edmonton Symptom Assessment Scale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>respiratory rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min Day 2 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min</time_frame>
    <description>respirations in 1 minute</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min Day 2 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min</time_frame>
    <description>heart beats in 1 minute</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min Day 2 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min</time_frame>
    <description>oxygen saturation as determined by oxygen saturation monitor</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min Day 2 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min</time_frame>
    <description>mmHg</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>general appearance (nurses subjective description)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min Day 2 - at time 0, 10 and 20 min</time_frame>
    <description>nurses subjective description of patient dyspnea, color, sweating and voiced or unvoiced expressions of distress</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">8</enrollment>
  <condition>Dyspnea</condition>
  <condition>Congestive Heart Failure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pre-fentanyl dose/fentanyl dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Crossover: 6-six minute walk test, subjective rating of dyspnea, heart rate, respiratory rate, oxygen saturation and participants' general appearance measured before and after a dose of fentanyl.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>fentanyl</intervention_name>
    <description>One time dose of 50mcg of fentanyl administered intranasally</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pre-fentanyl dose/fentanyl dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>sublimaze</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be experiencing activity-induced incident dyspnea without reversible&#xD;
             causes. They would have controlled background dyspnea without opioids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be physically able to safely ambulate in order to complete the 6MWT (may&#xD;
             have mobility devices and may use supplement oxygen prescribed pre-study).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are unable to perform the 6MWT for any reason or have contraindications&#xD;
             to performing the 6MWT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that have anatomical pathologies that would make intranasal administration&#xD;
             impossible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known allergies/sensitivities to fentanyl/sufentanil&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jana Pilkey, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>St. Boniface Hosptial</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Boniface General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Winnipeg</city>
        <state>Manitoba</state>
        <zip>R2H 2A6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 19, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 26, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 27, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 26, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 26, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>St. Boniface Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Jana Pilkey</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyspnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fentanyl</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

