<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01049204</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SSAT 030</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>EudraCT No. 2008-006769-95</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01049204</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Maraviroc on the Immune Function in HIV-1 Infected Subjects Receiving Immunisation With Novel Antigens</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomised, Placebo Controlled, Phase IV, Safety and Exploratory Immunogenicity Study on Maraviroc, an Oral ART CCR5 Inhibitor, on the Intensification of Immune Function in HIV-1 Infected Subjects Receiving Immunisation With Novel Antigens</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St Stephens Aids Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St Stephens Aids Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Impact of Maraviroc, a ART CCR5 inhibitor, on the intensification of immune function in HIV-1&#xD;
      infected subjects receiving immunisation with novel antigens&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study is to investigate the impact of adding Maraviroc (an anti-HIV agent)&#xD;
      to a participant's normal HIV medication, on immune function. As part of the study&#xD;
      participants will also receive three different vaccinations and a skin test. The study will&#xD;
      also look at whether Maraviroc influences the body's response to these.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The vaccines are given to stimulate the body's immune system, so we can therefore evaluate&#xD;
      the impact that Maraviroc has on this.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The duration of the study will be just over 24 weeks plus a screening period up to 4 weeks&#xD;
      prior to the start of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Maraviroc is a CCR5 antagonist with potent anti-HIV-1 activity, demonstrated in both&#xD;
      treatment naïve and experienced settings. Binding of maraviroc to CCR5 leads to the loss of&#xD;
      receptor function. Individuals with non-functioning CCR5 due to a 32 base pair deletion in&#xD;
      the encoding gene are observed at a 1% frequency in the northern European Caucasian&#xD;
      population. These individuals have near normal immune function, although differential&#xD;
      response to renal transplant and West Nile virus have been reported relative to individuals&#xD;
      with functional CCR5. The modest impact on immune function is indicative of a functional&#xD;
      overlap between CCR5 and other CC chemokine receptors. While the precise role of CCR5 has not&#xD;
      been established, data suggest a role in chemotaxis and inflammation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An excess of clinical events, infective, inflammatory or malignant, have not been reported in&#xD;
      persons receiving maraviroc relative to placebo or to efavirenz-based antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
      over 48 weeks follow-up. Indeed, individuals randomized to maraviroc were noted in these&#xD;
      studies to have modestly greater increases in CD4 T-cell numbers, not accounted for by&#xD;
      changes in lymphocyte counts or rates of viral suppression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The impact of inclusion of maraviroc in an antiretroviral treatment regimen on immune&#xD;
      function has not been reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In chronically infected HIV-1+ individuals who progress to AIDS, the full functionality of&#xD;
      the anti-HIV-1 CD8+ cytotoxic T lymphocyte response is progressively lost. This is&#xD;
      accompanied by diminished responses to neo- and recall antigens and skin anergy (loss of DTH&#xD;
      response). This is likely dependent on the loss of function and numbers of HIV-1-specific&#xD;
      CD4+ helper T lymphocytes (Appay and Sauce 2008). This process is apparently, at least&#xD;
      partially, irreversible despite otherwise successful, currently used antiretroviral drug&#xD;
      regimens. Accumulation of functionally inert ('anergic') HIV-1-specific CD4+ and CD8+ CD28-&#xD;
      CTLA-4hi T cells is observed, which lack proliferative and IL-2 producing ability and&#xD;
      cytolytic function despite maintaining the capacity to produce IFN-γ (Deeks and Walker 2007).&#xD;
      A balanced response in which the host responds appropriately to prevalent antigen, such as&#xD;
      HIV-1 Gag, yet remains relatively quiescent, may prove to be the strongest functional&#xD;
      correlate of virologic control (Imami et al. 2002; Imami et al. 2007).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent work has shown that tetanus antibody responses are significantly impaired in HIV&#xD;
      patients on successful ART (Hart et al. 2007). A recently identified CD4 T-cell subset, known&#xD;
      as follicular T cells (TFH) plays a crucial role in the development of humoral immune&#xD;
      responses to protein antigens such as tetanus toxoid (King et al. 2008). Follicular CD4 T&#xD;
      cells express a chemokine receptor called CXCR5, a protein called inducible co-stimulatory&#xD;
      factor (ICOS) and are readily identified in peripheral blood. Follicular CD4 T cells are&#xD;
      prone to activation induced cell death which is believed to be a major mechanism of CD4&#xD;
      T-cell depletion in chronic HIV-1 infection and therefore could be a vulnerable target in&#xD;
      retroviral disease. A reduction in circulating CD4 TFH numbers and/or function may account&#xD;
      for the failure of HIV-1 patients to respond to tetanus vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aims of this study are to investigate the impact of the addition of maraviroc to a&#xD;
      successful HIV-1 treatment regimen on in vitro (lymphoproliferative, ELISpot assays) and in&#xD;
      vivo (response to subcutaneous and GI administered vaccination by antibody and skin tests as&#xD;
      applicable) immune function, and to assess function of CD4 TFH cells by measuring cytokine&#xD;
      and co-stimulatory protein expression in this T-cell subset.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This 92 patient randomized, blinded placebo controlled trial plans to investigate the impact&#xD;
      of the addition of maraviroc to on-going successful PI/r based ART, with regards to multiple&#xD;
      immunology markers including markers of activation, CD4 and CD8 T-cell subsets, immune&#xD;
      function (Elispot and lymphoproliferative responses to HIV-1 and recall antigens and/or&#xD;
      peptides (Gag, TTox, CMV), and antibody response to oral (cholera) and deep subcutaneous/IM&#xD;
      (meningococcus) neoantigens and recall antigens (Tetanus toxoid)) and to assess function of&#xD;
      CD4 TFH cells by measuring cytokine and co-stimulatory protein expression in this subset.&#xD;
      Delayed type hypersensitivity will be tested at baseline and week 24, and read 48 hours post&#xD;
      administration of the Mantoux test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be stratified by CD4 nadir, with 50% of patients having a CD4 nadir &lt;200&#xD;
      cells/µl blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Maraviroc will be administered to patients at a dose level of 150mg BID. This dose is&#xD;
      approved for use in the UK.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    The data from the first 48 patients recruited has now been analysed, and it has been determined&#xD;
    that it is sufficient to meet the study objectives.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>July 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in tetanus antibody titres following vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in composite lymphocyte proliferation responses by group</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CD4 and CD8 subsets, activation and co-stimulation markers, plasma RNA viral load (pVL)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Response to oral and subcutaneous neoantigens and recall antigens</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Influence on CCR5 antagonism on CD4 follicular T-cell counts and function</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">48</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nadir CD4 count &gt;200 cells/µl blood and randomised to Maraviroc 150mg BD</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nadir CD4 count &gt;200 cells/µl blood and randomised to placebo twice daily for 24 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nadir CD4 count ≤200 cells/µl blood and randomised to Maraviroc 150mg BD</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Nadir CD4 count ≤200 cells/µl blood and randomised to placebo twice daily for 24 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Maraviroc</intervention_name>
    <description>Maraviroc 150 mg twice daily for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 3</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Celsentri</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo twice daily for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group 4</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV-1 antibody positive&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  On a virologically suppressive regimen for at least 24 weeks and stable on a PI/r&#xD;
             (ATV, LPV or DRV) plus Truvada or Kivexa for at least 4 weeks prior to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current HIV-1 RNA &lt;50cps/ml plasma on 2 occasions &gt;4 weeks apart&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior CCR5 or CXCR4 antagonist use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior tetanus toxoid immunisation or known tetanus antibodies. Immunisation must have&#xD;
             taken place in the past 10 years, but not within 1 month of baseline visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known CD4 nadir&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the subject is a woman of child bearing potential, she must agree to use a double&#xD;
             barrier method of contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior immunologically active agents (use of IL-2, GH or GHRH,&#xD;
             corticosteroids (except inhaled), G- and GM-CSF) deemed to potentially impact study&#xD;
             results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of HIV, cholera or meningococcal immunisation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other known immune deficiency or use of immune suppressant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of malignancy (except low volume Kaposi's sarcoma) or chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to maraviroc&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peanut or soya allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antiretroviral agents other than those in inclusion list&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drugs known to reduce exposure to maraviroc (CYP3A inducers)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to vaccines or vaccine components and/or components of skin test kits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating or planning to become pregnant during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute feverish, stomach or intestinal illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received an investigational medicinal product as part of a clinical trial within the&#xD;
             last 30 days&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Graeme Moyle</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>St Stephen's AIDS Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Stephen's Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>London</city>
        <zip>SW10 9NH</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 13, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 14, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 31, 2011</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 31, 2011</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 1, 2011</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HIV</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV-1 Infections</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>HIV Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Maraviroc</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

