<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03089567</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SMAHEN</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03089567</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Comparison of the Salivary Levels of Streptococcus Mutans in Pediatric Patients With Early Childhood Caries After the Application of Silver Diamine Fluoride or 5% Sodium Fluoride Varnish</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparison of the Salivary Levels of Streptococcus Mutans in Pediatric Patients With Early Childhood Caries After the Application of Silver Diamine Fluoride or 5% Sodium Fluoride Varnish</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Comparison of the salivary levels of Streptococcus mutans in pediatric patients with Early&#xD;
      Childhood Caries after the application of Silver Diamine Fluoride or 5% Sodium Fluoride&#xD;
      Varnish&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Dental caries is the most common chronic disease in children (Benjamin, 2010). Studies&#xD;
      suggest there is a positive correlation between bacterial titers of Streptococcus mutans and&#xD;
      dental caries (Pannu et. al., 2013). National surveys suggest children 2 to 5 years old have&#xD;
      27.90% of primary teeth with caries. This number near doubles to 51.17% for children 6 to 11&#xD;
      years old (United States, National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, 1999-2004). The&#xD;
      American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry discusses this prevalence, in particular the finding&#xD;
      of caries in young children, calling it early childhood caries (ECC), defined as &quot;the&#xD;
      presence of 1 or more decayed (noncavitated or cavitated lesions), missing (due to caries),&#xD;
      or filled tooth surfaces in any primary tooth in a child 71 months of age or younger&quot; or&#xD;
      severe early childhood caries (S-ECC), defined as any sign of smooth surface caries in&#xD;
      children younger than three years of age (AAPD, 2008). Oral health disparities also vary by&#xD;
      race, ethnicity and socioeconomic status. Among children ages 3-5 years old, the prevalence&#xD;
      of dental caries was significantly higher for non-Hispanic black individuals, 19%, compared&#xD;
      to non-Hispanic white individuals, 11%. Furthermore, the prevalence of dental caries was&#xD;
      nearly twice as high for Hispanic individuals, 26%, compared to non-Hispanic white&#xD;
      individuals (Dye et. al., 2012).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of fluoride in dentistry has played a significant role in reducing the prevalence and&#xD;
      severity of dental caries. Water fluoridation is considered to be one of the ten greatest&#xD;
      achievements in public health of the twentieth century (CDC, 1999). Sodium Fluoride (SF)&#xD;
      varnishes have become a mainstay in many pediatric dental practices. Despite their intended&#xD;
      use as desensitizing agents, fluoride varnishes are used routinely to inhibit the&#xD;
      demineralization of enamel, promote remineralization of enamel, and arrest early enamel&#xD;
      carious lesions (Chu et. al, 2008, CDC 2001). Fluoride also interferes with cariogenic&#xD;
      bacteria's ability to metabolize carbohydrates, reducing their acid production, and ability&#xD;
      to adhere to tooth surfaces, possibly reducing their ability to initiate decay (CDC, 2001).&#xD;
      The ability of fluoride, namely SF varnishes to effect bacterial counts of S. mutans has been&#xD;
      described in a limited extent in the literature. Chandak describes fluoride varnish's ability&#xD;
      to reduce S. mutans counts in dental plaque, suggesting another way fluoride aids in the&#xD;
      reduction on dental caries (Chandak et. al., 2016). However, other studies do not support SF&#xD;
      varnishes abilities to significantly reduce plaque S. mutans counts (Sajjan, et. al., 2013).&#xD;
      Other studies attempt to examine the effects of fluoride varnishes' ability to effect S.&#xD;
      mutans adherence and biofilm formation. In their study Chau et. al, described a reduction in&#xD;
      S. mutans adhesion and subsequent biofilm accumulation in the presence of a number of&#xD;
      commercially available SF varnishes (Chau et. al, 2014).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similar to fluoride compounds, the antimicrobial effects of silver containing compounds have&#xD;
      been used in dentistry for nearly a century. The mechanism behind these compounds'&#xD;
      antibacterial effect is derived from the bioactive silver ion's ability to disrupt and&#xD;
      irreversibly damage vital bacterial enzyme systems (Lansdown 2006). Despite their use&#xD;
      internationally since the early twentieth century, silver containing compounds have fallen&#xD;
      out of favor over time. More recently, silver diamine fluoride (SDF), currently approved by&#xD;
      the FDA for treatment of dentinal hypersensitivity, has been shown to possess caries&#xD;
      arresting properties. The clinical applications of SDF are seemly vast. Average operating&#xD;
      room (OR) wait times vary between providers and can range from days to months depending on&#xD;
      such factors as the provider's availability and resources, the patient's symptomatology,&#xD;
      medical history, and extent of treatment. The patient population served at the Yale-New Haven&#xD;
      Hospital Pediatric Dental Center is diverse both demographically and medically. Due to the&#xD;
      demand and need for comprehensive dental treatment under general anesthesia, average OR wait&#xD;
      times are 4 to 6 months. Indications for OR treatment include medically complex patients,&#xD;
      uncooperative or pre-cooperative behavior profiles, patients with extensive and&#xD;
      multi-quadrant decay patterns, and patients who do not meet selection criteria for sedation&#xD;
      modalities. SDF's ability to arrest dental decay allows for patients on lengthy wait list&#xD;
      awaiting treatment in the OR to avoid having their caries progress significantly. SDF is not&#xD;
      a solution to caries; however it can be a useful tool in stemming the progression of decay&#xD;
      for children awaiting surgical intervention under general anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In light of SDF's ability to arrest dental caries, there is a question about its ability to&#xD;
      impact the etiology of caries initiation, namely its effect on salivary S. mutans counts in&#xD;
      the oral cavity. Few studies have investigated SDF's ability to alter bacterial counts in the&#xD;
      oral environment in children. The application of SDF to human dentin blocks resulted in the&#xD;
      development of fewer colony forming units of a number of cariogenic bacteria, including S.&#xD;
      mutans, compared to the control group (Mei, 2013). Similar results were described in a study&#xD;
      examining the effect of silver fluoride on S. mutans biofilm formation (Knight et. al.,&#xD;
      2009). The impact of such an effect would be profound and could change caries management and&#xD;
      prevention in the pediatric population (Duangthip, Chu et. al. 2016).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The increased interest and popularity of SDF has the potential to change the manner in which&#xD;
      dental caries are treated in the pediatric population. Applications can prevent more invasive&#xD;
      and costly need for general anesthesia, or other advanced behavior management techniques, or&#xD;
      possibly prevent the progression of decay and avoid the loss of teeth (Chu, 2000).&#xD;
      Furthermore, the potential ability of SDF to affect the bacterial composition of the oral&#xD;
      environment, possibly reducing the initiation of caries has the exciting potential to be a&#xD;
      ground breaking public health achievement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Application of SDF on carious teeth will show a higher decrease the salivary bacterial counts&#xD;
      of S. mutans form baseline in 2-6 years old patients with ECC when compared to S. mutans&#xD;
      levels after sodium fluoride varnish application and no treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preliminary Research Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient selection: Healthy 2-6 years old patients with ECC awaiting comprehensive dental&#xD;
      treatment under general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria: ASA I without prior history of dental restorations&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria: Patient with: special healthcare needs, xerostomia, complicated medical&#xD;
      history (ASA II-VI)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Experimental Groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  30 Patients that will receive 38% SDF application&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  30 Patients that will receive 5% NaF varnish application&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  30 Patient in Control group that will receive no treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Salivary collection: Salivary samples will be collected with SalivaBio Children's Swab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A baseline S. mutans level will be obtained and quantified using Saliva-Check Mutans (GC&#xD;
      America).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All carious teeth will receive a rubber cup and paste dental prophylaxis followed by either a&#xD;
      topical application of 38% SDF, or 5% NaF varnish or no topical treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow up: Further measurement of S. mutans levels will be obtained at 1, 3, 6 months after&#xD;
      initial SDF, NaF varnish applications no treatment, without dental prophylaxis. Following&#xD;
      salivary sample collections, re-application of SDF and NaF varnish will be applied to&#xD;
      appropriate patient groups, and no further treatment provided to control group.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study was not conducted. No participants were enrolled&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 15, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 15, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 15, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Salivary levels of Streptococcus mutans</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary samples will be obtained with Children's Swab (SalivaBio) and S. Mutans level will be measured using Saliva-Check Mutans (GC America)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Salivary levels of Streptococcus mutans</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary samples will be obtained with Children's Swab (SalivaBio) and S. Mutans level will be measured using Saliva-Check Mutans (GC America)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Salivary levels of Streptococcus mutans</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary samples will be obtained with Children's Swab (SalivaBio) and S. Mutans level will be measured using Saliva-Check Mutans (GC America)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Salivary levels of Streptococcus mutans</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Salivary samples will be obtained with Children's Swab (SalivaBio) and S. Mutans level will be measured using Saliva-Check Mutans (GC America)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Caries</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CONTROL GROUP</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients waiting for treatment under general Anesthesia without any intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sodium Fluoride Varnish</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Sodium Fluoride Varnish will be applied at 0,1,3 months Follow ups while waiting to receive dental treatment under general anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Silver Diamine Fluoride</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Silver Diamine Fluoride will be applied at 0,1,3 months Follow ups while waiting to receive dental treatment under general anesthesia</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sodium Fluoride</intervention_name>
    <description>5% Sodium Fluoride Varnish used for dental caries prevention and desensitizer</description>
    <arm_group_label>Sodium Fluoride Varnish</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Duraflor</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Silver diamine fluoride</intervention_name>
    <description>38% Silver Diamine Fluoride used for dental caries prevention and desensitizer</description>
    <arm_group_label>Silver Diamine Fluoride</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Advantage Arrest</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA I without prior history of dental restorations&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with: special healthcare needs, xerostomia, complicated medical history (ASA&#xD;
             II-VI)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>6 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Eunice Lee, DMD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale New Haven Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christel Haberland, DDS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale New Haven Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 20, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 21, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 23, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Silver diamine Fluoride</keyword>
  <keyword>Streptococcus mutans</keyword>
  <keyword>Caries prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Fluoride</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Listerine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fluorides</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sodium Fluoride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

