<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00427947</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9440-05</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2004-037</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00427947</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Leg Amputation and Continuous Sciatic Nerve Block</brief_title>
  <acronym>CAPDAF</acronym>
  <official_title>Continuous Popliteal Sciatic Nerve Block Interest in Postoperative Pain Management for Patients With Leg Amputation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Bordeaux</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Bordeaux</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Analgesia following leg amputation is based on morphine administration. For elderly patients&#xD;
      of ASA physical status 2 or 3, morphine sparing is possible when perinervous block techniques&#xD;
      are used. Phantom limb pain complicates leg amputation in 50 to 80% of cases. Prevention of&#xD;
      these pains has been studied in various clinical trials but the interest of perinervous block&#xD;
      technique remains to be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The purpose of the study is to evaluate the benefit of perioperative locoregional analgesia&#xD;
      by ropivacaine via a popliteal sciatic catheter on intravenous morphine consumption during&#xD;
      the 72 first postoperative hours following leg (below knee) amputation The study will be&#xD;
      randomized, double blinded, controlled clinical trial and 84 patients undergoing leg&#xD;
      amputation (below knee) will be included Patients will be divided into 2 groups: one group of&#xD;
      patients who will benefit perioperative locoregional analgesia by ropivacaine via a popliteal&#xD;
      sciatic catheter and morphine for analgesia and the other one who will benefit placebo&#xD;
      through the catheter and morphine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will evaluate the efficacy of the continuous popliteal sciatic nerve block&#xD;
      in postoperative analgesia after leg amputation and prove the efficacy of a perioperative&#xD;
      analgesia by continuous popliteal sciatic nerve block to prevent phantom limb pain after leg&#xD;
      amputation in patients of ASA physical status 2 or 3.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analgesia following leg amputation is based on morphine administration. For elderly patients&#xD;
      of ASA physical status 2 or 3, morphine sparing is possible when perinervous block techniques&#xD;
      are used. Indeed, per operative placement of a perinervous catheter by the surgeon allows a&#xD;
      morphine consumption decrease of about 30%. Nevertheless, the interest of a sciatic block&#xD;
      providing analgesia in the tibial and fibular territories has still to be assessed in this&#xD;
      indication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phantom limb pain complicates leg amputation in 50 to 80% of cases. Risk factors of this&#xD;
      complication are numerous, from central or peripheral origin. Phantom limb pain postpones&#xD;
      patients' social and professional rehabilitation, and results in an increased medical&#xD;
      consumption. Prevention of these pains has been studied in various clinical trials, and&#xD;
      results need confirmation. Thus, epidural analgesia alone does not decrease the long term&#xD;
      incidence of phantom limb pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary : To compare intravenous morphine consumption during the 72 first postoperative hours&#xD;
      following leg (below knee) amputation of patients randomly assigned in two groups. One group&#xD;
      benefit from perioperative locoregional analgesia by ropivacaine via a popliteal sciatic&#xD;
      catheter, the other group is given placebo through the catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess tolerance and adverse effects (myalgia, infection, adverse effects of local&#xD;
           anaesthetics) of the popliteal sciatic catheter during the 72 first postoperative hours&#xD;
           and on the 7th postoperative day, in patients with ASA physical status 2 or 3&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To compare tolerance and adverse effects of morphine during the protocol in the 2 groups&#xD;
           of patients&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the long term effects of the preoperative continuous popliteal sciatic nerve&#xD;
           block: incidence of stump pain and phantom limb pain, time of outbreak, intensity (VAS),&#xD;
           characteristics (French version of the McGill Pain Questionnaire and DN4 questionnaire),&#xD;
           and the analgesic consumption over a year.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess the possibility for the patients to use a prosthesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eighty four patients scheduled for leg amputation (below knee), randomly allocated in 2&#xD;
      groups of forty patients, according to the type of analgesia. Patients were enrolled in the&#xD;
      general and vascular surgery unit, CHU (University Hospital) Pellegrin Bordeaux.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomised clinical trial, with two parallel groups, with direct individual benefit,&#xD;
      double-blinded, realised on a population of patients undergoing leg amputation, comparing&#xD;
      different clinical parameters of postoperative pain evaluation, and outbreak of phantom limb&#xD;
      pain according to the group of analgesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  One group of patients with locoregional analgesia associated with morphine&#xD;
           administration (assessed treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  One group of patients with morphine analgesia only (reference treatment). Patients will&#xD;
           be followed for one year. This study will last 3 years in a general and vascular surgery&#xD;
           unit, inclusion will be realised during 34 months by anaesthetists and surgeons, an&#xD;
           extension of this study for one year will be done with the objective of a cohort&#xD;
           follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis will be done with intention to treat.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anticipated results:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To prove the efficacy of the continuous popliteal sciatic nerve block in postoperative&#xD;
      analgesia after leg amputation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To prove the efficacy of a perioperative analgesia by continuous popliteal sciatic nerve&#xD;
      block to prevent phantom limb pain after leg amputation in patients of ASA physical status 2&#xD;
      or 3.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    lack of patients&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>December 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2009</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Total intravenous morphine consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>during the first 72 postoperative hours following leg (below knee) amputation</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tolerance and adverse effects (myalgia, infection, adverse effects of local anaesthetics) of the popliteal sciatic catheter, in patients with ASA physical status 2 or 3</measure>
    <time_frame>during the 72 first postoperative hours and on the 7th postoperative day</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>tolerance and adverse effects of morphine during the protocol in the 2 groups of patients</measure>
    <time_frame>during the first 72 postoperative hours</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of stump pain and phantom limb pain, time of outbreak, intensity (VAS), characteristics (French version of the McGill Pain Questionnaire and DN4 qu</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 3, 6 and 12 months postoperative</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>use of prosthesis</measure>
    <time_frame>1, 3, 6 and 12 months postoperative</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">6</enrollment>
  <condition>Phantom Limb</condition>
  <condition>Leg Amputation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Continuous sciatic nerve bloc : ropivacaine infusion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Continuous sciatic nerve bloc : NaCl Infusion</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ropivacaine/placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Continuous sciatic nerve bloc</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients scheduled for leg amputation following arteritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA score: 2-3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent obtained from the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients involved in another clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-infection OR post traumatic leg amputation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Blood coagulation disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Local anesthetic, morphine, or paracetamol allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Local inflammatory signs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with protective supervision&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Karine NOUETTE GAULAIN, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Bordeaux, France</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Antoine BENARD, Dr</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>university hospital, Bordeaux, France</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Département d'anesthésie réanimation I, Hopital Pellegrin, CHU de Bordeaux</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bordeaux</city>
        <zip>33076</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 26, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 26, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 29, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 28, 2009</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 28, 2009</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 29, 2009</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Jean-Pierre LEROY / Clinical Research and Innovation Director</name_title>
    <organization>University Hospital, Bordeaux</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>phantom limb pain</keyword>
  <keyword>amputation</keyword>
  <keyword>anesthetics, local</keyword>
  <keyword>postoperative analgesia</keyword>
  <keyword>ropivacaine</keyword>
  <keyword>analgesia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Phantom Limb</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

