<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02911077</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>160162</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>16-CC-0162</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02911077</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Longitudinal Changes in the Oral and Gut Microbiome of Individuals With Alcohol Dependence</brief_title>
  <official_title>Longitudinal Changes in the Oral and Gut Microbiome of Individuals With Alcohol Dependence</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many bacteria live in the gut. The gut is the tube that moves food from the mouth through the&#xD;
      stomach to the intestines. Heavy alcohol use disturbs these bacteria. There is evidence that&#xD;
      the bacteria in the gut may affect anxiety and depression. Researchers want to learn more&#xD;
      about these bacteria in order to better treat diseases such as alcohol dependence.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To identify the different bacteria that live in the mouth and gut. Also, to learn if these&#xD;
      bacteria change as a person goes through alcohol detoxification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People ages 18 and older who:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Enrolled in screening protocol 14-AA-0181&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Are going through detoxification treatment at the Clinical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have physical exams.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will answer questions about:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Anxiety and depression&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Alcohol use&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Sleep&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Abdominal and oral health&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diet&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will keep a regular record of their diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have breath alcohol analysis 4 times per day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will provide stool and oral specimens at most once a day for the first week.&#xD;
      Then, they will provide them once a week while they are at the Clinical Center.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For the oral specimen: A small brush rubs the tongue. They may not eat, drink, or&#xD;
           perform oral care within 2 hours of collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  For the stool specimen: They will receive a container that fits in the toilet. They will&#xD;
           let the nurse know right away when the sample is ready.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a dental visit. This consists of an oral exam and oral health&#xD;
      assessment. The dentist may recommend a cleaning or dental X-rays.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The microbiome exists in a complex symbiotic relationship with its human host, the&#xD;
      characterization of which is imperative for understanding a myriad of diseases. Until&#xD;
      recently, much of gut microbiome research has focused on gastrointestinal disorders. Recent&#xD;
      research, however, has implicated the gut microbiome in psychological disorders as well&#xD;
      through a proposed gut-brain axis. Of particular interest is characterization of the&#xD;
      microbiome of individuals with severe alcohol use disorders, as alcohol has been known to&#xD;
      profoundly alter the gut microbiome. For many years, scientists have theorized a connection&#xD;
      between the proinflammatory mediators produced by ethanol consumption, liver disease and the&#xD;
      gut microbiome. This study represents the first instance in which the naturalistic time&#xD;
      course of changes in the gut microbiome will be followed in alcoholics in whom detailed&#xD;
      history of alcohol consumption and diet have been obtained. We hypothesize that the gut&#xD;
      microbiome will renormalize spontaneously and without specific intervention over a time frame&#xD;
      of one or two weeks. Alcoholic patients also suffer from serious oral hygiene problems&#xD;
      associated with alterations in oral microbial flora. We hypothesize that abnormalities in the&#xD;
      oral microbiome will be detectable on admission, and that these will also rapidly renormalize&#xD;
      with abstinence and resumption of ordinary diet and oral hygiene. If not, the findings in&#xD;
      this study could point to the need for other interventions, such as administration of&#xD;
      probiotics. Twenty evaluable participants admitted to the Clinical Center for alcohol&#xD;
      detoxification will be enrolled. All patients will be admitted under the Unit and Clinic&#xD;
      Evaluation, Screening, Assessment, and Management protocol (14-AA-0181), which includes&#xD;
      adults 18 years of age or older seeking treatment for severe alcohol use disorders. Oral&#xD;
      (tongue brushings) and gut (stool) specimens will be collected daily for the first week and&#xD;
      then once a week for 28 days. Demographic characteristics, detailed drinking and dietary&#xD;
      histories, measures of addiction severity, comorbid mental disorders, and metabolic&#xD;
      indicators of other disease will be collected for correlation with microbiological results.&#xD;
      Dietary records will include use of probiotics. Exclusion criteria include use of&#xD;
      antibiotics, corticosteroids or immunosuppressive agents within the past month. Informed&#xD;
      consent will be obtained after consent for the screening and treatment protocol (14-AA-0181)&#xD;
      and in accordance with policies protecting participants with impaired decision-making.&#xD;
      Microbial identification will include 16S rRNA analysis and a validated Next Generation&#xD;
      Sequencing analysis pipelines. Statistical comparisons between each patient's oral and gut&#xD;
      microbiome samples will be evaluated and all results from this population will also be&#xD;
      compared to published microbiomes in both healthy volunteers as well as existing data from&#xD;
      alcohol dependent individuals. Participants will be compensated for research-related&#xD;
      discomfort and inconveniences in accordance with NIH guidelines.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 27, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 29, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 29, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Identification of bacteria in the gut and oral microbiomes over time</measure>
    <time_frame>all timepoints</time_frame>
    <description>Characterization of the gut and oral micro biome</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">23</enrollment>
  <condition>Alcoholic Intoxication</condition>
  <condition>Alcohol-Related Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AUD population</arm_group_label>
    <description>The participants/group were treatment-seeking AUD individuals admitted to the NIH CC 1SE Addictions Unit.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        inpatient treatment seeking alcohol dependent participants&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consented on screening and research protocol 14-AA-0181&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admitted to the NIH CC for inpatient detoxification treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently using or have used any of the following drugs within the last month by&#xD;
             self-report:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Antibiotics&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corticosteroids: inhaled, oral, intravenous or intramuscular&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunosuppressive or cytotoxic agents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Large doses of probiotics such as supplemental probiotics (ordinary dietary components&#xD;
             such as beverages/milk or yogurt DO NOT APPLY)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery of the GI tract with the exclusion of cholecystectomy and appendectomy&#xD;
             in the past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any bowel resection at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of active uncontrolled gastrointestinal disorders or diseases including&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease, ulcerative colitis, Crohn s disease, and/or infectious&#xD;
             gastroenteritis, colitis, or gastritis (per patient s report of whether or not they&#xD;
             have been diagnosed by a physician).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Enrolled in any investigational study that might affect the microbiome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI greater than or equal to 30 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Some of these exclusionary criteria have been adapted from the Human Microbiome Project&#xD;
        [40]. All exclusion measures will be collected from self-report.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gwenyth R Wallen, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?B_2016-CC-0162.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 7, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 21, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 22, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Bacteria</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alcoholism</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcohol-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Alcoholic Intoxication</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

