<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02915172</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2016-0323</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02915172</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lenvatinib and Capecitabine in Patients With Advanced Malignancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Trial of Lenvatinib (Multi-kinase Inhibitor) and Capecitabine (Anti-metabolite) in Patients With Advanced Malignancies</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Eisai Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There are 2 phases in this study: Phase 1 (dose escalation) and Phase 2 (dose expansion).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of Phase 1 of this clinical research study is to find the highest tolerable dose of&#xD;
      lenvatinib and Xeloda (capecitabine) that can be given to patients with advanced cancer. The&#xD;
      goal of Phase 2 of this study is to learn if the dose of lenvatinib and capecitabine found in&#xD;
      Phase 1 can help to control advanced cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The safety of this drug combination will be studied in both phases of the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If participant is are found to be eligible to take part in this study, they will be assigned&#xD;
      to a study group based on when they join this study. Up to 4 groups of up to 18 participants&#xD;
      will be enrolled in Phase 1 of the study, and up to 28 participants will be enrolled in Phase&#xD;
      2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If participant is enrolled in Phase 1, the dose of lenvatinib they receive will depend on&#xD;
      when they join this study. The first group of participants will receive the lowest dose level&#xD;
      of lenvatinib. Each new group will receive a higher dose of lenvatinib than the group before&#xD;
      it, if no intolerable side effects were seen. This will continue until the highest tolerable&#xD;
      dose of lenvatinib is found.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If participant is enrolled in Phase 2, they will receive lenvatinib at the highest dose that&#xD;
      was tolerated in Phase 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will receive the same dose of capecitabine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Drug Administration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each study cycle is 21 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant will take lenvatinib by mouth every day and capecitabine by mouth 2 times every&#xD;
      day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Length of Study Participation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant may continue taking the study drugs for as long as the doctor thinks it is in&#xD;
      their best interest. Participant will no longer be able to take the study drugs if the&#xD;
      disease gets worse, if intolerable side effects occur, or if they are unable to follow study&#xD;
      directions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient's participation on the study will be over after the end-of-study visit (described&#xD;
      below).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Week 2 of Cycle 1:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 3 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If participant is enrolled in Phase 2, they will have a tumor biopsy for biomarker&#xD;
           testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If participant is enrolled in Phase 2, blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for&#xD;
           biomarker, CTC, and cfDNA testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Week 3 of Cycle 1, blood (about 3 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Week 1 of Cycles 2 and beyond:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 3 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If participant is enrolled in Phase 2, blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for&#xD;
           biomarker, CTC, and cfDNA testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If participant can become pregnant, blood (about 1 teaspoon) will be collected for a&#xD;
           pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Weeks 2 and 3 of Cycles 2 and beyond, participant will be called by a member of the&#xD;
      study staff and asked about any side effects they may have. This call should last about 5-10&#xD;
      minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During Week 3 of Cycle 2 and then every even-numbered cycle after that (Cycles 4, 6, 8, and&#xD;
      so on), participant will have a CT scan or MRI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End-of-Study Visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After participant's last dose of study drug, they will have an end-of-study visit. At this&#xD;
      visit, the following tests and procedures will be performed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 3 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participant will have a CT scan or MRI to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If participant can become pregnant, blood (about 1 teaspoon) or urine will be collected&#xD;
           for a pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If participant is enrolled in Phase 2, blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for&#xD;
           biomarker, CTC, and cfDNA testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an investigational study. Lenvatinib is FDA approved and commercially available for&#xD;
      the treatment of certain types of thyroid cancer. Capecitabine is FDA approved and&#xD;
      commercially available for the treatment of certain types of breast and colorectal cancers.&#xD;
      It is considered investigational to use lenvatinib and capecitabine to treat advanced cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study doctor can explain how the study drugs are designed to work.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 46 participants will be enrolled in this study. All will take part at MD Anderson.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2016</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD) of Combination Treatment with Lenvatinib and Capecitabine in Advanced and/or Metastatic Cancer Refractory to Standard Treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>MTD defined by dose limiting toxicities (DLTs) that occur in the first cycle. DLT defined as any clinically grade 3 or 4 non-hematologic toxicity as defined in the NCI CTC v4.0,</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Antitumor Efficacy of Combination of Lenvatinib and Capecitabine in Breast Cancer and Solid Tumors with FGFR Abnormality</measure>
    <time_frame>42 days</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy evaluation done using RECIST criteria version 1.1.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Advanced Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasm of Breast</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Bone and Articular Cartilage</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Digestive Organs</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Eye Brain and Other Parts of Central Nervous System</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Female Genital Organs</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Ill-defined Secondary and Unspecified Sites</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Independent (Primary) Multiple Sites</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Lip Oral Cavity and Pharynx</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Male Genital Organs</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Mesothelial and Soft Tissue</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Respiratory and Intrathoracic Organs</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Thyroid and Other Endocrine Glands</condition>
  <condition>Malignant Neoplasms of Urinary Tract</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib + Capecitabine</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Phase 1 Study Escalation: Group consists of participants with various solid tumors.&#xD;
Dose of Lenvatinib received depends on when joining study. First group of participants receive lowest dose level of Lenvatinib. Each new group receives a higher dose of Lenvatinib than the group before it, if no intolerable side effects were seen. This continues until highest tolerable dose of Lenvatinib found.&#xD;
All participants receive the same dose of Capecitabine.&#xD;
Phase 2 Study Expansion: Group consists of participants with advanced breast cancer and any solid tumors with confirmed FGFR abnormalities.&#xD;
Participants receive Lenvatinib at the highest dose that was tolerated in Dose Escalation Phase.&#xD;
All participants receive the same dose of Capecitabine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Lenvatinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Phase 1 Dose Escalation: Starting dose of Lenvatinib 10 mg by mouth once daily of a 21 day cycle.&#xD;
Phase 2 Dose Expansion: Starting dose of Lenvatinib is maximum tolerated dose from Phase 1.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib + Capecitabine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>E7080</other_name>
    <other_name>Lenvima</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Capecitabine</intervention_name>
    <description>Phase 1 Dose Escalation and Phase 2 Dose Expansion: Capecitabine 1000 mg/m2 twice daily by mouth on Days 1 - 14 of a 21 day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lenvatinib + Capecitabine</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Xeloda</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with a histologically and/or cytologically confirmed solid tumor who are&#xD;
             resistant / refractory to approved therapies or for whom no curative therapies are&#xD;
             available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. All previous treatment (including surgery, radiotherapy and systemic anti-neoplastic&#xD;
             therapy) must have been completed at least three weeks prior to study entry and any&#xD;
             acute toxicities must have resolved.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Aged &gt;/= 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status score of &lt;/= 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Written informed consent prior to any study specific screening procedures with the&#xD;
             understanding that the patient may withdraw consent at any time without prejudice.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing and able to comply with the protocol guidelines for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Unstable metastases to the central nervous system (CNS).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any of the following laboratory parameters: a) hemoglobin &lt; 9 g/dL (5.6 mmol/L); b)&#xD;
             neutrophils &lt;1.5 x 109/L; c) platelets &lt;100 x 109/L; d) serum bilirubin &gt;25 µmol/L&#xD;
             (1.5 mg/dL); e) liver function tests with values &gt;3 x upper limit of normal (ULN) f)&#xD;
             serum creatinine &gt;1.5 x ULN or creatinine clearance &lt; 60 mL/minute&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Positive history of HIV, active hepatitis B or active hepatitis C or&#xD;
             severe/uncontrolled intercurrent illness or infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Centrally located non-small cell lung cancers and squamous cell lung cancers&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinically significant cardiac impairment or unstable ischemic heart disease including&#xD;
             a myocardial infarction within six months of study start&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with marked Baseline prolongation of QT/QTc interval (QTc interval &gt; 450 msec&#xD;
             for males or &gt; 470 msec for females) using the Fridericia method for QTc analysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Bleeding or thrombotic disorders, or using therapeutic dosages of anticoagulants, such&#xD;
             as warfarin. Occasional use of NSAIDs and antiplatelet agents such as aspirin,&#xD;
             clopidogrel, aggrenox and dipyridamole are not considered exclusionary if taken &lt;7&#xD;
             days per 28 days. However, if the patient requires chronic use (&gt;/=7 days out of 28&#xD;
             days) of full doses of aspirin or NSAIDs then the patient is excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Requirement for chronic use of full dose aspirin or non-steroidal anti-inflammatory&#xD;
             drugs (NSAIDs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Poorly controlled hypertension (defined as requiring changes in any hypertensive&#xD;
             regimen within 1 week of study entry) or patients diagnosed with hypertension based on&#xD;
             repeat blood pressure measurements of &gt;160/90 mmHg at Screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Proteinuria &gt; 1+ on urine dipstick testing or 30 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. A history of gastrointestinal malabsorption or having undergone surgery requiring&#xD;
             gastrointestinal anastomoses within four weeks of starting therapy or who have not&#xD;
             recovered from major surgery within three weeks of starting therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of alcoholism, drug addiction, or any psychiatric or psychological condition&#xD;
             which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would impair study compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Any treatment with investigational drugs within 30 days before the start of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Previous treatment with E7080&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Women who are pregnant or breast-feeding; women of childbearing potential with a&#xD;
             positive pregnancy test at Screening or no pregnancy test. Women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential unless (1) surgically sterile or (2) using adequate measures of&#xD;
             contraception (including two forms of contraception, one of which must be a barrier&#xD;
             method) in the opinion of the Investigator. Perimenopausal women must be amenorrheic&#xD;
             for at least 12 months to be considered of non-childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Fertile males with female partners who are not willing to use contraception or whose&#xD;
             female partners are not using adequate contraceptive protection&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Legal incapacity&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David S. Hong, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center Website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 26, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 23, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 23, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 26, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Advanced Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasm of breast</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of bone and articular cartilage</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of digestive organs</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of eye brain and other parts of central nervous system</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of female genital organs</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of ill-defined secondary and unspecified sites</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of independent (primary) multiple sites</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of lip oral cavity and pharynx</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of male genital organs</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of mesothelial and soft tissue</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of respiratory and intrathoracic organs</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of thyroid and other endocrine glands</keyword>
  <keyword>Malignant neoplasms of urinary tract</keyword>
  <keyword>Lenvatinib</keyword>
  <keyword>E7080</keyword>
  <keyword>Lenvima</keyword>
  <keyword>Capecitabine</keyword>
  <keyword>Xeloda</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Genital Neoplasms, Female</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Genital Neoplasms, Male</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urologic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thyroid Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lip Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bone Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Eye Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Soft Tissue Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Fibrous Tissue</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cartilage Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Capecitabine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lenvatinib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

