<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02912897</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RC14_0359</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02912897</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial to Assess the Safety and Feasibility of Adoptive Cell Therapy With Autologous EBV-specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocytes (CTL) in Patients With a First Clinical Episode Highly Suggestive of Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>MS and EBV-CTL</acronym>
  <official_title>An Open Single-center, Phase I Proof of Concept Trial to Assess the Safety and Feasibility of Adoptive Cell Therapy With Autologous EBV-specific Cytotoxic T Lymphocytes (CTL) in Patients With a First Clinical Episode Highly Suggestive of Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nantes University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Nantes University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The etiologic mechanisms involved in multiple sclerosis (MS) are not yet fully understood.&#xD;
      Indeed MS is a multifactorial disease involving genetic and environmental factors and&#xD;
      Epstein-Barr-Virus (EBV) could be one of these factors. However the link between EBV&#xD;
      infection and the immunological mechanisms underlying MS is not clear. Robust&#xD;
      sero-epidemiological evidences support an association between EBV infection and MS, and&#xD;
      immunological data suggest an altered/deficient immune response against this virus. In&#xD;
      healthy individuals EBV produces a persistent infection that is tightly controlled by the&#xD;
      immune system. In patients with MS, cellular and humoral immune studies demonstrate an&#xD;
      altered response against the virus with a T-cell abnormal reactivity against the EBV-infected&#xD;
      autologous B-cells, elevated humoral immune response to Epstein Barr Nuclear Antigen-1, and&#xD;
      in the case of children, an increased EBV shedding, demonstrating frequent EBV reactivations.&#xD;
      Thus, it has been proposed, that patients with MS present a partially inefficient control of&#xD;
      the EBV infection. Some experimental data support the hypothesis suggesting that the presence&#xD;
      of autoreactive EBV-B cells in the meninges of patients, probably due to an insufficient&#xD;
      clearance of these cells by the immune system, lead to the infiltration of autoreactive T&#xD;
      cells. Another hypothesis also suggests a deficient control of the virus, in that case during&#xD;
      the inactive phase of the disease. Together, the above data and hypotheses lead to the notion&#xD;
      that an immune intervention capable of restoring the host-EBV balance could be beneficial to&#xD;
      MS patients In this project, we will assess the feasibility and safety of autologous transfer&#xD;
      of several amounts of CD8 T cells directed against autologous EBV transformed B cell lines,&#xD;
      in order to finally restore an efficient control of EBV in MS patients. The main objective of&#xD;
      the project is to test the feasibility and safety of the process, while efficacy parameters&#xD;
      will be also assessed in secondary objectives.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 26, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Treatment-Related Adverse Events as Assessed by CTCAE</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">7</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cellular therapy with EBV specific autologous CTL infusion</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cellular therapy with EBV specific autologous CTL infusion</intervention_name>
    <description>CTL infusions at D0, M3 and M6</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cellular therapy with EBV specific autologous CTL infusion</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18&lt;Age≤45 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with :&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A clinically isolated syndrome (first acute or sub acute neurological event&#xD;
                  consistent with demyelination [i.e. optic neuritis, spinal cord syndrome,&#xD;
                  brainstem/ cerebellar syndrome])&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  And a MRI scan showing dissemination of MRI lesions in space based on 2017&#xD;
                  McDonald criteria At least 1 lesion detected in 2 or more following locations&#xD;
                  (sites) periventricular, cortical or juxtacortical, infratentorial, spinal cord&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  With a possible dissemination in time based on the revised McDonald cirteria and&#xD;
                  evicenced on simultaneous detection of one Gadolinium (Gd) enhancing and non-Gd&#xD;
                  enhancing lesions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Or demonstration of CSF-specific oligoclonal bands (OCBs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  EDSS Score &lt;3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients covered by health care insurance (social security)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Onset of symptoms occurring within 60 days of inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with HIV, HTLV, Hepatitis B, C Syphilis testing negative within 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive EBV serology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cell count (Leukocytes) &gt; 750/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinically definite multiple sclerosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients known to have HIV, HTLV Hepatitis A, B, C or Syphilis infections or patient&#xD;
             with active uncontrolled systemic bacterial, viral, parasitic or fungal infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with white blood cell count (Leukocytes) &lt; 750/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with childbearing potentiel refusing efficient contraceptive method&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients wishing to be pregnant during the course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under legal guardianship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant participation of any other trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with mental or psychiatry condition unable to understand the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any medically unstable condition or any health conditions that may&#xD;
             impact the safety of the patient as determined by the investigator or patient with any&#xD;
             stable condition treated with immunotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of cancer within 5 years or progressive cancer except for&#xD;
             basal or cell skin lesions surgically excised and cured, in situ cervical cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unable to comply with protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication for MRI or/and any known history of hypersensitivity to contrast&#xD;
             medium&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients currently treated with immunosuppressive drugs including oral or systemic&#xD;
             corticosteroids&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>David LAPLAUD, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>+ 33 (0)2 40 16 52 00</phone>
    <email>david.laplaud@univ-nantes.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nantes</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>David LAPLAUD, Doctor</last_name>
      <phone>+ 33 (0)2 40 16 52 00</phone>
      <email>david.laplaud@univ-nantes.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 13, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 23, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>EBV-CTL</keyword>
  <keyword>Multiple sclerosis</keyword>
  <keyword>cellular therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

