<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02913417</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Uveal Melanoma IIP</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02913417</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Yttrium90, Ipilimumab, &amp; Nivolumab for Uveal Melanoma With Liver Metastases</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Feasibility Study of Sequential Hepatic Internal Radiation and Systemic Ipilimumab and Nivolumab in Patients With Uveal Melanoma Metastatic to Liver.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>David Minor, MD</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>California Pacific Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jefferson Medical College of Thomas Jefferson University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Chicago</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>California Pacific Medical Center Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Reports to date show limited efficacy of immunotherapy for uveal melanoma. Recent&#xD;
      experimental and clinical evidence suggests synergy between radiation therapy and&#xD;
      immunotherapy. The investigators will explore this synergy with a feasibility study of 26&#xD;
      patients with uveal melanoma and hepatic metastases who will receive SirSpheres Yttrium-90&#xD;
      selective internal hepatic radiation followed by immunotherapy with the combination of&#xD;
      ipilimumab and nivolumab.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Despite rapid improvements in the treatment of cutaneous melanoma, there has been little&#xD;
      advance in therapy for uveal melanoma with hepatic metastases, an fatal orphan disease with&#xD;
      no established therapy. Studies by Dr. Sato and others have described some activity for&#xD;
      selective internal radiation with Yttrium90 microspheres (SIR-Spheres).There is limited&#xD;
      activity as single agents for both the immunotherapy drugs ipilimumab (anti-CTLA-4) and&#xD;
      nivolumab (anti-PD-1). In cutaneous melanoma the combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab is&#xD;
      clearly synergistic with improvement in response rates and progression-free survival over&#xD;
      single agents; however this has yet to be established for uveal melanoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent experimental and clinical evidence suggests additional synergy between radiation&#xD;
      therapy and immunotherapy. This synergy seems most evident when radiation is given through&#xD;
      large fraction stereotactic treatments or brachytherapy. The investigators will explore this&#xD;
      synergy with a feasibility study of 18 patients who will receive SirSpheres Yttrium-90&#xD;
      selective internal radiation given through the hepatic artery in two treatments followed by&#xD;
      immunotherapy with the combination of ipilimumab and nivolumab. The immunotherapy will be&#xD;
      given with the dose and schedule that has been established and FDA-approved for cutaneous&#xD;
      melanoma. Because of the generally low toxicity of Yttrium-90 selective internal radiation&#xD;
      therapy the investigators feel it can be given in full dosage prior to full dosage of&#xD;
      immunotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 10, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>safety and tolerability of sequential selective internal radiation with Yttrium90 followed by immunotherapy with ipilimumab and nivolumab.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Determine the safety and tolerability of sequential selective internal radiation with Y90 followed by immunotherapy with ipilimumab and nivolumab in patients with uveal melanoma metastatic to the liver. Endpoints are CTAE determined grade 3-5 toxicities.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Preliminary clinical efficacy</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>co-endpoints for this measure will be RECIST response rate and PFS</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>immunological changes</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in peripheral blood lymphocyte counts</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of tissue markers and response to immunotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Study of archival tumor tissue for tumor mutations, PDL-1, PDL-2, others</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Explore relationship of response to immunotherapy with tumor melanin</measure>
    <time_frame>5years</time_frame>
    <description>Correlate response with tumor production of melanin assessed by tumor density on MRI scans</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">26</enrollment>
  <condition>Uveal Melanoma</condition>
  <condition>Hepatic Metastases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>hepatic radiation followed by immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>SIR-Spheres Yttrium 90 will be given by injection into the hepatic artery in two treatments, one for each lobe. 3-5 weeks later patients receive concurrent ipilimumab 1mg/kg q 3 wk x 4 and nivolumab 3mg/kg q 3 weeks x 4, all followed by nivolumab 240mg/kg q 2 weeks or 480 mg q 4 weeks until progression or 3 years</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SIR-Spheres® Yttrium 90</intervention_name>
    <description>Patient treatment will consist of three parts: first, selective internal radiation with SIR-Spheres Yttrium-90 microspheres with dosage per package insert , reduced to give 35cGymax to normal liver; second, concurrent ipilimumab 1mg/kg and nivolumab 1mg/kg every 3 weeks for 4 doses (immunotherapy part 1); then maintenance nivolumab at 480 every 2 weeks (immunotherapy part 2) until progression or 3 years</description>
    <arm_group_label>hepatic radiation followed by immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>ipilimumab 1mg/kg every 3 weeks x 4</description>
    <arm_group_label>hepatic radiation followed by immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Yervoy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>nivolumab</intervention_name>
    <description>nivolumab 3mg/kg every 3 weeks x 4 then 480mg q 4 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>hepatic radiation followed by immunotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Opdivo</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Histologic diagnosis of metastatic uveal melanoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients must have measurable disease as defined by RECIST (see Section 6).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must have liver metastasis&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must have no more than one prior systemic therapeutic regimen. This includes&#xD;
             chemotherapy, biologic therapy, biochemotherapy, or investigational treatment. This&#xD;
             does not include any therapies given in the adjuvant setting. No prior anti-CTLA4&#xD;
             therapy. Prior anti PD-1 or anti-PDL-1 antibody therapy is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No concomitant therapy with any of the following: IL-2, interferon or other non-study&#xD;
             immunotherapy regimens; cytotoxic chemotherapy; immunosuppressive agents; other&#xD;
             investigation therapies; or chronic use of systemic corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with prior selective internal radiation are candidates are eligible as long&#xD;
             as they are candidates for repeat procedures and they have demonstrated progressive&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No known infection with HIV. Due to the mechanism of action of ipilimumab, activity&#xD;
             and side effects in an immune compromised patient are unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. No active infection with Hepatitis B.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. No active infection with Hepatitis C.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. ECOG performance status 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Women must not be pregnant or breast-feeding due to unknown effects of treatments on&#xD;
             the unborn fetus. All women of childbearing potential must have a blood test within 72&#xD;
             hours prior to randomization to rule out pregnancy. Women of childbearing potential&#xD;
             and sexually active males must be strongly advised to use an accepted and effective&#xD;
             method of contraception. Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must be using an&#xD;
             adequate method of contraception to avoid pregnancy throughout the study and for up to&#xD;
             12 weeks after the last dose of investigational product, in such a manner that the&#xD;
             risk of pregnancy is minimized. Sexually mature females who have not undergone a&#xD;
             hysterectomy or who have not been postmenopausal naturally for at least 24 consecutive&#xD;
             months (i.e., who have had menses at some time in the preceding 24 consecutive months)&#xD;
             are considered to be of childbearing potential. Women who are using oral&#xD;
             contraceptives, other hormonal contraceptives (vaginal products, skin patches, or&#xD;
             implanted or injectable products), or mechanical products such as an intrauterine&#xD;
             device or barrier methods (diaphragm, condoms, spermicides) to prevent pregnancy, or&#xD;
             are practicing abstinence or where their partner is sterile (e.g.,vasectomy) should be&#xD;
             considered to be of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients must have the following lab values obtained &lt; 4 weeks prior to starting&#xD;
             treatment:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  WBC ≥2000/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ANC ≥1500/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 8g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤ 3.0 xULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST and ALT &lt; 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ 2.0 x ULN, (except patients with Gilbert's Syndrome, who must have a&#xD;
                  total bilirubin less than 3.0 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Albumin ≥ 3g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients are excluded if they have liver tumor volume &gt; 50%&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients are excluded if they have active CNS metastases. Patients with history of CNS&#xD;
             metastases must have MRI scans that show stability of brain metastases for 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients are excluded if they have a history of any other malignancy from which the&#xD;
             patient has been disease-free for less than 2 years, with the exception of adequately&#xD;
             treated and cured basal or squamous cell skin cancer, superficial bladder cancer or&#xD;
             carcinoma in situ of the cervix, or stage 1 or 2 cutaneous melanoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients are excluded if they have a history of autoimmune disease, as follows:&#xD;
             Patients with a history of inflammatory bowel disease are excluded from this study as&#xD;
             are patients with a history of symptomatic disease (e.g., rheumatoid arthritis,&#xD;
             systemic progressive sclerosis [scleroderma], Systemic Lupus Erythematosus, autoimmune&#xD;
             vasculitis [e.g., Wegener's Granulomatosis]). Patients with a history of&#xD;
             Guillain-Barre Syndrome are excluded but myasthenia gravis or psoriasis is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients are excluded for any underlying medical or psychiatric condition which, in&#xD;
             the opinion of the investigator, will make treatment hazardous or obscure the&#xD;
             interpretation of adverse events, such as a condition associated with frequent&#xD;
             diarrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients are excluded if they have a history of prior treatment with ipilimumab or&#xD;
             CTLA-4 inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients are excluded if they have any concurrent medical condition requiring the use&#xD;
             of systemic steroids (the use of inhaled or topical steroids is permitted).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients are excluded if they have had prior hepatic arterial embolization therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David R. Minor, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>California Pacific Medical Center Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>California Pacific Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94115</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Chicago</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60637</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jefferson Medical College of Thomas Jefferson University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19107</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 21, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 23, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>California Pacific Medical Center Research Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David Minor, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Director Melanoma Center</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>uveal melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>liver metastases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Uveal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nivolumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <pending_results>
    <submitted>October 5, 2021</submitted>
    <returned>November 2, 2021</returned>
  </pending_results>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

