<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02543983</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>150188</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-M-0188</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02543983</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neurobiology of Suicide</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Neurobiology of Suicide</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no good treatments for people considering suicide. Researchers want to study&#xD;
      suicide with questions, blood tests, brain imaging, and sleep studies. They hope to better&#xD;
      understand suicide, so they can help suicidal people.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To understand what happens in the brain when someone has thought about or attempted suicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 1: Adults ages 18 70 who have thought about or attempted suicide recently&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 2: Adults ages 18 70 who have thought about or attempted suicide in the past&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 3: Adults ages 18 70 who have depression or anxiety, but have never thought about&#xD;
      suicide&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group 4: Healthy volunteers the same ages.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be screened in another protocol. Adults who have recently thought about or&#xD;
      attempted suicide must be referred by a doctor. They may do up to 3 phases of this study.&#xD;
      Groups 2, 3 and 4 will do only Phase 1 and will not get ketamine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 1: 1 week in hospital. Participants will have:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Questions about thoughts and feelings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thinking and memory tests and simple tasks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and urine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two MRI scans. Participants will lie on a table that slides into a metal cylinder that takes&#xD;
      pictures. They will have a coil over their head and earplugs and do a computer task.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sleep test. Disks and bands will be placed on the body to monitor it during sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Magnetic detectors on their head while they perform tasks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A wrist monitor for activity and sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lumbar puncture (optional). A needle will collect fluid from the back.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Shock experiments (optional). Participants will observe pictures and sounds and feel a small&#xD;
      shock on the hand.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 2: 4 days in hospital. A thin plastic tube will be placed in each arm, one for blood&#xD;
      draws, the other to get the drug ketamine once. Participants will repeat most of the Phase 1&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase 3: up to 4 more ketamine doses over 2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have follow-up calls or visits at 6 months and then maybe yearly for 5&#xD;
      years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A. Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      Suicide occurs across demographics and psychiatric disorders, killing at least one million&#xD;
      individuals worldwide each year. In contrast to other injury-related death such as homicide&#xD;
      or motor vehicle accidents, suicide rates have increased, particularly among middle-aged&#xD;
      adults. Clinicians have a limited ability to predict imminent suicidal behavior and few, if&#xD;
      any, efficacious treatments are available to treat suicidal patients. Advances in the&#xD;
      treatment of the suicidal patients have been hampered by an incomplete understanding of the&#xD;
      neurobiological underpinnings of the suicidal crisis, as suicidal thoughts and behaviors have&#xD;
      not been clearly linked with specific neural circuits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to evaluate possible biomarkers of suicidal thoughts and behaviors&#xD;
      in individuals currently experiencing a suicidal crisis. In taking a dimensional approach to&#xD;
      suicide research, we will be able to study phenomenology across Research Domain Criteria&#xD;
      (RDoC) units of analysis, from genes through circuits to self-report and experimental&#xD;
      paradigms. Through this approach, we can identify potential neurobiological risk factors for&#xD;
      both short and long-term suicide risk. As a secondary aim, we will use ketamine to identify&#xD;
      biomarkers of ketamine response in a sample at acute risk for suicide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      B. Study Population&#xD;
&#xD;
      Five participant populations will be recruited into this protocol in order to encompass the&#xD;
      continuum of suicide risk. A total of 325 individuals will be enrolled in the study.&#xD;
      Participant populations are individuals with the following conditions: 1.) recent suicidal&#xD;
      ideation with intent and/or suicide attempt (Group 1- active crisis , n= 65); 2) a past&#xD;
      history of suicide attempt, but no suicidal behavior in the last year (Group 2, n= 65,&#xD;
      attempters ); 3) anxiety or mood symptoms, but no recent or past suicidal thoughts or&#xD;
      behavior (Group 3, n= 65); 4) healthy controls with no psychiatric or suicide history (Group&#xD;
      4, n= 65); and lifetime suicidal thoughts with intent (Group 5, n=65, ideators ).&#xD;
&#xD;
      C. Design&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research protocol will occur across three phases: baseline, ketamine response and&#xD;
      optional repeated infusions. All participants will first be consented into Phase I, which may&#xD;
      last up to seven days. This baseline phase will entail multimodal assessment, using&#xD;
      pathophysiological markers (blood draw, lumbar puncture), neuroimaging (fMRI, MEG),&#xD;
      polysomnography, clinical ratings and experimental paradigms (shock experiments).&#xD;
      Participants will receive their regularly scheduled daily medications, but will not receive&#xD;
      additional treatment (including new prn medications, such as benzodiazepines for management&#xD;
      of anxiety or agitation) during this brief baseline phase. After completion of Phase I,&#xD;
      eligible participants from Group 1 or Group 5 only (active crisis or ideators) will be&#xD;
      offered participation in Phase II, the ketamine response phase. This phase, which will last&#xD;
      up to four days, consists of a single, open-label trial of ketamine (0.5 mg/kg). The focus of&#xD;
      this phase will be identification of potential biomarkers of antisuicidal ketamine response.&#xD;
      Participants who complete Phase II will be offered Phase III, which will involve repeated&#xD;
      ketamine infusions over two weeks (2 times/ per week for 2 weeks). Psychiatric medication&#xD;
      adjustment will be permitted during Phase III.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After participation in Phases I-III, participants in Groups 1-3 and 5 will be offered&#xD;
      standard clinical treatment (excluding healthy controls), or participation in another&#xD;
      protocol. In standard clinical treatment, adjustment of psychiatric medications and&#xD;
      commencement of psychotherapeutic interventions will be permitted. Finally, participants in&#xD;
      the first three groups (excluding healthy controls) will receive follow-up evaluations at six&#xD;
      months and 1 year after completion of Study Phase I.&#xD;
&#xD;
      D. Outcome Measures&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Phase I, the outcome measures will be underlying psychiatric, psychological, neuroimaging,&#xD;
      sleep and biological differences between the participant groups. In Phase II, the outcome&#xD;
      measures will be reductions in suicidal thoughts and depressive and anxiety symptoms at 24&#xD;
      hours post-ketamine infusion.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 21, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 21, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Study as Whole: Psychiatric, psychological, neuroimaging, sleep and biological differences between participants in Groups 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical and research data and samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Scale for Suicide Ideation</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical rating scale of suicidal ideation</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Montgomery-Asberg Depression Rating Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical rating scale of depression</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Hamilton Psychiatric Rating Scale for Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical rating scale of depression</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Phase II: Clinical Global Impression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical rating scale of psychiatric symptomology</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anhedonia and Hopelessness via the Snaith-Hamilton Pleasure Scale &amp;amp; the Beck Hopelessness Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical rating scale of anhedonia and hopelessness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Baseline and Response Biomarkers</measure>
    <time_frame>multiple time-points</time_frame>
    <description>Biomarkers</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">325</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteers</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be administered open-label intravenous ketamine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ketamine</intervention_name>
    <description>non-competitive N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor antagonist</description>
    <arm_group_label>1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase I: Groups 1-3 and 5 (Patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 to 70 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A level of understanding sufficient to agree to all required tests and examinations,&#xD;
             sign an informed consent document and verify understanding by a score greater than or&#xD;
             equal to 90% on the Baseline consent quiz&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals who are able to get pregnant must be willing to remain sexually abstinent&#xD;
             or use at least one form of effective birth control during participation in Phase I.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Additional Criteria for Group 1 (Active Crisis): Agree to be hospitalize&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase I: Group 4 (Healthy Volunteers)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 to 70 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A level of understanding sufficient to agree to all required tests and examinations,&#xD;
             sign an informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Individuals who are able to get pregnant must be willing to remain sexually abstinent&#xD;
             or use at least one form of effective birth control during participation in Phase I.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase II: Group 1 (Active Crisis) and Group 5 (Suicide Ideators)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients must have completed Study Phase I as a participant in Group 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants must verify understanding of the protocol by a score greater than or&#xD;
             equal to 80% on the Ketamine Response&#xD;
&#xD;
             consent quiz.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients in Group 1 or 5 must report at least minimal suicidal ideation, depressive or&#xD;
             anxiety symptoms to be eligible for this phase (see Monitoring Suicide Risk section).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MADRS score of over 10 (10 used as an outcome measure for remission)126&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  OR HAMA score of over 7 (7 used as an outcome measure for remission)127&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  OR SSI score of 2 or more (indicates any residual suicidal thoughts)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Individuals who are able to get pregnant must be willing to remain sexually abstinent&#xD;
             or use at least one form of effective birth control during participation in Phase II.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase III: Group 1 (Active Crisis) and Group 5 (Suicide Ideators)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants must have met all inclusion criteria for and completed Study Phase II as&#xD;
             a participant in Group 1 (active crisis) or Group 5 (Suicide Ideators).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Individuals who are able to get pregnant must be willing to remain sexually abstinent&#xD;
             or use at least one form of effective birth control during participation in Phase III.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase I: Groups 1-3 and 5 (Patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current psychotic features or cognitive impairment that would preclude understanding&#xD;
             of the consenting process or tests/examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Current drug or alcohol dependence&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Currently intoxicated or under the acute effects of an illicit substance will not be&#xD;
             consented into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Pregnant or nursing individuals or those who plan to become pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Serious, unstable medical conditions/problems including hepatic, renal,&#xD;
             gastroenterologic, respiratory, cardiovascular (including blood pressure, ischemic&#xD;
             heart disease), endocrinologic, neurologic, immunologic, or hematologic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Clinically significant abnormal laboratory tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Positive HIV test&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participants who, in the investigator s judgment, pose a current homicidal risk or&#xD;
             pose suicide risk that cannot be managed in a secure, voluntary inpatient setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Non-English speakers&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Additional Criteria for Group 1 (Active Crisis): For participants who still experience&#xD;
             the effects of their suicide attempt, i.e. someone who overdosed is significantly&#xD;
             drowsy or confused, the consenting process will occur after the patient has improved&#xD;
             from the effects. If there is a concern around a participant s capacity to consent,&#xD;
             the Human Subjects Protections Unit (HSPU) team member who is&#xD;
&#xD;
        monitoring the informed consent process will complete a capacity assessment. Participants&#xD;
        who are determined not to have capacity to consent to research will not be included in the&#xD;
        study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase I: Group 4 (Healthy Volunteers)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Current or past Axis I diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presence of medical illness likely to alter brain morphology and/or physiology (e.g.,&#xD;
             hypertension, diabetes) even if controlled by medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Current or past alcohol or substance abuse or dependence diagnosis (except for&#xD;
             nicotine or caffeine) (or substance abuse disorder per DSM-V).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Presence of psychiatric disorders or a history of suicide attempt or death in&#xD;
             first-degree relatives.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Pregnant or nursing individuals or those who plan to become pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. No lifetime suicide attempts or ideations&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Non-English speakers&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Positive HIV test&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusions for Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants with metal objects implanted in the body, such as aneurysm clips, neural&#xD;
             stimulators, implanted cardiac pacemakers, or auto-defibrillator, cochlear implant, or&#xD;
             ocular foreign body which would make having an MRI scan unsafe&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants who are uncomfortable in small closed spaces (have claustrophobia) and&#xD;
             would feel uncomfortable in the MRI machine&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants with a brain abnormality on an initial MRI scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with hearing loss that has been clinically evaluated and diagnosed and may be&#xD;
             worsened through participation in imaging procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase II: Group 1 (Active Crisis) and Group 5 (Suicide Ideators)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Treatment with a reversible MAOI within 2 weeks prior to study Phase II.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Treatment with any other concomitant medication not allowed within 5 (Omega)&#xD;
             half-lives prior to study Phase II.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects with one or more seizures without a clear and resolved etiology&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants with a positive urine for an illicit substance no more than 24 hours&#xD;
             prior to the ketamine infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Presence of current psychotic features or a diagnosis of Schizophrenia or any other&#xD;
             psychotic disorder as defined in the DSM-IV or DSM-V&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnant or nursing individuals or those who plan to become pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. A medical finding or condition that in the clinical judgement of the investigator&#xD;
             increases the risk of adverse effects from the ketamine administration (for example:&#xD;
             findings suggesting difficulties with kidney or cardiac function that may be&#xD;
             contraindications for an experimental intervention).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Phase III: Repeated Administration (Group 1) and Group 5 (Suicide Ideators)&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Intolerable or serious adverse reaction to ketamine during Phase II&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Treatment with a reversible MAOI within 2 weeks prior to study Phase III.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Treatment with any other concomitant medication not allowed within 5 (Omega)&#xD;
             half-lives prior to study Phase III.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with one or more seizures without a clear and resolved etiology&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants with a positive urine for an illicit substance no more than 24 hours&#xD;
             prior to each ketamine infusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Presence of current psychotic features or a diagnosis of Schizophrenia or any other&#xD;
             psychotic disorder as defined in the DSM-IV or DSM-V&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Pregnant or nursing individuals or those who plan to become pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusions for Imaging:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants with metal objects implanted in the body, such as aneurysm clips, neural&#xD;
             stimulators, implanted cardiac pacemakers, or auto-defibrillator, cochlear implant, or&#xD;
             ocular foreign body which would make having an MRI scan unsafe&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participants who are uncomfortable in small closed spaces (have claustrophobia) and&#xD;
             would feel uncomfortable in the MRI machine&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participants with a brain abnormality on an initial MRI scan&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with hearing loss that has been clinically evaluated and diagnosed and may be&#xD;
             worsened through participation in imaging procedures&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Carlos A Zarate, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Laura R Waldman, L.C.S.W.</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-9348</phone>
    <email>moodresearch@mail.nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2015-M-0188.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 25, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 5, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 5, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 9, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Neurobiology</keyword>
  <keyword>Suicide</keyword>
  <keyword>Ketamine</keyword>
  <keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

