<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02543996</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>150190</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>15-H-0190</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02543996</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Human Biospecimen Procurement Protocol: Biorepository to Support Translational Research to Identify Disease Mechanism(s)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Human Biospecimen Procurement and Analysis to Support Translational Research to Identify Genetic Etiology and Disease Mechanism(s) in Rare Genetic Vascular/Cardiovascular Diseases</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies show that rare genetic variants might lead to diseases. Researchers want to collect&#xD;
      blood and tissue samples so they can study them and better understand diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To collect blood and tissue samples for studies to identify underlying causes of disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People of all ages&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have blood and/or tissue samples collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples can be collected at the NIH Clinical Center. Participants doctors can collect the&#xD;
      samples and send them to NIH. NIH staff can collect samples off site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For blood samples, blood is taken from an arm vein using a needle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tissue collection may involve:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Buccal smear: Cells are collected by scraping the inside of the cheek with a cotton swab.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Saliva collection: Participants spit into a cup.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Skin biopsy: A special needle takes a very small skin sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical waste tissue: If participants have surgery, NIH may receive samples of tissue that&#xD;
&#xD;
      would routinely be removed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Umbilical cord or cord blood collection: If a participant has a baby, NIH may receive a&#xD;
&#xD;
      small piece of the umbilical cord or blood from the cord once the baby is delivered.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The diversity of human research programs at the National Institutes of Health (NIH) provides&#xD;
      a unique opportunity to study different patient populations with monogenetic and undiagnosed&#xD;
      diseases with vascular implications. Patient populations with mutations in almost every major&#xD;
      signaling pathway related to cardiovascular diseases are actively investigated at the NIH&#xD;
      Clinical Center. The purpose of this protocol is to obtain and analyze human biospecimens&#xD;
      from affected and unaffected cohorts (as reference biospecimens) to identify genetic etiology&#xD;
      and/or underlying disease mechanism(s) in rare genetic vascular/cardiovascular conditions.&#xD;
      The collections will consist of biospecimens obtained from participants consented under this&#xD;
      protocol and will also provide for the continued storage and analysis of biospecimens&#xD;
      previously obtained from NIH Institutional Review Board (IRB)-approved protocols, or from NIH&#xD;
      protocols nearing completion. The biospecimens collected under this protocol will include&#xD;
      blood (plasma, serum, peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMCs)), saliva, buccal mucosa,&#xD;
      urine, and skin biopsies. Additional biospecimens collected under other protocols may also be&#xD;
      transferred to this protocol, including, tissue and fluid aspirates (cerebrospinal fluid,&#xD;
      ascites, etc.), bone marrow, urine, saliva, skin biopsies, surgical tissue waste, malignant&#xD;
      and non-malignant tissue samples, and/or other direct derivatives from human tissues (i.e.&#xD;
      DNA, RNA, and induced pluripotent stems cells). Post-delivery umbilical cord core blood and&#xD;
      cord tissue waste will be collected at the time of delivery under this protocol and/or shared&#xD;
      if obtained under other protocols. Biospecimens may also be obtained as shared samples of&#xD;
      clinically indicated procedures done inside or outside NIH, provided the subject consents to&#xD;
      this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective of this protocol is to create a robust resource to support basic and&#xD;
      translational research by providing a mechanism for collecting, tracking, storing,&#xD;
      dispensing, analyzing, and disposing of laboratory research samples from affected and&#xD;
      unaffected cohorts. This research will advance high- quality research in the areas of&#xD;
      genetics and personalized medicine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As this is not a treatment protocol, there is no primary endpoint. Research studies will&#xD;
      include, but not be limited to, genomic studies, primary cell isolation and cell culture&#xD;
      studies for molecular and biochemical analysis, immunohistological analysis, generation of&#xD;
      patient-specific in vitro disease models (i.e. IPSCs), etc. As science is a continuously&#xD;
      evolving field, technological advances in research methods will be&#xD;
&#xD;
      incorporated into research studies accordingly.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 17, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 22, 2050</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 4, 2040</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To procure human biospecimens from affected and unaffected cohorts for on-going and future basic and translational research studies to identify underlying disease mechanism(s)</measure>
    <time_frame>ongoing</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective is to procure human biospecimens from affected and unaffected cohorts for on-going and future basic translational research studies to identify underlying disease mechanism(s) and potential therapeutic approaches</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10000</enrollment>
  <condition>Undiagnosed Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Affected or unaffected cohorts (including genetic carriers or non-carriers as</arm_group_label>
    <description>Affected or unaffected cohorts (including genetic carriers or non-carriers as reference biospecimens)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Affected or unaffected cohorts (including genetic carriers or non-carriers as reference&#xD;
        biospecimens)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA (SUBJECTS MUST MEET ONE OF THE FOLLOWING):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: older than 1 month of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affected pregnant women if they have been referred with a known or suspected pathology&#xD;
             or if they become pregnant while on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unaffected related pregnant women (including spouses/partners) for cord blood and&#xD;
             tissue collection (surgical waste) only at the time of delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitively impaired individuals that are affected&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitively impaired individuals that are related to an affected subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects willing to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy volunteers unable to give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitively impaired individuals who are not affected&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitively impaired individuals who are not related to affected subjects.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>1 Month</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manfred Boehm, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Katherine Carney</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 402-9841</phone>
    <email>katherine.carney@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2015-H-0190.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 12, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 5, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 5, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 9, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sample Collection</keyword>
  <keyword>Laboratory Research Specimens</keyword>
  <keyword>Biospecimen Procurement</keyword>
  <keyword>Rare Diseases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cardiovascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Undiagnosed Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

