<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02548130</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Centre CHUM</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02548130</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of MELD Score for 1000 Consecutive Liver Transplantations</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of the Introduction of the MELD Score to Prioritize the Waiting List on Survival, Blood Losses, And Transfusion Requirement for 1000 Consecutive Liver Transplantations, Observational Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this observational study was to evaluate the impact of the adoption of the MELD&#xD;
      system to prioritize patients on the waiting list for OLT on survival for 1000 consecutive&#xD;
      liver transplantations. Survival was evaluated on the waiting list, one month, and one year&#xD;
      after the transplantation. Another goal was to look at blood losses and transfusion&#xD;
      requirement after the adoption of the MELD score. The hypothesis was the MELD system will&#xD;
      ameliorate the survival rate on the waiting, but the post-OLT will be worse. Blood losses and&#xD;
      transfusions could be worse with the MELD system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      IMPACT OF THE INTRODUCTION OF THE MELD SCORE TO PRIORITIZE THE WAITING LIST ON SURVIVAL,&#xD;
      BLOOD LOSSES, AND TRANSFUSION REQUIREMENT FOR 1000 CONSECUTIVE LIVER TRANSPLANTATIONS,&#xD;
      OBSERVATIONAL STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
      INTRODUCTION&#xD;
&#xD;
      Orthotopic liver transplantation (OLT) has been classically associated with coagulation&#xD;
      defects, blood loss, and the need for massive blood product transfusions .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Transfusion of blood products may contribute to morbidity and mortality. Ironically, one&#xD;
      third of patients for OLT had acquired their diseases through transfusion of blood products.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Child-Turcotte score was developed to predict complications for Porto-cave shunt surgery.&#xD;
      This classification was used after to prioritize patients on the waiting for OLT. This&#xD;
      classification which includes 3 subjective variables (nutrition, encephalopathy, ascites&#xD;
      control) was improved by replacing nutrition by the international normalized ratio (INR) .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Model of End-Stage Liver Disease (MELD) score was initially created to predict survival&#xD;
      in patients with complications of portal hypertension undergoing elective placement of&#xD;
      transjugular intrahepatic porto-systemic shunts (TIPS) . The MELD score may be an improvement&#xD;
      of the Child-Turcotte-Pugh score as it includes 3 objectives laboratory test results:&#xD;
      bilirubin (mg/dL), creatinine (mg/dL), and INR. More recently, MELD score has been validated&#xD;
      both retrospectively and prospectively as an accurate predictor of mortality for patients who&#xD;
      have chronic end-stage liver disease . After, the MELD system was adopted to reduce the&#xD;
      ever-increasing mortality of patients on the waiting list for OLT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The MELD score is a numerical scale, ranging from 6 (less ill) to 40 (gravely ill). The MELD&#xD;
      system is constantly being scrutinized and revised. So it's difficult to compare patients'&#xD;
      MELD from different periods. Some authors have tried to use the MELD score to predict blood&#xD;
      product requirements or survival after OLT . Although the MELD system reduces the mortality&#xD;
      of patients on the waiting list, prioritizing the sickest patient raises a number of&#xD;
      concerns. One of the main concerns is that the MELD may worsen the post-OLT outcomes&#xD;
      resulting in futile transplantation. Many studies suggest that patients with high MELD score&#xD;
      have worse post-OLT outcomes than patients with low MELD score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The MELD system was adopted in the province of Quebec in July 2009. Before that the&#xD;
      allocation system was: first priority was for intubated patients in an intensive care unit.&#xD;
      The second priority was for patients in intensive care unit. The third priority was for&#xD;
      hospitalized patients, and the final priority was for patients at home.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this observational study was to evaluate the impact of the adoption of the MELD&#xD;
      system to prioritize patients on the waiting list for OLT on survival for 1000 consecutive&#xD;
      liver transplantations. Survival was evaluated on the waiting list, one month, and one year&#xD;
      after the transplantation. Another goal was to look at blood losses and transfusion&#xD;
      requirement after the adoption of the MELD score. The hypothesis was the MELD system will&#xD;
      ameliorate the survival rate on the waiting, but the post-OLT will be worse. Blood losses and&#xD;
      transfusions could be worse with the MELD system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      METHODS&#xD;
&#xD;
      After approval of the Ethic committee of the Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal&#xD;
      (CHUM) (15.113) and registration on Clinical Trials.gov a non-experimental comparative study&#xD;
      was conducted. 1000 consecutive liver transplantations were studied. Prioritization for the&#xD;
      first 300 OLTs was as Quebec's allocation system at that time. The last 700 OLTs were&#xD;
      prioritized according to the MELD system (since July 9th, 2009).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgery Protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eight hepatobiliary surgeons performed all the OLTs, and more than 25 anesthesiologists were&#xD;
      involved throughout the study period. Monitoring was standardized in all patients, as was the&#xD;
      anesthesia technique (arterial canula, pulmonary artery catheter, sufentanil, propofol,&#xD;
      rocuronium, desflurane). In the absence of uncontrollable bleeding coagulation disorders were&#xD;
      not corrected before or at the time of transplantation. No fresh frozen plasma (FFP),&#xD;
      platelets or cryoprecipitate were given and a &quot;wait-and-see&quot; approach of rescue therapy was&#xD;
      used instead of a prophylactic or preventive interventions. The triggering Hb level for RBC&#xD;
      transfusion was set between 60 and 70 g/L. An effort was made to start a RBC transfusion&#xD;
      after the blood loss was controlled. In the presence of diffuse oozing (any clinical evidence&#xD;
      of coagulation) plasma (10-15 ml/kg) were transfused if the international normalized ratio&#xD;
      (INR) value was higher than 1.5 to 2.0. Platelets were also transfused (5-10 units) if&#xD;
      platelets count was lower than 30 X 109 pl/L, and cryoprecipitate (5 units) if fibrinogen was&#xD;
      lower than 1.3-2.0 g/L. Aprotinin was administered in every case for the first 300 OLTs&#xD;
      according to the Hammersmith protocol (37). The last 700 OLTs received tranexamic acid as&#xD;
      antifibrinolytic according to the BART protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each anesthesiologist tried to lower the central venous pressure (CVP) before the anhepatic&#xD;
      phase by one third using a restricting intravenous fluid infusion approach, phlebotomy&#xD;
      without volume replacement or by a combination of both techniques. Phlebotomy consisted of&#xD;
      withdrawing blood (from the introducer of the pulmonary artery catheter) at the beginning of&#xD;
      the cas without any crystalloid or colloid volume replacement. Criteria for phlebotomy were:&#xD;
      Hb concentration above 85 g/L, and a normal renal function. The quantity of blood withdrawn&#xD;
      was guided by the patient's body mass (7-10 ml/kg). The phlebotomy was interrupted if the&#xD;
      arterial blood pressure dropped by more than 20% of the baseline value in spite of&#xD;
      vasopressor (phenylephrine or norepinephrine) administration. The CVP was slowly corrected&#xD;
      after unclamping the inferior vena cava to avoid hepatic congestion. The previously withdrawn&#xD;
      whole blood was returned to the patient at the end of surgery of before as needed. A cell&#xD;
      saver (CS) was used for every case except for the initial 75 OLTs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two surgeons were involved in each procedure. Neither venovenous bypass nor piggyback&#xD;
      technique was used except for very few cases where the piggyback technique was used. During&#xD;
      dissection, bleeding was controlled almost exclusively by electrocautery and metallic clips.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All livers were harvested from brain dead donors and where ABO-Rh compatibles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis The MELD score was determined for each patient according to the&#xD;
      equation: 0.957 X Loge creatinine mg/dL + 0.378 X Loge bilirubin mg/dL + 1.120 X Loge INR X&#xD;
      10 (14). The MELD score was adjusted according to the period (14). The data are expressed as&#xD;
      mean ± standard deviation of the mean or as a percentage. Statistical analysis was performed&#xD;
      using the Student'S T test, Welch T test as appropriate. The chi-square test served to&#xD;
      compare percentages.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 29, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 21, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 21, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival;</measure>
    <time_frame>one year</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>Per-operatively</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>transfusion of blood products</measure>
    <time_frame>Per0operatively</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>End Stage Liver Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients before MELD score</arm_group_label>
    <description>Recipients before the MELD score</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients after the MELD score</arm_group_label>
    <description>Recipients after the MELD score</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MELD score</intervention_name>
    <description>introduction of MELD score</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients after the MELD score</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients for a liver transplantation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients for a liver transplantation at the investigators' institution&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Manon Choiniere, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CrCHUM</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre Hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H2X 3E4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 7, 2015</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2015</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 14, 2015</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>End Stage Liver Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

