<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03956381</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CSP2018-03</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03956381</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Accuracy of OPS™ Femoral Neck Resection Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Study to Demonstrate the Accuracy of Femoral Neck Resection Compared to the Pre-operatively Selected OPS™ Plan in Total Hip Arthroplasty.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Corin</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Corin</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to determine the accuracy of the Optimized Positioning&#xD;
      System (OPS™) planning and delivery tools using different types of surgical approaches.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Total Hip Replacement (THR) is the gold standard for treatment of severe arthritis of the hip&#xD;
      as it relieves pain, restores function of the joint and improves quality of life for&#xD;
      patients. The restoration of hip mechanics can be influenced by the selected femoral stem&#xD;
      design and also by choices made by the surgeon during the surgical implantation. The&#xD;
      combination of femoral neck resection level and angle are key factors, particularly in&#xD;
      cementless hip arthroplasty, in determining post-operative leg length and femoral&#xD;
      anteversion. Historically, an estimation of prosthesis sizing and positioning has been made&#xD;
      via a process of manual or digital templating either pre or intraoperatively using images of&#xD;
      the implants positioned over the standard AP and lateral view hip x-rays taken in advance of&#xD;
      surgery with generic instruments used during the surgery to execute the femoral head&#xD;
      resection at the planned level. This process has a number of limitations. The OPS™ system&#xD;
      utilizes detailed pre-operative imaging including a CT scan to generate a plan for the&#xD;
      femoral neck resection level and angulation based on the anatomy of the individual patient.&#xD;
      Following validation of this plan by the operating clinician, a patient specific femoral&#xD;
      guide instrument is generated to help facilitate the reliable delivery of the planned&#xD;
      resection intraoperatively. The purpose of this study will be to evaluate the use of the&#xD;
      patient-specific femoral instrument in the hands of two surgeons using different prosthesis&#xD;
      combinations and surgical approaches. A total number of 40 participants will be enrolled.&#xD;
      Participants in this study will return for a single post-operative visit at 6 weeks to have&#xD;
      X-rays taken and to enable any post-operative study hip related complications to be recorded.&#xD;
      Once this has been completed, participants will be routinely followed-up by their orthopaedic&#xD;
      surgeon as required in accordance with standard clinical practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 24, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy of the final osteotomy level compared to the selected OPS™ plan preopertively.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks post-op (+/- 2 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Accuracy of the final osteotomy level compared to the selected OPS™ plan (+ or - 3mm). Two standard of care post-operative x-rays taken at 6 weeks will be used to evaluate the positioning of the total hip prosthesis from the resultant level of resection of the femoral neck. This parameter will be measured in mm.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the femoral stem size implanted compared to the selected OPS™ Plan preoperatively (± 1 size)</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>The femoral stem size used during the operation will be compared to the selected one by the OPS™ Plan. This parameter will be measured in units.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the acetabular cup size implanted compared to the selected OPS™ Plan preoperatively.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>The acetabular cup size used during the operation will be compared to the selected one by the OPS™ Plan. This parameter will be measured in mm.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the femoral head size implanted compared to the selected OPS™ Plan preoperatively.</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>The femoral head size used during the operation will be compared to the selected one by the OPS™ Plan. This parameter will be measured in mm.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measurement of any change in Leg length/ femoral head height compared to the preoperative OPS™ Plan (± 5mm).</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks post-op (+/- 2 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>The postoperative Leg length / femoral head height will be measured in mm and compared to the preoperative value.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of the acetabular cup orientation to the selected OPS™ Plan.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks post-op (+/- 2 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>The planned versus achieved acetabular cup orientation will be measured using 2D/3D registration software, in degrees.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">55</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Total Hip Arthroplasty</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>THR with OPS system-TriFit TS/Trinity combination</arm_group_label>
    <description>Hip prosthesis combination: TriFit TS stem/ Trinity cup implanted by Surgeon 1 via a posterolateral approach according to their standard of practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>THR with OPS system-MetaFix/Trinity combination</arm_group_label>
    <description>Hip prosthesis combination: MetaFix stem/ Trinity cup implanted by Surgeon 2 via a direct anterior approach according to their standard of practice.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Primary Total Hip Replacement with Trinity cup and TriFit TS stem via posterolateral surgical approach.</intervention_name>
    <description>The participant will undergo surgery using the hip prostheses and surgical approach used by their surgeon Investigator. A patient specific femoral guide, generated by the OPS™ plan preoperatively, will be used during the surgical step of femoral neck resection. These are not study specific procedures as the OPS™ system is already in use by the surgeon Investigator in their standard of practice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>THR with OPS system-TriFit TS/Trinity combination</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Primary Total Hip Replacement with Trinity cup and MetaFix stem via direct anterior surgical approach</intervention_name>
    <description>The participant will undergo surgery using the hip prostheses and surgical approach used by their surgeon Investigator. A patient specific femoral guide, generated by the OPS™ plan preoperatively, will be used during the surgical step of femoral neck resection. These are not study specific procedures as the OPS™ system is already in use by the surgeon Investigator in their standard of practice.</description>
    <arm_group_label>THR with OPS system-MetaFix/Trinity combination</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Study participants will be recruited from the clinic registry at each of the&#xD;
        investigational sites of those patients requiring a primary hip replacement. Those who meet&#xD;
        the inclusion/exclusion criteria will be invited to enrol into the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who understand the conditions of the study and are willing to return to the&#xD;
             clinical site at 6 weeks post-operatively.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients of either gender who are between 21-85 years inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with a diagnosis of osteoarthritis, rheumatoid arthritis or osteonecrosis and&#xD;
             are considered by the Investigator to be clinically and medically suitable to undergo&#xD;
             a primary total hip replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who meet the indications and none of the contraindications listed in the&#xD;
             Instructions for Use (IFU) supplied by the manufacturer for the femoral stem and&#xD;
             acetabular cup to be implanted.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients who meet the indications and none of the contraindications listed in the&#xD;
             Instructions for Use (IFU) supplied by the manufacturer for OPS™ Femoral Plan and OPS™&#xD;
             Femoral Patient Specific Instruments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who are unable to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who are unable to comply with all the required study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients whose insurance will not cover the cost of the pre-operative CT and&#xD;
             functional x-ray imaging required for use of the OPS system.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who are currently involved in any personal injury litigation, medical-legal&#xD;
             or worker's compensations claims.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>21 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jason Jennings, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Colorado Joint Replacement</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Colorado Joint Replacement</name>
      <address>
        <city>Denver</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.coringroup.com/uk/solutions/optimized-positioning-system-ops/</url>
    <description>Optimized Positioning System (OPS™)</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 8, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 17, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 20, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Femoral neck resection, offset, leg lenght, femoral anteversion</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

