<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03236467</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>D2395-P</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1I21RX002395-01A1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03236467</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neurohormonal Benefits of Exercise in Fibromyalgia and PTSD</brief_title>
  <acronym>EXFMPTSD</acronym>
  <official_title>Neurobiological and Psychological Benefits of Exercise in Fibromyalgia and PTSD</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>VA Boston Healthcare System</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The most recent conflicts are creating a new generation of Veterans, including an increasing&#xD;
      number of women Veterans, who present with comorbid PTSD and chronic pain conditions,&#xD;
      including Fibromyalgia (FM), from deployment-related physical injuries and exposure to&#xD;
      psychological trauma. Health behavior change is important in treating these conditions and&#xD;
      proactively preventing long-term negative health sequelae, in order to benefit these Veterans&#xD;
      directly and reduce the challenges to our healthcare system. The proposed SPiRE application&#xD;
      will use an innovative translational research approach to study whether a progressive -based&#xD;
      exercise program will reduce FM pain in patients with PTSD and to elucidate and modify&#xD;
      potential PTSD-related deficiencies in neurobiological and psychological responses to&#xD;
      exercise to optimize the physical and psychological benefits of exercise for these&#xD;
      individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and after consultation with the appropriate research oversight,&#xD;
      this study is temporarily suspended as of 3/15/20.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will compare the effects of a 12-week progressive exercise training program on 1)&#xD;
      Fibromyalgia (FM) pain and PTSD symptoms, 2) pain threshold and tolerance, and 3) relevant&#xD;
      biomarkers and neuromodulators including: a) anti-stress, anti-nociceptive, immune modulating&#xD;
      factors such as neuropeptide Y (NPY) and GABAergic neuroactive steroids such as&#xD;
      allopregnanolone and pregnanolone (together termed ALLO) b) factors that upregulate the&#xD;
      expression of NPY and the GABAergic neuroactive steroids, and otherwise modulate&#xD;
      inflammation, such as cortisol, c) excitatory factors such as substance P that directly&#xD;
      promote pain transduction and d) pro-inflammatory cytokines such as IL-6 and IL-8 that not&#xD;
      only increase pain and inflammation, but also contribute to psychological dysfunction (e.g.&#xD;
      anhedonia and depression) via impact on the CNS reward system. This study will focus on&#xD;
      Veterans with FM/PTSD. The study design includes a baseline, acute, cardiopulmonary exercise&#xD;
      assessment (CPX) that will inform the exercise prescription for a 12-week &quot;progressive&#xD;
      exercise&quot; training program, comprised of three 30-45 minute exercise sessions per week&#xD;
      (walking or running, depending on the ability/capacity of the participant). Exercise sessions&#xD;
      will be initially supervised by an exercise physiologist in the Clinical Studies Unit (CSU)&#xD;
      at the VA Boston Healthcare System and then each participant will transition into the home.&#xD;
      Weekly telephone calls by the PI will provide additional motivational support and problem&#xD;
      solving. Implementation of the prescribed exercise regimen will also be supported by the use&#xD;
      of heart rate and actigraph monitors programmed for the participant to achieve their&#xD;
      prescribed heart rate range (HRR). Finally, an &quot;endpoint&quot; CPX assessment will occur at week&#xD;
      13 to track changes in psychological and neurobiological factors and to delineate their&#xD;
      impact on pain and PTSD symptoms. Both CPX, maximum load, exercise tests will be performed in&#xD;
      accordance with guidelines published by the American College of Cardiology. Among Veterans&#xD;
      with FM/PTSD, changes in the biomarkers assessed after acute, CPX exercise testing will be&#xD;
      associated with improvements in pain and PTSD symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once identified, such biomarkers could be augmented by modification of the exercise regimen&#xD;
      to help enhance the anti-stress hormone levels for the FM/PTSD population and experience&#xD;
      clinically significant reductions in their symptoms. To obtain sufficient power, 36&#xD;
      participants (18/year) will be recruited. Data from this pilot work will be used to&#xD;
      demonstrate feasibility and inform the further development of individually prescribed&#xD;
      exercise regimens and a motivationally based exercise behavior change intervention aimed at&#xD;
      reducing chronic musculoskeletal pain, including FM, and PTSD symptoms in Veterans. In the&#xD;
      short-term, this SPiRE proposal will allow the PI to develop a more effective, motivationally&#xD;
      based, exercise behavior change protocol that fosters long-term exercise adherence in&#xD;
      patients with FM/PTSD. In the long-term, this intervention will be used as an adjunct to&#xD;
      cognitive interventions for these disorders to be further developed and studied via a larger&#xD;
      VA, NIH, or DOD-funded grant for which the PI will apply year 2 of the current SPiRE&#xD;
      proposal.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 29, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Using an innovative translational research approach to study whether a 12 week-progressive - exercise program will reduce FM pain in patients with PTSD and to elucidate and modify potential PTSD-related deficiencies in neurobiological and psychological responses to exercise</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fibromyalgia Impact Questionnaire-Revised</measure>
    <time_frame>Two Years</time_frame>
    <description>The FIQR has been found to be a useful and brief instrument to assess the overall impact and severity of FM.&#xD;
The FIQR consists of 21-items that assess pain, fatigue, stiffness, sleep, depression, memory, anxiety, balance, and environment sensitivity.&#xD;
All items are framed in the past 7 days and are scored on an 11-point numeric rating scores of 0 to 10.&#xD;
The total score ranges from 0 to 100, with higher scores representing greater symptom burden and functional limitations.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinician Administered PTSD Scale -5</measure>
    <time_frame>Two Years</time_frame>
    <description>This 30-item structured interview is designed to assess both the 17 symptoms of PTSD and the 8 hypothesized associated features. The scale yields a dichotomous diagnosis of PTSD, and also provides a continuous score of frequency and severity for each symptom. In addition, a behaviorally anchored probe question is provided for each symptom to increase the reliability of administration. The CAPS-5 is currently in the process of being validated however its previous version demonstrated excellent sensitivity (.81) and specificity (.95).57</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">36</enrollment>
  <condition>FM and PTSD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>FM + PTSD</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Individuals suffering from Fibromyalgia and PTSD</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Progressive Exercise Training</intervention_name>
    <description>Designed to ease primarily sedentary individuals into exercise training, increasing in intensity up to 80% of maximum Heart Rate Range over time.</description>
    <arm_group_label>FM + PTSD</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Only Veteran and civilian participants in whom a physical examination and medical&#xD;
             history indicate that the participant meets current diagnostic criteria for FM, as&#xD;
             specified by the American College of Rheumatology, will be eligible for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible participants who agree to a blood draw for measurement of biomarkers, must be&#xD;
             free of medications and other substances (e.g., illicit drugs and alcohol) that may&#xD;
             alter results for 2-6 weeks depending on the medication and frequency of use (which&#xD;
             must be cleared by MD consultants).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If on pain medications with short half-lives, participants must be off of them for 5&#xD;
             half-lives before testing, generally about 24 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any FM participant with an ICD-10 chronic pain diagnosis of a musculoskeletal&#xD;
             etiology, will also be eligible for inclusion in the study as many individuals with FM&#xD;
             also have such conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participant with a confirmed psychiatric diagnosis of PTSD will be included in the&#xD;
             study. Individuals in the PTSD group must meet diagnostic criteria for current chronic&#xD;
             PTSD (&gt;3 months) as assessed by the CAPS-5, 1-Month Diagnostic Version.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants will be excluded from participation in the study if they have a life&#xD;
             threatening or acute physical illness (e.g., cancer)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current schizophreniform illnesses (except for Psychosis NOS due to PTSD-related&#xD;
             sensory hallucinations)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated bipolar disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Or active suicidal or homicidal ideation requiring clinical intervention&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with current or past alcohol and/or substance dependence (less than three&#xD;
             months from date of screening assessment) will be excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals seeking interventional pain treatment, such as surgical interventions or&#xD;
             other pain clinic interventions, will also be excluded unless they agree to&#xD;
             participate in the biomarker procedure prior to the start of their pain intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Finally, participants who have a neuropathic origin to their pain will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Erica R. Scioli, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>VA Boston Healthcare System Jamaica Plain Campus, Jamaica Plain, MA</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VA Boston Healthcare System Jamaica Plain Campus, Jamaica Plain, MA</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02130</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 27, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 27, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 2, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Fibromyalgia and PTSD</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fibromyalgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myofascial Pain Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>This is a VABHS single site study. There are no plans to share the data outside of the VA Boston Healthcare System, unless specifically requested by authorized officials of VA.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

