<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03949088</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DialHypot</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03949088</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Integrated Strategies to Prevent Intradialytic Hypotension (The DialHypot Study)</brief_title>
  <acronym>DialHypot</acronym>
  <official_title>Integrated Strategies to Prevent Intradialytic Hypotension: a Prospective Randomized Cross-over Trial in Hypotension-prone Hemodialysis Patients (The DialHypot Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Parma</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Parma</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The present study is aimed at comparing different strategies of UF profiling, dialysate&#xD;
      sodium individualization and sodium profiling (even combining one with the other) and at&#xD;
      evaluating the effectiveness of a new UF profile which has an ascending/descending shape. The&#xD;
      goal of the study is to provide better dialysis tolerance and lower rates of intradialytic&#xD;
      hypotensive events by the application of this UF profile design in combination with a neutral&#xD;
      sodium balance.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, randomized, crossover trial. The study will be performed in 2 phases.&#xD;
      Each phase will be divided in several sub-phases (see &quot;4.1 Study phases&quot;). Phase 1 will&#xD;
      consist of 9 weeks of treatment (27 HD sessions) for each patient; phase 2 will consist of 11&#xD;
      weeks of treatment (33 HD sessions) for each patient. Each subject will be used as his/her&#xD;
      own control. Dry weight, anti-hypertensive medications and dialysis parameters will not be&#xD;
      modified during the study phases, except for UF rate and dialysate sodium concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study phases&#xD;
&#xD;
      1 - First phase: validation of the new UF profile with a standard dialysate sodium&#xD;
      concentration&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. run-in: constant Na concentration, constant UF rate - 2 weeks (6 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. 2-step descending Na profile, linear descending UF profile - 3 weeks (9 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. washout: constant Na concentration, constant UF rate - 1 week (3 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. 2-step descending Na profile, ascending/descending UF profile - 3 weeks (9 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
      2 - Second phase: combination of UF profiles and individualized dialysate sodium&#xD;
      concentration&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. run-in: standard constant Na concentration, constant UF rate - 2 weeks (6 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. individualized constant Na concentration, constant UF rate - 2 weeks (6 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. individualized 2-step Na profile, linear descending UF profile - 3 weeks (9 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. washout: individualized constant Na profile, constant UF rate - 1 week (3 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. individualized 2-step Na profile, ascending/descending UF profile - 3 weeks (9 sessions)&#xD;
&#xD;
      In phase 1 patients will be randomly assigned to one of the following sequences:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  (1), (2), (3), (4)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  (1), (4), (3), (2)&#xD;
&#xD;
      In phase 2 patients will be randomly assigned to one of the following sequences:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  (1), (2), (3), (4), (5)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  (1), (2), (5), (4), (3) Patients who will be included in phase 1 will undergo at least a&#xD;
           2-week washout period before entering phase 2. During these 2 weeks dry weight and&#xD;
           anti-hypertensive therapy may be re-evaluated and re-assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dialysis prescription&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every patient will undergo a standard HD with the following prescription:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  blood flow: individualized from 250 to 350 mL/min (this value will be established for&#xD;
           each patient at the beginning of the run-in phase on the basis of previous evaluations&#xD;
           and maintained unchanged for the whole duration of the study)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  dialysate flow: 500 mL/min&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  dialysate composition: HCO3- 34 mmol/L, K+ 3 mmol/L, Ca2+ 1.25 mmol/L, Mg2+ 0.5 mmol/L,&#xD;
           Cl- 111.5 mmol/L, acetate 3.0 mmol/L, glucose 1 g/L&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  dialysate temperature: 36°C&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  HD session duration: 4 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  during each dialysis session patients will be allowed to drink an amount of maximum 150&#xD;
           mL of water, tea or coffee and they will be allowed to eat a snack&#xD;
&#xD;
      UF profiles&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;linear descending&quot; UF profile: this profile provides a constantly decreasing UF rate&#xD;
           during dialysis, starting at a UF rate 1.33 fold the average UF rate (33,25% of total UF&#xD;
           rate)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;ascending/descending&quot; UF profile: this profile can be divided in 2 different phases.&#xD;
           The first one includes 3 ascending steps during the first hour of treatment, each step&#xD;
           lasting 20 minutes (during the 1st step UF rate is set at 15% of total UF rate, during&#xD;
           2nd step at 25% of total UF rate, during 3rd step at 35% of total UF rate). During the&#xD;
           following 3 hours UF rate is shaped as a linear descending UF profile, with a constantly&#xD;
           decreasing UF rate, starting at a UF rate 1.33 fold the average UF rate (33,25% of total&#xD;
           UF rate)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dialysate sodium&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. - First phase&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  &quot;standard&quot; concentration: the investigators will consider as &quot;standard&quot; a dialysate&#xD;
                sodium concentration of 140 mmol/L, which is the concentration usually prescribed&#xD;
                in our dialysis facility&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  dialysate sodium profile will be shaped as a descending 2-step ramping, each step&#xD;
                consisting of half the total treatment duration (2 hours), with a 6 mmol/L&#xD;
                difference between the concentrations defined for each of the two steps.&#xD;
                Considering a monocompartimental model with variable dialysate sodium, the profile&#xD;
                will be set on the basis of an &quot;equivalent sodium&quot;. This value will correspond to&#xD;
                the dialysate sodium concentration expected to produce the same diffusive balance&#xD;
                that a fixed standard concentration (140 mmol/L) would provide: 144 mmol/L for the&#xD;
                first 2 hours, 138 mmol/L for the last 2 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. - Second phase&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  &quot;individualized&quot; concentration: for each patient dialysate sodium concentration&#xD;
                will be established on the basis of the mean of the sodium plasma values measured&#xD;
                through pre-HD sampling during the run-in phase (2 repeated measurements before&#xD;
                each HD session, for a total of 12 values for each patient). Plasma values will be&#xD;
                obtained through a direct potentiometry analysis. Dialysate sodium concentration&#xD;
                will be set at the patient's average plasma sodium concentration&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  dialysate sodium profile will be shaped as a descending 2-step ramping, each step&#xD;
                consisting of half the total treatment duration (2 hours), with a 6 mmol/L&#xD;
                difference between the concentrations set for each of the two steps. Considering a&#xD;
                monocompartimental model with variable dialysate sodium, the profile will be set on&#xD;
                the basis of an &quot;equivalent sodium&quot;. This value will correspond to the dialysate&#xD;
                sodium concentration expected to produce the same diffusive balance that a fixed&#xD;
                individualized concentration (equal to the patient's average plasma sodium&#xD;
                concentration) would provide: &quot;average + 4&quot; mmol/L for the first 2 hours, &quot;average&#xD;
                - 2&quot; mmol/L for the last 2 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definition of &quot;dry weight&quot;, &quot;UF volume&quot; and &quot;interdialytic weight gain&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  dry weight will be estimated through standard clinical criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  total UF volume (net fluid to be removed) will be calculated before each session as the&#xD;
           difference between patient's weight and his/her dry weight. A limit of 12.5 mL/kg/h will&#xD;
           be considered as maximal total UF volume&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  IDGW will be calculated as the difference between patient's weight at the beginning of&#xD;
           dialysis and the weight registered at the end of the previous session UF and IDGW will&#xD;
           be respectively corrected for pre-HD weight (UF %) and dry weight (IDWG %), thus&#xD;
           obtaining measures that will be more relevant to each specific patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcome and definition of &quot;intradialytic hypotension&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome will be the incidence of intradialytic hypotensive episodes. Hypotensive&#xD;
      events and symptoms (headache, cramps, nausea and vomiting) will be recorded and analyzed as&#xD;
      both number of occurrences and time of occurrence from the beginning of the HD session. IDH&#xD;
      will be defined as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;symptomatic IDH&quot;: decrease in SBP ≥ 20 mmHg or in MAP ≥ 10 mmHg associated with&#xD;
           symptoms (KDIGO definition)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;asymptomatic IDH&quot;: drop in BP (SBP ≥ 20 mmHg or MAP ≥ 10 mmHg) within a 20 minutes&#xD;
           interval, regardless of symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  for patients whose SBP is &lt; 100 mmHg at the beginning of treatment, the investigators&#xD;
           will consider as IDH any decrease of SBP ≥ 10%&#xD;
&#xD;
      Interventions in case of hypotensive events&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Trendelenburg position&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  temporary stop of UF (10 minutes), then restarted at a UF rate equal to &quot;total UF - 100&#xD;
           mL&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  online infusion of 150 mL of saline solution&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  discontinuation of the session&#xD;
&#xD;
      BV monitoring Relative blood volume will be evaluated through the BVM system integrated in&#xD;
      the dialysis machine. RBV will be recorded every 10 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other outcome measurements&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  pre-, intra- (after every hour of treatment) and post-HD plasma sodium levels will be&#xD;
           determined by direct potentiometry&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  blood pressure and heart rate will be recorded every 20 minutes, or more frequently if&#xD;
           needed for clinical necessities, by machine-integrated BPM&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  achievement of UF will be considered as:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  achievement of dry weight: % target UFDW = UF vol / (preHD weight - dry weight) x&#xD;
                100&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  IDWG removal: % target UFWG = UF vol / IDWG x 100&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;UF failure&quot; will be defined as % target UFDW &lt; 70%&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  &quot;session failure&quot; will occur when treatment will have to be discontinued before 75% of&#xD;
           the prescribed time (before 3 hours of treatment)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Kt/V will be estimated through the system integrated in the machine (total body water&#xD;
           calculated using Watson's equation)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Occurrence of intradialytic hypotensive episodes (number of episodes within every HD session and time interval from HD start)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within each dialysis session from the time of enrolment to the end of each study phase (9-11 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Hypotensive events and symptoms (headache, cramps, nausea and vomiting) will be recorded and analyzed as both number of occurrences and time of occurrence from the beginning of the HD session.&#xD;
IDH will be defined as follows:&#xD;
&quot;symptomatic IDH&quot;: decrease in SBP ≥ 20 mmHg or in MAP ≥ 10 mmHg associated with symptoms (KDIGO definition)&#xD;
&quot;asymptomatic IDH&quot;: drop in BP (SBP ≥ 20 mmHg or MAP ≥ 10 mmHg) within a 20 minutes interval, regardless of symptoms&#xD;
for patients whose SBP is &lt; 100 mmHg at the beginning of treatment, the investigators will consider as IDH any decrease of SBP ≥ 10%</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Achievement of UF</measure>
    <time_frame>Within each dialysis session from the time of enrolment to the end of each study phase (9-11 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>achievement of dry weight: % target UFDW = UF vol / (preHD weight - dry weight) x 100&#xD;
IDWG removal: % target UFWG = UF vol / IDWG x 100&#xD;
&quot;UF failure&quot; will be defined as % target UFDW &lt; 70% &quot;session failure&quot; will occur when treatment will have to be discontinued before 75% of the prescribed time (before 3 hours of treatment)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dialysis dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Within each dialysis session from the time of enrolment to the end of each study phase (9-11 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>Kt/V: estimated through the system integrated in the machine (total body water calculated using Watson's equation)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypotension During Dialysis</condition>
  <condition>Dialysis Hypotension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Linear descending UF profile</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>2-step descending Na profile, linear descending UF profile 3 weeks (9 sessions)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Run-in &amp; washout phases</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>constant Na concentration, constant UF rate 3 weeks (6+3 sessions)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ascending/descending UF profile</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>2-step descending Na profile, ascending/descending UF profile 3 weeks (9 sessions)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>UF and Na profiling</intervention_name>
    <description>Modulation of UF and dialysate sodium</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ascending/descending UF profile</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Linear descending UF profile</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Run-in &amp; washout phases</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  thrice weekly HD regimen for more than 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  &quot;hypotension-prone patients&quot;: ≥ 3 episodes of IDH in the month preceding the run-in&#xD;
             phase of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IDWG &lt; 1.4% of dry weight (corresponding to &lt; 1 kg in a 70-kg person)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  twice weekly HD regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  residual daily urine output &gt; 300 mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  active acute disease or hospitalization in the 8 weeks preceding the run-in phase&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Enrico Fiaccadori, Prof.</last_name>
    <phone>+390521703336</phone>
    <email>enrico.faccadori@unipr.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Parma - UO Nefrologia AOU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Parma</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Enrico Fiaccadori, Prof.</last_name>
      <phone>+390521703336</phone>
      <email>enrico.faccadori@unipr.it</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 7, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 11, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 14, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 14, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 16, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Parma</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Enrico Fiaccadori</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>University Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Intradialytic hypotension (IDH)</keyword>
  <keyword>Ultrafiltration (UF) profiling</keyword>
  <keyword>Sodium (Na) profiling</keyword>
  <keyword>Hemodialysis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

