<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03944811</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>29011</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03944811</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bone Height Gain Following Transcrestal Sinus Floor Elevation Using Piezoelectric Surgery Versus The Conventional Osteotome Technique</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Bone Height Gain Following Transcrestal Sinus Floor Elevation Using Piezoelectric Surgery Versus The Conventional Osteotome Technique in Patients With Atrophic Posterior Maxillae: A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Missing teeth usually result in functional and cosmetic deficits. Traditionally, they have&#xD;
      been restored with dentures or fixed bridges. However, dental implants represent an excellent&#xD;
      alternative which rely on the maintenance of a direct structural and functional connection&#xD;
      between living bone and implant surface, which is termed osseointergration. When sufficient&#xD;
      bone is available in maxilla, implant rehabilitation has shown high success rates of 84-92 %.&#xD;
      Atrophy of the alveolar crest and pneumatization of the maxillary sinus limits the quality&#xD;
      and quantity of residual bone, therefore complicating the placement of implants in the&#xD;
      posterior maxillary area.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Many solutions were suggested to overcome the problem of placing implants in the vertically&#xD;
      compromised bone height in the maxillary posterior region. These solutions include the&#xD;
      placement of short wide implants, long tilted zygomatic implants, vertical ridge augmentation&#xD;
      and elevation of the sinus membrane to increase the available length for implant placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The use of short implants (&lt;10 mm in length) is a reasonable solution that reduces the risk&#xD;
      of interference with anatomic structures and claimed to have success rate as high as&#xD;
      conventional implants. However, short implants have faced many challenges due to less&#xD;
      bone-to-implant contact, more crestal bone resorption, and compromised crown-to-implant&#xD;
      ratio. Another treatment option is the use of zygomatic implants. However, many complications&#xD;
      may be associated with zygomatic implants such as oro-antral fistula formation, maxillary&#xD;
      sinusitis, and peri-implant bleeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vertical augmentation of the resorbed alveolar ridge is another treatment option. It can be&#xD;
      done by onlay grafting, distraction osteogenesis and guided bone regeneration. Although&#xD;
      success rates of various bone grafting techniques are high, there are many inherent&#xD;
      disadvantages which include prolonged treatment times, raised treatment costs and increased&#xD;
      surgical invasion associated with patient morbidity and potential complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To overcome these problems, elevation of the sinus membrane techniques were proposed, it can&#xD;
      be performed either through a lateral window, or via a crestal access. The selection between&#xD;
      these two techniques is mainly based on the remaining residual vertical subsinus bone height.&#xD;
      Lateral approach of sinus elevation is indicated when the residual bone height is of 4 mm or&#xD;
      less, while the crestal approach is used in case of residual ridge of 5-6 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Many long term studies and systematic reviews have showed that osteotome mediated sinus floor&#xD;
      elevation (OSFE) technique is a highly predictable method for rehabilitation of patients with&#xD;
      atrophied posterior maxilla with survival rates ranging from 92 % to 100 %. However,&#xD;
      endoscopic studies have demonstrated the risk of membrane perforation while performing&#xD;
      transalveolar sinus floor elevation. Moreover, the Summers technique can cause some&#xD;
      complications as headache and paroxysmal positional vertigo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The piezoelectric internal sinus elevation (PISE) technique was first introduced by Sohn in&#xD;
      2009. Using piezoelectric ultrasonic vibration (25-30 kHz), the piezosurgery device cuts only&#xD;
      mineralized structures precisely without cutting soft tissues even in case of accidental&#xD;
      contact. Moreover, the cavitation effect produces a hydropneumatic pressure in the&#xD;
      physiological saline solution that leads to atraumatic sinus membrane elevation. Another&#xD;
      advantage of piezosurgery is its precision as the movement of the piezosurgery knife is very&#xD;
      small, so the cutting precision is great and the patients discomfort is minimal. In addition,&#xD;
      the air-water cavitation effect of the piezoelectric device sustains a blood-free surgical&#xD;
      field which improves visualization of the surgical field. This technique overcomes the&#xD;
      problem of benign paroxysmal positional vertigo caused by malleting during the osteotome&#xD;
      mediated sinus floor elevation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 22, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Amount of bone height gain</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Alveolar Bone Loss</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transcrestal sinus floor elevation using Summers technique</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transcrestal sinus floor elevation using piezoelectric surgery</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>piezoelectric device</intervention_name>
    <description>crestal approach will be used to augment the maxillary sinus with simultaneous implant placement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcrestal sinus floor elevation using piezoelectric surgery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Summers technique</intervention_name>
    <description>Summers technique</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transcrestal sinus floor elevation using Summers technique</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Patients having one missing upper posterior tooth residual bone height beneath&#xD;
             maxillary sinus from 5-8 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A minimum of 6 mm residual bone width at site of implant placement.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The recipient site of the implant should be free from any pathological&#xD;
                  conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No diagnosed bone disease or medication known to affect bone metabolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who are cooperative, motivated and hygiene conscious.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients having adequate inter-occlusal space of 8-10 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Systemic conditions/diseases that contraindicate surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Radiation therapy in the head and neck region or chemotherapy during the 12&#xD;
                  months prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who have any habits that might jeopardize the osseointegration process,&#xD;
                  such as current smokers.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with parafunctional habits that produce overload on implant, such as&#xD;
                  bruxism and clenching.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients that have any pathology in the maxillary sinuses.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ahmed Hassan El Barbary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 7, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 9, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 10, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Omar Ashour</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alveolar Bone Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

