<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03946956</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S20160164a</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03946956</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fighting Social Inequality in Cardiovascular Health I</brief_title>
  <acronym>FISICH-I</acronym>
  <official_title>Fighting Social Inequality in Cardiovascular Health I</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Odense University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Regionshospitalet Silkeborg</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Vejle Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Svendborg Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Nykøbing Falster Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Odense University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study attempts to reduce social inequality in cardiovascular health by performing an&#xD;
      interventional screening trial on how best to decrease cardiovascular disease (CVD) among&#xD;
      people with low social status&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although CVDs have decreased, they are still among the most predominant cause of morbidity&#xD;
      and mortality in the western world, incl. Denmark, where about 420,000 people have recognized&#xD;
      CVD symptoms. Due to an aging population, the decline has not reduced CVD admissions and&#xD;
      healthcare costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Denmark, the CVD related hospital admission costs are DKK 4.6 billion and the&#xD;
      pharmaceutical cost DKK 2.4 billion. The Danish National Board of Health has reported that&#xD;
      CVD carries the second largest socioeconomic difference in burden of disease. Unfortunately,&#xD;
      population-based health checks and screening for risk factors has proven not efficient.&#xD;
      Consequently, screening of asymptomatic CVD is discussed intensively. In the investigators&#xD;
      first unique CVD screening RCT (2008-11), the VIVA trial, they randomized more than 50.000&#xD;
      65-74 year old men for population-based ultrasound screening for abdominal aortic aneurysm&#xD;
      (AAA), peripheral arterial disease (PAD) and hypertension. In case of positive finding,&#xD;
      preventive medical actions were initiated. A significant reduction in overall mortality by 7%&#xD;
      after 5 years was observed (paper submitted). Using a non-contrast CT scan, instead of the&#xD;
      ultrasound based screening approach, has the opportunity to identify aneurysms in the entire&#xD;
      aortic, coronary artery calcification (CAC) and arterial fibrillation, so individualized risk&#xD;
      assessment and initiation of preventive actions on those with sign of early asymptomatic CVD&#xD;
      is possible. The investigators therefore initiated a second trial (DANCAVAS) in 2014&#xD;
      randomizing 45.000 65-74 year old men with the potential of a huge beneficial effect on&#xD;
      health, quality of life (QoL) and survival. However, screening is impaired by lower social&#xD;
      class, and adherence to initiated prevention could be impacted as well. Consequently, they&#xD;
      want to conduct a third RCT (FISICH) to test a number of add-ons to screening that&#xD;
      potentially balance the benefits across socio economic groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The perspective is to establish a clear decision foundation for public health care policy&#xD;
      incl. benefits, cost effectiveness and impact on social inequality of alternative variants of&#xD;
      population screening for CVD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses The primary hypothesis is that an extensive circulatory screening and intervention&#xD;
      programme reduces social inequality in cardiovascular health and fulfills the WHO criteria&#xD;
      for screening. However, this reduction can be even more pronounced, if factors reducing the&#xD;
      social selection to attend screening and adherence to preventive actions initiated are&#xD;
      identified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aims are to&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Test whether prebooking and/or supplemental informative pictures of the screening&#xD;
           session and consultation improves attendance rate in general, and particular among those&#xD;
           with the lowest educational level, lowest income level, and psychiatric disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Investigate whether confrontation of imaging of own arterial lesions at consultation&#xD;
           after screening and/or an e-mail 3 and 12 months after the consultation in case of&#xD;
           positive findings improves adherence to suggested cardiovascular preventive actions, and&#xD;
           whether it influences quality of life, in general and especially concerning those with&#xD;
           the lowest educational level, lowest income level, and psychiatric disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      In FISICH-I 20.000 60-64 year old men are randomized to the control group, while another&#xD;
      5.000 are randomized to the screening and intervention program for CAC, aortic and iliac&#xD;
      aneurysms, atrial fibrillation, PAD, hypertension, diabetes and hypercholesterolaemia. There&#xD;
      is no exclusion criteria. The screening setup is similar to DANCAVAS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A small questionnaire on life style, medical history, and the QoL a.o. will be enclosed&#xD;
           with the invitation. Non-responders are re-invited once.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The participant will be informed at attendance to the screening visit, and their consent&#xD;
           will be obtained together with the questionnaire, weight, height, and waist&#xD;
           circumference.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The CT scan will cover the area from the mandibular bone distally to the proximal third&#xD;
           of the femur. Calcium scores for the common carotids, coronary arteries, aorta, and&#xD;
           common iliac, and femoral arteries will be calculated. The aorta are visualized, and the&#xD;
           diameter is measured in ascending, arcus, descending and abdominal, and if possible in&#xD;
           the iliac arteries. Further the heart rhythm during the CT scan is evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Bilateral blood pressure will be recorded three times after 5 minutes of supine rest,&#xD;
           and concurrently the ankle blood pressure are measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The HbA1c and lipid parameters will be measured. Biobank blood samples are then taken,&#xD;
           centrifuged, labelled, cooled, and stored at -80 degrees Celsius.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up visit after screening If the CAC is above the median or if an aneurism of&#xD;
      peripheral arterial disease are detected the participant is informed of the finding and its&#xD;
      implications at a follow-up visit. At this visit, the patient will be recommended suitable&#xD;
      prophylactic measures, including smoking cessation, walking/exercise, a lowfat diet.&#xD;
      Additionally to start treatment with aspirin 75 mg/day and atorvastatin 40 mg/day. If an&#xD;
      aneurism is large the patient is referred vascular surgical assessment for the repair.&#xD;
      Otherwise, an annual check-up of the aneurism including a CT scan will be offered. If no&#xD;
      positive findings (CAC above the median, aneurysm or PAD) are detected, the participants will&#xD;
      be informed of the findings by e-mail or ordinary post as preferred.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Independent of the above findings, the patients will be encouraged to see their GP for&#xD;
      further assessment if potential undiagnosed hypertension (systolic blood pressure &gt;160 mmHg),&#xD;
      diabetes mellitus (HbA1c &gt;48 mmol/mol), or significant isolated hypercholesterolemia&#xD;
      (total-cholesterol &gt;8.0 mmol/l) are observed, as possible continuous medical treatments will&#xD;
      be better managed by the GPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The GPs will be informed by a letter of all negative and positive results and the initiated&#xD;
      actions. Additionally in the FISICH-I trial, four further randomizations are performed. In&#xD;
      the written invitations to the screening examination two further randomizations are&#xD;
      performed;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  prebooking versus active booking&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  +/- addition of illustrations of the examinations during the screening session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Power calculations and Randomisations&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomisation will be performed in SPSS by providing each individual a random number from&#xD;
      1-20. Those numbered +16 will be invited to participate in the screening program. Those&#xD;
      numbered 17 and 18 will be prebooked, while those numbered 19 and 20 will have to book&#xD;
      themselves through web-booking, email or phone.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Those with an equal number (18 and 20) will receive supplemental informative pictures of the&#xD;
      screening session.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In case of positive finding a new random number from 1-4 is given. Those numbered 3 and 4&#xD;
      will be confronted with imaging of their own arterial lesions, whilst others will receive&#xD;
      standard information. Those with an equal number (2 and 4) will receive a SMS, e-mail and&#xD;
      phone call 3 &amp; 12 months after the consultation. If all groups after randomisations are&#xD;
      equally sized,- 182 will only be additionally randomized to be remembered prescription&#xD;
      renewal after 3 and 12 months, and 182 will only have been randomized to the standard of&#xD;
      booking (Control group for all invited). If 12 months compliance to initiated preventive&#xD;
      medication is 66%, then with 0.05 significance level, and 80% power, the smallest difference&#xD;
      detectable is 15%, which seems clinical relevant. However, merged analyses adjusting for the&#xD;
      other interventions will be performed reducing the smallest detectable difference and reveal&#xD;
      potential synergistic combinations. Similar group comparisons will be performed for all&#xD;
      randomized interventions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline variables Age, smoking, previous or current stroke, ischemic heart disease, PAD,&#xD;
      chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, diabetes, hypertension, use of statins, useof&#xD;
      antithrombotics, body mass index, systolic- and diastolic blood pressure, ankle brachial&#xD;
      index, marital status, highest educational level, personal- andin house income, psychiatric&#xD;
      morbidity defined as any diagnosis and/or use of medications for mental illness, and QoL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline and outcome variables from national registries The CPR number assigned to Danish&#xD;
      citizens enables individual-level linkage to multiple nation-wide healthcare and&#xD;
      administrative registries which have proved valid.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Registry-based information on outpatient visits, hospitals admissions and procedures (The&#xD;
      Danish National Patient Registry), relevant prescribed drugs dispensed (The Danish National&#xD;
      Prescription Registry), socio economic status etc. (Registries at Statistics Denmark) and&#xD;
      primary care service use (National Health Insurance Service Registry) will be obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcomes The primary outcomes are&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Attendance to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. One-year adherence to initiated lipid-lowering and/or antithrombotic medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary outcome is:&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. QoL,&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analysis Baseline characteristics will be analysed using conventional summary&#xD;
      statistics.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Attendance rates adjusted for invitation layout and booking-method, as well as compliance one&#xD;
      year after initiation (def.: received a prescription 9-12 months after the consultation)&#xD;
      adjusted for image-confrontation and post-consultation phone call are compared by logistic&#xD;
      regression analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 31, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>2 x factorial design regarding attendance rate to cardiovacular screening</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Attendance rate to screening</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of invited attending screening</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life of invitation to screening</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of life measured by EurQol 5D</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>Cardiac Disease</condition>
  <condition>Vascular Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prebooking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomised to this arm receives a prebooked appointment to screening</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Web based booking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomised to this arm receives an invitation to book a screening appointment webbased or by contacting the trial office.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pictured invitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomised to this arm receives a pictured invitation to screening</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Texted invitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomised to this arm receives a classical texted invitation to screening</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prebooking</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants are receiving a prebooked appointment for CVD screening or being invited to book an appointment for CVD Screening</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pictured invitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prebooking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Texted invitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Web based booking</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pictured invitation</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants are receiving an illustrated invitation CVD screening or a classical text-invitation to book an appointment for CVD Screening</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pictured invitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prebooking</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Texted invitation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Web based booking</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men aged 60-64 living in the municipalities of Funen, Silkeborg, Vejle and surrounding&#xD;
             municipailties&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men not aged 60-65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men not living in the mentioned municipalities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <minimum_age>60 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jes S Lindholt</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Odense University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nykøbing Falster Sygehus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nykøbing Falster</city>
        <zip>4800</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Odense University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Odense</city>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Region Hospital Silkeborg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Silkeborg</city>
        <zip>8600</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Svendborg Sygehus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Svendborg</city>
        <zip>5700</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Vejle Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vejle</city>
        <zip>7100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 9, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 9, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 13, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 10, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 10, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 14, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Odense University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jes Lindholt</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Screening</keyword>
  <keyword>Prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular</keyword>
  <keyword>Public health</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data will be analysed on Statistics Denmarks secured server</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

