<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05007990</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210020</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>21-HG-0020</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05007990</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Caregiving Networks Across Disease Context and the Life Course</brief_title>
  <official_title>Caregiving Networks Across Disease Context and the Life Course: A Comparative Longitudinal Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the U.S., about 53 million informal, unpaid caregivers provide care to a person who is&#xD;
      ill, is disabled, or has age-related loss of function. These caregivers may be adult&#xD;
      children, spouses, parents, or others. The stress of providing long-term care affects&#xD;
      caregivers health and well-being. Researchers want to learn more about this stress and its&#xD;
      effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To learn how the caregiving process affects the health and well-being of caregivers over&#xD;
      time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults aged 18 years and older who are caregivers for a person with a chronic medical&#xD;
      condition and who have already given consent to take part in other study activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be put in different groups. They will complete some or all of the following&#xD;
      tasks over 1 year. They may repeat these tasks once a year for up to 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will fill out 2 online surveys. One will ask about their health and their&#xD;
      caregiving experience. The other will ask them to list people in their social network and&#xD;
      their care recipient s social network who give them support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will have a 2-part phone interview. It will be audio recorded. In part 1, they&#xD;
      will be asked about the people they listed in the survey. In part 2, they will be asked about&#xD;
      their caregiving experience and events in the care recipient s life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may fill out a weeklong diary every 3 months. It will ask about their daily&#xD;
      social activities, well-being, and stress levels. It will also ask about their thoughts and&#xD;
      feelings about caregiving.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants may give a blood sample each year they are in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Description: Caregivers will be invited to participate in surveys and interviews to&#xD;
      assess their cognitions and emotions about caregiving, caregiving burden, and caregiving or&#xD;
      support network systems during the life of the Care Recipient. This study will further&#xD;
      investigate these same families during bereavement if and when that occurs, for those who&#xD;
      opt-in to this component of the study. In addition, biomarkers will be evaluated in&#xD;
      consenting individuals to assess genetic susceptibility to stress and stress-related&#xD;
      dysregulations in the endocrine and immune systems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives: The primary objectives of this study are to investigate the natural history of&#xD;
      family caregiver stress over time, providing opportunity to understand the social,&#xD;
      psychological, behavioral, and biological factors that characterize caregivers response to&#xD;
      long-term caregiving during the life and after death of a Care Recipient with a chronic&#xD;
      medical condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints: To assess the change over time in terms of social, psychological, behavioral, and&#xD;
      biological factors associated with caregiving.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population: Participants will include caregivers, additional family members, and others&#xD;
      involved in providing care and support to a Care Recipient with a chronic medical condition.&#xD;
      The anticipated enrollment ceiling is approximately 450 families, potentially encompassing&#xD;
      2,250 participants. Adults ages 18 years and older will be recruited.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Sites/Facilities Enrolling Participants: NIH CC&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration: 10 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration: 5 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2030</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Family-Based</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Natural History</measure>
    <time_frame>Annually / quarterly</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate the natural history of family caregiving to identify the social, psychological, behavioral, and biological mechanisms that determine possible long-term changes in health during the life and after death of a Care Recipient with a chronic medical condition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2250</enrollment>
  <condition>Inherited Metabolic Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Undiagnosed Diseases</condition>
  <condition>Batten's Disease</condition>
  <condition>Tay Sachs</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants include individuals who are caregivers of an individual with a chronic medical condition, OR individuals who support caregivers of an individual with a chronic medical condition.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bereaved</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants include individuals who were caregivers of an individual with a chronic medical condition who has died, OR individuals who support the caregiver.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Referencing the enrollment numbers from the study of Inherited Diseases, Caregiving, and&#xD;
        Social Networks (PI: Koehly, protocol #12HG0022), this longitudinal study will initially&#xD;
        recruit from existing participants enrolled in #12HG0022. Family caregivers providing&#xD;
        ongoing support for a chronically ill individual may be identified and informed about the&#xD;
        Longitudinal Caregiving Study by an intramural NIH investigator involved in natural history&#xD;
        protocols. Caregivers may also be recruited through other (nonNIH) clinicians, researchers,&#xD;
        advocacy groups, online and traditional advertising, and ClinicalTrials.gov.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        To be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the following&#xD;
        criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults aged 18 years and older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-identify as a formal or informal caregiver to the Care Recipient (individual with&#xD;
             a chronic medical condition) OR is identified (i.e., referred) by a participant as a&#xD;
             formal or informal caregiver to the Care Recipient OR is otherwise identified (i.e.,&#xD;
             referred) by a participant as a part of the caregiving network&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to consent to research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fluency in English will be needed to complete interview as well as to read, comprehend&#xD;
             surveys and consent forms, as appropriate validated measures in other languages are&#xD;
             not readily available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physically capable of participating in applicable assessments&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Care Recipients (as defined in this protocol)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staff of NHGRI&#xD;
&#xD;
        Staff of NHGRI are unable to participate in this study as a safeguard against the risk of&#xD;
        ethical concerns. As per OHSRP SOP 404, NIH staff may be a vulnerable class of study&#xD;
        subjects. Excluding staff of the Institute conducting the study assures there will not be&#xD;
        any perceived or actual conflict of interest, pressure/coercion to participate among&#xD;
        co-workers, subordinates, work unit-members, etc. As further noted in OHSRP SOP 404,&#xD;
        exclusion further protects this class of subjects privacy and confidentiality; and protects&#xD;
        the study s scientific integrity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Persons with impaired neuro-sensory or decision-making ability (adults unable to provide&#xD;
        consent) will not be enrolled in the study. Persons with impaired neuro-sensory or decision&#xD;
        making ability would not be able to participate with independent responses to the various&#xD;
        social behavioral measures we use in the study interview and survey. Learning information&#xD;
        about these individuals through other people instead of themselves would introduce bias to&#xD;
        this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura M. Koehly, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patricia M Cooper</last_name>
    <phone>(301) 451-0911</phone>
    <email>patricia.cooper@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>For more information at the NIH Clinical Center contact Office of Patient Recruitment (OPR)</last_name>
      <phone>800-411-1222</phone>
      <phone_ext>TTY8664111010</phone_ext>
      <email>prpl@cc.nih.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicalstudies.info.nih.gov/cgi/detail.cgi?A_2021-HG-0020.html</url>
    <description>NIH Clinical Center Detailed Web Page</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 25, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Family Network</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Support</keyword>
  <keyword>Natural History</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetic Conditions</keyword>
  <keyword>Rare Diseases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuronal Ceroid-Lipofuscinoses</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Undiagnosed Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

