<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05006534</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>202005095RINA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05006534</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Polatuzumab Vedotin in Patients With Relapsed and Refractory Diffuse Large B Cell Lymphoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Efficacy and Adverse Effect of Polatuzumab Vedotin in Patients With Diffuse Large B Cell Lymphoma: an Observation Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study enrolled patients with relapsed or refractory diffuse large B cell lymphoma&#xD;
      treated with polatuzumab vedotin-based chemoimmunotherapies. Patients were allowed to use&#xD;
      chemotherapy regimens other than Rituximab and Bendamustine and transplantation following&#xD;
      polatuzumab vedotin was also allowed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Polatuzumab vedotin has been demonstrated to be an effective treatment for patients with&#xD;
      relapsed/refractory diffuse large B cell lymphoma in an international phase II clinical&#xD;
      trial. The clinical trials was conducted in Europe and the United States. Although there is a&#xD;
      phase III trial about polatuzumab vedotin in newly diagnosed patients with diffuse large B&#xD;
      cell lymphoma, the double-blind design has limited the efficacy assessment and side effect&#xD;
      observation, making it difficult to provide clinicians with further information.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This program hopes to evaluate the clinical course and treatment response of these patients&#xD;
      in order to facilitate clinicians' understanding of this drug and to improve patients'&#xD;
      quality of life and medical care, as well as to prevent the occurrence of related&#xD;
      complications and treatment toxicity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 29, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 29, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>From the use of PoV to death related to any cause</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>The assessment is based on PET/CT or contrast CT, as determined by the investigator. Including complete remission and partial remission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events [Safety and Tolerability]</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 2 year</time_frame>
    <description>Will estimate the safety and tolerability of polatuzumab vedotin when added to intensive chemotherapy regimens</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Relapsed Non Hodgkin Lymphoma</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Lymphoma</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients treated with Polatuzumab vedotin&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The informed consent form must be signed before any study specific tests or procedures&#xD;
             are done&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Adult male and female patients ≥20 years at the time of inclusion in the study Ability&#xD;
             to understand and follow study-related instructions&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Histological diagnosis of primary refractory or relapsed aggressive B-cell non-Hodgkin&#xD;
             lymphoma (B-NHL), confirmed by a biopsy of involved nodal or extranodal site. Patients&#xD;
             with any of the following histologies can be included:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  DLBCL not otherwise specified (NOS)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  T-cell/histiocyte-rich large B-cell lymphoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Primary cutaneous DLBCL, leg type&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Epstein-Barr virus (EBV)-positive DLBCL, NOS&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  DLBCL associated with chronic inflammation&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Primary mediastinal (thymic) large B-cell lymphoma Refractory disease is defined&#xD;
                  as no complete remission to first line therapy. Relapsed disease is defined as&#xD;
                  complete remission to first line therapy followed by disease relapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects must have received adequate first line therapy including at a minimum: i)&#xD;
             anti-CD20 monoclonal antibody unless Investigator determines that tumor is CD20&#xD;
             negative, and ii) an anthracycline containing chemotherapy Regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy test result within 7&#xD;
             days prior to the first study drug Administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. For women of childbearing potential: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from&#xD;
             heterosexual intercourse) or use contraceptive measures, and agreement to refrain from&#xD;
             donating eggs&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. For men: agreement to remain abstinent (refrain from heterosexual intercourse) or use&#xD;
             contraceptive measures, and agreement to refrain from donating sperm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Primary or secondary central nervous system (CNS) lymphoma at the time of recruitment&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Richter's transformation or prior chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Vaccination with a live vaccine within 4 weeks prior to Treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Received polatuzumab vedotin as part of the first line therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ongoing treatment or study procedures within any other Investigational Medicinal&#xD;
             Product (IMP) clinical trial with the exception of follow-up. In case of a preceding&#xD;
             clinical trial, last application of the respective IMP(s) must have been done more&#xD;
             than five elimination half-lives before start of study medication in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of severe allergic or anaphylactic reactions to human, humanized, chimeric, or&#xD;
             murine monoclonal antibodies&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or their ingredients or to drugs&#xD;
             with similar structure&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Pregnancy or breastfeeding, or intending to become pregnant during the study or within&#xD;
             12 months after the last dose of study drug&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Cheng-Hong Tsai, MD, MSc, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Taiwan University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Diffuse large B-cell lymphoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Polatuzumab vedotin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, B-Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lymphoma, Large B-Cell, Diffuse</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

