<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05001503</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Stability UO 001 v1.0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05001503</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Controlled Trial to Demonstrate a Reduction in the Number of Oliguria Events in Patients Being Managed in a Critical Care Unit, Following Cardiac Surgery, When a Novel Oliguria Prediction Tool (STABILITY UO) is Used to Identify Patients at Risk, Compared to Standard of Care.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pivotal Phase, Randomised Controlled Trial to Demonstrate a Reduction in the Number of Oliguria Events in Patients Being Managed in a Critical Care Unit, Following Cardiac Surgery, When a Novel Oliguria Prediction Tool (STABILITY UO) is Used to Identify Patients at Risk, Compared to Standard of Care.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rinicare Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rinicare Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acute kidney injury (AKI) is experienced by 12% of patients following surgery and in up to&#xD;
      50% of patients following cardiac surgery. It is associated with an increased risk of death&#xD;
      and prolonged stay in critical care after surgery. In addition to the patient impact, AKI&#xD;
      costs the NHS alone between £434m and £620m per year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One way that AKI is diagnosed is by looking at a patient's urine output and checking how much&#xD;
      is produced over time. If this value is too low for a patient, they are diagnosed with&#xD;
      oliguria. Too many of these oliguria events leads to a diagnosis of AKI. The product to be&#xD;
      tested (Stability UO) aims to reduce the number of patients who suffer three or more oliguria&#xD;
      events after surgery by processing the data entered by the care team and providing the care&#xD;
      team with additional information about the patient's risk of oliguria over the next six&#xD;
      hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients over 18 who present at Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust for non-emergency&#xD;
      cardiac surgery will be screened and asked to consent to be randomised as part of the trial.&#xD;
      Patients undergoing certain operations and those with unsuitable medical history (e.g.&#xD;
      patients being treated for dialysis) will not be invited to participate. The randomisation&#xD;
      will determine if their care team has access to the Stability UO software after surgery.&#xD;
      While the care team looks after the patients in the cardiothoracic critical care unit (CTCCU)&#xD;
      after surgery, they will enter that the patient's weight and amount of urine passed each hour&#xD;
      into the software and review the output. The primary questions the study will answer is if&#xD;
      there is a difference between number of oliguria events between the two groups of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is funded by the device manufacturer: Rinicare Ltd.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute Risk Reduction (ARR) of patients experiencing ≥3 oliguria events.</measure>
    <time_frame>post cardiac surgery CTCCU stay (average 2-5 days with some staying more than 3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An oliguria event is defined as an hourly urine output of less than 0.5ml/kg/hr.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of oliguria events during post cardiac surgery CTCCU stay</measure>
    <time_frame>post cardiac surgery CTCCU stay (average 2-5 days with some staying more than 3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An oliguria event is defined as an hourly urine output of less than 0.5ml/kg/hr.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Absolute Risk (AR), Relative Risk (RR), Relative Risk Reduction (RRR) of severe oliguria events</measure>
    <time_frame>post cardiac surgery CTCCU stay (average 2-5 days with some staying more than 3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An severe oliguria event is defined as an hourly urine output of less than 0.3ml/kg/hr.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Median length of total stay in hospital</measure>
    <time_frame>post cardiac surgery CTCCU stay (average 2-5 days with some staying more than 3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>median length of stay in hospital</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in post-operative serum creatinine concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>post cardiac surgery CTCCU stay (average 2-5 days with some staying more than 3 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Standard blood test to measure serum creatinine concentration (umol/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">362</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Kidney Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The clinical team has access to the Stability UO software. All other care is given as standard.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard care given.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Stability UO</intervention_name>
    <description>STABILITY UO is a standalone software, based on a Bayesian model, which quantifies the risk of an individual patient developing severe oliguria (0.3mg/kg/hr for 6 hours). The model identifies at risk patients by predicting future urine output, using only previously recorded urine output values for that individual, allowing clinicians to see the predicted risk of a patient developing severe oliguria in real time.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is willing and able to give informed consent for participation in the study,&#xD;
             including being able to receive study materials at least 24 hours prior to their&#xD;
             planned operation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is Male or Female, aged 18 years or above,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is due to undergo elective or urgent cardiac surgery, and who is expected to&#xD;
             be managed on the CTCCU postoperatively,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the Investigator's opinion, able and willing to comply with all study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing emergency surgery (i.e surgery that has to take place in the next&#xD;
             available theatre even if this is out of standard operating hours)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having ventricular assist device implantation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving a heart transplant,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who would be unable to be treated by standard of care CTCCU therapies and&#xD;
             practices,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are receiving pre or intra-operative dialysis or haemofiltration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other significant disease or disorder which, in the opinion of the Investigator,&#xD;
             may either put the participant at risk because of participation in the study, or may&#xD;
             influence the result of the study, or the participant's ability to participate in the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roberto Mosca, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Eric D Carlson, MRes</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0)1615 37 59 29</phone>
    <email>eric@rinicare.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stuart Grant, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+44 (0)1615 37 59 29</phone>
    <email>stuart.grant@rinicare.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Wythenshawe Hospital (Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <state>Greater Manchester</state>
        <zip>M23 9LT</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Juliette Novasio, Ph.D</last_name>
      <phone>0161 291 5773</phone>
      <email>juliette.novasio@mft.nhs.uk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Roberto Mosca, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Howitt SH, Oakley J, Caiado C, Goldstein M, Malagon I, McCollum C, Grant SW. A Novel Patient-Specific Model for Predicting Severe Oliguria; Development and Comparison With Kidney Disease: Improving Global Outcomes Acute Kidney Injury Classification. Crit Care Med. 2020 Jan;48(1):e18-e25. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000004074.</citation>
    <PMID>31663925</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Howitt SH, Grant SW, Caiado C, Carlson E, Kwon D, Dimarakis I, Malagon I, McCollum C. The KDIGO acute kidney injury guidelines for cardiac surgery patients in critical care: a validation study. BMC Nephrol. 2018 Jun 25;19(1):149. doi: 10.1186/s12882-018-0946-x.</citation>
    <PMID>29940876</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Oliguria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

