<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05001581</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SLukasH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05001581</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Irreparable Rotator Cuff Tears Treatment. Comparison of Two Methods: With and Without Biceps Tendon Augmentation</brief_title>
  <official_title>Massive and Irreparable Rotator Cuff Tears Treated by Arthroscopic Partial Repair and Partial Repair With Long Head of the Biceps Tendon Augmentation. Comparison of Clinical and Radiological Findings</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Saint Lucas Hospital, Poland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Saint Lucas Hospital, Poland</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Management of massive rotator cuff tears (MRCT) is associated with high rates of failure. The&#xD;
      long head of the biceps tendon augmentation (LHBTA) by reinforcement of the reconstruction&#xD;
      and additional blood supply may improve healing and provide better outcome than partial&#xD;
      repair only.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with irreparable supraspinatus muscle (SSP) tear, and complete infraspinatus muscle&#xD;
      (ISP) tear are including in the prospective, comparative study. Excluding criteria consist&#xD;
      of: problems or previous surgery of contralateral shoulder, subscapularis muscle tear larger&#xD;
      than stage 2 by Lafosse classification, uncontrolled diabetes and previous surgery. First&#xD;
      group consisting of patients treated by partial cuff repair with LHBTA. Second group is&#xD;
      comparative group consisting of patients treated by only partial cuff repair without LHBTA.&#xD;
      Group stratification depends on quality of the biceps tendon. In case of good tendon quality&#xD;
      - its used for biological augmentation, if it's degenerated- tenotomy of the tendon and only&#xD;
      partial repair is performing. Irreparability is defined as SSP ≥ 3 in Goutallier&#xD;
      classification and stage 3 in Patte classification what is preoperatively assessed by MRI.&#xD;
      Assessment tools consisting of range of motion (ROM), strength measurements in position&#xD;
      adequate to assess reconstructing tendons and muscles force, Acromio-humeral index (AHI),&#xD;
      Constant, SST, Hamada, and Sugaya scores. Goutallier classification for SSP and ISP and&#xD;
      diameter of the teres minor muscle (TMn). Radiological and clinical assessment is performing&#xD;
      one year after the surgery&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 30, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>2 different groups. Differences in type of surgery Comparison of two ways of treatment</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of improvement in shoulder range of motion</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Range of motion ( ROM) of every patient is measured preoperatively and postoperatively using goniometer and the result is presented in degrees. Comparision of two methods will be perform to assess better method for ROM improvement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of improvement in shoulder strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Strength will be measured by dynamometer in Kilograms [Kg] by main investigator in external rotation position, flexion, abduction and Jobe test position for every patient at the end of the study. Comparison of two methods will be perform to assess better method for shoulder strength improvement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of improvement in shoulder pain in VAS score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Pain is assessed preoperatively and postoperatively using VAS score ( from 0 to 10, when 0 is no pain and 10 is the higher possible pain). Comparison of two methods will be perform to assess better method for shoulder pain reduce.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of shoulder function measured in Constant-Murley Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Function of the shoulder will be assess by Constant Murlay score which describes shoulder function in daily routines: In this score range is 0-100 when 100 is the best result.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of shoulder function measured in SST Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Function of the shoulder will be assess by SST score which describes shoulder function in daily routines: In this score range is 0-100% when 100% is the best result.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of radiological outcome in Hamada score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Radiological outcome will be assessed by Hamada score. This score measure shoulder cuff arthropathy ( stage 1-5 when 1 is the best result). For every patient this score will be calculated through study completion and comparison of two methods will be performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of radiological outcome in Sugaya score</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 2.5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Radiological outcome will be assessed by Sugaya score. This score is used to measure quality of tendon reconstruction in MRI view. Range of points in this score is 1-5 when 1 is the best result. For every patient this score will be calculated through study completion and comparison of two methods will be performed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Massive Rotator Cuff Tears</condition>
  <condition>Rotator Cuff Injuries</condition>
  <condition>Shoulder Pain Chronic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment with biceps augmentation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Complete repair of ISP if possible with partial SSP repair and biceps augmentation after its tenodesis</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment without biceps augmentation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Complete repair of ISP if possible with partial SSP repair and biceps tenotomy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Arthroscopic partial repair of massive rotator cuff tear</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgery relies on arthroscopic reconstruction of the rotator cuff tendons. Because of irreparability of Supraspinatus tendon ( always) and infraspinatus tendon ( sometimes) surgeon performed partial repair to cover humeral head by the tendons</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment without biceps augmentation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Arthroscopic partial repair of rotator cuff with biceps augmentation</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgery relies on arthroscopic reconstruction of the rotator cuff tendons. Because of irreparability of Supraspinatus tendon ( always) and infraspinatus tendon ( sometimes) surgeon performed partial repair to cover humeral head by the tendons and because of good quality of the long head of the biceps tendon, its uses as biological reinforcement of the reconstruction to achieve better clinical and radiological outcome</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment with biceps augmentation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Massive and irreparable rotator cuff tear:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  chronic supraspinatus tear with retraction grade 3 and muscle fatty infiltration (&#xD;
             measured in MRI ) &gt; 3*&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infraspinatus tear with retraction and fatty muscle degeneration&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previosus surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Imposibility to performed MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  no compliance&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roman Brzoska, Ph.D, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>St Lukes's Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hubert Laprus, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+48 691 891 274</phone>
    <email>hubert.laprus@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Laprus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bielsko-Biala</city>
        <state>Śląskie</state>
        <zip>43-309</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hubert M Laprus, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+48 691891274</phone>
      <email>hubert.laprus@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Saint Lucas Hospital, Poland</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hubert Laprus</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Hubert Laprus, MD, Principal investigator. Department of Orthopaedic Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Massive rotator cuff</keyword>
  <keyword>Partial repair</keyword>
  <keyword>biceps augmentation</keyword>
  <keyword>shoulder arthroscopy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Shoulder Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rotator Cuff Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

