<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05008341</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>JZP110-401</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05008341</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluate Sunosi速 PK in Breast Milk and Plasma of Healthy Postpartum Women Following Single Dose Oral Administration</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 4, Open-Label, Single-Dose Study to Evaluate Sunosi速 (Solriamfetol) Pharmacokinetics in Breast Milk and Plasma of Healthy Postpartum Women Following Oral Administration of Sunosi速</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jazz Pharmaceuticals</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jazz Pharmaceuticals</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of study JZP110-401 is to evaluate solriamfetol pharmacokinetics (PK) in the&#xD;
      breast milk and plasma of healthy postpartum women following the administration of the drug.&#xD;
      The study also aims to estimate the potential daily solriamfetol dose received by the infant&#xD;
      from the breast milk of the nursing mother. The safety and tolerability of single oral doses&#xD;
      of solriamfetol will also be assessed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 27, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 27, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Concentration (Cmax) of Solriamfetol in Breast Milk and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The observed maximum breast milk and plasma concentrations (Cmax) of solriamfetol after administration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Reach Maximum Concentration (Cmax) (Tmax) in Breast Milk and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The time to reach the maximum breast milk and plasma concentrations (Tmax) of solriamfetol after administration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Concentration-Time Curve From Time 0 to the Time t of the Last Quantifiable Concentration (AUC 0-t) in Breast Milk and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The area under the plot of breast milk and plasma concentrations of solriamfetol against time after drug administration from predose (time 0) to Time t of the Last Quantifiable Concentration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area Under the Concentration-Time Curve From Time 0 to Infinity (AUC 0-inf) in Breast Milk and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The area under the plot of breast milk and plasma concentrations of solriamfetol against time after drug administration from predose (time 0) to Infinity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent Elimination Half-Life (t^1/2) of Solriamfetol in Breast Milk and Plasma</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The half-life or the period of time required for the concentration of solriamfetol in breast milk and plasma to be reduced to one-half of the administered amount.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent Oral Clearance (CL/F) of Solriamfetol</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent oral clearance (CL/F) of solriamfetol in plasma.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent Volume of Distribution (Vd/F) of Solriamfetol</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent volume of distribution (Vd/F) of solriamfetol in plasma.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Milk:Plasma Ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Area Under the concentration-time curve (AUC) in breast milk divided by AUC in plasma.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Amount Excreted in Breast Milk Over 72 Hours (Amilk)</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The amount of solriamfetol excreted in breast milk samples over 72 hours.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily Infant Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose, 1, 1.5, 3, 6, 8.5, 10, 13, 15, 21, 24, 28, 36, 44, and 72 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>Daily solriamfetol dose that may be received by the infant through breastfeeding.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Relative Infant Dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 24 hours post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of the weight-adjusted maternal solriamfetol dose excreted in breast milk over 24 hours.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment-Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Predose (-2 to 0 hours) up to Days 9-11 post-dose.</time_frame>
    <description>A treatment-emergent adverse event (TEAE) is defined as an adverse event (AE) that either began after first study drug dose or worsened after dosing.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Narcolepsy</condition>
  <condition>Obstructive Sleep Apnea</condition>
  <condition>Excessive Daytime Somnolence</condition>
  <condition>Excessive Sleepiness</condition>
  <condition>Postpartum</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Solriamfetol</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive a single oral dose of solriamfetol 150 mg with 240 mL water at 0 hour on the morning of Day 1, 2 hours after completion of a light breakfast.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Solriamfetol 150 mg Oral Tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>Single-dose 150 mg tablet orally administered.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Solriamfetol</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Sunosi速</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy adult female 18 to 50 years of age, inclusive, at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Weigh at least 50 kg, and have a body mass index within 18 to 35 kg/m2 inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Between 10 days and 52 weeks postpartum, inclusive, after delivery of a normal,&#xD;
             healthy infant by the time of dosing, and actively lactating from both breasts.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If breastfeeding, agree to withhold breastfeeding their infant(s) from approximately 2&#xD;
             hours before dosing to approximately 72 hours after dosing and resume breastfeeding&#xD;
             after completion of study Day 4 procedures OR have made a decision to wean their&#xD;
             infant(s) before enrollment in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Agree not to use nicotine-containing products including tobacco (cigarettes, cigars,&#xD;
             chewing tobacco, snuff), e-cigarettes, and nicotine lozenge/gum/patch within 3 days&#xD;
             prior to check-in on Day -1, and for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Have used a medically acceptable method of contraception for at least the 2 months&#xD;
             prior to dosing on Day 1, and consent to use a medically acceptable method of&#xD;
             contraception throughout the entire study period and for 30 days after the study is&#xD;
             completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Agree to comply with study-specified diet while in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Able to understand and comply with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Ensure that their breastfed infant(s) is able to feed from a bottle before study&#xD;
             participation begins.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Agree to ensure nutrition is available for their infant(s) through stored breast milk,&#xD;
             or alternative nutritional sources as necessary, for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Are pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of any illness, physical finding, laboratory examination or electrocardiogram&#xD;
             (ECG) finding that, in the opinion of the investigator, might confound the results or&#xD;
             conduct of the study or pose a risk to the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History or presence of gastrointestinal, hepatic, or renal disease or any other&#xD;
             condition that may interfere with absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion&#xD;
             of drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Estimated creatinine clearance of &lt; 90 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of breast implants, breast augmentation, or breast reduction surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Presence of mastitis or other condition that would prevent the collection of milk from&#xD;
             one or both breasts.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence of active suicidal ideation as assessed by the Columbia-Suicide Severity&#xD;
             Rating Scale (C-SSRS).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History or presence of any clinically significant cardiovascular conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Resting supine systolic blood pressure &gt; 140 mmHg or &lt; 90 mmHg or supine diastolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &gt; 90 mmHg or &lt; 50 mmHg at the Screening Visit or at predose on Day 1.&#xD;
             Blood pressure measurement may be repeated once at the discretion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Resting supine pulse rate of &lt; 45 beats per minute (bpm) or &gt;100 bpm at the Screening&#xD;
             Visit or at predose on Day 1. Pulse rate measurement may be repeated once at the&#xD;
             discretion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Unwilling to refrain from, or anticipates the use of, any medication, including&#xD;
             prescription (with the exception of contraceptive agents) and non-prescription drugs&#xD;
             (with the exception of acetaminophen no more than 2600 mg a day and ibuprofen no more&#xD;
             than 1200 mg a day), antacids, vitamin supplements, or herbal remedies, beginning 14&#xD;
             days or 5 half-lives (whichever is longer) prior to Day 1 through the completion of&#xD;
             breast milk collection and blood sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Use of a monoamine oxidase inhibitor within 14 days prior to Day 1 through the&#xD;
             completion of breast milk collection and blood sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Unwilling to abstain from alcohol or caffeine/xanthine-containing products, including&#xD;
             coffee, tea, chocolate, and cola, within 48 hours prior to Day 1 through the&#xD;
             completion of breast milk collection and blood sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Self-reported routine consumption of more than 600 mg of caffeine per day.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Positive breath alcohol or urine drug screen (including cannabinoids) at screening or&#xD;
             at any point throughout the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Current or past (within the past 2 years) diagnosis of a moderate or severe substance&#xD;
             use disorder according to Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, 5th&#xD;
             Edition (DSM-5) criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Current or history (within the past 2 years) of seeking treatment for a substance&#xD;
             related disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. History or presence of phenylketonuria or a hypersensitivity or idiosyncratic reaction&#xD;
             to phenylalanine-derived products, or any excipient in the formulated drug product.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Has participated in another clinical trial of an investigational drug or medical&#xD;
             device within 30 days or five half-lives (whichever is longer) prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Any other condition that would cause a risk to the participant if they participate in&#xD;
             the trial, or to the ability of the participant to complete the study, based on the&#xD;
             judgement of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Employee of the study unit or Jazz Pharmaceuticals, anyone involved in the conduct of&#xD;
             the trial, and first- and second-degree family member of anyone involved in the&#xD;
             conduct of the trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Clinical Trial Disclosure &amp; Transparency</last_name>
    <phone>215-832-3750</phone>
    <email>ClinicalTrialDisclosure@JazzPharma.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M3-Wake Research, Inc.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Raleigh</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sunosi</keyword>
  <keyword>Solriamfetol</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Postpartum Women</keyword>
  <keyword>Breast Milk</keyword>
  <keyword>Plasma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sleep Apnea, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Narcolepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Disorders of Excessive Somnolence</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleepiness</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

