<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05008692</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-5205</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05008692</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Apple-CPET Ted Rogers Understanding Exacerbations of Heart Failure</brief_title>
  <acronym>TRUE-HF</acronym>
  <official_title>Measuring Cardiopulmonary Fitness in Ambulatory Heart Failure Patients Through the Use of Apple Watch Features</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Health Network, Toronto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Apple Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Health Network, Toronto</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Heart Failure (HF) is a complex disease associated with the highest burden of cost to the&#xD;
      healthcare system. The cardiopulmonary exercise test (CPET) is instrumental in determining&#xD;
      the prognosis of patients with HF. This study will evaluate whether aggregate biometric data&#xD;
      from the Apple Watch combined with demographic, cardiac, and biomarker testing can improve&#xD;
      our ability to predict heart failure outcomes among a diverse ambulatory HF population&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Heart Failure (HF) has a prevalence of 3.5% suggesting that over one million Canadians are&#xD;
      affected by this disease, and more than 50,000 are newly diagnosed each year. This complex&#xD;
      disease is associated with the highest burden of cost to the healthcare system, attributable&#xD;
      to hospitalizations, missed work, medications, and health care services&#xD;
&#xD;
      Traditionally, clinicians have relied on static snapshots of patients to determine clinical&#xD;
      status and estimate prognosis. More advanced cardiac centers rely on cardiopulmonary exercise&#xD;
      testing (CPET), where patients are further stratified based on validated exercise parameters.&#xD;
      CPET remains underutilized and resource-intensive. It requires expensive equipment,&#xD;
      proficient personnel, and clinicians with specialized training. Thus, there is an unmet need&#xD;
      for a more widely available, accessible, and longitudinal assessment of clinical status to&#xD;
      better monitor and prognosticate patients outside of the ambulatory setting. Wearable devices&#xD;
      such as the Apple Watch hold great promise in this regard, as they provide near-continuous&#xD;
      monitoring of biometric data. By combining biometric data with demographic, cardiac, and&#xD;
      biomarker testing, the investigators will significantly improve our ability to predict heart&#xD;
      failure outcomes such as early warning of decompensation, clinical deterioration (symptoms&#xD;
      and brain natriuretic peptide (BNP) as a surrogate), hospitalization, mortality (using the&#xD;
      Seattle Heart Failure Model (SHFM) as a surrogate), and/or need for advanced heart failure&#xD;
      therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our study has 5 research questions based on 2 primary outcomes and 3 secondary outcomes in&#xD;
      clinically diverse adult ambulatory heart failure patients :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Research Question:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Can biometric data obtained from the Apple Watch be used to estimate cardiorespiratory&#xD;
           fitness, as assessed by CPET?&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Does the 'predicted' Apple 6 MW estimate correlate with formal 6 MWT?&#xD;
&#xD;
           Secondary Research Questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Is there a relationship between novel biosensors, including oxygen saturation, and&#xD;
           markers of poor prognosis specifically as defined by the SHFM, BNP, Quality of life&#xD;
           (QOL) indicators, and CPET parameters?&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Can surrogates of cardiorespiratory fitness obtained from the Apple Watch, including&#xD;
           novel biosensors, predict acute decompensation of heart failure as defined rapid clinic&#xD;
           visits, need for IV diuretics, ED visits, heart failure hospitalization and unscheduled&#xD;
           health care encounters during the 3-month follow-up?&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Can biometric data be used to improve a risk prediction model that can distinguish&#xD;
           between patients at high versus low risk of all-cause hospitalization (primary outcome),&#xD;
           all-cause mortality (secondary outcome), and a composite outcome of all-cause mortality,&#xD;
           need for ventricular assist device, or heart transplantation (secondary composite&#xD;
           outcome) over a 2 year period?&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Apple Watch metrics prediction of CPET parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Measure predictive power of Apple Watch metrics such as heart rate against CPET parameters such as peak VO2</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>6 minute walk test</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of Apple 6MW estimate with measured 6MWT</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apple Watch sensors and markers of poor prognosis</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between novel biosensors, including oxygen saturation, and markers of poor prognosis specifically as defined by the Seattle Heart Failure Model (SHFM), BNP, Quality of life (QOL) and CPET parameters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apple Watch Sensors and unscheduled visits</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Identify whether Apple Watch sensors including estimated peak VO2 predict a composite outcome of unscheduled visits (including: rapid clinic visits, need for IV diuretics, ED visit and HF hospitalization)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biomarkers and digital signatures as a predictor of composite rehospitalisation, advanced therapies and mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Identify novel biomarkers (eg. ST2, cell-free DNA, peripheral markers of the microbiome) collected by the biobank and digital signatures assessed by the Apple Watch (eg. behaviors, exercise, medication adherence) that predict a composite outcome of mortality, advanced heart failure therapies and hospitalizations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Heart Failure, Systolic</condition>
  <condition>Heart Failure, Diastolic</condition>
  <condition>Heart Transplantation</condition>
  <condition>Heart Failure，Congestive</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult (&gt;17 years of age), ambulatory heart failure patients currently followed by the&#xD;
        University Health Network.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  broad age range (&gt; 17 years of age)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diverse races/ethnicities,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  equal female and male representation,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NYHA functional class I-IV, heart failure with reduced and preserved ejection fraction&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Physical disability that prevents exercise testing&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Heather J Ross, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Health Network, Toronto</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Enza De Luca, RN</last_name>
    <phone>416-340-4800</phone>
    <email>enza.deluca@uhn.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Farid Foroutan, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>416-340-4800</phone>
    <email>farid.foroutan@uhn.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Toronto General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 2N2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Enza De Luca, RN</last_name>
      <phone>416-340-4800</phone>
      <email>enza.deluca@uhn.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Health Network, Toronto</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Heather Ross</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Chief Division of Cardiology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Wearable</keyword>
  <keyword>Apple Watch</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiopulmonary Exercise Test</keyword>
  <keyword>6MWT</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarker</keyword>
  <keyword>peak VO2</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient Reported Outcomes</keyword>
  <keyword>QOL</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure, Systolic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure, Diastolic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

