<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05001763</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IUNU-UC-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05001763</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prucalopride for Postoperative Ileus in Patients Undergoing Robot-assisted Laparoscopic Radical Cystectomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial of Prucaloprude Succinate in Promoting the Recovery of Intestinal Function After Robot-assisted Laparoscopic Radical Cystectomy and Urinary Diversion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Affiliated Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Affiliated Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The first purpose is to determine whether prucalopride can promote the recovery of intestinal&#xD;
      function after robot-assisted laparoscopic radical cystectomy and urinary diversion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary objectives is to speed up postoperative ventilation, defecation, reduce the&#xD;
      time of first solid food tolerance, reduce postoperative hospital stay, reduce the incidence&#xD;
      of readmission due to intestinal obstruction and the incidence of complications within 180&#xD;
      days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The incidence of bladder cancer is getting higher and higher. 30% of them are myometrial&#xD;
      invasive bladder cancer, which requires radical cystectomy. This operation is more traumatic,&#xD;
      because it involves many physiological structures, and there will be many postoperative&#xD;
      complications, of which intestinal complications are the most common. The main manifestation&#xD;
      is postoperative ileus (POI).&#xD;
&#xD;
      At present, one is chewing gum after surgery, and the other is the Avimopan, which is&#xD;
      recognized as the method to promote intestinal recovery after operation. Avimopan is a&#xD;
      peripheral μ-opioid receptor antagonist, which can improve intestinal dysfunction. Because&#xD;
      Avimopan has not been widely used in China, its clinical application is limited. It is&#xD;
      reported that prucalopride may be one of the methods to promote the recovery of intestinal&#xD;
      motility after operation. Prucalopride, an alternative to benzamide, has selective 5-HT4&#xD;
      agonist activity and has previously been shown to significantly improve intestinal motility&#xD;
      and transport. The drug was well tolerated and there was no obvious adverse reaction. In&#xD;
      addition, prucalopride has been approved in Europe and America for symptomatic treatment of&#xD;
      chronic constipation in women whose laxatives do not provide adequate relief. However, its&#xD;
      perioperative use in radical cystectomy has not been tested. This study will test the ability&#xD;
      and safety of prucalopride to promote the recovery of postoperative intestinal function 2&#xD;
      days before radical cystectomy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to defaecation, measured in hours, from the time the surgery ends till the first observed</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 days after surgery</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative first passing flatus reported by the patients</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 days after surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>First solid food tolerance time</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 30 days after surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative C-reactive protein(CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>postoperative day 1 and 3</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of postoperative hospital stay (LOS)(days)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days or until hospital discharge whichever occurs first</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of readmission within 180 days</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 180 days after surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of complications defined according to the Clavien-Dindo Classification within 180 days</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 180 days after surgery</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events related to drug usage</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 7 days after drug usage</time_frame>
    <description>include Diarrhoea, Flatulence, Nausea, Abdominal pain, Headaches, Menstrual disorder, Dizziness, Skeletal pain, ECG nodal arrhythmia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Postoperative Ileus</condition>
  <condition>Bladder Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Glucose, 2mg, tablet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prucalopride</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Prucalopride, 2mg, tablet. First given 2 days before surgery beginning on POD 1, until defecation or for a maximum of 7 days of postoperative treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prucalopride</intervention_name>
    <description>Prucalopride, 2mg, tablet. First given 2 days before surgery beginning on POD 1, until defecation or for a maximum of 7 days of postoperative treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prucalopride</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Resolor</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Glucose, 2mg, tablet.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. patients who are prepared to undergo robot-assisted laparoscopic radical cystectomy +&#xD;
             urinary diversion due to bladder tumor;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. urinary diversion: ileal cystectomy or orthotopic neobladder;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. age ≥ 18 years old and ≤ 80 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG score ≤ 1;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. important laboratory indicators meet:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Blood routine test: neutrophil count ≥ 1.5 × 109 g / L, leukocyte count ≥ 4.0 ×&#xD;
                  109 × 10 ~ 9/L, platelet count ≥ 100 × 109 / L, hemoglobin ≥ 9 g /dl&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Electrolytes: 135mmol/L ≤ serum sodium ≤ 145mmol/L , 2.25mmol/L ≤ serum calcium ≤&#xD;
                  2.75mmol/l, 3.5mmolexL ≤ serum potassium ≤ 5.5mmo/L; Liver function index:&#xD;
                  glutamic pyruvic transaminase (ALT) and aspartate oxaloacetic transaminase (AST)&#xD;
                  ≤ 2.5 times the upper limit of normal value (ULN), total bilirubin TBIL ≤ 1.5 ×&#xD;
                  ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
             d. Renal function: serum creatinine ≤ 21. 5 × ULN, eGFR ≥ 30 mL / min; e. Coagulation&#xD;
             function: international standardized ratio (INR) &lt; 1.5. f. The left ventricular&#xD;
             ejection fraction ((LVEF)) was 50%;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The drugs that affected the observation of this experiment were not used one week&#xD;
             before the selection. Atropine drugs; P-glycoprotein inhibitors: ketoconazole,&#xD;
             verapamil, cyclosporine A, quinidine; erythromycin;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have good defecation habits, which is defecating more than 3 times a week;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Have no previous intestinal surgery and no history of other tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The subjects voluntarily participated, and the subjects themselves must sign an&#xD;
             informed consent form (ICF), to show that they understand the purpose and procedures&#xD;
             of this study, and are willing to participate in the study. Subjects must be willing&#xD;
             and comply with the prohibitions and restrictions set out in the study program.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who cannot tolerate radical cystectomy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. patients with myometrial invasive urothelial carcinoma with distant metastasis&#xD;
             (abdominal CT scan + enhancement, chest CT scan, ECT- bone scan, PET-CT, MRI, etc.).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. uncontrollable concomitant diseases, including, but not limited to, persistent&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, arrhythmia, interstitial lung disease, severe chronic&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disease associated with diarrhoea, or mental illness / social&#xD;
             conditions, which will limit compliance with research requirements, significantly&#xD;
             increase the risk of AE or impair the patient's ability to write informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with the allergy or hypersensitivity of prucalopride;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients with active or symptomatic viral hepatitis or other chronic liver diseases,&#xD;
             known to be infected with human immunodeficiency virus (HIV);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active pulmonary tuberculosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients with severe heart, liver and kidney diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with a history of constipation, which is defined as defecation less than 3&#xD;
             times a week, and strenuous defecation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with inflammatory bowel disease (ulcerative colitis or Crohn's disease);&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients with rare genetic diseases such as galactose intolerance, Lapp lactase&#xD;
             deficiency or glucose-galactose malabsorption shall not take prucalopride.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Previous operations involving intestinal, history of other tumors, history of&#xD;
             intestinal obstruction;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Lack of legal capacity or limitation of legal capacity;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Other situations in which researchers considered it inappropriate to participate in&#xD;
             this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Elimination standard&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those who were treated with other local or systemic that interfere this study at the&#xD;
             same time;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Using other foods and drugs that interfere the tolerance judgment at the same time;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Violating the requirements of the study scheme, not according to the dose and course&#xD;
             of treatment specified in the study plan;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Poor quality, incomplete and inaccurate of data recording;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Poor compliance;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Loss of follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Termination criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects require discontinuation of research treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Deterioration of disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any clinical AE, laboratory examination abnormalities or concomitant diseases,&#xD;
             according to the judgment of the researchers, continuing to participate in the study&#xD;
             is not the greatest benefit to the subjects;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Serious adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The informed consent form can no longer be signed freely because of imprisonment or&#xD;
             forced detention for the treatment of mental illness or somatic disease (such as&#xD;
             infectious diseases);&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Postoperative imagings indicate ileus;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. At the end of treatment, the function of intestines still do not recover.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hongqian Guo, MD</last_name>
    <phone>13605171690</phone>
    <email>dr.ghq@nju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Shiwei Zhang, MD</last_name>
    <phone>13813916981</phone>
    <email>zsw999@hotmall.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Affiliated Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Hongqian Guo</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Executive officer of Department of Urology, Drum Tower Hospital, Medical School of Nanjing University, Institute of Urology, Nanjing University</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ileus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prucalopride</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

