<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05009394</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-02346</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05009394</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Surgical Treatments for Post-amputation Pain in Amputees</brief_title>
  <official_title>Surgical Treatments for Post-amputation Pain in Amputees</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Chalmers University of Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Sweden</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Göteborg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Chalmers University of Technology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a double-blind randomised controlled trial (RCT) on three surgical techniques for the&#xD;
      treatment of neuroma pain, however we will also monitor stump pain and phantom limb pain. The&#xD;
      three treatments are targeted muscles reinnervation (TMR), regenerative peripheral nerve&#xD;
      interface (RPNI), and an active control (non-reconstructive TMR). Patients will be follow-up&#xD;
      for 5 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Neuroma pain, stump pain, and phantom limb pain (PLP) can develop after the loss of a body&#xD;
      part and fall within the umbrella term post-amputation pain. However, the underlaying causes&#xD;
      to post-amputation pain are diverse and must be addressed accordingly. Surgical treatments&#xD;
      for neuroma pain have become a popular approach and have shown great potential for successful&#xD;
      outcomes. The two surgical interventions, Targeted Muscle Reinnervation (TMR) and&#xD;
      Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interface (RPNI), are globally used in pain management&#xD;
      therapies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This double-blind RCT will take place at Sahlgrenska University Hospital, Mölndal, Sweden.&#xD;
      Thirty-three participants with neuroma pain who are suitable for a surgical approach to&#xD;
      manage this pain, will be recruited and randomly assigned to one of the surgical treatments&#xD;
      (TMR, RPNI or control) in an allocation ratio of 1:1:1 (n=11 per group). Each participant&#xD;
      will be followed-up in the short-term (1-, 3-, 6-, 12-months post-surgery) and in the&#xD;
      long-term (3- and 5-years post-surgery). After the 12-months follow-up, the study will be&#xD;
      unblinded for the evaluator and the participants. At this time, if a participant experiences&#xD;
      no change in pain or is unsatisfied with the result, further treatment will be discussed with&#xD;
      the clinical investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study design is chosen to be able to follow neuroma pain, stump pain and phantom limb&#xD;
      pain intensity before and after surgical treatment as well as to investigate how pain&#xD;
      develops up to five years post-surgery. The evaluation methods in the study are based on&#xD;
      previously used methods in the literature for neuroma-, stump- and PLP-related pain research.&#xD;
      The questionnaires are previously used in clinical settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This project will be conducted at the Center for Bionics and Pain Research (CBPR), which is&#xD;
      an interdisciplinary collaboration between Chalmers University of Technology (Chalmers),&#xD;
      Sahlgrenska University Hospital (SU), and the University of Gothenburg (GU).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuroma pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>12-months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in neuroma pain intensity will be measured by numerical rating scale (NRS, 0-10), where 0 - no pain and 10 - worst imaginable pain, between baseline period and at the 12-months follow-up visit.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stump pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>12-months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in stump pain intensity will be measured by numerical rating scale (NRS, 0-10), where 0 - no pain and 10 - worst imaginable pain, between baseline period and at the 12-months follow-up visit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phantom limb pain (PLP) intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>12-months post-surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Difference in PLP intensity will be measured by numerical rating scale (NRS, 0-10), where 0 - no pain and 10 - worst imaginable pain, between baseline period and at the 12-months follow-up visit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">33</enrollment>
  <condition>Amputation Neuroma</condition>
  <condition>Amputation Stump</condition>
  <condition>Phantom Limb Pain</condition>
  <condition>Pain, Neuropathic</condition>
  <condition>Pain, Nerve</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Targeted Muscle Reinnervation (TMR)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this surgical procedure, the residual peripheral nerve is transferred to an available muscle in the stump that has been deinnervated from its native nerve. The surgical procedure includes three core steps: preparation of the residual nerve; motor nerve identification from the targeted muscle; and coaptation. To prepare the residual nerve, the surgeon identifies the injured nerve that has developed a painful neuroma and cuts the nerve back to healthy fascicles. Next, the surgeon dissects the motor nerve to a nearby target and thereby denervates a native muscle. Lastly, the injured nerve where the neuroma was excised is transferred and coapted to the newly severed motor nerve stump innervating the targe muscle. The surgery time is approximately 2-3 hours and it takes place in the hospital. The patient can leave the hospital the same day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interface (RPNI)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The RPNI procedure involves construction of a residual peripheral nerve split into several nerve fascicles and implanted into free skeletal muscle grafts. The surgeon first identifies the injured nerve and excises the terminal neuroma. Then, this peripheral nerve is transected into several intraneural fascicles. Next, autologous muscle grafts are harvested from a healthy donor site and the transected nerve endings are placed in the middle part of each muscle graft, in parallel to the muscle fibres. The muscle graft is wrapped around the distal transected nerve ending and anchored by epimysial sutures, and an RPNI is created. This is repeated for each group of fascicles obtained from splitting a transected nerve. The surgery time is approximately 2-3 hours and it takes place in the hospital. The patient can leave the hospital the same day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard neuroma treatment, neuroma excision and muscle burying</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The standard neuroma treatment includes excision of the terminal neuroma and burying the nerve into an adjacent deep muscle. As in the TMR and RPNI procedure, the surgeon starts with finding the injured nerve and excises the terminal neuroma into healthy fascicles. Next, the surgeon identifies a deep nearby muscle which is away from joint motion and has limited output opportunities for the nerve. The nerve is then channelled inside to the deep muscle without applying any tension on it and secured by sutures. The surgery time is approximately 1-2 hours and it takes place in the hospital. The patient can leave the hospital the same day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Targeted Muscle Reinnervation (TMR)</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical procedure used to rewire injured proximal nerves to motor nerves directly innervating an otherwise redundant target muscle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Targeted Muscle Reinnervation (TMR)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interface (RPNI)</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical procedure where the injured nerve is split into fascicles and wrapped in free muscle grafts.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interface (RPNI)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard neuroma treatment, neuroma excision and muscle burying</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical procedure without any nerve reconstruction, where the injured nerve is buried in an adjacent deep muscle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard neuroma treatment, neuroma excision and muscle burying</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant is ≥ 18 years old at time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant must be in generally good health to manage a surgical treatment, as&#xD;
             per the clinical investigator's opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The post-operative amputation follow-up is greater than 1 year at time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant must be diagnosed with neuroma pain within their residual limb(s), at&#xD;
             latest the time of screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant must have a neuroma pain intensity average of &gt;2 on the Numerical&#xD;
             Rating Scale (NRS) after the baseline period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If the participant is under pharmacological treatments, there must be no variations on&#xD;
             the medication dosages (steady consumption) for at least 1 month before the screening&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The participant has sufficient understanding of Swedish or English to be able to&#xD;
             participate in all study assessments, per the principal investigator's opinion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurological or other conditions that affect nerve regeneration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active infection or bacteria in the residual limb.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The candidate has used tobacco within 6 weeks prior to surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mental inability, reluctance or language difficulties that result in difficulty&#xD;
             understanding the meaning of study participation, as per the principal investigator's&#xD;
             discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing participation in a clinical study that the clinical investigator deems to be&#xD;
             detrimental to participation in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Max Ortiz Catalan, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chalmers University of Technology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Emily Pettersen, MSc</last_name>
    <email>emily.pettersen@vgregion.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Paolo Sassu, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <email>paolo.sassu@vgregion.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Center for Bionics and Pain Research, CBPR</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mölndal</city>
        <state>Västra Götaland</state>
        <zip>431 80</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dumanian GA, Potter BK, Mioton LM, Ko JH, Cheesborough JE, Souza JM, Ertl WJ, Tintle SM, Nanos GP, Valerio IL, Kuiken TA, Apkarian AV, Porter K, Jordan SW. Targeted Muscle Reinnervation Treats Neuroma and Phantom Pain in Major Limb Amputees: A Randomized Clinical Trial. Ann Surg. 2019 Aug;270(2):238-246. doi: 10.1097/SLA.0000000000003088.</citation>
    <PMID>30371518</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Souza JM, Cheesborough JE, Ko JH, Cho MS, Kuiken TA, Dumanian GA. Targeted muscle reinnervation: a novel approach to postamputation neuroma pain. Clin Orthop Relat Res. 2014 Oct;472(10):2984-90. doi: 10.1007/s11999-014-3528-7.</citation>
    <PMID>24562875</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Woo SL, Kung TA, Brown DL, Leonard JA, Kelly BM, Cederna PS. Regenerative Peripheral Nerve Interfaces for the Treatment of Postamputation Neuroma Pain: A Pilot Study. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2016 Dec 27;4(12):e1038. doi: 10.1097/GOX.0000000000001038. eCollection 2016 Dec.</citation>
    <PMID>28293490</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Chalmers University of Technology</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Max Ortiz Catalan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neuroma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Phantom Limb</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neuralgia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

