<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05002998</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HZNP-TEP-402</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-005999-36</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05002998</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>TEPEZZA® (Teprotumumab-trbw) Post-Marketing Requirement Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3b/4, Double-masked, Randomized, International, Parallel-assignment, Multicenter Trial in Patients With Thyroid Eye Disease to Evaluate the Safety and Tolerability of Different Dosing Durations of Teprotumumab</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Horizon Therapeutics USA, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Horizon Pharma USA, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a double-masked, randomized, parallel-assignment, multicenter trial examining the&#xD;
      safety and tolerability of teprotumumab in the treatment of Thyroid Eye Disease (TED) in&#xD;
      adult participants. This international, Phase 3b/4 trial is being conducted to fulfill an FDA&#xD;
      post-marketing requirement for a descriptive trial to evaluate the safety, efficacy and need&#xD;
      for re-treatment of 3 different teprotumumab treatment durations for TED. In addition, serum&#xD;
      samples from participants with a Baseline Clinical Activity Score (CAS) ≥3 will be evaluated&#xD;
      for biomarkers of disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants will be screened for eligibility within 4 weeks prior to the Baseline (Day 1)&#xD;
      Visit. Approximately 300 participants who meet the trial eligibility criteria will be&#xD;
      randomized on Day 1 in a 1:1:1 ratio in a double-masked fashion (stratified by CAS(clinical&#xD;
      activity score) [≥3 (active) or &lt;3 (inactive)] and disease severity [severe disease, defined&#xD;
      as both proptosis above normal for race and gender with binocular diplopia at Baseline vs.&#xD;
      non-severe disease]) to receive:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  4 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the&#xD;
           remaining 3 infusions) (Cohort 1) followed by 4 infusions of:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Placebo if a participants is a treatment responder at Week 12 or&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Teprotumumab 20 mg/kg if a participant is a treatment non-responder at Week 12&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  8 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the&#xD;
           remaining 7 infusions) (Cohort 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  16 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the&#xD;
           remaining 15 infusions) (Cohort 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three weeks following the final infusion of the Initial Treatment Period, there will be a&#xD;
      comprehensive End-of-Initial Treatment Visit at Week 24 (Cohorts 1 and 2)/Week 48 (Cohort 3).&#xD;
      At this visit, all participants will be assessed for treatment response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proptosis responders in all cohorts and non-responders in Cohorts 1 and 2 who choose not to&#xD;
      receive a second treatment course, will enter a 52 week Initial Follow-up Period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proptosis non-responders in Cohorts 1 and 2 who choose to receive a second treatment course&#xD;
      (8 infusions) of teprotumumab will receive an infusion q3W.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proptosis non-responders in Cohort 3 are not eligible for a second treatment course following&#xD;
      initial treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in any of the 3 cohorts who are proptosis responders following the Initial&#xD;
      Treatment Period and who flare during the Initial Follow up Period will be eligible to&#xD;
      receive re treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>4 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the remaining 3 infusions) (Cohort 1) followed by 4 infusions of:&#xD;
Placebo if a participant is a treatment responder at Week 12 or&#xD;
Teprotumumab 20 mg/kg if a participant is a treatment non-responder at Week 12&#xD;
8 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the remaining 7 infusions) (Cohort 2)&#xD;
16 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the remaining 15 infusions) (Cohort 3)</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-masked except for the pharmacy staff.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who experience at least 1 treatment-emergent adverse event (TEAE) and the percentage of participants who experience at least 1 AESI during treatment with teprotumumab</measure>
    <time_frame>Screening to End of Study (last visit possible is Week 136)</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment emergent adverse events and adverse events of special interest will be evaluated from the beginning of the study until follow up.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percentage of Participants who receive re-treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 27 to Week 136</time_frame>
    <description>Participants who are not proptosis responders after initial treatment or participants who are proptosis responders after initial treatment but who have flared during follow-up (relapsed).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Thyroid Eye Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 4 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>• 4 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the remaining 3 infusions) (Cohort 1) followed by 4 infusions of:&#xD;
Placebo if a participant is a treatment responder at Week 12 or&#xD;
Teprotumumab 20 mg/kg if a participant is a treatment non-responder at Week 12</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 8 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>8 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the remaining 7 infusions) (Cohort 2)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 16 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>16 infusions of teprotumumab (10 mg/kg for the first infusion and 20 mg/kg for the remaining 15 infusions) (Cohort 3)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Teprotumumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Teprotumumab is a fully human anti-IGF-1R mAb. Teprotumumab will be provided in single-dose 20-mL glass vials as a freeze-dried powder containing, in addition to the drug substance, 20 mmol/L histidine-histidine chloride, 250 mmol/L trehalose and 0.01% polysorbate 20 (w/w).&#xD;
Prior to administration, each vial containing 500 mg teprotumumab freeze-dried powder will be reconstituted with 10 mL of sterile water for injection. The resulting solution will have a concentration of 47.6 mg/mL teprotumumab-trbw antibody. The reconstituted teprotumumab solution must be further diluted in 0.9% (w/v) sodium chloride (NaCl) solution prior to administration</description>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 16 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 4 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 8 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TEPEZZA</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo will consist of a normal saline (0.9% NaCl) solution and will be administered in 100 mL or 250 mL infusion bags, as appropriate, per weight-based dosing volumes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Teprotumumab 4 Infusions</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Saline Solution</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female between the ages of 18 and 80 years, inclusive, at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Initial diagnosis of TED within 7 years prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Proptosis ≥3 mm from baseline (prior to diagnosis of TED), as estimated by treating&#xD;
             physician, and/or proptosis &gt;3 mm above normal for race and gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants must be euthyroid with the baseline disease under control or have mild&#xD;
             hypo or hyperthyroidism (defined as free thyroxine and free triiodothyronine levels&#xD;
             &lt;50% above or below the normal limits) at Screening. Every effort should be made to&#xD;
             correct the mild hypo- or hyperthyroidism promptly and to maintain the euthyroid state&#xD;
             for the duration of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Does not require immediate surgical ophthalmological intervention and is not planning&#xD;
             corrective surgery/irradiation during the course of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Diabetic participants must have HbA1c ≤8.0% at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participants with a history of IBD (ulcerative colitis or Crohn's disease) must be in&#xD;
             clinical remission for at least 3 months, with no history of bowel surgery within 6&#xD;
             months prior to Screening and no planned surgery during the trial. Concomitant stable&#xD;
             therapies for IBD without modifications in the 3 months prior to Screening are&#xD;
             allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Women of childbearing potential (including those with an onset of menopause &lt;2 years&#xD;
             prior to Screening, non-therapy-induced amenorrhea for &lt;12 months prior to Screening&#xD;
             or not surgically sterile [absence of ovaries and/or uterus]) must have a negative&#xD;
             serum pregnancy test at Screening and negative urine pregnancy tests at all&#xD;
             protocol-specified time points (i.e., prior to each dose and throughout the&#xD;
             participant's participation in the Follow-up Period); participants who are sexually&#xD;
             active with a non-vasectomized male partner must agree to use 2 reliable forms of&#xD;
             contraception during the trial, 1 of which is recommended to be hormonal, such as an&#xD;
             oral contraceptive. Hormonal contraception must be started at least 1 full cycle prior&#xD;
             to Baseline and continue for 180 days after the last dose of teprotumumab. Highly&#xD;
             effective contraceptive methods (with a failure rate &lt;1% per year), when used&#xD;
             consistently and correctly, include implants, injectables, combination oral&#xD;
             contraceptives, some intrauterine devices, sexual abstinence or vasectomized partner.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Willing and able to comply with the prescribed treatment protocol and evaluations for&#xD;
             the duration of the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Decreased best-corrected visual acuity due to optic neuropathy, as defined by a&#xD;
             decrease in vision of 2 lines on the Snellen chart, new visual field defect or color&#xD;
             defect secondary to optic nerve involvement within the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Corneal decompensation unresponsive to medical management.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Decrease in proptosis of ≥2 mm in the study eye between Screening and Baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Prior orbital irradiation, orbital decompression or strabismus surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Alanine aminotransferase or aspartate aminotransferase &gt;3 × the upper limit of normal&#xD;
             or estimated glomerular filtration rate ≤30 mL/min/1.73m2 at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Use of any steroid (intravenous [IV], oral, steroid eye drops) for the treatment of&#xD;
             TED or other conditions within 3 weeks prior to Screening. Steroids cannot be&#xD;
             initiated during the trial. Exceptions include topical and inhaled steroids, as well&#xD;
             as steroids used to treat infusion reactions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any treatment with rituximab (Rituxan® or MabThera®) within 12 months prior to the&#xD;
             first infusion of teprotumumab or tocilizumab (Actemra® or Roactemra®) within 6 months&#xD;
             prior to the first infusion of teprotumumab. Use of any other non-steroid&#xD;
             immunosuppressive agent within 3 months prior to the first infusion of teprotumumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any previous treatment with teprotumumab, including previous enrollment in this trial&#xD;
             or participation in a prior teprotumumab trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Treatment with any mAb within 3 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Identified pre-existing ophthalmic disease that, in the judgment of the Investigator,&#xD;
             would preclude trial participation or complicate interpretation of trial results.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Use of an investigational agent for any condition within 60 days or 5 half-lives,&#xD;
             whichever is longer, prior to Screening or anticipated use during the course of the&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Malignant condition in the past 5 years (except successfully treated basal/squamous&#xD;
             cell carcinoma of the skin or cervical cancer in situ).&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Current drug or alcohol abuse or history of either within the previous 2 years, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator or as reported by the participant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Known hypersensitivity to any of the components of teprotumumab or prior&#xD;
             hypersensitivity reactions to mAbs.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Human immunodeficiency virus, untreated or positive viral load for hepatitis C or&#xD;
             hepatitis B infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any other condition that, in the opinion of the Investigator, would preclude inclusion&#xD;
             in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. After 150 participants with a CAS &lt;3 at Baseline have been randomized, an additional&#xD;
             exclusion criterion will apply: CAS &lt;3 at Baseline.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Saba Sile, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Horizon Therapeutics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Horizon Therapeutics</last_name>
    <phone>1-866-479-6742</phone>
    <email>clinicaltrials@horizontherapeutics.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.TEPEZZA.com</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>TED</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Eye Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Graves Ophthalmopathy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

