<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05005325</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC/0867 Fatima Amjad</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05005325</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Functional Movement Screen Differences in Male and Female Footballers as an Injury Prevention Tool.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Functional Movement Screen Differences in Male and Female Footballers as an Injury Prevention Tool.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Football is definitely a sport commonly held across the world. It is played mostly at the&#xD;
      professional level and as a leisure sport as well. Many countries organize football matches&#xD;
      at different levels, and these matches include various age groups ranging from adolescents to&#xD;
      young adults. As the participation in football is increasing it is also increasing the risk&#xD;
      of developing injuries. It exposes the athlete to contact injuries and non-contact injuries.&#xD;
      The intensity of the body's biomechanical and physiological reactions when playing football&#xD;
      is enhanced because it has sporadic and irregular activity. This increased workload can&#xD;
      increase the risk of injury. Many sport specialists perform movements which are related to&#xD;
      that specific sport but the paradigm has been shifted to a more integrated functional&#xD;
      approach which includes principles of proprioceptive neuromuscular facilitation, muscle&#xD;
      synergy and motor learning and it is important to inspect the basic fundamental movements as&#xD;
      these occur throughout many athletic activities. Before participating in the sporting event,&#xD;
      athletes undergo a comprehensive pre-participation examination which includes examination of&#xD;
      health status, underlying medical problems and musculoskeletal system, it is a standard&#xD;
      approach to injury screening. However, this does not evaluate the intrinsic risk factors&#xD;
      which might be associated with the injury during field.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Functional movement screening (FMS) was developed by Cook et al. It evaluates range of&#xD;
      motion, muscular imbalances and core strength by means of seven different movement. It is&#xD;
      used to analyze the pattern of various fundamental movements and then highlights the&#xD;
      limitations in that pattern and recognizes asymmetries in relation to that pattern of&#xD;
      movement and eventually compares these inadequacies with outcomes that will improve a&#xD;
      pragmatic approach to injury prevention. Prior studies reported that during pre-participation&#xD;
      FMS can predict injuries in various athletes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several research studies carried out by researchers in this area have been involved in the&#xD;
      exploring the strategies that can enhance the efficiency and performance of footballers in&#xD;
      the field and investigate the effects of injuries on performance. Studies including FMS as an&#xD;
      injury and evaluation tool have subjects which includes athletes playing multiple sports and&#xD;
      generally involved male footballers, but the studies comparing scores of FMS among female&#xD;
      footballers with male footballers are scarce. With advances in society and knowledge of&#xD;
      participation in sports, more women participate in sports events, and the pre-participation&#xD;
      and injury of this particular population should be explored. This research will discover this&#xD;
      particular issue and bring to light the needs of female footballers and contributes to&#xD;
      recognizing FMS as a predictive method for injury.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional Movement Screen</measure>
    <time_frame>6th week</time_frame>
    <description>Functional Movement Screen (FMS) will be used as a 'Pre' and 'Post' assessment tool to evaluate the risk of injury/dysfunctional performance among male and female footballers.&#xD;
Minimum and Maximum score interpretation required</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">264</enrollment>
  <condition>Sports Physical Therapy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group(Male)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be included in the study after screening from inclusion criteria. Each participant will perform FMS during a single session before competition as pre testing. It consists of 7 movement tasks and 3 clearance screens. Movement task will include deep squat, hurdle step, inline lunge, shoulder mobility, active straight-leg raise, trunk stability push-up and rotary stability. Five of the 7 tasks (hurdle step, inline lunge, shoulder mobility, active straight-leg raise and rotary stability) will be performed on both right and left sides. In addition to these, 3 clearance screen will assess the presence of pain with shoulder internal rotation/flexion, end range spinal flexion and end range spinal extension. Participants will be instructed for each task performance and will perform 3 attempts for each task.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group(Female)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be included in the study after screening from inclusion criteria. Each participant will perform FMS during a single session before competition as pre testing. It consists of 7 movement tasks and 3 clearance screens. Movement task will include deep squat, hurdle step, inline lunge, shoulder mobility, active straight-leg raise, trunk stability push-up and rotary stability. Five of the 7 tasks (hurdle step, inline lunge, shoulder mobility, active straight-leg raise and rotary stability) will be performed on both right and left sides. In addition to these, 3 clearance screen will assess the presence of pain with shoulder internal rotation/flexion, end range spinal flexion and end range spinal extension. Participants will be instructed for each task performance and will perform 3 attempts for each task.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experimental group(Male)</intervention_name>
    <description>Hurdle steps Deep squats Inline lunges Shoulder Clearing Active straight leg raise Trunk stability pushup Rotary stability Spinal extension exam Spinal flexion exam</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group(Male)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Experimental group(Female)</intervention_name>
    <description>Hurdle steps Deep squats Inline lunges Shoulder Clearing Active straight leg raise Trunk stability pushup Rotary stability Spinal extension exam Spinal flexion exam</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental group(Female)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male and Female Footballers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Athletes training at least 3 times per week (&gt;1.5h/week)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent injury of lower extremity within past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of traumatic brain injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of concussion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of cervical spine injury within the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of shoulder surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of anterior cruciate ligament repair&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of meniscal repair&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Achilles tendon repair&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of ankle fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent eye and ear disorders within past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving physical therapy for musculoskeletal injuries&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>22 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Danish Latif, MSPT-SPT</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Riphah International University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ra'ad Arena</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rawalpindi</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>46000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Functional Movement Screen,</keyword>
  <keyword>Footballers,</keyword>
  <keyword>Speed</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

