<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05006482</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>URCC-19178</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2021-01760</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>URCC-19178</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>URCC-19178</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>URCC-19178</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>R01CA249467</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>UG1CA189961</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05006482</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Geriatric Evaluation and Management With Survivorship Health Education (GEMS) for Older Survivors of Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Optimizing Functional Outcomes of Older Cancer Survivors After Chemotherapy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Rochester NCORP Research Base</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Rochester</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase III trial compares the effect of geriatric evaluation and management with&#xD;
      survivorship health education (GEMS) to usual care on patient-reported physical function in&#xD;
      older survivors of cancer. Survivorship care for older adults of cancer usually consists of&#xD;
      getting advice from their doctor. This advice may include how to do their daily activities,&#xD;
      so they are less tired or how to manage multiple diseases, or long-term side effects from&#xD;
      treatment. GEMS may help improve the physical ability to perform activities of daily living,&#xD;
      mental well-being, and memory in older survivors of cancer after chemotherapy. This study may&#xD;
      help doctors learn if including GEMS in their practices improves physical, mental and memory&#xD;
      functions in their patients. The study may also help to understand how such care affects&#xD;
      cancer patients and their caregivers' quality of life.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To compare the efficacy of GEMS to usual care for improving patient-reported physical&#xD;
      function (Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Fatigue Physical Well-Being Subscale&#xD;
      [FACIT-PWB]) in older cancer survivors at 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To compare the efficacy of GEMS to usual care for improving patient-reported cognitive&#xD;
      function (FACT-cognitive function [Cog]) in older cancer survivors at 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: Practice sites are randomized to 1 of 2 arms. Participants are assigned to arms&#xD;
      based on practice site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM I: Patients and caregivers receive routine survivorship follow-up care at their doctor's&#xD;
      office for 5 visits over 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ARM II: Patients and caregivers participate in GEMS consultation over 1 hour that includes&#xD;
      discussion of results and recommendations from geriatric assessment. Patients also&#xD;
      participate in survivorship health education sessions over 75 minutes twice weekly for 4&#xD;
      weeks. Patients also participate in Exercise for Cancer Patients (EXCAP) program, which&#xD;
      includes daily walking and resistance exercises.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study intervention, participants are followed up at 6 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported physical function as assessed by the Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy Physical Well-Being Subscale (FACIT PWB) in cancer survivors.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The FACIT-F is a 40-item questionnaire divided into 5 domains: physical well-being (PWB; 7-items), social/family well-being (SWB; 7-items), emotional well-being (EWB; 6-items), functional well-being (FWB; 7-items), and fatigue (13-items). Each question uses a 5-point rating scale (0=Not at all; 1=A little bit; 2=Somewhat; 3=Quite a bit; and 4=Very much).&#xD;
We will test the efficacy of the GEMS intervention on self-reported physical function at 6 months by calculating the average between-arm difference in change in the FACIT-PWB subscale score from baseline to 6 months. To estimate the intervention effects, we will use an ANCOVA model with an additional random effect term to account for clustering.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported cognitive function as assessed by Functional Assessment of Cancer Therapy-Cognitive Function (FACT-Cog).</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The FACT-Cog provides an overall score and subdomain scores (perceived cognitive impairment (PCI), perceived abilities, comments from others, impact on quality of life) (37 items each with a 5 point Likert scale response). The secondary aim will be the FACT-Cog Perceived Cognitive Impairment score [PCI] at 6 months. We will apply the same analytical approach as for the primary aim to assess the intervention effect on FACT-Cog PCI and same statistical power considerations apply.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">780</enrollment>
  <condition>Malignant Solid Neoplasm</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (usual care)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients and caregivers receive routine survivorship follow-up care at their doctor's office for 5 visits over 12 months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (GEMS intervention)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients and caregivers participate in GEMS consultation over 1 hour that includes discussion of results and recommendations from geriatric assessment. Patients also participate in survivorship health education sessions over 75 minutes twice weekly for 4 weeks. Patients also participate in EXCAP program, which includes daily walking and resistance exercises.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Best Practice</intervention_name>
    <description>Receive usual follow-up survivorship care</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (usual care)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>standard of care</other_name>
    <other_name>standard therapy</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Comprehensive Geriatric Assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>Complete geriatric assessment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (GEMS intervention)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Educational Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Participate in survivorship health education sessions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (GEMS intervention)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Education for Intervention</other_name>
    <other_name>Intervention by Education</other_name>
    <other_name>Intervention through Education</other_name>
    <other_name>Intervention, Educational</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exercise Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Participate in EXCAP program</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (GEMS intervention)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Questionnaire Administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Ancillary studies</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I (usual care)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (GEMS intervention)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tailored Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Participate in GEM consultation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm II (GEMS intervention)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: 65 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: Have completed or will have completed curative-intent adjuvant&#xD;
             chemotherapy for any solid tumor malignancy in last 4 weeks. Run-in study procedures&#xD;
             can occur during the last 4 weeks of adjuvant chemotherapy but must be completed no&#xD;
             later than 4 weeks after the completion of adjuvant chemotherapy. Cancer survivors who&#xD;
             will receive other curative-intent treatments (e.g., hormonal treatment, monoclonal&#xD;
             antibodies, radiation) other than surgery are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: Be willing and able to come in for study visits or willing to&#xD;
             undergo informed consent and assessments remotely via tele-health visits when&#xD;
             necessary&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: Be willing and able to provide informed consent and must sign&#xD;
             consent in-person or remotely if it is not convenient or feasible to provide informed&#xD;
             consent in-person&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: Speak and read English and/or Spanish. Spanish-speaking cancer&#xD;
             survivors are eligible as long as there are appropriate resources in place for&#xD;
             completion of study procedures at the practice site. Registration for Spanish-speaking&#xD;
             cancer survivors must be approved by the University of Rochester Cancer Center (URCC)&#xD;
             National Cancer Institute Community Oncology Research Program (NCORP) Research Base&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CAREGIVERS: 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CAREGIVERS: Selected by the cancer survivor when asked if there is a &quot;family member,&#xD;
             partner, friend or caregiver (age 18 years or older) with whom you discuss or who can&#xD;
             be helpful in health-related matters.&quot; A caregiver need not be someone who lives with&#xD;
             the cancer survivor or provides direct hands-on care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CAREGIVERS: Speak and read English and/or Spanish. Spanish-speaking caregivers are&#xD;
             eligible as long as there are appropriate resources in place for completion of study&#xD;
             procedures. Registration for Spanish-speaking caregivers must be approved by the URCC&#xD;
             NCORP Research Base&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: Have surgery planned within six months of informed consent. Cancer&#xD;
             survivors who previously had surgery are eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CANCER SURVIVORS: Have a condition that precludes their ability to participate in&#xD;
             informed consent or procedures (e.g., dementia and/or Blessed Orientation Memory&#xD;
             Concentration [BOMC] Score &gt;= 11)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CAREGIVERS: Caregivers unable to understand the informed consent form or study&#xD;
             procedures due to cognitive, health, or sensory impairment will be excluded. Capacity&#xD;
             to conduct informed consent procedures and study procedures will be determined by the&#xD;
             coordinators in collaboration with the cancer survivors' oncologists. These procedures&#xD;
             are similar to that of URCC 13070, which enrolled caregivers of older patients with&#xD;
             advanced cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CAREGIVERS: Have surgery planned within six months of informed consent. Caregivers who&#xD;
             previously had surgery are eligible&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>65 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Supriya G Mohile</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Rochester NCORP Research Base</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jillian VanCott</last_name>
    <phone>585-275-5513</phone>
    <email>URCC_19178@URMC.Rochester.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Rochester NCORP Research Base</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Supriya Mohile</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Medicine and Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

