<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00525473</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>200701077M</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00525473</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Correlation of Genetic Polymorphism of Azathioprine Metabolizing Enzymes and Correlation to Clinical Adverse Effects</brief_title>
  <official_title>Correlation of Genetic Polymorphism of Two Azathioprine Metabolizing Enzymes and Their Correlation to Clinical Adverse Effects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Azathioprine (AZA) has long been used in dermatology in treating autoimmune bullous&#xD;
      dermatoses and generalized eczematous disorders as well as some photodermatoses. Its&#xD;
      metabolic process inside human body and its side effects relies on genetic polymorphism of&#xD;
      some enzymes such as thiopurine s-methyltransferase (TPMT) and inosine triphosphate&#xD;
      pyrophosphatase gene (ITPA). This study aims to analyze the relative contribution of TMPT and&#xD;
      ITPA mutations to the development of toxicity induced by AZA treatment and to detect the&#xD;
      correlation of the genetic polymorphism.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Dermatologists have been using azathioprine for more than 30 years. This synthetic purine&#xD;
      analog is derived from 6-mercaptopurine. It is thought to act by disrupting nucleic acid&#xD;
      synthesis and has recently been found to interfere with T-cell activation. The most&#xD;
      recognized uses of azathioprine in dermatology are for immunobullous diseases, generalized&#xD;
      eczematous disorders, and photodermatoses. Azathioprine is extensively metabolized, and only&#xD;
      about 2% is excreted, unchanged, in the urine. Once freed of its imidazole derivative, the&#xD;
      mercaptopurine moiety undergoes metabolism from 3 competing enzymes. Activity of the 2&#xD;
      catabolic enzymes thiopurine s-methyltransferase (TPMT), an enzyme with great genetic&#xD;
      polymorphism, and xanthine oxidase (XO) produces inactive metabolites. Decreased TPMT or XO&#xD;
      activity results in the increased production of toxic metabolites. Decreased TPMT activity is&#xD;
      frequently a consequence of genetic polymorphisms, while decreased XO activity may be&#xD;
      mediated by medications such as allopurinol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Azathioprine is generally well tolerated and has a favorable therapeutic index compared with&#xD;
      many other traditional immunosuppressants. Dose-limiting toxicity from azathioprine treatment&#xD;
      affects up to 37% of patients. Administration of azathioprine to a patient with TPMT&#xD;
      deficiency results in significant accumulation of thioguanine nucleotides, and it becomes&#xD;
      clinically manifest by increased hematopoietic toxicity, with potentially grave consequences.&#xD;
      Screening for thiopurine methyltransferase (TPMT) polymorphisms, TPMT*3A, *3C, *2 will&#xD;
      prospectively identify approximately 10% of patients. In Chinese, the reported incidence of&#xD;
      homozygous wild-type、heterozygote、homozygous mutation of TPMT is 95.3%, 4.7% and 0%&#xD;
      respectively. The relationship to hematologic complication is more established, but its&#xD;
      relationship to gastrointestinal side effects is controversial. Genetic polymorphism of the&#xD;
      other newly identified enzyme, inosine triphosphate pyrophosphatase gene (ITPA) has also been&#xD;
      associated with other adverse effect of azathioprine, such as flu-like symptoms, rash and&#xD;
      pancreatitis. ITPA 94C&gt;A allele is found at low frequency in Central/South American&#xD;
      populations (1-2%), at a constant frequency across Caucasian and African populations (6-7%),&#xD;
      and is highest in Asian populations (14-19%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of our study was to determine the relative contribution of, TMPT(A719G) and&#xD;
      ITPA(C94A) mutations to the development of toxicity induced by AZA treatment in dermatology&#xD;
      patients and to detect the correlation of these two genetic polymorphism.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hepatotoxicity was defined by serum alanine transaminase levels greater than twice the upper&#xD;
      normal limit (50 IU/l) and resolution after withdrawal of AZA; pancreatitis by severe&#xD;
      abdominal pain and serum amylase &gt; 800 IU/l; neutropenia by a neutrophil count of &lt; 2.0 × 109&#xD;
      cells.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Genetic polymorphism tests before azathioprine therapy may reduce toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>2008.1.1</time_frame>
    <description>current treatment to nausea/vomiting adverse effects induced by azathioprine combined with pre-therapeutic genetic screening, especially polymorphism ITPA C94A, may reduce the possibility for developing hematopoietic toxicity and/or hepatotoxicity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">166</enrollment>
  <condition>Azathioprine</condition>
  <condition>Thiopurine Methyltransferase</condition>
  <condition>Inosine Triphosphate Pyrophosphatase</condition>
  <condition>Genetic Polymorphism</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azathioprine</intervention_name>
    <description>azathioprine usual dosage 100mg per day</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Chinese Han patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have used or are using azathioprine in treating skin diseases will be&#xD;
             asked about treatment effects and adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No special exclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tsen-Fang Tsai, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Taiwan University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Taiwan University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>100</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 3, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 3, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 5, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 16, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 16, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">May 17, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Azathioprine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

