<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00527982</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2004-0104</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00527982</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Celecoxib as Adjuvant Biologic Therapy in Patients With Head and Neck and Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Celecoxib as Adjuvant Biologic Therapy in Patients With Early Stage Head and Neck and Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To examine the effect of celecoxib treatment on histological response, markers of&#xD;
           proliferation (Ki-67), and apoptosis. Secondary endpoints include time to second primary&#xD;
           or recurrence and survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To examine the toxicity associated with celecoxib administration in patients with&#xD;
           previously treated Head and Neck Head and neck squamous cell carcinomas (HNSCC)or&#xD;
           Non-small-cell lung carcinoma (NSCLC).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In order to enroll in this trial, you must also be enrolled in Protocol 2003-0424. The study&#xD;
      procedures and tests that are part of this study are the same procedures and tests that are&#xD;
      part of Protocol 2003-0424. Even though a procedure or test is described in both this consent&#xD;
      and the consent for Protocol 2003-0424, you will only have the described procedure or test&#xD;
      done once. For example, both this study and Protocol 2003-0424 require a complete physical&#xD;
      exam before beginning treatment. In this case, you will only have one physical exam that will&#xD;
      count for both studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Celecoxib is a drug that slows the production of chemicals in the body that cause&#xD;
      inflammation. Celecoxib works by interfering with the action of the chemical cyclooxygenase,&#xD;
      a chemical that is involved in inflammation. It is believed that the product of chemicals&#xD;
      that cause inflammation may be involved in cancer development.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before treatment starts, you will have a complete physical exam, including measurement of&#xD;
      height, weight, blood pressure, and vital signs. You will have blood samples drawn for&#xD;
      routine blood tests (about 3 teaspoons) and for research purposes (about 4 teaspoons) . Women&#xD;
      who are able to have children must have a negative pregnancy test (blood or urine). You will&#xD;
      also have a chest x-ray and a CT scan of your chest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will also have a bronchoscopy (tissue sample from the lung) at the beginning of this&#xD;
      study for lab analysis. For this procedure, you will be given drugs to relax. Then, a local&#xD;
      anesthetic will be sprayed in your nose and throat to numb those areas. A slim, flexible tube&#xD;
      with a light will be placed through your nose or mouth and into your lungs. Tweezers will be&#xD;
      fed through the tube to collect lung tissue (biopsy) samples from 6 different places in your&#xD;
      lungs. During the bronchoscopy procedure, a complete inspection of the airways will be&#xD;
      performed. Any suspicious areas that are seen under the white-light and autofluorescence&#xD;
      bronchoscopy will be identified and more biopsies and brushings will be performed to evaluate&#xD;
      whether any pre-cancerous tissue is present. You will also have a bronchial brushing next to&#xD;
      each biopsy site. In a bronchial brushing, a small brush is fed through the tube into your&#xD;
      lungs and a sample of lung tissue is gently scraped off. When the biopsies and brushings are&#xD;
      done, you will have a bronchial lavage (bronchial washing). In the bronchial lavage, a small&#xD;
      amount of water (about 4 tablespoons) is sprayed into your lungs and then suctioned out&#xD;
      through the tube. This fluid is used to collect additional tissue and mucous samples. In&#xD;
      addition, a sputum (saliva) sample will be taken and the inside of your cheek will be scraped&#xD;
      (buccal sample).&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you have had HNSCC, you will also have a laryngoscopy. In a laryngoscopy, a lighted tube&#xD;
      is placed down your throat and the larynx is checked. The back of your throat will be sprayed&#xD;
      with an anesthetic before this procedure to make the procedure more comfortable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study you will be randomly assigned (as in the toss of a coin) to one of two groups.&#xD;
      Participants in one group will receive celecoxib. Participants in the other group will&#xD;
      receive no treatment. Current standard practice for individuals who have had therapy for&#xD;
      early stage NSCLC or HNSCC is follow-up (no treatment). You have a 2 to 1 chance of being&#xD;
      assigned to the treatment group. That means that 2 out of every 3 participants in this study&#xD;
      will be assigned to the treatment group.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are assigned to the treatment group you will take celecoxib by mouth in two divided&#xD;
      doses at least 8 hours apart every day. Your study doctor will tell you exactly how many&#xD;
      pills you should take each day. You will take celecoxib for up to 12 months. You will be&#xD;
      taken off study if intolerable side effects occur or if the disease comes back.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are assigned to the treatment (celecoxib) group, you will have a physical exam by a&#xD;
      physician or nurse at months 3, 6, and 12 for the first year of treatment. If you are&#xD;
      assigned to the &quot;no treatment&quot; group, the nurse will contact you by phone every 3 months for&#xD;
      the first year on this study to see how you are doing and you will have a physical exam by&#xD;
      either a physician or a nurse every 6 months. During the first year, all participants will&#xD;
      have blood samples taken at each clinic visit for routine blood tests (about 3 teaspoons) and&#xD;
      for research purposes (about 4 teaspoons). In addition, all participants will have a chest&#xD;
      x-ray and chest CT at months 6 and 12. All participants will also have a bronchoscopy and&#xD;
      provide sputum, saliva, and buccal smear samples at 12 months. If you have been treated for&#xD;
      HNSCC, you will have a laryngoscopy at 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the first year, you will be followed for a minimum of 2 more years and a maximum of 6&#xD;
      years. You will have physical exams at 24 and 36 months. You will have blood draws (about 3&#xD;
      teaspoons for routine tests and 4 teaspoons for research purposes), a chest x-ray and a chest&#xD;
      CT at 18, 24, 30 and 36 months. After 36 months, you will have a physical exam by a physician&#xD;
      or nurse every 6 months for up to 6 years. Every 12 months the physical exam will be done by&#xD;
      a physician. The other physical exams will be done by a nurse. You will have blood drawn for&#xD;
      routine tests (about 3 teaspoons) and research purposes (about 4 teaspoons) every 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This research study includes two bronchoscopies done one year apart. These bronchoscopies are&#xD;
      being done primarily for research purposes and are unlikely to provide information useful in&#xD;
      your individual treatment. These bronchoscopies do have risks associated with them. These&#xD;
      risks are described in section 4 of this informed consent document.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent research on early stage NSCLC indicates that adjuvant chemotherapy after surgery&#xD;
      increases the length of time a person may survive and the length of time before cancer&#xD;
      recurs. However, this adjuvant chemotherapy also has side effects that can be severe and in&#xD;
      rare cases fatal. If you have had surgery for NSCLC and wish to receive adjuvant&#xD;
      chemotherapy, you may only enroll in this study and Protocol 2003-0424 after you have&#xD;
      completed the adjuvant chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of this study you will provide samples of your lung tissue, saliva, blood, and&#xD;
      scrapings from the inside of your cheek. Fluid and mucous collected during the bronchoscopies&#xD;
      will also collected. These samples will be studied by scientists to learn about genes and&#xD;
      proteins in people who have been treated for early NSCLC or HNSCC. The samples will also be&#xD;
      used to grow cells and cultures that will be used to test chemotherapy drugs. These cells and&#xD;
      cultures will also be used to learn about genes and proteins.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an investigational study. Celecoxib is a commonly used drug that is approved by the&#xD;
      FDA for treatment of arthritis, colon polyps, and pain. The use of celecoxib to help prevent&#xD;
      cancer is approved by the FDA for research only. A total of up to 70 individuals will take&#xD;
      part in this multicenter study. Up to 50 will be enrolled at UT MD Anderson Cancer Center.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Termination due to poor accrual.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>September 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Histological Responses</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with histological response based on changes in bronchoscopies from baseline to 12 months.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1</enrollment>
  <condition>Head and Neck Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Celecoxib treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>600 mg orally (PO) daily</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Celecoxib</intervention_name>
    <description>600 mg by mouth daily for a total of 12 months.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Celecoxib treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Celebrex</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with either: a) histologically proven stage I, II, or IIIa NSCLC who have&#xD;
             undergone a complete surgical resection of the primary tumor OR b) stage I or II HNSCC&#xD;
             who have undergone definitive local treatment (surgery or radiation therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. HNSCC patients: Definitive local treatment &lt;/= 12 months prior to trial enrollment.&#xD;
             NSCLC patients: Surgery &lt;/= 12 months prior to trial enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No evidence residual cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Smoking history of at least 10 pack years. May be current or former smoker.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Performance status of &lt; = 2 (Zubrod)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Age =&gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participants must have no contraindications for undergoing bronchoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients must have no active pulmonary infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Participants must not be taking oral non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on a&#xD;
             regular basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participants must have the following blood levels: total granulocyte count &gt;1500;&#xD;
             platelet count &gt; 100,000; total bilirubin &lt; = 1.5 mg. %; and creatinine &lt; = 1.5 mg %.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Participants must complete the pretreatment evaluation and must consent to&#xD;
             bronchoscopy and to endobronchial biopsy for biomarker studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. All subjects who agree to participate will be given a written and verbal explanation&#xD;
             of the study requirements and a consent form that must be signed prior to&#xD;
             registration. Subjects will be informed that (a) they must be willing to take capsules&#xD;
             daily for the duration of the trial, (b) they must be willing to take biopsies through&#xD;
             bronchoscopy and give blood samples at the specified times, (c) they must schedule and&#xD;
             keep the specified follow-up visits with their physicians and the study clinics, and&#xD;
             (d) side effects and health risks may occur, as described in the informed consent&#xD;
             form.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Participant must be enrolled in UT MD Anderson Cancer Center protocol #2003-0424&#xD;
             titled &quot;A Phase IIb Vanguard Study Characterizing the Occurrence of Recurrent or&#xD;
             Second Primary Tumors in Patients with a Prior History of a Definitively Treated Stage&#xD;
             I/II Head and Neck or Non-Small Cell Cancer who are Current or Former Smokers.&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients with prior head and neck cancer only: Participants must have no&#xD;
             contraindications for undergoing laryngoscopy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Subject must be considered legally capable of providing his or her own consent for&#xD;
             participation in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of radiation therapy to the chest. For those patients with head and neck&#xD;
             cancer who received radiation, no more than 10% of the lung volume (apices) may be&#xD;
             included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of systemic chemotherapy. Exception: NSCLC patients may have had up to 4&#xD;
             cycles of platinum-based doublet therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnant or breast-feeding (a negative pregnancy test within 72 hours of enrollment&#xD;
             for women with child-bearing potential is required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants with active gastric or duodenal ulcers or a history of ulcers requiring&#xD;
             prophylactic H2 blockers.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Participants with active pulmonary infections or recent history of pulmonary infection&#xD;
             (within one month).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participants with acute intercurrent illness&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participants requiring chronic ongoing treatment with Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory&#xD;
             drugs (NSAIDs). (Casual or non-prescribed use of NSAIDs is permitted as long as their&#xD;
             use does not exceed one week at a time.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Participants who are allergic to aspirin or sulfanamides.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients may not take high dose antioxidants (vitamins E or C) during the study&#xD;
             period. &quot;High dose&quot; will be determined by the study investigators.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients may not take high dose synthetic or natural Vitamin A derivatives (&gt; 10,000&#xD;
             IU per day).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of biologic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Women of childbearing potential and men with partners of childbearing potential who&#xD;
             are not using an effective method of contraception. Use of contraception will be&#xD;
             verified at office visits during first year on study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of cardiovascular diseases that might include one of the following: myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, angina, coronary angioplasty, congestive heart failure, stroke, or&#xD;
             coronary bypass surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Diagnosis of diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of deep venous thrombosis, pulmonary embolism, systemic lupus erythematosus,&#xD;
             family history of protein S or C deficiencies, prior heparin-induced thrombocytopenia,&#xD;
             or known Factor V Leiden mutation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Family history of premature CAD. This is defined as individuals with either: 1) father&#xD;
             with MI prior to age 55, or 2) mother with MI prior to age 60.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Waun K. Hong, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>U.T.M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 10, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 11, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <results_first_submitted>January 6, 2011</results_first_submitted>
  <results_first_submitted_qc>March 21, 2011</results_first_submitted_qc>
  <results_first_posted type="Estimate">April 20, 2011</results_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 4, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 4, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 6, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Head and Neck Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Celecoxib</keyword>
  <keyword>Celebrex</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Celecoxib</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>

  <clinical_results>

    <participant_flow>
      <recruitment_details>Recruitment Period: September 29, 2005 to December 18, 2007. Patients were recruited at UT MD Anderson Cancer Center.</recruitment_details>
      <pre_assignment_details>One patient registered determined to be inevaluable. Trial termination due to poor accrual and study program redesign.</pre_assignment_details>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="P1">
          <title>Celecoxib Treatment</title>
          <description>Celecoxib 600 mg orally daily</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="P2">
          <title>No Treatment</title>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <period_list>
        <period>
          <title>Overall Study</title>
          <milestone_list>
            <milestone>
              <title>STARTED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="0"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
            <milestone>
              <title>NOT COMPLETED</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </milestone>
          </milestone_list>
          <drop_withdraw_reason_list>
            <drop_withdraw_reason>
              <title>Physician Decision</title>
              <participants_list>
                <participants group_id="P1" count="1"/>
                <participants group_id="P2" count="0"/>
              </participants_list>
            </drop_withdraw_reason>
          </drop_withdraw_reason_list>
        </period>
      </period_list>
    </participant_flow>

    <baseline>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="B1">
          <title>Celecoxib Treatment</title>
          <description>Celecoxib 600 mg orally daily</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B2">
          <title>No Treatment</title>
        </group>
        <group group_id="B3">
          <title>Total</title>
          <description>Total of all reporting groups</description>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <analyzed_list>
        <analyzed>
          <units>Participants</units>
          <scope>Overall</scope>
          <count_list>
            <count group_id="B1" value="1"/>
            <count group_id="B2" value="0"/>
            <count group_id="B3" value="1"/>
          </count_list>
        </analyzed>
      </analyzed_list>
      <measure_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Age</title>
          <units>years</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>&lt;=18 years</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Between 18 and 65 years</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>&gt;=65 years</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Gender</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>Female</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
            <class>
              <title>Male</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="0"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="0"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
        <measure>
          <title>Region of Enrollment</title>
          <units>participants</units>
          <param>Number</param>
          <class_list>
            <class>
              <title>United States</title>
              <category_list>
                <category>
                  <measurement_list>
                    <measurement group_id="B1" value="1"/>
                    <measurement group_id="B3" value="1"/>
                  </measurement_list>
                </category>
              </category_list>
            </class>
          </class_list>
        </measure>
      </measure_list>
    </baseline>

    <outcome_list>
      <outcome>
        <type>Primary</type>
        <title>Histological Responses</title>
        <description>Number of patients with histological response based on changes in bronchoscopies from baseline to 12 months.</description>
        <time_frame>Baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
        <population>No analysis. One registered patient inevaluable for response, study terminated early.</population>
        <group_list>
          <group group_id="O1">
            <title>Celecoxib Treatment</title>
            <description>Celecoxib 600 mg orally daily</description>
          </group>
          <group group_id="O2">
            <title>No Treatment</title>
          </group>
        </group_list>
        <measure>
          <title>Histological Responses</title>
          <description>Number of patients with histological response based on changes in bronchoscopies from baseline to 12 months.</description>
          <population>No analysis. One registered patient inevaluable for response, study terminated early.</population>
          <analyzed_list>
            <analyzed>
              <units>Participants</units>
              <scope>Measure</scope>
              <count_list>
                <count group_id="O1" value="0"/>
                <count group_id="O2" value="0"/>
              </count_list>
            </analyzed>
          </analyzed_list>
        </measure>
      </outcome>
    </outcome_list>

    <reported_events>
      <time_frame>21 months</time_frame>
      <group_list>
        <group group_id="E1">
          <title>Celecoxib Treatment</title>
          <description>Celecoxib 600 mg orally daily</description>
        </group>
        <group group_id="E2">
          <title>No Treatment</title>
        </group>
      </group_list>
      <serious_events>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, serious adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="1"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="0"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </serious_events>
      <other_events>
        <frequency_threshold>5</frequency_threshold>
        <category_list>
          <category>
            <title>Total</title>
            <event_list>
              <event>
                <sub_title>Total, other adverse events</sub_title>
                <counts group_id="E1" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="1"/>
                <counts group_id="E2" subjects_affected="0" subjects_at_risk="0"/>
              </event>
            </event_list>
          </category>
        </category_list>
      </other_events>
    </reported_events>

    <certain_agreements>
      <pi_employee>All Principal Investigators ARE employed by the organization sponsoring the study.</pi_employee>
      <restrictive_agreement>There is NOT an agreement between Principal Investigators and the Sponsor (or its agents) that restricts the PI's rights to discuss or publish trial results after the trial is completed. </restrictive_agreement>
    </certain_agreements>
    <point_of_contact>
      <name_or_title>Waun K. Hong, MD/Professor</name_or_title>
      <organization>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</organization>
      <email>CR_Study_Registration@mdanderson.org</email>
    </point_of_contact>
  </clinical_results>
</clinical_study>

