<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02228954</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IMPACT-RCC study</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02228954</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>IMaging PAtients for Cancer Drug selecTion - Renal Cell Carcinoma (IMPACT-RCC)</brief_title>
  <acronym>IMPACT-RCC</acronym>
  <official_title>Watchful Waiting in Patients With Good and Intermediate Risk Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma; an Imaging Guided Observational Approach. Part of: Towards Patient Tailored Cancer Treatment Supported by Molecular Imaging. IMPACT Study: Imaging Patients for Cancer Drug Selection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Radboud University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dutch Cancer Society</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Radboud University</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rationale. In part of the patients with good and intermediate risk metastatic renal cell&#xD;
      carcinoma (mRCC) the disease course is indolent and immediate start of systemic therapy is&#xD;
      not necessary. By now, the investigators are not able to identify those patients with&#xD;
      indolent disease and the minor group of patients with rapidly progressive disease. In&#xD;
      patients with indolent disease, a watchful waiting period is preferred, since their quality&#xD;
      of life will not be unnecessary hampered by adverse events and therapy resistance is not&#xD;
      induced. This study aims to identify those patients for whom a watchful waiting period is&#xD;
      possible by molecular imaging. Furthermore several types of systemic therapy are possible&#xD;
      once the progression is proven. These systemic treatments are comparable in terms of&#xD;
      efficacy, but not in terms of toxicity and their impact on quality of life. As a secondary&#xD;
      objective, the usefulness of a decision aid guiding the choice of the patients is studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess in patients with good or intermediate prognosis mRCC who are eligible for watchful&#xD;
      waiting, the added value beyond clinical work-up of:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. FDG-PET and 89Zr-girentuximab-PET results measured at presentation to predict rapid&#xD;
           progression (≤ 2 months after the baseline scan) under watchful waiting.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. FDG-PET and 89Zr-girentuximab-PET results measured at presentation to predict prolonged&#xD;
           indolent (≥12 months after the baseline scan) disease under watchful waiting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the value of a therapy choice decision aid for patients with progressive disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study design. This is a multicenter non-blinded prospective observational study in 80 good&#xD;
      and intermediate prognosis mRCC patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population. Patients with good or intermediate prognosis mRCC according to the Heng&#xD;
      criteria, ≥18 years, without contra-indications for a watchful waiting period, able to&#xD;
      provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention. At baseline an FDG-PET-CT and 89Zr-girentuximab-PET will be made. During the&#xD;
      watchful waiting period, disease evaluation by CT according to the RECIST criteria will be&#xD;
      made frequently, until established progressive disease. At that moment, a second FDG-PET-CT&#xD;
      and, in case of a positive 89Zr-girentuximab-PET-scan at baseline, a second&#xD;
      89Zr-girentuximab-PET will be performed and the decision aid is used to help the patient to&#xD;
      choose their best treatment out of four options; pazopanib, sunitinib, combined interferon-α&#xD;
      with bevacizumab and (only in case of a positive 89Zr-girentuximab-PET) radioimmunotherapy&#xD;
      (RIT) with 177lutetium labelled girentuximab. Participation in the RIT trial is part of a&#xD;
      separate phase II study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nature and extent of the burden and risks associated with participation, benefit and group&#xD;
      relatedness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline, a 18F-FDG-PET-CT and 89Zr-Girentuximab-PET will be performed. During the&#xD;
      watchful waiting period CT's will be made. During therapy, follow-up will include standard&#xD;
      laboratory analysis, and CT-scans on regular visits to the outpatient clinic. Side effects of&#xD;
      the medication and adverse events as a consequence of the tumor biopsies may occur. The&#xD;
      radiation exposure of both PET investigations is acceptable and requires no shielding after&#xD;
      injection of 89Zr-labelled girentuximab. Patients may benefit from disease regression or&#xD;
      stabilization. All three treatment choices has proven clinical benefit in this patient&#xD;
      population. The risks of participation into the RIT trial are described in the phase II trial&#xD;
      protocol, which already has been judged by the Medical Ethics Review Committee.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Active, not recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 5, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to progression</measure>
    <time_frame>1-5 years (End of study)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess in patients with good or intermediate prognosis mRCC who are eligible for watchful waiting, the added value beyond clinical work-up of:&#xD;
FDG-PET and 89Zr-girentuximab-PET results measured at presentation to predict rapid progression (≤ 2 months after the baseline scan) under watchful waiting.&#xD;
FDG-PET and 89Zr-girentuximab-PET results measured at presentation to predict prolonged indolent (≥12 months after the baseline scan) disease under watchful waiting.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient and physician questionnaires on the added value of the decision aid</measure>
    <time_frame>1-5 years (End of study)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the value of a therapy choice decision aid for patients with progressive disease</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Clear-cell Metastatic Renal Cell Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Kidney Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Renal Cell Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Molecular imaging</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Renal Cell Cancer</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients with good or intermediate prognosis mccRCC according to the Heng criteria, ≥18&#xD;
        years, without contra-indications for a watchful waiting period, able to provide informed&#xD;
        consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histological or cytological documented mRCC with a clear cell component&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Good or intermediate prognosis, defined as none (good risk) or 1-2 intermediate risk)&#xD;
             of the below mentioned risk factors:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Karnofsky performance &lt;80&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Time from diagnosis detection of metastases &lt; 1 year&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Haemoglobin &lt; lower limit of normal (LLN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corrected calcium &gt; upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophils &gt; ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &gt; ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A watchful waiting period for 2 months is considered an option according to treating&#xD;
             medical oncologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No prior systemic treatment for RCC (also non-adjuvant)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Time from diagnosis of metastases &lt; 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Untreated central nervous system metastases, or symptomatic intracerebral metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breast feeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious and/or unstable pre-existing medical, psychiatric, or other condition that&#xD;
             would make the subject inappropriate for study participation including any serious&#xD;
             condition that could interfere with subject's safety, provision of informed consent,&#xD;
             or compliance with study procedure.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>VU University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Medical Center Groningen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Groningen</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Radboudumc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <zip>6525GA</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 26, 2014</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2014</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 29, 2014</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 12, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 12, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 13, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Clear-cell metastatic renal cell carcinoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Positron-Emission Tomography</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Renal Cell</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Kidney Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

