<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00972933</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08-144</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00972933</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Immunogenicity and Biomarker Analysis of Neoadjuvant Ipilimumab for Melanoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neoadjuvant Anti-CTLA4 Blockade With Ipilimumab in Patients With AJCC Stage IIIB-C (Tx,1-4, N1b,2b, 2c, 3, M0) Melanoma: Immunogenicity And Biomarker Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Diwakar Davar</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Bristol-Myers Squibb</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Ipilimumab is a manufactured monoclonal antibody, much like the antibodies usually made by&#xD;
      the human body to fight off infection; however it is not known why the human body does not&#xD;
      &quot;fight off&quot; a cancerous tumor. The idea behind developing this experimental drug is to&#xD;
      stimulate the immune system to make antibodies to kill cancer cells. This research study is&#xD;
      considered &quot;experimental&quot; because it has not received approval from the Food and Drug&#xD;
      Administration (FDA) for the treatment of this type of cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This monoclonal antibody has been specifically made to block Cytotoxic T Lymphocyte Antigen 4&#xD;
      (CTLA4), which is a protein found on cells of the immune system. CTLA4 seems to slow down the&#xD;
      immune response, so blocking it with an anti-CTLA4 antibody may make the immune response more&#xD;
      active. The purpose of this study is to see if Ipilimumab affects the response of the&#xD;
      patient's immune system toward their cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 26, 2017</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 17, 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To study the effects of ipilimumab upon the host immune response in nodal metastatic melanoma and in the peripheral blood comparing pre-treatment with post-treatment (baseline, 6 weeks) immunologic features.</measure>
    <time_frame>2.5 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To study the effects of ipilimumab upon the host immune response.</measure>
    <time_frame>2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To collect pilot data comparing pre-treatment with post-treatment proteomic and genetic features.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the clinical efficacy of preoperative neoadjuvant therapy with ipilimumab in high risk clinically and pathologically node-positive melanoma patients (AJCC stage IIIB-C).</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To collect safety data and evaluate the safety of neoadjuvant therapy with ipilimumab in high risk clinically and pathologically node-positive melanoma patients (AJCC stage IIIB-C).</measure>
    <time_frame>2.5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">59</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Ipilimumab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Induction ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV day 0, 21 (baseline, week 3) Maintenance Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV days 63 (+28 days) and, 84 (+28 days) - (3 weeks apart, starting 2-4 weeks following definitive lymphadenectomy)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ipilimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Excisional Biopsy - baseline Induction ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV day 0, 21 - baseline and week 3 Complete lymph node dissection - week ≥ 6 Maintenance Ipilimumab 10 mg/kg IV - Days 63 (+28 days) and, 84 (+28 days) - (3 weeks apart, starting 2-4 weeks following definitive lymphadenectomy)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Ipilimumab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MDX-010</other_name>
    <other_name>Yervoy</other_name>
    <other_name>BMS-734016</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to give written informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologic diagnosis of melanoma belonging to T1-4 N1b,2b,2c,3 M 0 AJCC stages, that&#xD;
             may present as any of the following groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary melanoma with clinically apparent (overt) regional lymph node metastases,&#xD;
             confirmed by pathological diagnosis (biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically detected recurrence of melanoma at the proximal regional lymph node(s)&#xD;
             basin, confirmed by pathological diagnosis (biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically or histologically detected primary melanoma involving multiple regional&#xD;
             nodal groups, confirmed by pathological diagnosis (biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically detected single site of nodal metastatic melanoma arising from an unknown&#xD;
             primary, confirmed by pathological diagnosis (biopsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients are eligible for this trial either at presentation for primary melanoma with&#xD;
             concurrent regional nodal metastasis, or at the time of clinically detected nodal&#xD;
             recurrence. Patients must undergo biopsy (punch) or open biopsy (if done as part of a&#xD;
             clinically indicated baseline diagnostic procedure) within 14 days of entry into the&#xD;
             study. Lymphadenectomy will be performed after at least 2 and generally not longer&#xD;
             than 4 weeks of ipilimumab therapy. Additional delays for definitive lymphadenectomy&#xD;
             are allowed if clinically indicated while awaiting the resolution of potential adverse&#xD;
             events from ipilimumab therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have been evaluated by standard-of-care full body imaging studies (CT,&#xD;
             PET-CT or MRI) as part of the initial clinical work-up at baseline (no more than 4&#xD;
             weeks prior to study enrollment) and after completion of 2 doses of ipilimumab (at 6-8&#xD;
             weeks after the first dose of ipilimumab and prior the definitive lymphadenectomy&#xD;
             procedure).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Required values for initial laboratory tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  White Blood Cell ≥ 3000/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute Neutrophil Count ≥ 1500/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets ≥ 100 x 103/uL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hemoglobin ≥ 10 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤ ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST/ALT ≤ 2.5 x Upper Limit of Normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ ULN, (except patients with Gilbert's Syndrome, who must have a total&#xD;
                  bilirubin less than 3.0 mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PT/PTT ≤ ULN (No active or chronic infection with HIV, Hepatitis B, or Hepatitis&#xD;
                  C.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate performance status (ECOG 0, 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women, ≥ 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must be willing to use an adequate method of&#xD;
             contraception to avoid pregnancy throughout the study and for up to 8 weeks after the&#xD;
             last dose of ipilimumab. WOCBP include any female who has experienced menarche and who&#xD;
             has not undergone a successful surgical sterilization procedure (hysterectomy,&#xD;
             bilateral tubal ligation, or bilateral oophorectomy) or is not post-menopausal.&#xD;
             Post-menopause is defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Amenorrhea ≥ 12 consecutive months without another cause, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For women with irregular menstrual periods and taking hormone replacement therapy&#xD;
                  (HRT), a documented serum follicle stimulating hormone (FSH) level ≥ 35 mIU/mL.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are using oral contraceptives, other hormonal contraceptives (vaginal&#xD;
             products, skin patches, or implanted or injectable products), or mechanical products&#xD;
             such as an intrauterine device or barrier methods (diaphragm, condoms, spermicides) to&#xD;
             prevent pregnancy, or are practicing abstinence or where their partner is sterile (eg,&#xD;
             vasectomy) should be considered to be of childbearing potential. WOCBP must have a&#xD;
             negative serum or urine pregnancy test (minimum sensitivity 25 IU/L or equivalent&#xD;
             units of HCG) within 72 hours before the start of ipilimumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinical, radiological/laboratory, or pathological evidence of distant&#xD;
             metastatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with evidence of soft tissue involvement by gross extranodal extension of&#xD;
             tumor manifest by fixation to the fascia, or matting of nodal tissue that would&#xD;
             compromise surgical resection as determined by the surgical oncologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had a history of acute diverticulitis, intra-abdominal abscess, GI&#xD;
             obstruction and abdominal carcinomatosis which are known risk factors for bowel&#xD;
             perforation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other malignancy from which the patient has been disease-free for less than 5&#xD;
             years, with the exception of adequately treated and cured basal or squamous cell skin&#xD;
             cancer, superficial bladder cancer or carcinoma in situ of the cervix.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Autoimmune disease: Patients with a history of inflammatory bowel disease are excluded&#xD;
             from this study, as are patients with a history of symptomatic disease (eg, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, systemic progressive sclerosis [scleroderma], systemic lupus erythematosus,&#xD;
             autoimmune vasculitis [eg, Wegener's Granulomatosis]); motor neuropathy considered of&#xD;
             autoimmune origin (e.g. Guillain-Barre Syndrome).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any underlying medical or psychiatric condition, which in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator will make the administration of ipilimumab hazardous or obscure the&#xD;
             interpretation of AEs, such as a condition associated with frequent diarrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with underlying heart conditions who are deemed ineligible for surgery by&#xD;
             cardiology consult.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any non-oncology vaccine therapy used for prevention of infectious diseases (for up to&#xD;
             1 month before or after any dose of ipilimumab).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of prior treatment with ipilimumab or prior CD137 agonist or CTLA-4&#xD;
             inhibitor or agonist.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of prior radiotherapy, chemotherapy, including infusion or perfusion therapy&#xD;
             for his current disease or any immunotherapy including tumor vaccines,&#xD;
             interferon-alfa, interleukins, levamisole or other biologic response modifiers within&#xD;
             the past 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concomitant therapy with any of the following: IL 2, interferon, or other non-study&#xD;
             immunotherapy regimens; cytotoxic chemotherapy; immunosuppressive agents; other&#xD;
             investigation therapies; or chronic use of systemic corticosteroids; unless&#xD;
             discontinued ≥ 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP), defined above in Section 4.1, who:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  are unwilling or unable to use an acceptable method of contraception to avoid&#xD;
             pregnancy for their entire study period and for at least 8 weeks after cessation of&#xD;
             study drug, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  have a positive pregnancy test at baseline, or&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  are pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners or subjects who are compulsorily detained (involuntarily incarcerated) for&#xD;
             treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (eg, infectious) illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Before study enrollment, WOCBP must be advised of the importance of avoiding pregnancy&#xD;
        during study participation and the potential risk factors for an unintentional pregnancy.&#xD;
        All WOCBP MUST have a negative pregnancy test before first receiving ipilimumab. If the&#xD;
        pregnancy test is positive, the patient must not receive ipilimumab and must not be&#xD;
        enrolled in the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Diwakar Davar, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UPMC/UPCI</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center/University of Pittsburgh Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15232</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 3, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 8, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 9, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 5, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 5, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 7, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Diwakar Davar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Immunogenicity Analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarker Analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>experimental</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ipilimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

