<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00972218</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A10-456</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00972218</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness and Safety of Spondylitis Related to Inflammatory Bowel Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Adalimumab (Humira®) in Spondyloarthritis Related to Crohn's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Abbott</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Adalimumab is an antibody treatment that targets and neutralizes a molecule produced in the&#xD;
      body that is associated with inflammation, tumor necrosis factor (TNF). This molecule is an&#xD;
      important factor in causing the inflammation seen in people with a form of inflammatory&#xD;
      spinal arthritis called spondylitis as well as inflammation in the bowel called Crohn's&#xD;
      disease. Spondylitis and Crohn's disease tend to go together and this study will assess to&#xD;
      what degree this treatment is effective for those patients that have both disorders at the&#xD;
      same time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of the present study is to assess the efficacy of adalimumab in&#xD;
      ameliorating the signs and symptoms of spondyloarthritis associated with CD. Although AS&#xD;
      patients with IBD were recruited in phase III trials of anti-TNF therapy and shown to respond&#xD;
      to treatment, this has not been established in a cohort of patients with exclusive&#xD;
      enteropathic spondyloarthritis. Evaluation of such a cohort will address several important&#xD;
      issues:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Firstly, it will answer the question of whether or not patients with enteropathic&#xD;
           spondyloarthritis respond to treatment with adalimumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Secondly, since patients with IBD represent a cohort at high risk of developing&#xD;
           spondyloarthritis, this approach will allow the study of the efficacy of adalimumab in&#xD;
           patients with pre-radiographic inflammatory back pain as determined by clinical,&#xD;
           laboratory, and radiological outcomes. In particular, the use of MRI as an outcome&#xD;
           measure will be explored. In addition, this will allow the further evaluation of&#xD;
           diagnostic criteria for pre-radiographic AS.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Thirdly, the efficacy of adalimumab in treating IBD associated with SpA has not been&#xD;
           previously determined. It has been assumed that the response should be the same as that&#xD;
           observed in idiopathic disease. However, it is important to note that the bowel disease&#xD;
           related to spondyloarthritis has different genetic associations from idiopathic disease&#xD;
           and may have a different underlying pathophysiology. Several biomarkers have been shown&#xD;
           to reflect response to anti-TNF therapies in spondyloarthritis e.g. MMP3 and VEGF.&#xD;
           However, other surrogates of disease, such as bowel permeability, have yet to be&#xD;
           examined.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Difficulty with enrollment&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>July 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2010</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The primary efficacy outcome measure will be the Ankylosing Spondylitis Assessment Study group 20 (ASAS 20) response at 24 weeks.</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ASAS 20 response</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ASAS 40, 50, 70, 5/6 responses</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bath Ankylosing Spondylitis Disease Activity Index (BASDAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bath Ankylosing Spondylitis Functional Index (BASFI)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Global Assessment of arthritic and CD-related disease activity</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Back Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nocturnal Back Pain</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR)/C-reactive protein (CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Acceptable Symptom State (PASS) assessments</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Spinal mobility assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>2 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Enthesitis assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Crohn's Disease Activity Index (CDAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Short form 36 (SF-36™)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Helplessness scale</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Spondyloarthritis Research Consortium of Canada Magnetic Resonance Imaging Index (SPARCC MRI)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum biomarkers matrix metalloproteinase 3 (MMP3), vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF), DKK-1, Wnt, RANKL, OPG and cytokines (e.g. IL17, IL23, IL18)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bowel permeability</measure>
    <time_frame>12 and 24 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Spondyloarthritis</condition>
  <condition>Crohn's Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Enteropathic spondyloarthritis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients have concomitant inflammatory spinal symptoms and inflammatory bowel disease.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Adalimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Adalimumab subcutaneous injections 40 mg dose every other week for 24 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Enteropathic spondyloarthritis</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Humira</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a clinical diagnosis with Crohn's disease, as determined by his/her&#xD;
             medical history and confirmation of diagnosis by a gastroenterologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has either moderate to severely active Crohn's disease as defined by a CDAI&#xD;
             score of &gt; 220 and &lt; 450 at Screening or active inflammatory back pain as defined by a&#xD;
             BASDAI ≥ 4&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has failed to respond to an adequate course, is intolerant to, or has&#xD;
             contraindication to eitherach of the following therapies: Corticosteroids&#xD;
             (Prednisone/Budesonide),MTX or Azathioprine/6-mercaptopurine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is on stable (≥ 1 month) concurrent therapies for Crohn's disease, including&#xD;
             5-aminosalicylates, prednisone (&lt;20 mg/day), budesonide (&lt;9 mg/day), azathioprine,&#xD;
             6-mercaptopurine, methotrexate, and antibiotics&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If female, patient is either not of childbearing potential, defined as postmenopausal&#xD;
             for at least 1 year or surgically sterile (bilateral tubal ligation, bilateral&#xD;
             oophorectomy or hysterectomy), or is of childbearing potential and practicing one of&#xD;
             the following methods of birth control:condoms, sponge, foams, jellies, diaphragm or&#xD;
             intrauterine device (IUD),contraceptives (oral or parenteral) for three months (90&#xD;
             days) prior to study drug administration), a vasectomized partner, total abstinence&#xD;
             from sexual intercourse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If patient is female and of childbearing potential, the results of a serum pregnancy&#xD;
             test performed at Screening, prior to the first dose of adalimumab, must be negative&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has Crohn's disease for at least 4 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has not taken NSAIDs (including OTC) for ≥2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has inflammatory back pain according to the Calin or Rudwaleit criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is able and willing to self-administer sc injections or has available a&#xD;
             qualified person(s) to administer sc injections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is able to give written informed consent and to complete the study&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has current diagnosis of colitis other than Crohn's disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has symptomatic known strictures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgical bowel resections within the past 6 months or is planning any resection at any&#xD;
             time point while enrolled in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ostomy or ileoanal pouch&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Short bowel syndrome as determined by the investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received prior treatment with intravenous immunoglobulin or any&#xD;
             investigational agents within four weeks of Baseline, or five half-lives of the&#xD;
             product, whichever was longer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has been previously treated with total lymphoid irradiation or anti-CD4 or&#xD;
             CAMPATH 1H monoclonal antibodies resulting in persistent CD4 lymphopenia (CD4&#xD;
             lymphocytes &lt; 500/mm3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient was previously exposed to a biologic TNF-inhibitor&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a history of cancer or lymphoproliferative disease other than:&#xD;
             Successfully and completely treated Cervical dysplasia, with no recurrence within the&#xD;
             last five years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of uncontrolled diabetes, unstable ischemic heart disease, congestive&#xD;
             heart failure, New York Heart Association (NYHA) III, IV, recent stroke (within three&#xD;
             months), chronic leg ulcer and any other condition (e.g., indwelling urinary catheter)&#xD;
             which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would put the subject at risk by&#xD;
             participation in the protocol or who would make the subject unsuitable for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Positive serology for hepatitis B indicating acute or chronic infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject is known to have immune deficiency, history of human immunodeficiency virus&#xD;
             (HIV) or is immunocompromised&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent or recurrent or severe infections requiring hospitalization or treatment&#xD;
             with intra-venous (IV) antibiotics within 30 days, or oral antibiotics within 14 days,&#xD;
             prior to Baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects who are pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of an allergic reaction or significant sensitivity to constituents of&#xD;
             adalimumab&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a history of clinically significant drug or alcohol abuse in the last year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous diagnosis or signs of central nervous system demyelinating diseases (e.g.,&#xD;
             optic neuritis, visual disturbance, gait disorder/ataxia, facial paresis, apraxia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a history of active tuberculosis (TB), histoplasmosis or listeriosis, or&#xD;
             other currently active infections suggestive of significant or profound&#xD;
             immunosuppression, such as Pneumocystis carinii, aspergillosis or other systemic&#xD;
             infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has latent TB (positive PPD skin test) or has other risk factors for the&#xD;
             activation of latent TB, e.g. previous exposure to TB, and has not initiated TB&#xD;
             prophylaxis prior to the first adalimumab treatment. In either case, the Principal&#xD;
             Investigator (sponsor) must be contacted before initiating the study treatment (see&#xD;
             Section 5.6.4, &quot;Screening for Latent Tuberculosis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects will be excluded if the CXR is found to have changes suggestive of old healed&#xD;
             tuberculous lesion (e.g. calcified nodule, fibrotic scar, apical or basilar pleural&#xD;
             thickening etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has any condition that would prevent participation or completion in this&#xD;
             study, including language limitation or possibility that the patient will not be&#xD;
             available for the complete study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient, in the opinion of the principal investigator, is unlikely to comply with the&#xD;
             study protocol or is unsuitable for any other reason.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Walter P Maksymowych, FRCP(C)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alberta</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alberta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Edmonton</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <zip>T6G2S2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 3, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 4, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 16, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Walter P. Maksymowych</name_title>
    <organization>University of Alberta</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Spondyloarthritis</keyword>
  <keyword>Ankylosing Spondylitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Crohn's disease</keyword>
  <keyword>adalimumab</keyword>
  <keyword>treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Spondylarthritis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adalimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

