<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00979173</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00018751</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00979173</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pharmacokinetics (PK) Study of AC480 for Recurrent Glioma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Pharmacokinetic Study of AC480 Administered Twice Daily in Surgically Resectable Malignant Glioma Patients Not on Enzyme-Inducing Anticonvulsants</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Annick Desjardins</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ambit Biosciences Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Duke University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective is to evaluate the intratumoral and plasma pharmacokinetics of AC480&#xD;
      among patients who are candidates for a resection with a recurrent malignant glioma who are&#xD;
      not on CYP-3A enzyme inducing anti-epileptic drugs (EIAEDS). Secondary objectives include the&#xD;
      following: to evaluate the antiproliferative effect of AC480 by FDG-PET Scan; to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety and tolerability of AC480; and, to describe 6-month progression-free survival (PFS)&#xD;
      and radiographic response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a single institution, open label, pharmacokinetic study of AC480 in patients with&#xD;
      recurrent malignant glioma. The study will enroll 5 patients who are not on enzyme inducing&#xD;
      anti-epileptic drugs (EIAEDs) and are scheduled to undergo salvage surgical resection for&#xD;
      preoperative treatment with AC480 at 300 mg orally twice daily (BID) for 14 (plus or minus 2)&#xD;
      days before surgery (Part I- Induction Therapy). After surgery (Part II- Maintenance&#xD;
      Therapy), patients will continue to be dosed with AC480 until disease progression or&#xD;
      intolerance, and will be evaluated after every other cycle (1 cycle is 28 days).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Plasma and tumoral pharmacokinetics, as well as FDG-PET data will be analyzed to determine&#xD;
      the intratumoral and plasma levels of AC480 obtained and its antiproliferative activity.&#xD;
      After recovery from surgery, all patients will resume AC480 at 300 mg orally BID until&#xD;
      evidence of disease progression or toxicity (Part II: Maintenance Therapy). Those patients&#xD;
      will be followed for determination of 6-month progression free survival. Patients will remain&#xD;
      on treatment for as long as they have clinical benefit from the treatment. There will be no&#xD;
      limit to the number of cycles of treatment a patient can receive providing they continue to&#xD;
      benefit from and are not intolerant to AC480 administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data collected in this study will be summarized in tables listing the mean, standard&#xD;
      deviation, and number of patients for continuous data, or in tables listing count and&#xD;
      percentage for categorical data, where appropriate. All patient data will be listed by&#xD;
      patient or by parameter, all statistical analyses will be performed and all data appendices&#xD;
      will be created by using the SAS system. Pharmacokinetic analysis will be made to determine&#xD;
      if AC480 reaches the intracerebral tumor tissue. Comparisons will be made between the data&#xD;
      obtained from the plasma of the same patients treated on AC480, including determination of&#xD;
      the tumor-to-plasma ratio. The most common side effects of AC480 are generally mild to&#xD;
      moderate in severity and include: nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, fatigue, cough, elevation of&#xD;
      the liver enzymes, anemia, and rash.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2010</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intratumoral and plasma pharmacokinetics of AC480 will be obtained on surgical tissue specimens from 5 patients treated pre-operatively with AC480.</measure>
    <time_frame>At time of resection</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-proliferative effect of AC480 by FDG-PET</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intratumoral and plasma pharmacodynamics of AC480</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6-month progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic response</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse event and toxicity monitoring</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Glioma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AC480</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients who are not on enzyme inducing anti-epileptic drugs (EIAEDs) and are scheduled to undergo salvage surgical resection treated with preoperative AC480 at 300 mg BID followed by post-surgical AC480 at 300 mg BID.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AC480</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will be initiated on AC480 300mg orally BID for 14 (+/-2 days) before surgery. After surgery, subjects will continue to be dosed with AC480 until either disease progression or intolerance, and will be evaluated every other cycle (i.e., every 4 weeks).</description>
    <arm_group_label>AC480</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a histologically confirmed diagnosis of a recurrent/progressive WHO&#xD;
             grade 4 malignant glioma (glioblastoma multiforme or gliosarcoma) or WHO grade 3&#xD;
             malignant glioma (anaplastic astrocytoma, anaplastic oligodendroglioma or anaplastic&#xD;
             mixed glioma) and be surgical candidates. Recurrence will be defined based on the&#xD;
             modified MacDonald criteria or based on histopathologic confirmation of tissue&#xD;
             obtained via surgical intervention. Patients with prior low-grade glioma are eligible&#xD;
             if histologic assessment demonstrates transformation to WHO grade III or IV malignant&#xD;
             glioma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Greater than or equal to 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Karnofsky Performance Status (KPS) greater than or equal to 60%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be presenting in first, second or third relapse. Relapse is defined as&#xD;
             progression following anti-cancer therapy other than surgery, including non-surgical&#xD;
             therapies that are considered standard treatment for high-grade glioma if administered&#xD;
             to patients with prior low-grade glioma. Prior therapy must have included external&#xD;
             beam radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate bone marrow, liver and renal function as assessed by the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hematocrit &gt; or = to 29%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count (ANC) &gt; or = to 1,500/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count &gt; or = to 125,000/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &lt; or = to 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALT and AST &lt; or equal to 2.5 x the ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  INR &lt; 1.5 or a PT/PTT within normal limits (unless on therapeutic&#xD;
                  anti-coagulation). Patients receiving anti-coagulation treatment with a&#xD;
                  low-molecular weight heparin will be allowed to participate, however oral&#xD;
                  warfarin is not permitted except for low-dose warfarin (1mg po DAILY).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine &lt; or = to 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum Na, K+, Mg2+, Phosphate and Ca2+ Within Normal Limit (WNL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An interval of at least 12 weeks from completion of standard, daily XRT, unless one of&#xD;
             the following occurs: a) new area of enhancement on MRI imaging that is outside the&#xD;
             XRT field; b) biopsy proven recurrent tumor; c) radiographic evidence of progressive&#xD;
             tumor on 2 consecutive scans at least 4 weeks apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An interval of at least 4 weeks from prior chemotherapy (except nitrosoureas which&#xD;
             require 6 weeks) unless there is unequivocal evidence of tumor progression and the&#xD;
             patient has recovered from all anticipated toxicities from prior therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An interval of a least 4 weeks from exposure to investigational agents, unless there&#xD;
             is unequivocal evidence of tumor progression and the patients has recovered from all&#xD;
             anticipated toxicities from prior therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written informed consent including HIPAA language according to institutional&#xD;
             guidelines. This informed consent shall include language whereby Ambit shall have&#xD;
             access to the patient's protected health information. A signed informed consent must&#xD;
             be obtained prior to any study specific procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If sexually active, patients will take contraceptive measures for the duration of the&#xD;
             treatments and for 3 months following discontinuation of AC480.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of childbearing potential (WOCBP) must have a negative serum or urine pregnancy&#xD;
             test (sensitivity &lt; or = to 25IU HCG/L) within 72 hours prior to the start of study&#xD;
             drug administration. Males and females age ≥ 18 years. WOCBP include any female that&#xD;
             has experienced menarche and who has not undergone successful surgical sterilization&#xD;
             (hysterectomy, bilateral tubal ligation or bilateral oophorectomy) or is not post&#xD;
             menopausal (defined as amenorrhea &gt; 12 consecutive months; or women on hormone&#xD;
             replacement therapy [HRT] with documented serum follicle stimulating hormone [FSH]&#xD;
             level &gt; 35 mIU/mL). Even women who are using oral, implanted or injectable&#xD;
             contraceptive hormones or mechanical products such as an intrauterine device or&#xD;
             barrier methods (diaphragm, condoms, spermicides) to prevent pregnancy or are&#xD;
             practicing abstinence or where the partner is sterile (e.g., vasectomy), should be&#xD;
             considered to be of childbearing potential.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having received bevacizumab are eligible four weeks after the last dose of&#xD;
             bevacizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects on enzyme-inducing antiepileptic drugs (phenytoin, phenobarbitol,&#xD;
             carbamazepine, oxcarbamazepine, and primidone).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects previously treated with targeted therapies to EGFR and HER2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than 3 prior episodes of progressive disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  WOCBP who are unwilling or unable to use an acceptable method to avoid pregnancy for&#xD;
             the entire study period and for at least 3 months after completion of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men who are unwilling or unable to use an acceptable method of birth control if their&#xD;
             sexual partners are WOCBP for the entire study period and for at least 3 months after&#xD;
             completion of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A serious uncontrolled medical disorder or active infection requiring IV antibiotics,&#xD;
             which would impair the ability of the subject to receive protocol therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled or significant cardiovascular disease, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A myocardial infarction within 12 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled angina within 6 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Congestive heart failure NYHA class 3 or 4, or subjects with history of&#xD;
                  congestive heart failure NYHA class 3 or 4 in the past, unless a screening&#xD;
                  echocardiogram (ECHO) performed within 3 months prior to study entry results in a&#xD;
                  left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) that is ≥ 45%;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diagnosed or suspected long QT syndrome;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any history of clinically significant ventricular arrhythmias (such as&#xD;
                  ventricular tachycardia, ventricular fibrillation, or torsades de pointes);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any subject with a history of any arrhythmia should be discussed with the Ambit&#xD;
                  Medical Monitor prior to entry into the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Prolonged QTc interval on pre-entry electrocardiogram (&gt; 450 msec);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any history of second or third degree heart block;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Heart rate &lt; 50 / minute on pre-entry electrocardiogram;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Uncontrolled hypertension.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) positivity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis (hep) B or C or other active liver disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent clinically significant toxicity from prior chemotherapy that is Grade 2 or&#xD;
             higher by the National Cancer Institute Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events&#xD;
             (CTCAE v3) (see Inclusion Criteria).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Drugs (or medical conditions) that are generally accepted to have a risk of causing&#xD;
             torsades de pointes (see Appendix E). Subjects who have discontinued any of these&#xD;
             medications must have a wash-out period of at least 5 days or 5 half-lives of the drug&#xD;
             (whichever is greater) prior to the first dose of AC480.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Proton pump inhibitors and histamine H2 antagonists. Other antacid agents may be&#xD;
             taken, but not within 8 hours before or 4 hours after dosing of AC480. A detailed log&#xD;
             recording administration of other antacids in relation to AC480 must be kept.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical condition, serious intercurrent illness, or other extenuating circumstance&#xD;
             that, in the judgment of the Principal Investigator, could jeopardize subject safety&#xD;
             or interfere with the objectives of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is &lt; 3 years free of another primary malignancy except: if the other primary&#xD;
             malignancy is not currently clinically significant or requiring active intervention,&#xD;
             or if other primary malignancy is a basal cell skin cancer or a cervical carcinoma in&#xD;
             situ.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent administration of warfarin, rifampin or St. John's Wort, except for&#xD;
             low-dose warfarin (1mg po DAILY).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prisoners or subjects who are compulsorily detained (involuntarily incarcerated) for&#xD;
             treatment of either a psychiatric or physical (e.g., infectious) illness.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Annick Desjardins, MD, FRCPC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Duke Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center at Duke University Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Durham</city>
        <state>North Carolina</state>
        <zip>27710</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.cancer.duke.edu/btc/</url>
    <description>The Preston Robert Tisch Brain Tumor Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 6, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 17, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 28, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 28, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 29, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Duke University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Annick Desjardins</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assist Professor of Medicine-Neurology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>malignant glioma</keyword>
  <keyword>glioblastoma multiforme</keyword>
  <keyword>gliosarcoma</keyword>
  <keyword>anaplastic astrocytoma</keyword>
  <keyword>anaplastic oligodendroglioma</keyword>
  <keyword>anaplastic mixed glioma</keyword>
  <keyword>Pro00018751</keyword>
  <keyword>Duke</keyword>
  <keyword>Ambit</keyword>
  <keyword>AC480</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

