<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01791868</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>P100148</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2011-006340-75</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01791868</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy Study of Intravenous Sodium Valproate in Addition to First Line Anti Epileptic Treatment of Generalized Convulsive Status Epilepticus.</brief_title>
  <acronym>VALSE</acronym>
  <official_title>Randomized and Multicenter Study Assessing the Efficacy of Intravenous Sodium Valproate in Addition to First Line Anti Epileptic Treatment of Generalized Convulsive Status Epilepticus.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Study Hypothesis Generalized Convulsive Status Epilepticus (GCSE) is a medical emergency&#xD;
      associated with an increased morbidity and a prolonged length of hospital stay. Only 50% of&#xD;
      patients are discharged from the hospital within the first month after GCSE. Recent&#xD;
      Guidelines from Experts highlight the necessity to improve the efficiency of the first line&#xD;
      anti-epileptic (AE) therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intravenous Sodium Valproate (SV) might be an adjuvant AE drug to the recommended first line&#xD;
      AEs. Intravenous SV is available, well tolerated and easily injectible but also has&#xD;
      pharmacologic properties for reducing the risk of seizures relapses and for being&#xD;
      neuroprotective. However, efficacy of intravenous as an adjuvant therapy in GCSE has never&#xD;
      been properly assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Purpose The primary purpose is to assess if the association of intravenous Sodium&#xD;
      Valproate with the recommended treatment for Generalized Convulsive Status Epilepticus&#xD;
      increases to 20 % the number of living patients, discharged from the hospital at day 15.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patient admitted Intensive Care Unit (ICU) for a Generalized Convulsive Status Epilepticus&#xD;
      (GCSE) will be randomized if they fulfil the inclusion criteria and after the written&#xD;
      informed consent is obtained from the patient's next of kin. In clack of closed relatives,&#xD;
      patients could be included according to the French Health Code for Case of medical emergency.&#xD;
      In this situation, patient's consent should be then obtained as soon as possible According to&#xD;
      randomization arm, patients will be treated either by intravenous sodium valproate (30 mg/kg&#xD;
      during 15 min then 1 mg/kg/h during 12 h) or intravenous placebo. All included patients will&#xD;
      benefit from first-line anti epileptic drugs and symptomatic medical care, in agreement with&#xD;
      the Experts recommendation (RFE 2009).&#xD;
&#xD;
      From day-1 to day-15, level consciousness(Glasgow Coma Scale, Richmond Agitation Sedation&#xD;
      Scale), delirium (Confusion Assessment Method For Intensive Care Unit), reoccurrence of&#xD;
      seizure, vital signs, organ dysfunction (Simplified Acute Physiology Score II, Sequential&#xD;
      Organ Failure) will be daily assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At day 2, the preventive oral anti-epileptic drug will be prescribed by a neurologist,&#xD;
      blinded from randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At Day 15 and Day 30, neurological status, cognitive functions (Mini Mental State&#xD;
      Examination, Frontal Assessment Battery, Glasgow Outcome Scale), and quality of life (SF36)&#xD;
      will be assessed by a neurologist, also not aware of the randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The number of patients alive and discharged from Hospital day 15 15th day will assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      300 patients with GCSE will be randomized, 150 in each arm, in 16 ICUs and over a period of 3&#xD;
      years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 2013</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients in ICU for a GCSE discharged alive from the hospital at Day 15.</measure>
    <time_frame>15 days</time_frame>
    <description>Increasing by 20 % the number of patients admitted in ICU for a GCSE who will be discharged alive from the hospital at Day 15.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of refractory status epilepticus</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if intravenous SV as an adjuvant anti-epileptic drug, and irrespectively of the cause of GCSE, decreases as frequency of refractory status epilepticus at 3 months without increase in rate of side effects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Morbidity related to ICU stay</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if intravenous SV as an adjuvant anti-epileptic drug, and irrespectively of the cause of GCSE, decreases as morbidity related to ICU stay at 3 months without increase in rate of side effects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive dysfunction</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To determine if intravenous SV as an adjuvant anti-epileptic drug, and irrespectively of the cause of GCSE, decreases as cognitive dysfunction at 3 months without increase in rate of side effects.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">245</enrollment>
  <condition>Generalized Convulsive Status Epilepticus</condition>
  <condition>Intensive Care Unit</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous sodium valproate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intravenous sodium valproate:&#xD;
30 mg/kg during 15 min then 1 mg/kg/h during 12 h</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intravenous Placebo:&#xD;
NaCl 0,9 % during 15 min at first then during 12 h.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Intravenous Sodium Valproate</intervention_name>
    <description>According to randomization arm, patients will be treated either by intravenous sodium valproate (30 mg/kg during 15 min then 1 mg/kg/h during 12 h) or intravenous placebo. All included patients will benefit from first-line anti epileptic drugs and symptomatic medical care, in agreement with the French Experts Recommendation 2009(RFE 2009).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous sodium valproate</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>DEPAKINE®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>According to randomization arm, patients will be treated either by intravenous sodium valproate (30 mg/kg during 15 min then 1 mg/kg/h during 12 h) or intravenous placebo. All included patients will benefit from first-line anti epileptic drugs and symptomatic medical care, in agreement with the French Experts Recommendation 2009(RFE 2009).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intravenous Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>NaCl 0.9%</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient older than 18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Admitted in a participating ICU for generalized convulsive status epilepticus (GCSE)&#xD;
             i.e. with persistent or repeated generalized seizures without regaining consciousness&#xD;
             over a period of five minutes. provided that the duration of the treatment prior&#xD;
             antiepileptic does not exceed:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Six hours if GCSE is already controlled at the time of inclusion (= disappearance&#xD;
                  seizures regardless of the state of consciousness)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Twenty-four hours if GCSE persisted or is recurrent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent collected from close relation or a family member of the&#xD;
             patient. Otherwise, inclusion according to French Health Code in case of medical&#xD;
             emergency. In this case, the written informed consent of patient has to be collected&#xD;
             as soon as possible then. in absence of a close of patient, the patient may be still&#xD;
             included. the consent of the prosecution will be collected&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other type of status epilepticus (including atypical form) occured before the onset of&#xD;
             anti epileptic.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patient of childbearing age ≥ 18 ans et &lt; 50 ans&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient prior treated by depakine in emergency for the GCSE&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The length of stay in hospital expected before the occurrence of GCSE &gt; 15 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected Length of stay in ICU &lt;12h .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women, eclampsia checked by a systematic pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing chronic or acute hepatitis, or Cirrhosis B or C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Family history of acute hepatitis, especially drug-related hepatitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other sodium valproate Contraindications : Hypersensitivity to sodium valproate or&#xD;
             derivatives, acute or chronic hepatitis; personal or family history of severe&#xD;
             hepatitis, in particular drug; hepatic porphyria, mefloquine or hypericum taking.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  life expectancy expected ≤ 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients already included in another clinical trial on GCSE.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non affiliation to a social health care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under tutelage.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has already been included in this protocol and who completed the clinical&#xD;
             trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hervé OUTIN, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Service de Réanimation Médico Chirurgicale, Hôpital Poissy Saint-Germain en Laye</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Raymond Poincare</name>
      <address>
        <city>Garche</city>
        <state>Haute DE Seine</state>
        <zip>92380</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2017</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 13, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 13, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 15, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 16, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Generalized convulsive status epilepticus</keyword>
  <keyword>Sodium valproate</keyword>
  <keyword>Refractory status epilepticus</keyword>
  <keyword>Mortality</keyword>
  <keyword>Epilepsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Intensive Care Unit</keyword>
  <keyword>Neurological sequela</keyword>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>Adult</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Status Epilepticus</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Valproic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

