<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01795573</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MCC-17263</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01795573</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ex-vivo Expanded Donor Regulatory T Cells for Prevention of Acute Graft-Versus-Host Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase I Trial of Ex-vivo Expanded Donor Regulatory T Cells for Prevention of Acute Graft-Versus-Host Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center and Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Clinical trial of allospecific regulatory t cells (Tregs) for prevention of acute&#xD;
      graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) in human leukocyte antigen (HLA) identical sibling&#xD;
      transplants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the safety of sirolimus based immune suppression and ex-vivo expanded donor&#xD;
      regulatory T cells for the prevention of acute graft-versus-host disease following allogeneic&#xD;
      hematopoietic cell transplantation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 29, 2014</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 14, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximally Tolerated dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>MTD of donor Treg in combination with standard dose SIR/TAC immune suppression. The occurrence of dose-limiting toxicity in &gt;= 33% serves as the boundary for the MTD of donor Treg.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acute GVHD incidence</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to day 100</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical evidence of acute GVHD will be recorded per standard grading scheme. GVHD grade will be reported weekly from day 0-100 both for site-specific involvement, as well as an overall composite score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Relapse Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as time from transplantation (day 0 as day of stem cell infusion per standard nomenclature) to relapse or death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-relapse Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as mortality while underlying malignancy is in remission.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as time from transplantation (day 0 as day of stem cell infusion per standard nomenclature) to death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Graft Versus Host Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cultured Treg cells</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Co-culturing of recipient dendritic cells and donor Treg cells given prior to allogeneic stem cell transplant</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cultured Treg cells</intervention_name>
    <description>Co-culturing of recipient dendritic cells and donor Treg. Treg administration will occur 2 days before the allogeneic stem cell transplant (i.e. day -2 with reference of day 0 as stem cell infusion date).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cultured Treg cells</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnoses:&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. Hematologic malignancies - Acute myelogenous leukemia (AML), acute lymphoblastic&#xD;
             leukemia (ALL), myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS), chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL),&#xD;
             non-Hodgkin lymphoma (NHL), Hodgkin lymphoma (HL), multiple myeloma (MM) - in complete&#xD;
             remission (CR). Complete remission is defined per morphologic, cytogenetic, FISH,&#xD;
             molecular, and radiographic imaging studies appropriate for each condition listed.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AML, ALL: Normal values for absolute neutrophil count (&gt;1000/microL) and platelet&#xD;
                  count (&gt;100,000/microL); Absence of extramedullary leukemia; Less than 5 percent&#xD;
                  blast cells present in the bone marrow&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MDS: Bone marrow with ≤5 percent myeloblasts with normal maturation of all cell&#xD;
                  lines; Peripheral blood demonstrates hemoglobin ≥11 g/dL, platelets ≥100 x&#xD;
                  10^9/L, neutrophils ≥1 x 10^9/L, and no circulating blasts&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CLL: Absence of constitutional symptoms attributable to CLL; No lymph nodes &gt;1.5&#xD;
                  cm in diameter on computed tomography; No hepatomegaly or splenomegaly by&#xD;
                  computed tomography; Absolute neutrophil count &gt;1500/microL; Platelet count&#xD;
                  &gt;100,000/microL; No clonal lymphocytes in the peripheral blood by&#xD;
                  immunophenotyping; Bone marrow with no evidence of clonal CLL (by flow cytometry&#xD;
                  and/or immunohistochemistry&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  NHL: No clinical evidence of disease or disease-related symptoms; Typically&#xD;
                  FDG-avid lymphomas: a post-treatment residual mass of any size is permitted as&#xD;
                  long as it is PET negative; Variably FDG-avid lymphoma/FDG avidity unknown: all&#xD;
                  lymph nodes normal size by CT; Spleen and liver non-palpable and without nodules;&#xD;
                  If pretreatment bone marrow biopsy was positive, repeat bone marrow biopsy must&#xD;
                  be negative; if morphologically indeterminate, immunohistochemistry should be&#xD;
                  negative If pretreatment bone marrow biopsy was positive, repeat bone marrow&#xD;
                  biopsy must be negative; if morphologically indeterminate, immunohistochemistry&#xD;
                  should be negative&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HL: No clinical evidence of disease or disease-related symptoms; A post-treatment&#xD;
                  residual mass of any size is permitted as long as it is PET negative; Spleen and&#xD;
                  liver must be non-palpable and without nodules; If a pre-treatment bone marrow&#xD;
                  biopsy was positive, an adequate bone marrow biopsy from the same site must be&#xD;
                  cleared of infiltrate; if this is indeterminate by morphology,&#xD;
                  immunohistochemistry should be negative&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MM: Absence of monoclonal protein in serum and urine by immunofixation with no&#xD;
                  current evidence of soft tissue plasmacytoma; Bone marrow aspirate and biopsy&#xD;
                  must demonstrate less than 5 percent clonal plasma cells; In patients who lack&#xD;
                  measurable M proteins in the serum and urine being monitored using the FLC&#xD;
                  levels, the definition of CR requires a normalization of the free light chain&#xD;
                  (FLC) ratio in addition to the above criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MDS: May have achieved CR through either hypomethylating agent therapy, induction&#xD;
                  chemotherapy, or other therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  MDS: Low/intermediate-1 IPSS risk category patients are eligible only if they&#xD;
                  have failed prior therapy or are transfusion-dependent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripheral blood white blood count (WBC) greater than 2,000 per microliter (required&#xD;
             for collection of dendritic cell precursors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate vital organ function: Left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) ≥ 45% by&#xD;
             multigated acquisition (MUGA) scan or echocardiogram; Forced expiratory volume in one&#xD;
             second (FEV1), forced vital capacity (FVC), and diffusing lung capacity oxygenation&#xD;
             (DLCO) ≥ 50% of predicted values on pulmonary function tests; Transaminases (AST, ALT)&#xD;
             &lt; 3 times upper limit of normal values; Creatinine clearance ≥ 50cc/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infectious disease criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No active infection; infection controlled with antimicrobial therapy is not&#xD;
                  excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HIV negative by ELISA or reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR)&#xD;
                  [if ELISA is positive and RT-PCR is negative, the ELISA is considered false&#xD;
                  positive]&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatitis B and C negative by serology or RT-PCR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Must complete full screening panel: HIV 1, 2 serology and RT-PCR; human T cell&#xD;
                  lymphotropic virus types 1/2 (HTLV-1/2) serology; rapid plasma reagin (RPR)&#xD;
                  serology; Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) serology; Cytomegalovirus (CMV) serology;&#xD;
                  herpes simplex virus (HSV) serology; Varicella-. Zoster Virus (VZV) serology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Performance status: Karnofsky Performance Status Score ≥ 60%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement to utilize effective contraceptive methods during the study (for one year)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eligible donors will include siblings age ≥ 18 matched with the recipient at HLA-A, B,&#xD;
             C, and DRB1&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antithymocyte globulin (ATG) as part of the conditioning regimen&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joseph Pidala, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Moffitt Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H Lee Moffitt Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tampa</city>
        <state>Florida</state>
        <zip>33612</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.moffitt.org/</url>
    <description>H. Lee Moffitt Cancer Center &amp; Research Institute</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 18, 2013</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2013</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 20, 2013</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>GVHD</keyword>
  <keyword>AML</keyword>
  <keyword>ALL</keyword>
  <keyword>MDS</keyword>
  <keyword>CLL</keyword>
  <keyword>NHL</keyword>
  <keyword>HL</keyword>
  <keyword>MM</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Graft vs Host Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

