<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03454724</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MeRes-201706</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03454724</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study of MeRes100 in the Treatment of Patient With Coronary Artery Disease.</brief_title>
  <acronym>MeReS100-China</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multi Center Randomized Control Study of MeRes100 Sirolimus Eluting BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System in Treatment of Coronary Artery Disease Patients: MeRes - China.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Meril Life Sciences Pvt. Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Meril Life Sciences Pvt. Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Multi Center Randomized Control Study of MeRes100 Sirolimus Eluting BioResorbable&#xD;
      Vascular Scaffold System in treatment of approximately 484 subjects with Coronary Artery&#xD;
      Disease in China. Eligible subjects shall have up to two de novo lesions in different&#xD;
      epicardial vessels (One lesion in each coronary artery or it's major branch),Target lesion&#xD;
      shall have visually estimated diameter stenosis ≥ 70% (or ≥ 50% and has clinical evidence of&#xD;
      myocardial ischemia), lesion length ≤ 24mm, reference vascular diameter visually ≥ 2.75mm and&#xD;
      ≤ 4.0mm. And subjects must meet all the study inclusion / exclusion criteria before enrolment&#xD;
      in the study.All subjects shall accept clinical follow up at 1 month, 6 months, 12 months, 2&#xD;
      years, 3 years, 4 years and 5 years post procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Multi Center Randomized (MeRes:XIENCE=1:1) Control Study of MeRes100 Sirolimus&#xD;
      Eluting BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System in treatment of approximately 484 subjects&#xD;
      with Coronary Artery Disease in China. The post marketed XIENCE Everolimus Eluting Coronary&#xD;
      Stent System will serve as the control device, to evaluate the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
      MeRes100 Sirolimus Eluting BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System in coronary artery disease,&#xD;
      and to support the product registration approval of the China Food and Drug Administration&#xD;
      (CFDA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible subjects shall have up to two de novo lesions in different epicardial vessels ( One&#xD;
      lesion in each coronary artery or it's major branch),Target lesion shall have visually&#xD;
      estimated diameter stenosis ≥ 70% (or ≥ 50% and has clinical evidence of myocardial&#xD;
      ischemia), lesion length ≤ 24mm, reference vascular diameter visually ≥ 2.75mm and ≤ 4.0mm.&#xD;
      And subjects must meet all the study inclusion / exclusion criteria before enrolment in the&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All the subjects shall accept angiography follow up at 12 months post procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OCT subgroup ((N=80, 40 from test group and 40 from control group) shall accept follow up of&#xD;
      OCT at immediately and 12 months post procedure. In segment late lumen loss at 12 months post&#xD;
      procedure is the primary endpoint, and the percentage of stent strut neointimal coverage&#xD;
      assessed with OCT at 12 months post procedure is the key secondary endpoint.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>1:1 Randomization of Study Device and Control</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>In-segment Late Lumen Loss</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Angiographic analysis for measuring Late Lumen Loss in both the treatment group</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The percentage of stent strut neointimal coverage assessed with OCT</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>OCT analysis will be done to identify percentage of Neointimal coverage</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">484</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MeRes100 BRS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>MeRes100 Sirolimus Eluting BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System indicated for the treatment of coronary artery disease along with standard percutaneous angioplasty procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Xience EES</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Xience EES is a Everolimus Eluting Coronary Stent System indicated for the treatment of coronary artery disease along with standard percutaneous angioplasty procedure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MeRes100 Sirolimus-Eluting BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System</intervention_name>
    <description>MeRes100 Sirolimus-Eluting BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System used in the treatment of patients with coronary artery disease along with standard percutaneous angioplasty procedure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MeRes100 BRS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Xience EES</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Xience EES Everolimus Eluting Coronary Stent System</intervention_name>
    <description>Xience EES Everolimus Eluting Coronary Stent System indicated for the treatment of coronary artery disease along with standard percutaneous angioplasty procedure.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MeRes100 BRS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Xience EES</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  General inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Age ≥ 18 and ≤75years old, man or non-pregnant or non-lactating woman.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subjects with asymptomatic ischemic evidence, stable or unstable angina, or old&#xD;
                  myocardial infarction &gt;7 days, suitable for selective PCI. Subjects without&#xD;
                  contraindications of coronary artery bypass grafting.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subjects be able to understand the purpose of this study, volunteer to&#xD;
                  participate and sign informed consent, willing to accept invasive imaging&#xD;
                  follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Angiographic inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. One de novo target lesion or up-to two de novo target lesions in different epicardial&#xD;
             vessels: Different epicardial vessels are defined as left anterior descending artery&#xD;
             (LAD) and its branches, left circumflex artery (LCX) arteries and its branches, and&#xD;
             right coronary arteries (RCA) and its branches. Thus, for example, the subject must&#xD;
             not have two target lesions required to be treated at the LAD and its branches at the&#xD;
             same time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Target lesion diameter stenosis ≥ 70% (or ≥ 50% simultaneously shall have clinical&#xD;
             evidence of myocardial ischemia), and TIMI flow grade ≥1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Target lesion length ≤ 24mm (estimated visually); reference vessel diameter between ≥&#xD;
             2.75 mm to ≤ 4.00 mm.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Each target lesion can be fully covered by one scaffold.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  General exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Any non-target lesion in coronary artery needs to be treated simultaneously or&#xD;
                  selectively (anticipation within 1 year), non-target lesion defined as any lesion&#xD;
                  that does not fulfill the inclusion/exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Any newly onset acute myocardial infarction within 1 week (&lt; 7days) or,&#xD;
                  myocardial enzyme has not return to normal level (clinically non-significant)&#xD;
                  after myocardial infarction.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subject has undergone prior PCI within the target vessel during the last 12months&#xD;
                  or plans to receive another PCI within 6months or subject with history of CABG.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Subjects with severe heart failure, such as ≥ grade III NYHA or left ventricular&#xD;
                  ejection fraction &lt;30% (accessed by ECHO/ultrasound or left ventricular&#xD;
                  angiography).&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Blood tests shows the platelet count is less than 100 × 109 / L, or more than 700&#xD;
                  ×109 / L, the white blood cells count is less than 3 × 109 / L.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Pre-procedure severe liver or kidney functional damaged: serum creatinine&gt; 1.5mg&#xD;
&#xD;
                  / dl (132.6μmol / L) or subject is receiving hemodialysis, ALT or AST were three&#xD;
                  times greater than the upper limit of normal.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Subjects with bleeding tendency, active gastrointestinal ulcers, history of&#xD;
                  cerebral hemorrhage or history of subarachnoid hemorrhage, history within six&#xD;
                  months of ischemic stroke, contraindications of anti-platelet agents and&#xD;
                  anticoagulants treatment, and subjects cannot receive anti-thrombolytic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Hypersensitive or allergic to antiplatelet drugs(such as aspirin and&#xD;
                  clopidogrel), anticoagulant drugs(such as heparin), contrast media, and scaffold&#xD;
                  components(such as PLLA，PDLLA, sirolimus, everolimus, iridium and platinum).&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. The subject's life expectancy is less than 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Subjects who anticipated in other drug or medical device clinical trial but&#xD;
                  haven't finished the primary endpoint evaluation visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. The investigators judged that subjects were poorly compliance and unable to&#xD;
                  complete the study as required.&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Subjects have accepted substantial organ transplant or ready to undergo organ&#xD;
                  transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Subjects have unstable arrhythmia, such as high-risk ventricular premature beats,&#xD;
                  and ventricular tachycardia.&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Subjects are receiving or planning to receive chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
              15. Subjects have received or planning to receive radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
              16. Subjects with immunosuppressive or autoimmune diseases, are receiving or planning&#xD;
                  to receive immunosuppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
              17. Patients suffering from HIV, HBV or HCV infections&#xD;
&#xD;
              18. Subjects are planning to receive or are receiving long-term anticoagulation&#xD;
                  therapy, such as heparin, warfarin and similar agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
              19. Subjects are planning to accept selective surgery within 12 months, need to&#xD;
                  discontinue aspirin or clopidogrel (DAPT therapy).&#xD;
&#xD;
              20. Subjects with diffuse peripheral vascular disease, cannot use 6F catheter.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Angiographic exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects with coronary artery triple vessel lesion in LAD, LCX or RCA, all need to be&#xD;
             treated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Target lesion locates in left main.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Target lesion locates in the aorto-ostial of RCA (within 3 mm of the origin of the&#xD;
             RCA).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Target lesion locates within 3 mm of the origin of the LM, LAD and LCX.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Target lesion involving a bifurcation with a:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Side branch ≥2.0 mm in diameter, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Side branch with diameter stenosis ≥ 50%, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Side branch requiring protection guide wire, or&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Side branch requiring pre-dilatation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Anatomy proximal to or within the lesion that may impair delivery of the&#xD;
&#xD;
             MeRes100TM or Xience EES, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Extreme angulation (≥ 90°) proximal to or within the target lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Excessive tortuosity (≥ two 45° angles) proximal to or within the target lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Moderate or heavy calcification proximal to or within the target lesion&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Target lesion involves a myocardial bridge.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Target vessel contains thrombus as indicated in the angiographic images or IVUS.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Target vessel has been previously treated with a stent at any time prior to the index&#xD;
             procedure such that the MeRes100TM or XIENCE stent would need to cross the stent to&#xD;
             reach the target lesion..&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Target vessel has been previously treated with a stent and the target lesion is within&#xD;
             5 mm proximal to a previously treated lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Chronic complete occlusive lesion (preoperative TIMI grade 0 flow).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Target lesion which prevents complete balloon pre-dilatation, defined as full balloon&#xD;
             expansion with the following outcomes:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Residual %DS is &lt; 40% (per visual estimation), ( ≤ 20% is strongly recommended).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. TIMI Grade-3 flow (per visual estimation).&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. No angiographic complications (e.g., no-reflow, distal embolization, side branch&#xD;
                  closure).&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. No dissections NHLBI grade D-F.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. No chest pain lasting &gt; 5 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. No ST depression or elevation lasting &gt; 5 minutes.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gao Runlin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fuwai Hospital CAMS</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Imrankhan M Lohani, M.Sc.</last_name>
    <phone>9619608544</phone>
    <email>Imrankhan.lohani@merillife.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ashok Thakkar, Ph.D</last_name>
    <phone>9879443584</phone>
    <email>ashok.thakkar@merillife.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 15, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 5, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 6, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 13, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 13, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 14, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>BioResorbable Vascular Scaffold System</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronary Artery Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Ischemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronary Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sirolimus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Everolimus</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

