<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01245166</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MCCD09013B</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01245166</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase III Randomized, Double-blind, Parallel-group Study to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Acarmet (Metformin HCl 500 mg Plus Acarbose 50 mg Tablets) Versus Acarbose Alone in Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</brief_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lotus Pharmaceutical</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lotus Pharmaceutical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Type 2 diabetes mellitus is a chronic metabolic disorder which is caused by both insulin&#xD;
      secretion deficiency and insulin action defect. In this type of subjects, fasting&#xD;
      hyperglycemia is the result of the elevated rate of basal hepatic glucose production, and it&#xD;
      is coexisting with hyperinsulinemia.After a meal, the impaired control of hepatic glucose&#xD;
      production by insulin and decreased insulin-mediated glucose uptake by muscle contributed&#xD;
      nearly equally to postprandial hyperglycemia(Scheen, 1997). Type 2 diabetic subjects&#xD;
      experience significant morbidity and mortality from microvascular (retinopathy, nephropathy,&#xD;
      and neuropathy) and macrovascular (cardiovascular disease, stroke, and peripheral vascular&#xD;
      disease) complications. The appropriate treatment and good glycemic control of diabetes is&#xD;
      therefore important and necessary (Vaag, 2006). Evidences suggest that combination therapy&#xD;
      using oral antidiabetic agents with different mechanisms of action may be more effective in&#xD;
      achieving and maintaining target blood glucose level (Turner et al., 2005).There are five&#xD;
      classes of oral antihyperglycemic agents (sulfonylureas, biguanides, α- ucosidase inhibitors,&#xD;
      thiazolidinediones and meglitinides) currently available to improve glycemic control in&#xD;
      subjects with type 2 diabetes, each of which works through a different mechanism of action.&#xD;
      Metformin, a biguanide which has insulin-sensitizing properties, can be used alone or in&#xD;
      combination with other classes of agents. Metformin is the currently the first-choice&#xD;
      treatment in subjects with diagnosed type 2 diabetic subjects and obesity, characterized by&#xD;
      insulin-resistance. Metformin also provides reduction of body weight and ameliorates lipid&#xD;
      abnormalities and is thought to be related to a reduction in hepatic gluconeogenesis (Hundal&#xD;
      &amp; Inzucchi, 2003).Acarbose, the α-glucosidase inhibitor, is approved for the treatment of&#xD;
      type 2 diabetes, and first approved for prediabetes treatment (Chiasson et al., 1994; Breuer,&#xD;
      2003; Chiasson et al., 2002). The drug was launched worldwide as a type 2 diabetes&#xD;
      monotherapy and combination therapy in 1990 which has proven efficacious as first-line&#xD;
      therapy (Coniff et al., 1995) and in combination with sulfonylureas or insulin (Kelley et&#xD;
      al., 1998). Acarbose and metformin are both associated with beneficial effects on&#xD;
      hyperglycemia, hyperinsulinemia, body weight, and, in some studies,triglyceride levels&#xD;
      (Krentz et al., 1994). Because these factors are part of a cluster of risk factors for&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease, combining the two drugs may be useful. In long-term clinical studies,&#xD;
      acarbose has shown a favorable safety profile (Hasche et al., 1999).In combination with&#xD;
      metformin, acarbose has been shown to improve long-term glycemic control (Rosenstock et al.,&#xD;
      1998; Halimi et al., 2000). This study was conducted as a further vestigation into the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of concurrent use of acarbose and metformin in type 2 diabetes mellitus&#xD;
      subjects.Lotus Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd. intends to initiate Phase III program to investigate&#xD;
      assess the efficacy and safety of metformin in combination with acarbose for type 2 diabetes&#xD;
      mellitus subjects considered inadequately blood glucose control. Since combination tablet of&#xD;
      acarbose and metformin has not yet been approved by the Taiwan DOH, this study is conducted&#xD;
      to evaluate the efficacy and safety of combination tablet of acarbose and metformin in the&#xD;
      treatment of type 2 diabetes mellitus subjects in Taiwan. Acarbose is chosen as an&#xD;
      active-comparator.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date>November 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The changes from baseline in HbA1c to the end of treatment period</measure>
    <time_frame>-4 weeks, 0 week, 8 weeks, 12 weeks, 16 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the change from baseline to the end of treatment in FBG, PBG, lipid profiles, and body weight. The safety evaluation will include: 1) Adverse events; 2) Laboratory data; 3) Physical examination; 4) Vital signs; 5) 12- lead ECG</measure>
    <time_frame>-4 weeks, 0 week, 4 weeks, 8 weeks, 12 weeks, 16 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">220</enrollment>
  <condition>The Objectives of the Study is to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of Acarmet (Metformin HCl 500 mg</condition>
  <condition>Plus Acarbose 50 mg Tablets) Thrice Daily Versus Acarbose 50 mg Thrice Daily Over 16 Weeks in</condition>
  <condition>Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus.</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acarbose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin/Acarbose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acarbose</intervention_name>
    <description>Acarbose 50 mg, per orem, thrice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acarbose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Metformin/Acarbose</intervention_name>
    <description>Metformin HCl 500 mg plus Acarbose 50 mg Tablets, per orem, thrice daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metformin/Acarbose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects may be included in the study only if they meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Male or female subjects aged ≥ 20 and ≤ 80 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subject with type 2 diabetes mellitus;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subject with documented HbA1c ≥ 7 % and ≤ 10 % within 3 months prior study and at&#xD;
                  screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Body mass index &lt; 35 kg/m2;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Subject is willing and able to comply with study procedures and sign informed&#xD;
                  consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects will be excluded from the study for any of the following reasons:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Subject with type 1 diabetes or secondary diabetes;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subject with history or concurrent ketonuria or other acidosis;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Subject with type 2 diabetes mellitus treated with high dose of sulfonylurea&#xD;
                  (gliclazide &gt; 320 mg, glibenclamide &gt; 20 mg, glimepiride &gt; 6 mg, and glipizide &gt;&#xD;
                  20 mg) or with biguanides (metformin &gt; 2000 mg), or of α-glucosidase inhibitors&#xD;
                  (acarbose &gt; 300 mg), or with meglitinides (repaglinide &gt; 6 mg and nateglinide &gt;&#xD;
                  360 mg), thiazolidinedione (rosiglitazone &gt; 4 mg, pioglitazone &gt; 30 mg) or with&#xD;
                  insulin;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Subject with gastrointestinal disease that may interfere with absorption of the&#xD;
                  investigational products at discretion of investigator, including but are not&#xD;
                  limited to malabsorption syndromes and gastric ulcer;&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Subject with kidney function impairment defined as serum creatinine &gt; 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
                  for male, serum creatinine &gt; 1.4 mg/dL for female, or liver function impairment&#xD;
                  defined as ALT &gt; 3 X ULN, or AST &gt; 3 X ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Subject with history of drug or alcohol abuse within the past 1 year;&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Subject who have been diagnosed with acute myocardial infarction or cardiac&#xD;
                  failure within 6 months preceding screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Subject with hypersensitivity to acarbose and/or metformin products;&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Subject with active cancer, defined as ongoing, progressing cancer, or &lt; 5 years&#xD;
                  of stable disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Hemoglobin values &lt; 10 gm/dl for females or &lt;11 gm/dl for males;&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. Female subject of childbearing potential who:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  is lactating; or · has positive urine pregnancy test at Visit 1; or&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  refuse to adopt reliable method of contraception during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Subject is contraindicated to acarbose and/or metformin treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. Subject has received any investigational agent within 28 days prior to the first&#xD;
                  dose of investigational product;&#xD;
&#xD;
              14. Subject who have a history or evidence of a medical condition that would expose&#xD;
                  them to an undue risk of a significant adverse event during the course of the&#xD;
                  trial, including but not limited to hepatic, renal, respiratory, cardiovascular,&#xD;
                  endocrine,immune, neurological, or hematological disease as determined by the&#xD;
                  clinical judgment of the investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Taichung Veterans General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taichung</city>
        <zip>40705</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Elaine Liu, Bachelor</last_name>
      <phone>886-2-2778-5188</phone>
      <phone_ext>335</phone_ext>
      <email>elaine@lotuspharm.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2010</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 19, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 19, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 22, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 19, 2010</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 19, 2010</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">November 22, 2010</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>Dr. Wayne-Huey-Herng Sheu</name_title>
    <organization>Taichung Veterans General Hospital</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Metformin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Acarbose</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

