<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01244789</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ENGOT-EN2-DGCG</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2010-023081-52</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01244789</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chemotherapy or Observation in Stage I-II Intermediate or High Risk Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Randomized Trial of Postoperative Chemotherapy or no Further Treatment for Patients With Node-negative Stage I-II Intermediate or High Risk Endometrial Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Danish Gynecological Cancer Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Arbeitsgemeinschaft Gynaekologische Onkologie Austria</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>North Eastern German Society of Gynaecological Oncology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Nordic Society of Gynaecological Oncology - Clinical Trials Unit</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Belgian Gynaecological Oncology Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mario Negri Gynecologic Oncology group (MaNGO)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Israeli Society of Gynecologic Oncology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Multicenter Italian Trials in Ovarian cancer and gynecologic malignancies (MITTO)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Central and Eastern European Oncology Group</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Danish Gynecological Cancer Group</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with stage 1 &amp; 2 endometrial cancer are treated with surgery. Despite the fact that&#xD;
      disease is confound to uterus, unfortunately some of these patients may relapse and die of&#xD;
      their disease. Postoperative radiotherapy cannot improve survival. Chemotherapy has shown&#xD;
      survival benefit in more advanced stage disease (stage 3 &amp; 4).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study evaluates if one can improve survival in intermediate and high risk early-stage&#xD;
      patients by offering them postoperative chemotherapy. This is a randomized phase 3 trial&#xD;
      where effect of postoperative chemotherapy is compared with postoperative observation alone&#xD;
      (standard strategy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Substudy: Translational research&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with medium and high risk stage I and II endometrial cancers have, despite radical&#xD;
      surgery, a rather high risk for progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adjuvant radiotherapy was the traditional therapy for many decades. Four randomized phase III&#xD;
      studies and a meta-analysis have revealed that adjuvant radiotherapy improves local control&#xD;
      at the cost of excessive short and long term toxicity, though has absolutely no impact on&#xD;
      survival.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Two phase III studies have randomized between adjuvant radiotherapy versus adjuvant&#xD;
      chemotherapy, both failed to show any difference in survival between radiotherapy and&#xD;
      chemotherapy, though both studies are criticized for inferior chemotherapy regimens or&#xD;
      inclusion of good prognosis patients. The GOG-122 study on more advanced cases (stage 3 &amp; 4)&#xD;
      randomized between combination chemotherapy versus whole abdominal irradiation and found&#xD;
      significant improvement in survival in the chemotherapy arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      NSGO-EC-9501 and MaNGO studies have indicated that adjuvant chemotherapy added to adjuvant&#xD;
      radiotherapy may improve survival compared to adjuvant radiotherapy alone in early stage&#xD;
      medium and high risk patients. One may conclude that impact on survival comes only from&#xD;
      chemotherapy. Many investigators have therefore adapted adjuvant chemotherapy as standard&#xD;
      treatment in various countries including Denmark. However, such conclusion has low level of&#xD;
      evidence, as there are no randomized phase III studies comparing postoperative observation&#xD;
      alone versus adjuvant chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is of utmost importance to demonstrate efficacy of adjuvant combination chemotherapy in a&#xD;
      randomized phase III trial comparing to no further treatment in the medium and high risk node&#xD;
      negative stage 1 &amp; 2 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Combination chemotherapy regimen of paclitaxel-carboplatin is proposed in this study, as this&#xD;
      combination is effective and well tolerated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The eligible patients for such a study are a fraction of patients with endometrial cancer&#xD;
      therefore this study will be performed within the ENGOT collaboration.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 15, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>To detect an overall absolute difference in five-year survival of 10%, from 72% to 82%, at the 2.5% level with 80% power, 135 deaths corresponding to 644 patients are needed. Assuming a dropout rate of 5%, 678 patients have to be accrued, leaving 644 patients for the overall analysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Survival in endometrioid subgroup</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>In the endometrioid subgroup an absolute difference in five-year survival of 12%, from 74% to 86% is expected. Assuming this, 79 deaths corresponding to 438 patients are needed to yield 80% power at the 2.5% level. Assuming a dropout rate of 5%, 678 patients have to be accrued, leaving 644 patients for the overall analysis and 75% of these, or 483 patients, for the analysis in the endometrioid subgroup.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Specific Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Acute toxicity (0-6 months from randomization). Late toxicity is registered during whole study period. Exploratory endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>EORTC QLQ-30 EORTC QLQ-EN-34</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of isolated pelvic relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of isolated distant relapse</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of mixed (local &amp; distant) relapses</measure>
    <time_frame>May 2017</time_frame>
    <description>Exploratory endpoint</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">244</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Observation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>postoperative observation only</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Combination chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>postoperative 6 courses of 3 weekly iv carboplatin-paclitaxel combination chemotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>carboplatin and paclitaxel</intervention_name>
    <description>6 courses of iv 3-weekly chemotherapy Carboplatin AUC5 Paclitaxel 175mg/m2</description>
    <arm_group_label>Combination chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>observation</intervention_name>
    <description>active observation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Observation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Target Population&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Only node-negative patients are eligible: Histological confirmed endometrial carcinoma&#xD;
             with no macroscopic remaining tumour after primary surgery and lymph-node negative&#xD;
             disease, with one of the following postoperative FIGO 2009 stage and grade:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Stage I grade 3 endometrioid adenocarcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Stage II endometrioid adenocarcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Stage I and II type 2 histology (clear cell, serous, squamous cell carcinoma, or&#xD;
                  undifferentiated carcinoma) Prior therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients have undergone hysterectomy (total abdominal hysterectomy, radical&#xD;
             hysterectomy, laparoscopic or robotic hysterectomy) and bilateral&#xD;
             salpingo-oophorectomy (BSO) and pelvic lymphadenectomy (LNE).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. LNE: minimum 12 pelvic nodes (6 from each side) should be removed. Para-aortic LNE is&#xD;
             optional&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Omentectomy strongly recommended in clear cell, serous or undifferentiated carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Surgery performed within 10 weeks of randomization. If the dates for hysterectomy and&#xD;
             lymph node dissection are different, 10 weeks are counted from the last surgery, and&#xD;
             in that case the gap between two surgeries should not exceed 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Other inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients must give informed consent according to the rules and regulations of the&#xD;
             individual participating centres&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients have not received any other anticancer therapy other than surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adjuvant vaginal brachytherapy is permitted in both arms. In chemotherapy arm, timing&#xD;
             of VBT should not cause delay in chemotherapy delivery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients must have a WHO performance status of 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients must have an adequate bone-marrow, renal and hepatic function (WBC&#xD;
             ≥3.0x109/L, neutrophils ≥1.5x109/L, platelets ≥100x109/L, total S-bilirubin &lt;2 x upper&#xD;
             normal value, ALAT &lt;2.5 x upper normal value, estimated GFR &gt;50 ml/min (measured or&#xD;
             calculated according to Cockroft-Gault or Jeliffe). Up to 5% deviation for&#xD;
             hematological values and 10% deviation for s-bilirubin and ALAT are tolerated.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Life expectancy of at least 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients must be fit to receive combination chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient's age &gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Target Disease Exceptions&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Carcinosarcoma, Sarcomas or small cell carcinoma with neuroendocrine differentiation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Prohibited Treatments and/or Therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. External Beam Radiotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Concurrent cancer therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Concurrent treatment with an anticancer investigational agent or participation in&#xD;
             another anticancer clinical trial Other exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Previous or concurrent malignant disease except for curatively treated carcinoma in&#xD;
             situ of the cervix or basal cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Active infection or other serious underlying medical condition, which might prevent&#xD;
             the patient from receiving treatment or to be followed&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Whatever reasons which interferes with an adequate follow-up&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mansoor R Mirza, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Danish Gynecological Cancer Group</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Danish Gynecological Cancer Group (DGCG)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <zip>2100</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 18, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 18, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 19, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 21, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 21, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 22, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>endometrial cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>chemotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>carboplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>paclitaxel</keyword>
  <keyword>Stage 1 &amp; 2</keyword>
  <keyword>node-negative</keyword>
  <keyword>intermediate risk</keyword>
  <keyword>high risk</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

