<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00968370</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2008-009</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00968370</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Trial in Childhood Pneumonia With Malnutrition</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized, Controlled Clinical Trial of Day-care Based and Hospitalized Management of Severe and Very Severe Pneumonia, With Severe Malnutrition, With/Without Associated Co-morbidities in Children</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Basel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institute of Child health &amp; Shishu Sasthya Foundation Hospital (ICHSH), Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Radda MCH-FP Centre, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The impetus for this study came from the findings of the investigators' recently published&#xD;
      study entitled &quot;Day-care management of severe and very severe pneumonia, without associated&#xD;
      co-morbidities such as severe malnutrition, in an urban health clinic in Dhaka, Bangladesh&quot;.&#xD;
      If day-care management is found to have comparable efficacy to that of hospital management of&#xD;
      severe and very severe pneumonia in children then they could be managed at outpatient,&#xD;
      day-care set ups reducing hospitalization and thus freeing beds for management of other&#xD;
      children who need hospital care. Such management could also be implemented in rural areas of&#xD;
      Bangladesh and potentially to other developing countries. Additionally, availability of the&#xD;
      treatment facility in community set-ups will be cost and time saving for the population. But,&#xD;
      as patients with severe malnutrition were excluded from the pilot study for ethical reasons,&#xD;
      the peer reviewers of the manuscript felt that the study findings cannot be applied to the&#xD;
      treatment of severe and very severe pneumonia in general. Similarly, management of severely&#xD;
      malnourished children with associated complications relies on hospital-based treatment. In&#xD;
      another study, a day-care clinic approach by providing antibiotics, micronutrients, diet and&#xD;
      supportive care to severely malnourished children showed that they could be successfully&#xD;
      managed at existing day-care clinics using a protocolized approach. Therefore, after the&#xD;
      successful conduction and publication of these two study results in international journals&#xD;
      with severe and very severe pneumonia as well as severe malnutrition at the day-care clinic,&#xD;
      it is mandatory to perform the final study where the investigators will include severe&#xD;
      malnutrition as well as associated co-morbidities to be applied to the treatment of severe&#xD;
      and severe pneumonia in children in general to make the treatment approach more widely&#xD;
      applicable.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acute lower respiratory infections particulary pneumonia, are the leading cause of childhood&#xD;
      morbidity and death in the developing countries such as Bangladesh [3]. Acute respiratory&#xD;
      tract infection causes more than 2 million child deaths worldwide each year, mostly from&#xD;
      pneumonia and 90% of them occur in less-developed countries [4-6]. Recent estimates suggest&#xD;
      that 1.9 million (95% CI 1.6 million to 2.2 million) children died from acute respiratory&#xD;
      tract infection throughout the world in 2000, and 70% of them occurred in Africa and&#xD;
      Southeast Asia [7]. ARI is also a major cause of visits to the outpatient and emergency&#xD;
      departments as well as admissions to the hospitals. Although bronchiolitis, tracheobronchitis&#xD;
      and pneumonia, each accounts for about one-third of ALRI cases, pneumonia is responsible for&#xD;
      most ALRI deaths. Three studies that reported diagnoses in children who died of ALRI revealed&#xD;
      that a median of 89% (range 71% to 100%) of ALRI deaths was associated with pneumonia [8-10].&#xD;
      In Bangladesh, acute lower respiratory tract infections account for 25% of deaths in the&#xD;
      under-5 age group and 40% of all infantile deaths [11]. A study conducted at the Dhaka&#xD;
      Hospital of ICDDR,B in 1986-88 in 401 under-5 children with ALRI has documented that&#xD;
      pneumonia was most common among them and a respiratory pathogen (both bacterial and viral)&#xD;
      was identified in 30% cases. The case fatality rates were 14% in bacterial pneumonia and 3%&#xD;
      in viral pneumonia [12]. Bacterial infections play a major role in childhood pneumonia in&#xD;
      developing countries. Pooled data from lung aspiration studies, mostly from developing&#xD;
      countries, reported bacterial isolation rates of 52-62% [13, 14]. The case-fatality rate in&#xD;
      severe ALRI in children aged 1-4 years was reported to be 10-15 times higher in the&#xD;
      developing than in the developed countries [15, 16]. It is usually not possible to determine&#xD;
      the specific cause of pneumonia by either clinical or chest X-ray features. In children,&#xD;
      Streptococcus pneumoniae and Haemophilus influenzae are the two most important bacterial&#xD;
      pathogens [17, 18]. Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV) is also an important cause of ARI among&#xD;
      preschool children [12, 18]. Emerging evidence suggests that Mycoplasma pneumoniae and&#xD;
      Chlamydia pneumoniae may cause pneumonia among older children. Available data also suggests&#xD;
      that mixed viral and bacterial infections are common in children in developing countries&#xD;
      [12], which require antimicrobial therapy. The WHO recommendations for treatment of pneumonia&#xD;
      are based on data that Streptococcus pneumoniae and Haemophilus influenzae are the most&#xD;
      common causes of bacterial pneumonia in developing countries [9].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Depending on clinical presentation, pneumonia can be classified as very severe, severe or&#xD;
      non-severe, with specific treatment guidelines available for each [8, 16, 19, 20]. The WHO&#xD;
      defines very severe pneumonia as clinical symptoms and signs of pneumonia (cough or&#xD;
      difficulty breathing with one or more danger signs like cyanosis, convulsions, drowsiness,&#xD;
      stridor in calm child or inability to drink, all signifying hypoxaemia or severe respiratory&#xD;
      distress) and severe clinical malnutrition [8, 16, 19, 20]. Severe pneumonia is defined as&#xD;
      cough or difficulty breathing with lower chest wall in drawing with or without fast breathing&#xD;
      defined as the respiratory rate ³ 50 breaths per minute for children aged 2-11 months and ³&#xD;
      40 breaths per minute for children aged 12-59 months [8, 16, 19, 20]. Lower chest wall in&#xD;
      drawing is defined as inward movement of the bony structures of the lower chest wall with&#xD;
      inspiration, observed while the child is at rest [21]. Finally, non-severe pneumonia is&#xD;
      defined as cough or difficulty breathing with fast breathing as defined earlier [8, 16, 19,&#xD;
      20]. Antibiotic therapy is indicated irrespective of the severity of pneumonia. Proper&#xD;
      management of children presenting in health centres and hospitals with respiratory symptoms&#xD;
      is the cornerstone of acute respiratory infection control. To address the high mortality&#xD;
      associated with ALRI, WHO launched a programme for control of ARI with the major objective to&#xD;
      reduce the child mortality and to promote rational use of antibiotic. Current standard ARI&#xD;
      case management recommends ambulatory treatment of children with cough and normal breathing&#xD;
      without antibiotics assuming viral infection or mild bacterial infections; treatment of those&#xD;
      with rapid respiration (tachypnoea) indicating lower respiratory infection or pneumonia with&#xD;
      an antibiotic (non-severe pneumonia); and hospitalisation of those with lower chest wall in&#xD;
      drawing (indicative of severe pneumonia) and treatment with parenteral antibiotics and&#xD;
      supportive cares [22, 23]. Vaccination against measles, pertussis, Haemophilus influenzae&#xD;
      type b (Hib) and Streptococcus pneumoniae can help decrease the incidence and/or lessen the&#xD;
      severity of respiratory infections. However, newer vaccines against respiratory infections&#xD;
      such as Hib and pneumococcal conjugate vaccines are not widely available in developing&#xD;
      countries. Under-5 children with respiratory symptoms are brought to the general&#xD;
      practitioners as well as to primary health care facilities for treatment and health care&#xD;
      providers are required to differentiate between acute upper respiratory infections (AURI) and&#xD;
      acute lower respiratory infections (ALRI)/pneumonia, categorize severity of pneumonia taking&#xD;
      into consideration the nutritional status of the patients, and provide either ambulatory&#xD;
      therapy or refer patients for hospitalization, as appropriate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Management of severe and very severe pneumonia in children relies on hospital-based&#xD;
      treatment, but practical barriers often prevent children in areas with highest rates from&#xD;
      receiving hospital care. It is recommended that children with severe or very severe pneumonia&#xD;
      be hospitalised [8, 16, 19, 20] for supportive treatment, including suction, oxygen therapy&#xD;
      for hypoxemia, fluid and nutritional management, and close monitoring [8, 16, 19, 20]. In&#xD;
      Bangladesh, there are not enough hospital beds for admission of all severe and very severe&#xD;
      cases of pneumonia. In addition, hospitalization may not be possible because of the inability&#xD;
      of parents to visit the hospital. Reliable demographic information on this issue is not&#xD;
      available in most hospitals in Bangladesh due to poor record keeping system. However, we have&#xD;
      reviewed data for a 2-month period (May and June 2007) from the Institute of Child Health and&#xD;
      Shishu Sasthya Foundation Hospital (ICHSH), Mirpur, Dhaka, and observed that only 52/120&#xD;
      (43%) children with severe and very severe pneumonia were admitted into the hospital, and the&#xD;
      majority (57%) could not be admitted due to the lack of beds and most of them were sent home&#xD;
      after some supportive therapy and parenteral antibiotics from the outpatient department of&#xD;
      the hospital. It is therefore important to provide institutional care for children who cannot&#xD;
      be hospitalised. A prospective observational study was conducted to examine the feasibility&#xD;
      of day-care-facility-based, modified primary care as an alternative for children denied&#xD;
      hospital admission who would otherwise be sent home. We developed and prospectively evaluated&#xD;
      a day-care clinic approach of management by providing antibiotics, feeding and supportive&#xD;
      care during stay at the clinic, and continuation of care at home by parents as an effective&#xD;
      alternative to hospitalization for such children. We have recently published the study&#xD;
      results as &quot;Day-care management of severe and very severe pneumonia, without associated&#xD;
      co-morbidities such as severe malnutrition, in an urban health clinic in Dhaka, Bangladesh&#xD;
      [1]&quot;. From June 2003 to May 2005, 251 children with severe and very severe pneumonia were&#xD;
      enrolled at the Radda Clinic. The mean±SD age of the children was 7 ±7 months, and 143/251&#xD;
      (57%) of them were hypoxemic with mean ± SD oxygen saturation of 93 ± 4% that increased to 98&#xD;
      ± 3% on oxygen therapy. The mean ± SD day-care period was 7 ± 2 days. Day-care management of&#xD;
      severe and very severe pneumonia was assessed successful in 234/251 [93% (95% CI, 89-96%)]&#xD;
      children, and the management was assessed to have failed in the remaining 17/251 [7% (95% CI,&#xD;
      4.3-10.6%)] children of whom 11/251 [4.4% (95% CI, 2.5-7.7%)] had to be referred to hospital&#xD;
      and 6/251 [2.4% (95% CI 1.1-5.1%)] discontinued treatment. There were no deaths during the&#xD;
      day-care study period; however, 4/251 [1.6% (95% CI 0.6%-4%)] children died during the&#xD;
      3-month follow-up period, and another 11/251 [4.4% (95% CI, 2.5-7.7%)] required hospital&#xD;
      admission during the 3-months' follow-up period. The results of the study indicate that&#xD;
      children with severe and very severe pneumonia without associated co-morbidities such as&#xD;
      severe malnutrition can be successfully managed at day-care clinics [1]. If the day-care&#xD;
      management is found to have comparable efficacy to that of hospitalized management of severe&#xD;
      and very severe pneumonia in children then they could be managed at day-care set ups on an&#xD;
      outpatient basis, reducing hospitalization and thus freeing up of beds for management of&#xD;
      other children with greater need for hospital care. Additionally, availability of the&#xD;
      treatment facility in community set-ups will be both time-and cost-savings for the&#xD;
      population. But, as patients with severe malnutrition were excluded from the pilot study for&#xD;
      ethical reasons, the peer journal reviewers [1] correctly commented that the study findings&#xD;
      cannot be generalised and applied to the treatment of severe and very severe pneumonia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similarly, the case-fatality from severe malnutrition has been as high as 60% in the 1990's&#xD;
      primarily due to faulty case management [24-26]. The management of severely malnourished&#xD;
      children with associated complications relies on hospital-based treatment. In Bangladesh,&#xD;
      only a few hospitals have beds dedicated for the management of severely malnourished&#xD;
      children. Hospitalization may not also be possible as a result of the inability of the&#xD;
      parents to visit a hospital either due to distance or financial reason (s), even after&#xD;
      appropriate referral. It is, however, important to provide institutional care to such&#xD;
      children, at least until stabilization of their acute conditions. If such children are sent&#xD;
      home with antibiotics, it would be important to establish an expensive, home follow up&#xD;
      system, without which a significant proportion of them could be reasonably expected to have a&#xD;
      fatal outcome. With the implementation of a protocolised management at the Dhaka Hospital,&#xD;
      ICDDR,B, the case-fatality of such children reduced from 19% to 5% [27, 28]. In another&#xD;
      study, we evaluated a day-care clinic approach of management of severely malnourished&#xD;
      children by providing antibiotics, micronutrients, diet, and supportive care during stay at&#xD;
      an established day-care centers, followed by continuation of care by parents at home as an&#xD;
      effective alternative to hospitalization. From February 2001 to November 2003, 264 severely&#xD;
      malnourished children were enrolled at the Radda Clinic, where they received protocolized&#xD;
      management with antibiotics, micronutrients and milk-based diet from 08:00 to 17:00 daily,&#xD;
      while their mothers were educated on continuation of supportive care at home at night. They&#xD;
      were transitioned to the day-care nutrition rehabilitation unit (NRU) of the Radda Clinic&#xD;
      following resolution of acute illness, received NRU diets daily until attainment of 80%&#xD;
      weight-for-length. Fifty-two percent of the children were boys, and 78%, 21% and 1% of all&#xD;
      children had marasmus, marasmus-kwashiorkor and kwashiorkor, respectively. Only 13% had&#xD;
      severe malnutrition alone, while 35% had pneumonia, 35% had diarrhoea and 17% had both&#xD;
      pneumonia and diarrhoea. The mean ± SD duration of acute and NRU phases were 8 ± 4 and 14 ±&#xD;
      13 days respectively. The mean ± SD weight gain (g/kg) of the children was more rapid during&#xD;
      acute (10 ± 7) than the NRU phase (6 ± 5). The day-care management of severe malnutrition was&#xD;
      assessed successful in 216/264 [82% (95% CI, 77-86%)] children, and failure in the remaining&#xD;
      48/264 [18% (95% CI, 14-23%)] children of whom 17/264 [6% (95% CI, 4-10%)] had to be referred&#xD;
      to hospital and 31/264 [12% (95% CI, 8-16%)] discontinued treatment. The results clearly&#xD;
      demonstrated that severely malnourished children could be successfully managed at existing&#xD;
      day-care clinics using a protocolized approach [2].&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, after the successful conduction and publication of results of these two studies on&#xD;
      management of severe and very severe pneumonia [1] and severe malnutrition [2] at the&#xD;
      day-care clinic, it is prudent to perform the final study in which we will assess if&#xD;
      treatment of children with severe and very severe pneumonia in association with severe&#xD;
      malnutrition will be possible on a day-care basis. If successful, this treatment approach&#xD;
      could be more widely applicable. In the proposed study, we would identify under-5 children&#xD;
      with severe and very severe pneumonia with severe malnutrition with/without associated&#xD;
      co-morbidities attending the outpatient department of the Radda Clinic and the outpatient and&#xD;
      emergency departments of ICHSH and randomize them, in equal numbers, for management either at&#xD;
      the day-care centre (Radda Clinic) or hospital (ICHSH), subject to the consent of respective&#xD;
      parents/guardians. About 3000 children with pneumonia visit the Radda Clinic each year, and&#xD;
      we estimate that about 200 of them will have severe and very severe pneumonia with severe&#xD;
      malnutrition requiring hospitalization. Similarly, about 700 children with severe and very&#xD;
      severe pneumonia with severe malnutrition visit the outpatient and emergency departments of&#xD;
      the ICHSH each year. Our study patients will be selected from these children population of&#xD;
      the Radda Clinic and ICHSH, and we hope to complete enrolment of the requisite 440 (220/site)&#xD;
      children during 3-year period of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale&#xD;
&#xD;
      Malnutrition and severe malnutrition are prevalent and ALRI/pneumonia is the leading cause of&#xD;
      under-5 morbidity and deaths in Bangladesh. Hospital management is recommended for children&#xD;
      with either or both of these problems. However, there simply is not enough beds to&#xD;
      hospitalise every child with these problems. It is often not possible to provide appropriate&#xD;
      treatment and supportive care at home to children refused admission to a hospital. With a few&#xD;
      exceptions, childhood malnutrition is a problem of the poor, and thus parents of children&#xD;
      with severe malnutrition and/or pneumonia are often unable to provide private care to their&#xD;
      children, and some times unable to take their children to a hospital far off from their&#xD;
      community. What happens to such children remains largely unknown; however, many can be&#xD;
      expected to have a fatal outcome. Successful management of such children at a day-care clinic&#xD;
      in their community would provide better access to their treatment and care and affordable to&#xD;
      the parents. Proved effective, this management could also be implemented in Bangladesh and&#xD;
      potentially to other developing countries. The day-care based management is expected to be&#xD;
      cost effective intervention and contribute significantly to reduction of under-5 child&#xD;
      mortality due to severe and very severe pneumonia as well as severe malnutrition.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>November 2008</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of success with 95% confidence interval (CI)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Case fatality rate with 95% CI -day-care clinic/hospital</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of failure rate with 95% CI</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of illness (d)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of referral &amp; discontinuation with 95% CI</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of success (d)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of complications</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost of treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">440</enrollment>
  <condition>Malnutrition</condition>
  <condition>Pneumonia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Day-care clinic</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Inj. Ceftriaxone and other micronutrients will be given to children at the day-care clinic from 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. daily.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hospital management</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Hospital management: all children admitted at the hospital will be managed with injection Ceftriaxone and other micronutrients for the total duration of hospitalization as per approved protocol.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Day-care clinic</intervention_name>
    <description>Inj. Ceftriaxone and other micronutrients will be given to children at the day-care clinic from 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. daily.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Day-care clinic</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hospital Management</intervention_name>
    <description>Inj. Ceftriaxone and other micronutrients will be given to children at the hospital from admission till discharge.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hospital management</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 2 to 59 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sex: Both boys and girls&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe and very severe pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe malnutrition (defined as &lt; - 3 weight-for-height Z-score)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Attending Radda Clinic or ICHSH between 8:00 to 16:00&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent by respective parents/guardians&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-severe pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nosocomial pneumonia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bronchiolitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bronchial asthma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Living long distance (&gt;5 km) from the Radda Clinic and ICHSH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Visits during late hours of the day (after 16:00)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents/guardians not consenting for enrolment of children in the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>59 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research Bangladesh</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dhaka</city>
        <zip>1212</zip>
        <country>Bangladesh</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Bangladesh</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 28, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 28, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 31, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 14, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 14, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">July 16, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Severe and very severe pneumonia</keyword>
  <keyword>severe malnutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>children</keyword>
  <keyword>day-care management</keyword>
  <keyword>hospital management</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Malnutrition</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

