<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00965939</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>S51257</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>B32220095818</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00965939</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Observational Study to Assess Response to Tamoxifen in Breast Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>CYPTAMBRUT-2</acronym>
  <official_title>Study to Assess Response to Tamoxifen in (cT3)/ Inoperable Locally Advanced / Metastatic ER-positive Breast Cancer by the 'Tamoxifen Activity Score' Based on Drug Interaction and Polymorphisms in Genes Coding for Tam. Metabolising Enzymes.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Vlaamse Vereniging voor Obstetrie en Gynaecologie</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Vlaamse Vereniging voor Obstetrie en Gynaecologie</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      CYPTAM-BRUT 2 is a prospective, multicentric study including postmenopausal women receiving&#xD;
      tamoxifen for metastatic, locally advanced (stage IIIB/C) or in the neoadjuvant setting for&#xD;
      measurable estrogen-receptor positive breast cancers. The primary endpoint is the difference&#xD;
      in efficacy of tamoxifen, defined as the objective response rate using RECIST criteria,&#xD;
      between women with a normal versus low Tamoxifen Activity Score (TAS) after 3-6 months of&#xD;
      tamoxifen use. The TAS score is based on the presence of genetic variations and drug&#xD;
      interactions. Secondary endpoints are time to progression, clinical benefit, serum metabolite&#xD;
      concentrations, endometrial changes and menopausal symptoms. Patients using tamoxifen in the&#xD;
      neoadjuvant setting needs being operated between 4-6 months following the start of tamoxifen.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This multi-centre open label single arm non randomized observational study will compare the&#xD;
      efficacy in terms of overall response rate and progression free survival of tamoxifen as&#xD;
      first line therapy in 3 groups of postmenopausal women with measurable hormone dependent&#xD;
      large, locally advanced or metastatic breast cancer. The 3 groups are women with a normal and&#xD;
      those with a low 'tamoxifen activity score' based on genetic polymorphisms for CYP2D6 and&#xD;
      other genes that are important in the metabolism of tamoxifen using SEQUENOM's MassARRAY&#xD;
      technology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is subject to Ethical Commission approval and patient consent. The study will&#xD;
      necessitate collection of blood for genetic analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will investigate the relation between the studied genotype, the use of drugs that&#xD;
      interfere with tamoxifen and tamoxifen-related endpoints like regression of metastatic or&#xD;
      locally advanced or large oestrogen receptor positive breast cancer in tamoxifen users. The&#xD;
      'tamoxifen activity score' has been used by a group in the US showing a link with tamoxifen&#xD;
      compliance. The score will be adapted to the Belgian situation based on the prevalence of&#xD;
      polymorphism in a Belgian population. The efficacy of tamoxifen will be correlated with a&#xD;
      predefined 'tamoxifen activity score' which is based on the presence of single nucleotide&#xD;
      polymorphisms (SNP) in relevant genes combined with the effect of well known drugs that&#xD;
      interfere with the metabolism of tamoxifen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted in several clinical sites in Belgium. All patients will receive&#xD;
      tamoxifen 20mg daily. Patients with a large operable or inoperable non-metastatic breast&#xD;
      cancer will be considered for surgery no more than 4 months on tamoxifen. If operable, they&#xD;
      will postoperatively receive the most appropriate adjuvant therapy and for hormone therapy&#xD;
      either continue tamoxifen or receive an oral aromatase inhibitor as decided by the clinician.&#xD;
      If women with a locally advanced inoperable breast cancer are not operable after the 4 months&#xD;
      of neo-adjuvant therapy, another appropriate salvage therapy will be proposed. Women with&#xD;
      metastatic breast cancer will continue treatment until clinical or imaging progression or&#xD;
      unacceptable toxicity development. Patients that experience progression of their disease as&#xD;
      defined by RECIST criteria will receive salvage therapy by an oral aromatase inhibitor if&#xD;
      tamoxifen is given in first line but some patients may require another therapy like&#xD;
      chemotherapy. The study will require approximately 14 months to recruit and another 7 months&#xD;
      to events/data analyses as the estimated time to progression in this setting is 9-12 months&#xD;
      if tamoxifen is given as first line endocrine therapy for those in the metastatic setting&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>February 2009</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ORR</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months/ 6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TTP</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months/ 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical benefit (CR + PR + SD ≥ 6 months)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months/6months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Endometrial thickness and uterine volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline/ 3 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability of tamoxifen-HRQoL questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline/ 3months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">300</enrollment>
  <condition>ER-positive Breast Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Female, with ER-positive breast cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  - Female &gt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written and voluntary informed consent understood signed and dated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically confirmed measurable invasive adenocarcinoma of the&#xD;
             breast either large (cT3), locally advanced stage IIIB/C inoperable, or metastatic and&#xD;
             not amenable to curative therapy with surgery or radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Measurable disease is defined as follows: CT scan for metastatic or locally advanced&#xD;
             stage IIIB disease and ultrasound of the breast for operable large size breast cancers&#xD;
             where tamoxifen is given for neoadjuvant endocrine therapy .&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be postmenopausal as defined by criteria in appendix 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Breast cancer should be considered as oestrogen receptor positive by the clinician&#xD;
             using immunohistochemistry readings as is standard procedure for local pathologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior endocrine tamoxifen therapy in the adjuvant setting is allowed if there is more&#xD;
             than 12 months after completion of adjuvant tamoxifen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior radiotherapy is allowed but evaluable lesions that have been irradiated need to&#xD;
             be progressive before starting in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent use of bisphosphonates is allowed if they are started 2 weeks before study&#xD;
             start and these drugs should be continued as planned throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate renal and liver function Serum creatinine and serum bilirubin ≤ 1.5 X ULN&#xD;
             Serum ALT and AST ≤ 2.5 X ULN (or ≤ 5 in case of liver metastases)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum calcium should be ≤ 11,6 mg/dl&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status 0,1,2 (appendix 2)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  - Male&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life threatening disease requiring a quick response (eg, extensive hepatic or&#xD;
             pulmonary involvement)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CNS involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 12 months since stopping tamoxifen in the adjuvant setting&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous chemotherapy, tamoxifen or more than one line hormone therapy or targeted&#xD;
             therapy for locally advanced/ metastatic breast cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bone lesions only&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One line of prior endocrine therapy with an oral aromatase inhibitor for locally&#xD;
             advanced or metastatic breast cancer is not allowed also not if there is clear&#xD;
             progression according to RECIST and the clinician judges tamoxifen an appropriate&#xD;
             second line therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contra indication for tamoxifen: history of DVT/vaginal bleeding of unknown origin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of other malignancy that may interfere with at least 6 months of tamoxifen&#xD;
             therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Patrick Neven</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UZ Leuven</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Imelda ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bonheiden</city>
        <state>Antwerpen</state>
        <zip>2820</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AZ St-Maarten Campus Rooienberg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Duffel</city>
        <state>Antwerpen</state>
        <zip>2570</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Heilig-Hartziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lier</city>
        <state>Antwerpen</state>
        <zip>2500</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ziekenhuizen Oost-Limburg campus St-jan</name>
      <address>
        <city>Genk</city>
        <state>Limburg</state>
        <zip>3600</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Virga Jesse Ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hasselt</city>
        <state>Limburg</state>
        <zip>3500</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AZ St-Blasius</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dendermonde</city>
        <state>Oost-Vlaanderen</state>
        <zip>9200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maria-Middelares</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gent</city>
        <state>Oost-Vlaanderen</state>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gent</city>
        <state>Oost-Vlaanderen</state>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AZ St-Nikolaas</name>
      <address>
        <city>St-Niklaas</city>
        <state>Oost-Vlaanderen</state>
        <zip>9100</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <state>Vlaams-Brabant</state>
        <zip>3000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Heilig-Hartziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roeselare</city>
        <state>West-Vlaanderen</state>
        <zip>8800</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UCL</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <zip>1200</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2015</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2009</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 24, 2009</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 26, 2009</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">October 28, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

