<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00544596</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NCI-2009-00273</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2009-00273</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CO07901</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2007-0145</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CDR0000570006</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>CO 07901</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>8062</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>P30CA014520</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>U01CA062491</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00544596</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>R-(-)-Gossypol Acetic Acid, Cisplatin, and Etoposide in Treating Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors or Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1 Study of R-(-)-Gossypol (AT-101) in Combination With Cisplatin and Etoposide in Patients With Advanced Solid Tumors and Extensive-Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I trial is studying the side effects and best dose of R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid&#xD;
      when given together with cisplatin and etoposide in treating patients with advanced solid&#xD;
      tumors or extensive stage small cell lung cancer. R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid may stop the&#xD;
      growth of cancer by blocking blood flow to the tumor. Drugs used in chemotherapy, such as&#xD;
      cisplatin and etoposide, work in different ways to stop the growth of tumor cells, either by&#xD;
      killing the cells or by stopping them from dividing. Giving R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid&#xD;
      together with combination chemotherapy may help kill more tumor cells.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the maximum tolerated dose (MTD) or recommended phase II dose (RP2D) of&#xD;
      AT-101 (R-(-)-gossypol) when combined with cisplatin and etoposide in patients with advanced,&#xD;
      refractory solid tumors and/or extensive stage small cell lung cancer (ES-SCLC). In addition,&#xD;
      to determine the MTD or RP2D of AT-101 when combined with cisplatin, etoposide, and Neulasta.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To evaluate the toxicity and tolerability of AT-101 in combination with cisplatin and&#xD;
      etoposide in patients with advanced, refractory solid tumors and/or ES-SCLC. In addition,&#xD;
      evaluate the toxicity and tolerability of AT-101 with cisplatin, etoposide, and Neulasta.&#xD;
&#xD;
      III. To evaluate the antitumor activity of this combination per tumor measurements using the&#xD;
      Response Evaluation Criteria In Solid Tumors (RECIST) criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To evaluate the pharmacokinetics of AT-101 as a single agent and in combination with&#xD;
      cisplatin and etoposide in plasma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      II. To perform pharmacodynamic studies (genotyping of drug metabolizing enzymes, gene&#xD;
      expression, and proteomics of drug-related pathways) on archived blood samples from patients&#xD;
      treated with AT-101 in combination with cisplatin and etoposide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a dose-escalation study of R-(-)-gossypol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive oral R-(-)-gossypol twice daily on days 1-3, cisplatin intravenously (IV)&#xD;
      over 60 minutes on day 1*, and etoposide IV over 30 minutes on days 1*-3. Treatment repeats&#xD;
      every 21 days for up to 6 courses during the dose escalation and 4 courses in the expanded&#xD;
      extensive stage small cell lung cancer cohort, in the absence of disease progression or&#xD;
      unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood samples are collected on day 1 of courses 1 and 2 for pharmacokinetic analysis,&#xD;
      biomarker assays, and correlative studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed for 30 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      [Note: *Cisplatin and etoposide will be started on day 2 during course 1; they will be given&#xD;
      on day 1 during all subsequent courses.]&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2007</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity and tolerability of R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid in combination with cisplatin and etoposide in terms of types and severities by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) version 3.0</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed up to 30 days after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The 95% confidence interval will be obtained.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Response as assessed by RECIST criteria</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed up to 30 days after completion of study treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Responses will be summarized by simple descriptive summary statistics delineating complete and partial responses as well as stable and progressive disease. A 95% confidence interval of the overall response rate will be constructed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid in combination with cisplatin and etoposide</measure>
    <time_frame>Days 1 and 2 of courses 1 and 2</time_frame>
    <description>Summarized by dose level with simple summary statistics: means, medians, ranges, and standard deviations.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Extensive Stage Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Unspecified Adult Solid Tumor, Protocol Specific</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid, cisplatin, etoposide)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive oral R-(-)-gossypol twice daily on days 1-3, cisplatin IV over 60 minutes on day 1*, and etoposide IV over 30 minutes on days 1*-3. Treatment repeats every 21 days for up to 6 courses during the dose escalation and 4 courses in the expanded extensive stage small cell lung cancer cohort, in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
Blood samples are collected on day 1 of courses 1 and 2 for pharmacokinetic analysis, biomarker assays, and correlative studies.&#xD;
After completion of study treatment, patients are followed for 30 days.&#xD;
[Note: *Cisplatin and etoposide will be started on day 2 during course 1; they will be given on day 1 during all subsequent courses.]</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid</intervention_name>
    <description>Given orally</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid, cisplatin, etoposide)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AT-101</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>cisplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid, cisplatin, etoposide)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CACP</other_name>
    <other_name>CDDP</other_name>
    <other_name>CPDD</other_name>
    <other_name>DDP</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>etoposide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (R-(-)-gossypol acetic acid, cisplatin, etoposide)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>EPEG</other_name>
    <other_name>VP-16</other_name>
    <other_name>VP-16-213</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the dose-escalation cohorts: patients must have histologically confirmed malignancy&#xD;
             that is metastatic or unresectable and for which standard curative or palliative&#xD;
             measures do not exist or are no longer effective; in the MTD expansion cohort:&#xD;
             patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed extensive-stage small&#xD;
             cell lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have received prior therapy that inhibits the B-cell lymphoma 2&#xD;
             (Bcl-2) family&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with small cell lung cancer may have received prior prophylactic cranial&#xD;
             irradiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior whole brain radiotherapy allowed for patients with brain metastases provided&#xD;
             they have stable/improved lesions for at least 1 month following treatment, no&#xD;
             neurological symptoms and not require corticosteroids; an magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
             (MRI) of the brain or computed tomography (CT) scan of the head must be performed at&#xD;
             baseline if patient has a history of brain metastases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status =&lt; 2 (Karnofsky &gt;= 60%)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of greater than 12 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Leukocytes &gt;= 3,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &gt;= 1,500/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelets &gt;= 100,000/mcL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) (serum glutamic oxaloacetic transaminase&#xD;
             [SGOT])/alanine aminotransferase (ALT) (serum glutamic pyruvate transaminase [SGPT])&#xD;
             =&lt; 2.5 x institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serum creatinine &lt; 1.5 x institutional upper limit of normal OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Creatinine clearance &gt;= 45 mL/min/1.73 m^2, as calculated by Cockroft-Gault formula,&#xD;
             for patients with creatinine levels above institutional normal; a 24 hour urine&#xD;
             collection and creatinine clearance can be measured if indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The effects of AT-101 on the developing human fetus are unknown; for this reason and&#xD;
             because other therapeutic agents used in this trial are known to be teratogenic, women&#xD;
             of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception (hormonal&#xD;
             or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry, for the duration&#xD;
             of study participation, and for at least one month following the last dose of AT-101;&#xD;
             should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while participating in this&#xD;
             study, she should inform her treating physician immediately&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should display the ability to understand and the willingness to sign a&#xD;
             written informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients of child bearing potential must not be pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have measurable or evaluable disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients without small cell lung cancer who have had chemotherapy, radiotherapy or&#xD;
             hormonal therapy within 4 weeks (6 weeks for nitrosoureas or mitomycin C) prior to&#xD;
             entering the study or those who have not recovered (=&lt; grade 1) from clinically&#xD;
             significant adverse events due to agents administered more than 4 weeks earlier; prior&#xD;
             treatment with a platinum-based chemotherapy regimen in combination with thoracic&#xD;
             radiation therapy is allowed for patients with ES-SCLC provided that recurrence of the&#xD;
             SCLC occurred more than 6 months from definitive therapy for limited-stage small cell&#xD;
             lung cancer; no other prior chemotherapy is allowed for the patients with ES-SCLC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to recover fully (as judged by the investigator) from prior surgical&#xD;
             procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent treatment with an investigational agent other than the investigational&#xD;
             agent(s) used in this study OR treatment within 4 weeks of study entry with any&#xD;
             investigational agent(s) or device(s)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any prior use of racemic gossypol or AT-101&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of allergic reactions attributed to compounds of similar chemical or biologic&#xD;
             composition to AT-101 or other agents used in study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requirement for routine use of hematopoietic growth factors (including granulocyte&#xD;
             colony stimulating factor, granulocyte macrophage colony stimulating factor, or&#xD;
             interleukin-11) or platelet transfusions to maintain absolute neutrophil counts or&#xD;
             platelets counts above the required thresholds for study entry; if patient requires&#xD;
             routine use of erythropoietin, eligibility at investigator discretion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition (e.g., gastrointestinal tract disease resulting in an inability to take&#xD;
             oral medication or a requirement for IV alimentation, prior surgical procedures&#xD;
             affecting absorption, or active peptic ulcer disease) that impairs their ability to&#xD;
             swallow and retain AT-101 tablets&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with malabsorption syndrome, disease significantly affecting gastrointestinal&#xD;
             function, or resection of the stomach or small bowel are excluded; subjects with&#xD;
             ulcerative colitis, inflammatory bowel disease, or a partial or complete small bowel&#xD;
             obstruction are also excluded&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncontrolled intercurrent illness including, but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, unstable angina pectoris, cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmia, or psychiatric illness/social situations that would limit compliance with&#xD;
             study requirements&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women are excluded from this study because the effects of AT-101 on the&#xD;
             developing human fetus are unknown, but could potentially include teratogenic or&#xD;
             abortifacient effects; because there is an unknown but potential risk for adverse&#xD;
             events in nursing infants secondary to treatment of the mother with AT-101,&#xD;
             breastfeeding should be discontinued if the mother is treated with AT-101; these&#xD;
             potential risks may also apply to other agents used in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)-positive patients on combination antiretroviral&#xD;
             therapy are ineligible because of the potential for pharmacokinetic interactions with&#xD;
             AT-101 or other agents used in this study; in addition, these patients are at&#xD;
             increased risk of lethal infections when treated with marrow-suppressive therapy;&#xD;
             appropriate studies will be undertaken in patients receiving combination&#xD;
             antiretroviral therapy when indicated&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with &gt; grade 2 symptomatic hypercalcemia (based on investigator discretion)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anne Traynor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Wisconsin, Madison</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sanford Cancer Center-Oncology Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sioux Falls</city>
        <state>South Dakota</state>
        <zip>57104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gundersen Lutheran</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Crosse</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>54601</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UW Health Oncology - 1 South Park</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53715</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Wisconsin Hospital and Clinics</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madison</city>
        <state>Wisconsin</state>
        <zip>53792</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 13, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 13, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">October 16, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2014</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2014</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">April 2, 2014</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Small Cell Lung Carcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acetic Acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Retinol acetate</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gossypol acetic acid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Gossypol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

