<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00487331</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2006-1113</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00487331</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Acupuncture for Treatment of Uncontrolled Pain: A Feasibility Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Acupuncture for Treatment of Uncontrolled Pain: A Feasibility Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical research study is to learn if using acupuncture with or without&#xD;
      electrical stimulation in cancer patients with high levels of pain can help to relieve the&#xD;
      pain.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Acupuncture involves the insertion of small, solid, sterile needles into specific points on&#xD;
      the skin. The needles are placed in areas that are intended to help relieve pain. Electrical&#xD;
      stimulation is often applied to the needles to improve the treatment effects. The procedure&#xD;
      is designed to be comfortable and relaxing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Acupuncture Sessions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are found to be eligible to take part in this study, you will receive acupuncture&#xD;
      sessions 1-3 times per week in the acupuncture clinic at M. D. Anderson. The number of&#xD;
      sessions will depend on the type and location of the pain you may be experiencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For each session, you will be placed in a comfortable position and the study&#xD;
      doctor/acupuncturist will find points on your body and/or ears where the needles will be&#xD;
      placed. These points will be chosen based on the symptoms you are having at the time of&#xD;
      treatment, the location of the pain, and the type of pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Very thin, solid, sterile, stainless steel needles will be used. All of the needles are&#xD;
      specially made for acupuncture. The depth of the needle in the skin, the number of needles,&#xD;
      and whether the needles are near or far from the areas of pain will vary from person to&#xD;
      person, based on standard acupuncture procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In most instances, needles placed on body points will remain in place for about 20-30&#xD;
      minutes. This length of time is the same for some points on the ears as well, but in some&#xD;
      instances, small gold or stainless steel needles may be placed on the ears. These needles for&#xD;
      the ears are designed to remain in place for 3-4 days. The ear needles are slightly larger&#xD;
      than the head of a pin and have a small ridge that is designed to help them remain in place.&#xD;
      If you prefer, a small flesh colored adhesive patch can be placed over the ear needles as&#xD;
      added protection. This is usually not necessary, but can be added if you prefer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Electrical stimulation may be added to some of the needles, depending on the type of pain you&#xD;
      are experiencing and where it is located. This involves placing wires on the needles, which&#xD;
      are connected to a machine that delivers a mild electrical current through the wires. The&#xD;
      intensity (strength) of the electrical current will be adjusted gradually until it is at a&#xD;
      comfortable level for you.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      At each session, before you receive the acupuncture, the following procedures will be&#xD;
      performed:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Your vital signs will be measured.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will be asked about any medications you may be taking and any side effects you may&#xD;
           be experiencing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The color and coating of your tongue and the quality of your pulse will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If you are receiving medications that are known to affect your blood counts, blood&#xD;
           (about 1 teaspoon) will be drawn for routine tests to check your blood counts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each study visit will last about 1 hour. During the study, you may still receive your regular&#xD;
      pain treatments outside of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Length of Study Participation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      You may receive up to 10 acupuncture sessions (depending on the location and type of pain).&#xD;
      If intolerable side effects or symptoms occur, you will be taken off study early.&#xD;
&#xD;
      End-of-Study Visit:&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the day of your last acupuncture session (called the end-of-study visit), or if you go off&#xD;
      study early for any reason, the following procedures will be performed:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Your medical history will be recorded. Your vital signs will be measured. You will be asked&#xD;
      about any medications you may be taking and any side effects you may have experienced.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will complete the same 2 pain questionnaires as before. You will also complete a&#xD;
      questionnaire that has questions about your level of satisfaction with the acupuncture&#xD;
      services that were provided. In total, the 3 questionnaires should take about 15 minutes to&#xD;
      complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Your tongue and pulse will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Completion:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the end-of-study visit, your participation in this study will be over.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an investigational study. The needles used in this study are FDA approved for use in&#xD;
      patients with cancer. It is considered experimental, however, to provide acupuncture services&#xD;
      to patients with cancer who have uncontrolled pain. Up to 64 patients will take part in this&#xD;
      study. All will be enrolled at M. D. Anderson.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2013</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2013</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patients' Reported Satisfaction with Acupuncture Services</measure>
    <time_frame>Derived from surveys completed by participating patients over 3 Years</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">52</enrollment>
  <condition>Solid Tumors</condition>
  <condition>Pain</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Acupuncture sessions 1-3 times per week. 2 pain questionnaires + satisfaction survey completed at beginning and end of treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Acupuncture</intervention_name>
    <description>Acupuncture sessions 1-3 times per week.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Survey</intervention_name>
    <description>2 pain questionnaires + satisfaction survey completed at beginning and end of treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>questionnaire</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients, or the legal guardians of patients must have the ability to understand&#xD;
             English, sign a written informed consent, and be willing to follow protocol&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ECOG Performance Status of 0, 1, or 2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pain score &gt;/= 4 on the on a 0-10 NRS pain scale after all efforts have been attempted&#xD;
             in the PMC to control pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Local infection at or near the acupuncture site. (Although acupuncture is a minimally&#xD;
             invasive procedure, patients will be excluded if there is an indication of infection.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Deformities that could interfere with accurate acupuncture point location.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known coagulopathy and taking any dose of warfarin (i.e., Coumadin) or heparin,&#xD;
             including low molecular weight heparin (i.e., Lovenox). Patients may participate if&#xD;
             they are taking Plavix, aspirin or other non-steroidal anti-inflammatory agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Mental incapacitation or significant emotional or psychological disorder that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigators, precludes study entry as these patients may not be able&#xD;
             to cooperative with this slightly invasive procedure or with the data collection&#xD;
             process.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Labs: platelets &lt;100,000 and/or WBC &lt; 3000 on most recent report. (Note: Whether or&#xD;
             not lab work is drawn prior to beginning the acupuncture treatment will be left to the&#xD;
             discretion of the referring physician. Patients with platelets &lt;100,000 may&#xD;
             participate with written approval from the attending physician.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Planned changes in the pain medication regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Women who are pregnant.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Larry C. Driver, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 15, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 15, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 18, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 7, 2015</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 7, 2015</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 9, 2015</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Solid Tumors</keyword>
  <keyword>Acupuncture</keyword>
  <keyword>Uncontrolled Pain</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

