<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00487760</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>999907161</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>07-HG-N161</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00487760</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>African American Families and Lung Cancer Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>African American Families and Lung Cancer Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Human Genome Research Institute (NHGRI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will learn more about the beliefs of family members of African American patients&#xD;
      with lung cancer and whether these beliefs are associated with their interest in genetic&#xD;
      testing for disease risk and willingness to participate in genetics research. Lung cancer is&#xD;
      the second most common form of cancer and the leading cause of cancer deaths for men and&#xD;
      women in the United States. Like most cancers, there are racial and ethnic disparities (gaps)&#xD;
      in lung cancer cases and deaths. The age-adjusted rates for blacks and whites (years 2000 to&#xD;
      2003) was 76.9 per 100,000 and 66.0 per 100,000, respectively. Mortality rates were 62.5 per&#xD;
      100,000 for blacks and 55.3 per 100,000 for whites. Cigarette smoking is the most preventable&#xD;
      cause of lung cancer. Findings are that African Americans begin smoking at older ages and&#xD;
      smoke fewer cigarettes per day than Caucasian Americans do. Yet the severity of lung cancer&#xD;
      is greater for African Americans. Behavioral, social, environmental, and genetic factors may&#xD;
      explain the differences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants (subjects) ages 18 to 55 who are family of patients with lung cancer who&#xD;
      self-identify as African Americans may be eligible for this study. Washington, D.C.,&#xD;
      researchers plan to recruit 115 lung cancer patients and 200 family members-100 current&#xD;
      smokers and 100 who never smoked. Lung cancer patients, who must have been born in the United&#xD;
      States, will be recruited from those who are receiving care at the Washington Cancer&#xD;
      Institute at the Washington Hospital Center. They will be asked to list relatives and friends&#xD;
      they consider to be as close as family. Patients will be asked permission for researchers to&#xD;
      contact those people. Family members will receive a letter telling them that unless they&#xD;
      decline to participate, they will be contacted by a telephone interviewer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The survey will feature questions to evaluate family members' explanations for the causes of&#xD;
      lung cancer, as well as their reactions to possible reasons for the disparity in lung cancer&#xD;
      between African Americans and Caucasian Americans. Subjects will be asked about perceived&#xD;
      personal risk, worry about developing lung cancer, smoking history, motivation to quit&#xD;
      smoking, feelings about the lung cancer patient's diagnosis, racial identify, experience with&#xD;
      racial discrimination, pros and cons of genetic testing, and interest in genetic testing. The&#xD;
      survey will take up to 20 minutes to complete.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study may or may not have a direct benefit for those who participate. However, lung&#xD;
      cancer patients and their families will be offered a free self-help guide to stop smoking.&#xD;
      They will be referred to local smoking cessation programs. Knowledge gained from the study&#xD;
      may be used to design smoking cessation methods and research studies related to genetics for&#xD;
      minority populations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of the African American (AA) Families and Lung Cancer Study is to learn more&#xD;
      about (1) the beliefs of family members of AA patients with lung cancer about why AA get lung&#xD;
      cancer and (2) whether these beliefs are associated with their interest in genetic testing&#xD;
      for lung cancer risk and willingness to participate in clinical genetics research. We plan to&#xD;
      recruit 200 AAs (n = 100 current smokers and n = 100 never smokers) who are considered to be&#xD;
      as close as family (both biological and non-biological kin) to patients with lung cancer who&#xD;
      self-identify as AA (n = 115). Patients will be recruited from Washington Cancer Institute at&#xD;
      the Washington Hospital Center in Washington, DC. Family members who self-identify as AA and&#xD;
      are between the ages 18 and 55 will be eligible for the study. A Washington Hospital Center&#xD;
      recruiter will approach patients and ask their willingness to be contacted for a telephone&#xD;
      survey about their general well-being. As part of the survey, patients will be asked to&#xD;
      enumerate family and friends who they consider to be as close as family, and asked to&#xD;
      specifically focus on those who are current cigarette smokers and those who have never&#xD;
      smoked. Patients will be asked to give permission to contact some or all of those enumerated.&#xD;
      These family members will be mailed a letter to inform them that unless they call to decline&#xD;
      they will be contacted by a telephone interviewer. The survey will include questions to&#xD;
      assess family members' explanations for the causes of lung cancer and reactions to possible&#xD;
      explanations for disparities in lung cancer between AA and Caucasian Americans (CA),&#xD;
      perceived personal risk and worry about developing lung cancer, smoking history, motivation&#xD;
      to quit smoking, emotional responses to the patient's diagnosis, racial identity, experience&#xD;
      with racial discrimination, pros and cons of genetic testing, and interest in genetic testing&#xD;
      (the primary outcome variable). Data analysis using hierarchical linear modeling will assess&#xD;
      whether patient characteristics and family members' endorsement of genetics as the cause of&#xD;
      lung cancer are associated with their interest in genetic testing and participation in&#xD;
      clinical genetics research.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 11, 2007</start_date>
  <completion_date>August 2, 2011</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be included in this study, patients with lung cancer must meet inclusion&#xD;
        criteria at 2 steps: (1) initial screening and written consent to be contacted by&#xD;
        telephone, and (2) provision of verbal consent at the time of telephone contact to complete&#xD;
        the survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Step 1a: In order to be approached about the study, patients must be (1) at least 18 years&#xD;
        of age, (2) diagnosed with lung cancer at any stage (Stages Ia-IV), (3) approved for&#xD;
        contact by their oncologist, and (4) identified by the recruiter or identified in medical&#xD;
        records as Black.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Step 1b: In order to provide consent for contact for the telephone survey, patients must&#xD;
        self-identify as AA/Black and must have been born in the U.S. Also, patients must be&#xD;
        willing to give permission to contact at least one family member or friend considered as&#xD;
        close as family who is a current cigarette smoker between the ages of 18 and 55 in order to&#xD;
        provide consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Step 2: At the point of the patient survey, all patients will be asked their&#xD;
        race/ethnicity. All patients who self-identify as AA/Black as defined by this research will&#xD;
        be administered the patient survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Family:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Family members must self-identify as AA and be between the ages of 18 and 55 to be eligible&#xD;
        for the study. Family also must meet the following inclusion criteria to be classified as&#xD;
        either a current smoker (defined below) or a never smoker (defined below). These criteria&#xD;
        for current smoker and never smoker are based on standard criteria used in smoking&#xD;
        research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Current Smoker: to be included as a smoker , the family member must report having smoked at&#xD;
        least 100 cigarettes in their lifetime, and smoked 7 or more cigarettes in the past 7 days&#xD;
        at the time of the family member survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Never Smokers: to be included as a never smoker , a family member must report no to having&#xD;
        smoked at least 100 cigarettes in their lifetime.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Former smokers (i.e., family who have smoked at least 100 cigarettes in their lifetime but&#xD;
        smoked fewer than 7 cigarettes in the past 7 days) because previous research shows&#xD;
        consistently that these individuals hold attitudes and beliefs more similar to those of&#xD;
        current smokers than never smokers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients who describe themselves as AA or Black but were not born in the U.S. will be&#xD;
        excluded from participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Washington Hospital Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington, D.C.</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20010</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arthur CM, Katkin ES. Making a case for the examination of ethnicity of Blacks in United States Health Research. J Health Care Poor Underserved. 2006 Feb;17(1):25-36.</citation>
    <PMID>16520504</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baty BJ, Kinney AY, Ellis SM. Developing culturally sensitive cancer genetics communication aids for African Americans. Am J Med Genet A. 2003 Apr 15;118A(2):146-55.</citation>
    <PMID>12655495</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clark R, Anderson NB, Clark VR, Williams DR. Racism as a stressor for African Americans. A biopsychosocial model. Am Psychol. 1999 Oct;54(10):805-16.</citation>
    <PMID>10540593</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2, 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 16, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 16, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">June 19, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>African-American Families</keyword>
  <keyword>Genetic Risk Communication</keyword>
  <keyword>Interest in Genetic Testing and Genetics Research</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Disparities</keyword>
  <keyword>Smoking Cessation</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

