<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04993469</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>B6702021000410</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04993469</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patient Reported Outcome on Genital Sensitivity and Sexual Function After Genital Gender Affirming Surgery</brief_title>
  <acronym>PROGAS</acronym>
  <official_title>Patient Reported Outcome on Genital Sensitivity and Sexual Function After Genital Gender Affirming Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University Hospital, Ghent</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Hospital, Ghent</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      For genital gender affirming surgery, it remains unclear to what extent genital sensitivity&#xD;
      might be expected and what the impact of this might be on sexual functioning.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Gender dysphoria refers to an inner mental unrest resulting from an incongruity between the&#xD;
      assigned biological sex and the mentally experienced sex. The generally accepted treatment&#xD;
      for gender dysphoria aims to bring a person's physical characteristics in line with his or&#xD;
      her perceived gender identity. This gender-affirming treatment consists of a combination of&#xD;
      psychological counselling, hormonal therapy and, if desired, genital gender-affirming&#xD;
      surgery. This involves the removal of the biological reproductive organs and in some cases&#xD;
      (part of) the biological sex organs. These can be replaced by surrogate sex organs of the&#xD;
      desired sex while maintaining urological and sexual function. In transgender women, this is&#xD;
      achieved with vulvoplasty or vaginoplasty, while in transgender men, metoidioplasty or&#xD;
      phalloplasty is performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While urological functioning is an extensively studied topic in transgender patients after&#xD;
      genital gender confirmation surgery, sexual functioning is often considered of secondary&#xD;
      importance, even though it is one of the goals of gender confirmation surgery. In the&#xD;
      transgender man, a phalloplasty is performed using microsurgical techniques that allow the&#xD;
      nerves of the donor flap (usually from the forearm or upper leg) to be connected to the&#xD;
      genital and inguinal nerves. In metoidioplasty, the clitoris is preserved and forms the base&#xD;
      of a micro-penis. In the transgender woman, the glans penis is partially preserved to create&#xD;
      a clitoris. The purpose of this is to achieve maximum sensitivity of the genital area.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are few reports in the literature demonstrating sensory recovery in these extensively&#xD;
      operated body parts, let alone what the added value on sexual functioning might be as a&#xD;
      result of this recovery of genital sensitivity. At Ghent University Hospital, we now have&#xD;
      more than 30 years' experience with such operations and have shared this experience in an&#xD;
      almost entirely retrospective manner in various publications to date. However, in order to&#xD;
      address the bias associated with retrospective research, this study aims to prospectively and&#xD;
      observationally collect data on these patients who are counseled in a pathway for gender&#xD;
      dysphoria. This study will include all patients - after informed consent - and will collect&#xD;
      specific data on surgical outcome (complications after surgery, duration of surgery, type of&#xD;
      surgery) and functional outcome (tailored questionnaires for patients undergoing such a&#xD;
      treatment with questions on urination, erections, sexual experience, quality of life, patient&#xD;
      satisfaction and genital sensitivity) for each of these various surgical options. These&#xD;
      outcomes will be verified at follow-up moments (after 3 months, 6 months, 12 months and 24&#xD;
      months). Specifically for the component on genital sensitivity, we plan to follow up patients&#xD;
      3-monthly by means of a Semmes-Weinstein monofilament test of the genital region up to 24&#xD;
      months postoperatively. The aim of this study is therefore to use this prospectively&#xD;
      collected data to truthfully map our experience, to be critical, to reflect and optimize our&#xD;
      daily clinical practice in the interest of the patient.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2030</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single group assignment Single centre open label prospective</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in genital sensitivity pattern at 24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline function test, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 21 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Mapping of pressure thresholds of Semmes-Weinstein monofilaments in pre-defined areas of the neo-genital area</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in postoperative sexual function</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with Male Sexual Health Questionnaire/Female Sexual Function Index questionnaires (MSHQ/FSFI) with added questions specifically on penetrative sexual activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in self-assessment of genital anatomy and genital sensitivity</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 9, 12, 15, 18, 21 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with Self-Assessment of Genital Anatomy and Sexual Function (Male and Female) questionnaires (SAGASF-M/SAGASF-F)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in voiding function</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire on Male and Female Lower Urinary Tract Symptoms (ICIQ-MLUTS/ICIQ-FLUTS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in urinary continence</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire on Urge Incontinence short form questionnaire (ICIQ-UI SF)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in maximum flow rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Uroflowmetry at baseline, followed by uroflowmetry at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by uroflowmetry (Qmax)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in satisfaction with life by Likert and VAS scales</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with Satisfaction with life scale (SWLS) questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in satisfaction with life by Likert and VAS scales</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with Subjective happiness scale (SHS) questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life assessed by Likert scales.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the EuroQol questionnaire EQ-5D-3L.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life assessed by VAS scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questionnaire, followed by reassessment at 3, 6, 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed by the EuroQol questionnaire EQ-VAS (0-100)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective patient satisfaction with surgical and functional outcome assessed by Likert scales.</measure>
    <time_frame>Assessed at 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with seven subjective patient satisfaction questions on different surgical and functional outcomes aspects using Likert scales</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient motivations for surgery and extent to which these expectations were met as a result of the operation assessed by VAS scales</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline questions, followed by reassessed at 12 and 24 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Assessed with fourteen motivational questions using VAS scales (0-100)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Postoperative complication rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 90 days postoperatively</time_frame>
    <description>Categorized according to Clavien-Dindo classification system</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Gender Dysphoria</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Genital sensation and sexual functioning assessment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Genital sensation testing with clinical assessment and self-examination questionnaire.&#xD;
Sexual functioning testing with questionnaires.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Semmes-Weinstein monofilament testing and questionnaires</intervention_name>
    <description>Semmes-Weinstein test for the assessment of genital sensation Battery of questionnaires assessing sexual function, voiding function, quality of life and patient satisfaction</description>
    <arm_group_label>Genital sensation and sexual functioning assessment</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Voluntarily signed written informed consent according to the rules of Good Clinical&#xD;
             Practice (Declaration of Helsinki) and national regulations&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Transgender male, female of gender non-conforming patient with diagnosed gender&#xD;
             dysphoria and the specific wish to undergo genital gender affirming surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fit for operation, based on the surgeon's expert opinion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient is able and willing to attend the follow-up consultations&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of signed written informed consent and thus a patient unwilling to&#xD;
             participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cisgender patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients unfit for operation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient declares that it will be impossible for him to attend the follow-up&#xD;
             consultations&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>The study is specific to patients with gender dysphoria who wish to undergo genital gender affirming surgery.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>110 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital Ghent</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ghent</city>
        <state>East-Flanders</state>
        <zip>9000</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wietse Claeys, MD</last_name>
      <phone>003293321702</phone>
      <email>wietse.claeys@uzgent.be</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Nicolaas Lumen, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>003293322276</phone>
      <email>nicolaas.lumen@uzgent.be</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Anne-Françoise Spinoit, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Nicolaas Lumen, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wietse Claeys, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Phalloplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Metoidioplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaginoplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Vulvoplasty</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gender Dysphoria</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

