<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04996836</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04996836</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Breast Cancer, Omics, and Precision Medicine</brief_title>
  <acronym>BR(E)2ASTOME</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Predictive and Prognostic Power of the Early Breast canceR gEnetic and Epigenetic Abnormalities Through Liquid biopSy and neTwOrk MEdicine Algorithm: the BR(E)2ASTOME Phase II Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The standard tissue biopsy strategy for cancer detection is not comprehensive enough to&#xD;
      profile the whole epi-genomic signatures of breast cancer (BC) and ensure an accurate&#xD;
      prognosis and prediction of drug response. Liquid-based assays have the potential to reduce&#xD;
      the molecular heterogeneity of BC and a possible utility for improving disease management. In&#xD;
      particular, genomic DNA (gDNA) and circulating tumor (ctDNA) can be sequenced for genetic and&#xD;
      epigenetic (DNA methylation) profiling of the BC patients to enhance personalized prognosis&#xD;
      and prediction of drug therapy. We describe a study protocol for evaluating the clinical&#xD;
      utility of the early use of the network-oriented BR(E)2ASTOME algorithm which combine the&#xD;
      power of liquid-based assays, advanced epi-genomics platform, and network analysis to&#xD;
      identify improve precision medicine and personalized therapy of BC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The BR(E)2ASTOME study will be performed at the U.O.C. Patologia Molecolare e Clinica,&#xD;
      University of Campania &quot;L. Vanvitelli&quot;, Naples (Italy) with a long-standing experience in&#xD;
      diagnosis and treatment of BC (Refs.). From each study participant, total of 10 mL of&#xD;
      pheripheral blood in EDTA tubes will be collected at time of BC diagnosis. Blood-based assays&#xD;
      will be performed to obtain genetic and/or epigenetic big data from ct-DNA and gDNA,&#xD;
      respectively. A network-oriented algorithm combined with patient-level clinical information&#xD;
      will be applied to big data in order to identify clusters of genes (BC-modules) harboring&#xD;
      novel genetic mutations, in the NGS-ctDNA BC-group, and differentially methylated regions&#xD;
      (DMRs), in the RRBS-gDNA group, with a potential predictive and prognostic role in BC&#xD;
      management. In the NGS-ctDNA-RRBS-gDNA group, we will evaluate whether the multi-omics&#xD;
      approach is more informative as compared to the single-omic paradigm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BC patients (males and females) will be randomized to the 2 study arms: ctDNA-NGS +&#xD;
      gDNA-RRBS, and standard of care alone. No modifications of intervention assignment will be&#xD;
      possible after randomization process of patients. The BR(E)2ASTOME study will provide&#xD;
      evidence about the potential clinical utility of early use liquid-based assays and&#xD;
      network-oriented biomarkers in prognosis and prediction of drug response in BC management.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thus, results from BR(E)2ASTOME study will bring to identify not only new molecular&#xD;
      mechanisms associated with BC, but also non-invasive biomarkers that can direct towards an&#xD;
      early diagnosis, contribute to monitor the cancer progression and the response to therapeutic&#xD;
      treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Network-oriented buomarkers in prognosis of BC</measure>
    <time_frame>1 years</time_frame>
    <description>We will evaluate whether the network-oriented BR(E)2ASTOME approach will identify BC modules useful for a better stratification of BC severity.&#xD;
We will measure:&#xD;
DNA methylation levels and associations with clinical parameters (survival, hospitalization, all-cause mortality).&#xD;
We will evaluate potential novel genetic mutations in targeted genes and associations with clinical parameters (survival, rate of hospitalization, all-cause mortality)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Network-oriented buomarkers of Drug Response</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>We will evaluate whether the network-oriented BR(E)2ASTOME approach will identify BC modules useful for predicting the individual drug response.&#xD;
We will measure DNA methylation levels, and potential novel genetic mutations, and their association with clinical parameters (poor/good response to drug therapy).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BC diagnosis and Omics</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be offered:&#xD;
Liquid biopsy of ctDNA and targeted NGS (BRCA1, BRCA2, CHEK2, PALB2, BRIP1, TP53, PTEN, STK11, CDH1, ATM, BARD1, MLH1, MRE11A, MSH2, MSH6, MUTYH, NBN, PMS1, PMS2, RAD50, RAD51C, RAD51D, NF1, EPCAM, SMARCA4, CDK12);&#xD;
Whole-genome RRBS</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>BC diagnosis and standard of the care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will not be offered targeted NGS or whole-genome RRBS but will receive their usual clinical care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Next Generation Sequencing and Network Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Next Generation Sequencing and Network Analysis will profile genetic and epigenetic abnormalities in blood from patients with BC.</description>
    <arm_group_label>BC diagnosis and Omics</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sporadic BC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inherited BC&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males and Females&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inflammatory diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cardiovascular diseases&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Giuditta Benincasa, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+390815667916</phone>
    <email>giuditta.benincasa@unicampania.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Campania &quot;Luigi Vanvitelli&quot;</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Giuditta Benincasa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Liquid biopsy</keyword>
  <keyword>DNA methylation</keyword>
  <keyword>Omics</keyword>
  <keyword>Biomarkers</keyword>
  <keyword>Network Analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>Precision Medicine</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

