<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04996550</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CROWD-COMPARE</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04996550</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Are Carvedilol and Metoprolol Succinate Comparable Treatments in Heart Failure Patients With Reduced Ejection Fraction</brief_title>
  <acronym>CROWD-COMPARE</acronym>
  <official_title>Cluster and Registry Trial of the Working Group of Heart Failure in Denmark. Are Carvedilol and Metoprolol Succinate Comparable Treatments in Heart Failure Patients With Reduced Ejection Fraction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Odense University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Odense University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of CROWD-COMPARE is to compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol&#xD;
      succinate on all-cause mortality or first hospitalization for worsening heart failure in&#xD;
      patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment&#xD;
      with beta-blockers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Heart failure with reduced ejection fraction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall prevalence of heart failure with reduced ejection fraction (HFrEF) is 1-2% in the&#xD;
      adult population and increasing with age to more than 10% in the population over 70 years.&#xD;
      Patients with HFrEF have markedly reduced life expectancy, physical capacity and quality of&#xD;
      life. Activation of the sympathetic nervous system is one of the cardinal pathophysiologic&#xD;
      abnormalities in patients with HFrEF. Levels of circulating catecholamines increase in&#xD;
      patients with HFrEF in proportion to the severity of the disease and those with the highest&#xD;
      plasma levels of norepinephrine have the most unfavorable prognosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Beta-blocker in heart failure with reduced ejection fraction:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prospective randomized clinical trials of sympathetic antagonists with several different&#xD;
      beta-blockers have shown that these medications can reduce symptoms, improve left ventricular&#xD;
      function, increase functional capacity, decrease the number of hospitalization for worsening&#xD;
      heart failure and mortality in patients with HFrEF. Current heart failure guidelines&#xD;
      therefore recommend treatment with a beta-blocker in HFrEF patients as a class 1A indication.&#xD;
      However, small differences exist between beta-blockers. Metoprolol is a second generation&#xD;
      beta-blocker that selectively inhibit β1-adrenoceptors, whereas carvedilol is a third&#xD;
      generation beta-blocker, that nonselectively inhibit β1-adrenoceptors with additional&#xD;
      inhibition of α1-adrenoceptors. Therefore, controversy exists whether beta-blockers exert a&#xD;
      class effect or whether one beta-blocker is superior to another. In the largest prospective&#xD;
      randomized clinical trial that directly compared the efficacy of beta-blockers, the&#xD;
      Carvedilol or Metoprolol European Trial (COMET), carvedilol increased survival in patients&#xD;
      with HFrEF compared with metoprolol tartrate. However, the results of the COMET trial was&#xD;
      debated for two reasons. First, it compared carvedilol with the short-acting metoprolol&#xD;
      tartrate formulation. Metoprolol tartrate, however, is not the formulation used in key HFrEF&#xD;
      metoprolol trials and is not recommended in current heart failure guidelines. Second, the&#xD;
      metoprolol tartrate target dose in the COMET trial was 50 mg twice daily, whereas the&#xD;
      long-acting metoprolol succinate dose in the Metoprolol CR/XL Randomized Intervention Trial&#xD;
      (MERIT) trial was 200 mg once daily,10 as recommended by the heart failure guidelines.&#xD;
      Further, Carvedilol was dosed at full guideline target dose in COMET.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No pharmaceutical company has shown interest in carrying out such a comparative study.&#xD;
      Attempts have been made to compare these medications based on information from different&#xD;
      studies, but these so-called network meta-analyses are severely hampered by having different&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria, different end-points, ect. At the same time the patent of&#xD;
      both carvedilol and metoprolol succinate has expired in Denmark.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of CROWD-COMPARE is to compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol&#xD;
      succinate on all-cause mortality or first hospitalization for worsening heart failure in&#xD;
      patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment&#xD;
      with beta-blockers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design and cluster allocation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      CROWD-COMPARE is a crossover comparative effectiveness study with random allocation of&#xD;
      clusters. Each participating department of cardiology will be allocated to four periods&#xD;
      (clusters): two periods with carvedilol as the principal beta-blocker and two periods with&#xD;
      metoprolol succinate as principal beta-blocker. Departments will be randomly allocated as to&#xD;
      whether they will begin with the carvedilol or the metoprolol succinate cluster and then&#xD;
      alternate between clusters annually.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If a cluster becomes scheduled to stop before four years due to organizational changes (eg.&#xD;
      if the department of cardiology associated heart failure clinic is closed or merged with&#xD;
      another clinic), the investigators may change the duration of the remaining periods for that&#xD;
      cluster in order to get compatible allocation periods for the two medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible departments:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All 23 danish departments of cardiology with a heart failure clinic associated, which report&#xD;
      to the Danish Heart Failure Registry are eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment in allocation arms:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment in clusters will adhere to Danish and European guidelines, where the indication for&#xD;
      beta-blocker treatment is symptomatic heart failure (NYHA ≥ II) with LVEF ≤40%. There is no&#xD;
      difference in indication or contraindications for the two medications. Carvedilol or&#xD;
      metoprolol succinate will be titrated to target dose (Carvedilol 25 mg twice daily or&#xD;
      metoprolol succinate 200 mg once daily) or the maximal tolerated dose according to standard&#xD;
      heart failure care. There will not be any extra patient visits due to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection during the allocation period:&#xD;
&#xD;
      As the respective departments of cardiology with an associated heart failure clinic are&#xD;
      cluster randomized, there will be no study-related collection of data on individual patients&#xD;
      during the allocation period. All data will be obtained from national registries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up:&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the purpose of follow-up, data from the Danish Heart Failure Registry, which is routinely&#xD;
      uploaded to Statistics Denmark, will be linked in anonymous form to hospital admissions,&#xD;
      diagnosis, vital status, cause of death, dispensed descriptions and biochemistry from The&#xD;
      Danish National Patient Registry, The Danish Civil Registration System, The Clinical&#xD;
      Laboratory Information System and the Danish National Prescription Registry.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The National Prescription Registry entries in Statistics Denmark have a delay of 12 to 18&#xD;
      months, while vital status and admissions are updated with only a few months delay. Hence,&#xD;
      the primary endpoint will be assessed two years after the end of the 4-year allocation&#xD;
      period. At that time, we will be able to identify patients, who have filled in a prescription&#xD;
      for carvedilol or metoprolol succinate during the allocation period. Further, we will have&#xD;
      data on survival and hospital admission for a minimum follow-up period of two years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data management plan:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be stored and analyzed on the Statistics Denmark servers through our agreement&#xD;
      with the Division of Research Services at Statistics Denmark. There is no extra storage of&#xD;
      data in relation to this scientific study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint will be a combined endpoint of all-cause mortality or first&#xD;
      hospitalization for worsening heart failure. To have adequate statistical power, we will need&#xD;
      an overall event rate of 15% (840 events) for the primary outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proportional hazard regression of time to the primary endpoint from time of first claiming a&#xD;
      prescription for carvedilol or metoprolol succinate, comparing carvedilol clusters with&#xD;
      metoprolol succinate clusters adjusted for department of cardiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All-cause mortality&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A combined endpoint of all-cause mortality or first hospitalization for worsening heart&#xD;
           failure according to heart rhythm (sinus rhythm or atrial fibrillation/flutter)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary analyses:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Cost-effectiveness analysis of each strategy&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Proportion of patients who remained on beta-blocker treatment for a minimum of one year&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Proportion of patients who switched from their initially prescribed beta-blocker to the&#xD;
           other&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Proportion of patients who reached target dose&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intention to treat cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses will be performed on all participating departments of cardiology with an associated&#xD;
      heart failure clinic, which report data to the Danish Heart Failure Registry during the study&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size considerations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on data from the Danish Heart Failure Registry, we expect that 2700 patients annually&#xD;
      will be candidates for the treatment with either carvedilol or metoprolol succinate. Some of&#xD;
      these patients will already be on betablockers before first visit or hospitalization. In the&#xD;
      Danish Heart Failure Registry, 1-year mortality is 10%. With 23 clusters and an estimated&#xD;
      overall rate of the primary endpoint of 15% (see above for description of primary endpoint),&#xD;
      we will need to recruit registry data from 1400 patients per year (5600 patients in total) to&#xD;
      obtain 840 events over a period of four years to detect at relative reduction of 20% between&#xD;
      treatment groups with a significance level of 5% and a power of 90% (α=0.05, β=0.10).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistics:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses will be performed according to the CONSORT statement recommendation for cluster&#xD;
      trials. Statistical analyses will be performed using commercially or open-source available&#xD;
      statistical software. Primary results will be assessed as intention-to-treat. In addition, we&#xD;
      will conduct an instrumental variable analysis, where the cluster randomization is used as an&#xD;
      instrument for actually received treatment. In case of low-compliance to the cluster&#xD;
      allocated treatment then instrumental variables is the only way to estimate the causal&#xD;
      effect. Continuous data will be presented as median (25-75% range). A two-tailed p value of&#xD;
      0.05 or less is considered statistically significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results for subgroups will be presented. These will be prespecified prior to trial&#xD;
      termination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical aspects:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The two beta-blockers are considered equal in Danish and European heart failure guidelines.&#xD;
      Participating departments of cardiology will continue to follow best practice, with each&#xD;
      department having one of the two beta-blockers as principal option at a given period of time.&#xD;
      Departments who do not wish to switch between principal beta-blockers will not be included.&#xD;
      Of importance, all patients will be prescribed the medication that is considered best for&#xD;
      them. Hence, all patients will receive the same individually tailored treatment as patients&#xD;
      do today at their respective department of cardiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be informed about the trial in two ways: 1) by a posted bulletin in the&#xD;
      department stating that the department is participating in CROWD-COMPARE, and 2) by the&#xD;
      treating physician informing them, upon prescribing the beta-blocker, that the department is&#xD;
      participating in a national effort to compare two equivalent medications, which according to&#xD;
      heart failure guidelines are both first-line choices, and that currently the department of&#xD;
      cardiology is using the prescribed medication in cases where the patient and treating&#xD;
      physician after individual assessment do not have a preference for either beta-blocker.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The price difference between the two beta-blockers varies, but is less than 0.50,- kr./day.&#xD;
      (Daily cost: carvedilol 25 mg x 2: 0.63,- kr./day. versus metoprolol succinate 200 mg x 1:&#xD;
      0.57,- kr./day. (April the 30th, 2021). For this reason, the current study will not cause the&#xD;
      individual patient nor society (as the patient receives state sponsored premiums for their&#xD;
      medications) substantial extra expenses. In case of side effects after the initiation of a&#xD;
      beta-blocker, patients can be changed to the other at the discretion of the clinician. The&#xD;
      study does not result in extra visits for the patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study follows the Helsinki Declaration II.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 3, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 18, 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2, 2028</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>6 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>A combined endpoint of all-cause mortality or first hospitalization for worsening heart failure.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>A combined endpoint of all-cause mortality and first hospitalization for worsening heart failure according to heart rhythm (sinus rhythm or atrial fibrillation/flutter).</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cost-effectiveness analysis of each strategy.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients who remained on beta-blocker treatment for a minimum of one year.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients who switched from their initially prescribed beta-blocker to the other.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients who reached target dose.</measure>
    <time_frame>Four years with randomized cluster allocation and two year of follow-up.</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5600</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Heart Failure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Carvedilol group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Treated with Carvedilol</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Metoprolol succinate group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Treated with Metoprolol succinate</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carvedilol</intervention_name>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate on all-cause mortality or first hospitalization for worsening heart failure in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Carvedilol group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Metoprolol Succinate</intervention_name>
    <description>To compare the efficacy of carvedilol and metoprolol succinate on all-cause mortality or first hospitalization for worsening heart failure in patients with heart failure with reduced ejection fraction with an indication for treatment with beta-blockers.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Metoprolol succinate group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All 23 danish departments of cardiology with a heart failure clinic associated, which&#xD;
        report to the Danish Heart Failure Registry are eligible.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  NYHA ≥ II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  LVEF ≤40%&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No indication for beta-blocker treatment or contraindications for the two for the two&#xD;
             study drugs (Carvedilol or metoprolol succinate)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mikael K Poulsen</last_name>
    <phone>+45 24798402</phone>
    <email>mikael.kjaer.poulsen1@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ann Banke</last_name>
    <phone>+45 26278303</phone>
    <email>ann.banke@rsyd.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Cardiology, Odense University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Odense</city>
        <state>Region Of Southern Denmark</state>
        <zip>5000</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mikael K Poulsen, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+45 24798402</phone>
      <email>mikael.kjaer.poulsen1@rsyd.dk</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ann Banke, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+45 26278303</phone>
      <email>ann.banke@rsyd.dk</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Odense University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mikael Kjaer Poulsen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Failure</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Metoprolol</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carvedilol</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Final results.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

