<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04996901</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>958374</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04996901</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prognostic Factors in Patients With STEMI Treated by pPCI</brief_title>
  <official_title>Prognostic Factors in Patients With ST-Segment Elevation Myocardial Infarction Treated by Primary Percutaneous Coronary Intervention</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The First College of Clinical Medical Science, China Three Gorges University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The First Affiliated Hospital of Dalian Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jiangxi Provincial People's Hopital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Central Hospital of Enshi Tujia And Miao Autonomous Prefecture</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Xiangyang No.1 People's Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Prognostic Factors in patients with STEMI Treated by pPCI is a retrospective observational&#xD;
      study in China.This study aims to identify the main prognostic factors to recognize patients&#xD;
      with increased major adverse cardiovascular events risks and conduct a further intervention&#xD;
      for these patients. The study will provide clinical, functional, and invasive treatment&#xD;
      measures with systematic serial sampling and evaluation. Moreover, the knowledge on the&#xD;
      prognostic factors of STEMI patients treated by primary percutaneous coronary intervention&#xD;
      will be increased.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Currently, primary percutaneous coronary intervention is the first choice for patients with&#xD;
      acute ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction. In the past 40 years, the development of&#xD;
      rapid reperfusion therapy has gradually reduced the mortality rate of cardiovascular disease.&#xD;
      Compared with drug thrombolysis therapy, pPCI can effectively improve epicardial blood flow&#xD;
      reperfusion, reduce infarct size and improve survival rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, although epicardial blood flow reperfusion in patients with STEMI can be improved by&#xD;
      pPCI, the short-term and long-term major adverse cardiovascular events (MACE) in patients&#xD;
      with STEMI caused by ischemia-reperfusion injury, no-reflow phenomenon, microvascular&#xD;
      obstruction, and delayed microvascular perfusion are still worrying. Clinical studies have&#xD;
      reported that mechanical hemodynamic support device is not satisfactory for STEMI patients&#xD;
      who still develop circulatory failure after pPCI treatment, and it may only have a better&#xD;
      effect on high-risk patients. Clinical studies reported that the incidence of in-hospital&#xD;
      congestive heart failure in STEMI patients treated with pPCI was 6%. One retrospective study&#xD;
      of 251079 patients with STEMI by Wu et al showed that the in-hospital mortality rate of STEMI&#xD;
      patients could be as high as 9.2%. However, there are no reliable scoring criteria to&#xD;
      evaluate the incidence of acute congestive heart failure after pPCI in patients with STEMI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As STEMI patients are often complicated with hypertension, hypercholesterolemia, diabetes,&#xD;
      and other risk factors, each patient may face a different situation and more personalized&#xD;
      assessment criteria are needed to deal with complex clinical problems, especially for those&#xD;
      at high risk. We are committed to developing a prediction model to predict the risk of&#xD;
      in-hospital acute heart failure in STEMI patients treated with pPCI, to adjust the diagnosis&#xD;
      and treatment plan for those medium-and high-risk patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 16, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Major Adverse Cardiovascular Events</measure>
    <time_frame>in-hospital outcome, an average of 9 days</time_frame>
    <description>acute heart failure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>ST-segment Elevation Myocardial Infarction (STEMI)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>derivation cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>Data from Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University will be used as a derivation cohort.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>validation cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>Data from Yichang Central People's Hospital will be used as a derivation cohort.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>no intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>no intervention</description>
    <arm_group_label>derivation cohort</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>validation cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      plasma&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All patients with STEMI were treated by primary percutaneous coronary intervention in&#xD;
        Renmin Hospital of Wuhan university and Yichang Central People's Hospital from January 2015&#xD;
        to December 2020.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age≥18&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction was defined according to the universal&#xD;
             definition of myocardial infarction.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient with heart failure in admission.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. STEMI with symptom-onset-to-balloon time&gt;24h.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. pPCI was not successful.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients were complicated with congenital heart disease, valvular heart disease,&#xD;
             severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, malignant tumor, multiple organ failure&#xD;
             in admission.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Liwei Cheng</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Renmin Hospital of Wuhan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jing Chen, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>13659840327</phone>
    <email>chenjing1984@whu.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Renmin Hospital of Wuhan university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuhan</city>
        <state>Hubei</state>
        <zip>430000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jing Chen, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>13659840327</phone>
      <email>chenjing1982@whu.edu.cn</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ibanez B, James S, Agewall S, Antunes MJ, Bucciarelli-Ducci C, Bueno H, Caforio ALP, Crea F, Goudevenos JA, Halvorsen S, Hindricks G, Kastrati A, Lenzen MJ, Prescott E, Roffi M, Valgimigli M, Varenhorst C, Vranckx P, Widimský P; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2017 ESC Guidelines for the management of acute myocardial infarction in patients presenting with ST-segment elevation: The Task Force for the management of acute myocardial infarction in patients presenting with ST-segment elevation of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J. 2018 Jan 7;39(2):119-177. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehx393.</citation>
    <PMID>28886621</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nabel EG, Braunwald E. A tale of coronary artery disease and myocardial infarction. N Engl J Med. 2012 Jan 5;366(1):54-63. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1112570. Erratum in: N Engl J Med. 2012 Mar 8;366(10):970.</citation>
    <PMID>22216842</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Keeley EC, Boura JA, Grines CL. Primary angioplasty versus intravenous thrombolytic therapy for acute myocardial infarction: a quantitative review of 23 randomised trials. Lancet. 2003 Jan 4;361(9351):13-20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>12517460</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pluijmert NJ, Bart CI, Bax WH, Quax PHA, Atsma DE. Effects on cardiac function, remodeling and inflammation following myocardial ischemia-reperfusion injury or unreperfused myocardial infarction in hypercholesterolemic APOE*3-Leiden mice. Sci Rep. 2020 Oct 6;10(1):16601. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-73608-w.</citation>
    <PMID>33024178</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Allencherril J, Jneid H, Atar D, Alam M, Levine G, Kloner RA, Birnbaum Y. Pathophysiology, Diagnosis, and Management of the No-Reflow Phenomenon. Cardiovasc Drugs Ther. 2019 Oct;33(5):589-597. doi: 10.1007/s10557-019-06901-0. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31418141</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Aggarwal S, Xie F, High R, Pavlides G, Porter TR. Prevalence and Predictive Value of Microvascular Flow Abnormalities after Successful Contemporary Percutaneous Coronary Intervention in Acute ST-Segment Elevation Myocardial Infarction. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2018 Jun;31(6):674-682. doi: 10.1016/j.echo.2018.01.009. Epub 2018 Mar 7.</citation>
    <PMID>29525249</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Thiele H, Zeymer U, Neumann FJ, Ferenc M, Olbrich HG, Hausleiter J, de Waha A, Richardt G, Hennersdorf M, Empen K, Fuernau G, Desch S, Eitel I, Hambrecht R, Lauer B, Böhm M, Ebelt H, Schneider S, Werdan K, Schuler G; Intraaortic Balloon Pump in cardiogenic shock II (IABP-SHOCK II) trial investigators. Intra-aortic balloon counterpulsation in acute myocardial infarction complicated by cardiogenic shock (IABP-SHOCK II): final 12 month results of a randomised, open-label trial. Lancet. 2013 Nov 16;382(9905):1638-45. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)61783-3. Epub 2013 Sep 3.</citation>
    <PMID>24011548</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schrage B, Ibrahim K, Loehn T, Werner N, Sinning JM, Pappalardo F, Pieri M, Skurk C, Lauten A, Landmesser U, Westenfeld R, Horn P, Pauschinger M, Eckner D, Twerenbold R, Nordbeck P, Salinger T, Abel P, Empen K, Busch MC, Felix SB, Sieweke JT, Møller JE, Pareek N, Hill J, MacCarthy P, Bergmann MW, Henriques JPS, Möbius-Winkler S, Schulze PC, Ouarrak T, Zeymer U, Schneider S, Blankenberg S, Thiele H, Schäfer A, Westermann D. Impella Support for Acute Myocardial Infarction Complicated by Cardiogenic Shock. Circulation. 2019 Mar 5;139(10):1249-1258. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.118.036614.</citation>
    <PMID>30586755</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ouweneel DM, Eriksen E, Sjauw KD, van Dongen IM, Hirsch A, Packer EJ, Vis MM, Wykrzykowska JJ, Koch KT, Baan J, de Winter RJ, Piek JJ, Lagrand WK, de Mol BA, Tijssen JG, Henriques JP. Percutaneous Mechanical Circulatory Support Versus Intra-Aortic Balloon Pump in Cardiogenic Shock After Acute Myocardial Infarction. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017 Jan 24;69(3):278-287. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2016.10.022. Epub 2016 Oct 31.</citation>
    <PMID>27810347</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Auffret V, Cottin Y, Leurent G, Gilard M, Beer JC, Zabalawi A, Chagué F, Filippi E, Brunet D, Hacot JP, Brunel P, Mejri M, Lorgis L, Rouault G, Druelles P, Cornily JC, Didier R, Bot E, Boulanger B, Coudert I, Loirat A, Bedossa M, Boulmier D, Maza M, Le Guellec M, Puri R, Zeller M, Le Breton H; ORBI and RICO Working Groups. Predicting the development of in-hospital cardiogenic shock in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction treated by primary percutaneous coronary intervention: the ORBI risk score. Eur Heart J. 2018 Jun 7;39(22):2090-2102. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehy127.</citation>
    <PMID>29554243</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu J, Hall M, Dondo TB, Wilkinson C, Ludman P, DeBelder M, Fox KAA, Timmis A, Gale CP. Association between time of hospitalization with acute myocardial infarction and in-hospital mortality. Eur Heart J. 2019 Apr 14;40(15):1214-1221. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehy835.</citation>
    <PMID>30698766</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Luo Y, Wang X, Ye Z, Lai Y, Yao Y, Li J, Liu X. Remedial hydration reduces the incidence of contrast-induced nephropathy and short-term adverse events in patients with ST-segment elevation myocardial infarction: a single-center, randomized trial. Intern Med. 2014;53(20):2265-72. Epub 2014 Oct 15.</citation>
    <PMID>25318787</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Arbab-Zadeh A, Nakano M, Virmani R, Fuster V. Acute coronary events. Circulation. 2012 Mar 6;125(9):1147-56. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.111.047431. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22392862</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>ST Elevation Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

