<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04994405</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21-00267</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04994405</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lower Tourniquet Pressure Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Double-blinded, Randomized Controlled Trial Evaluating Effectiveness of Lower Tourniquet Pressures in Hand Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NYU Langone Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NYU Langone Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study design is a prospective, double-blinded, randomized controlled trial evaluating&#xD;
      the quality of bloodless surgical field with lower tourniquet pressures based on systolic&#xD;
      blood pressure (SBP) compared to standard tourniquet pressures. A secondary goal is to&#xD;
      evaluate the effect of lower tourniquet pressures on post-operative tourniquet site pain. The&#xD;
      rationale behind the study is to provide evidence-based guidelines on tourniquet use to&#xD;
      continue providing quality surgical care while minimizing pain and potential harm to&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients undergoing hand and upper extremity surgery at our institution will be offered&#xD;
      participation in this study. Consenting patients will be randomized in a double-blinded&#xD;
      fashion to either standard tourniquet pressure of 250 mmHg or lower tourniquet pressures&#xD;
      based on SBP. Demographic data will be recorded as well as details of the surgical procedure.&#xD;
      Post-operatively, the operating surgeon will complete a questionnaire about the quality of&#xD;
      bloodless surgical field and the patient will complete a questionnaire about post-operative&#xD;
      pain. This study will enroll approximately 150 patients. Statistical analysis will be&#xD;
      completed to analyze the effectiveness of the intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of the bloodless surgical field provided by lower tourniquet pressures</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately After surgery in recovery room time</time_frame>
    <description>Surgeon-completed questionnaire rating the quality of the bloodless operative field using a 4-point Likert scale ranging from 1 (excellent) meaning no blood in the surgical field to 4 (poor) meaning blood in the surgical field obscures view throughout the procedure. This survey will be completed immediately post-operatively.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Effect of lower tourniquet pressures based on SBP on post-operative tourniquet site pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately After surgery in recovery room time</time_frame>
    <description>Patient-completed questionnaire rating their tourniquet site pain post-operatively using the Visual Analogue Scale (VAS) ranging from 0 meaning no pain to 10 meaning worst possible pain. This survey will be completed post-operatively in the recovery unit.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Hand Injuries</condition>
  <condition>Upper Extremity Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard Pressure</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The extremity tourniquet used during hand surgery for these participants will be the standard pressure of 250 mmHg.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Lower Tiered Pressures</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The study intervention is the inflation of the extremity tourniquet to a pressure lower than the standard pressure of 250 mmHg during hand surgery for these participants determined by tiered guidelines based on systolic blood pressure (SBP).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tourniquet Pressure</intervention_name>
    <description>The procedural intervention will be inflation of a pneumatic tourniquet to a lower than standard pressure as determined by the patient's SBP in hand and upper extremity surgery. The control will be inflation of a pneumatic tourniquet at a standard pressure of 250 mmHg in hand and upper extremity surgery.&#xD;
The tourniquet used will be the standard tourniquet used for hand and upper extremity surgery at our institutions - a tourniquet 18 inches in length and 3 inches in width manufactured by Stryker (Kalamazoo, MI) used in conjunction with a protective sleeve matched to the size of the tourniquet cuff which is provided by the manufacturer. Both pieces are supplied in a sterile packaging. No other tourniquets will be used.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Lower Tiered Pressures</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patient age 18 or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing hand or upper extremity procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tourniquet is used for procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness and ability to consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with procedures that are over 120 minutes in length&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ali Azad</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NYU Langone Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ali Azad</last_name>
    <phone>929-455-2600</phone>
    <email>Ali.azad@nyulangone.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Madeline Rocks</last_name>
    <phone>929-455-2600</phone>
    <email>madeline.rocks@nyulangone.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hand Injuries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arm Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data that underlie the results reported in this article, after deidentification (text, tables, figures, and appendices).</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Beginning 9 months and ending 36 months following article publication or as required by a condition of awards and agreements supporting the research.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>The investigator who proposed to use the data. Upon reasonable request. Requests should be directed to ali.azad@nyulangone.org. To gain access, data requestors will need to sign a data access agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

