<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04995601</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TP1400-04</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04995601</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Wearable Technology to Reduce Risk of DVT and Increase Patient Compliance</brief_title>
  <acronym>SBIR2</acronym>
  <official_title>Wearable Technology to Reduce Risk of DVT and Increase Patient Compliance</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Recovery Force LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Massachusetts, Amherst</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Recovery Force LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary purpose of this study is to conduct a multi-site clinical trial of the Recovery&#xD;
      Force Movement and Compressions (RF MAC) System. The study is a randomized comparative study&#xD;
      of DVT prophylaxis using either standard IPC (Group 1) or the RF MAC system (Group 2) in 300&#xD;
      patients after TJR surgery at two study sites: Tufts Medical Center (Boston, Massachusetts)&#xD;
      and Eskenazi Hospital (Indianapolis, Indiana). This study is funded by a Phase II SBIR&#xD;
      awarded to Recovery Force from the National Institutes of Health, National Heart, Lung and&#xD;
      Blood Institute (R44-HL132624-02).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      DVT is the most feared complication of total joint replacement (TJR), with more than 300,000&#xD;
      total hip and 700,000 total knee replacements performed annually in the U.S. Current&#xD;
      recommendations for postoperative DVT prophylaxis after TJR include anti-coagulant&#xD;
      medications and/or intermittent pneumatic compression (IPC) of the lower limb for a minimum&#xD;
      of 10-14 days. Most current IPC devices are non-mobile, making early postoperative mobility,&#xD;
      which is especially important in TJR patients, cumbersome and time-consuming. Upon hospital&#xD;
      discharge, most patients go home on pharmacologic DVT prophylaxis. Even when at-home external&#xD;
      compression therapy is prescribed (IPC or compression stockings), data suggests compliance&#xD;
      rates as low as 10-50%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recovery Force (RF) has produced the next generation of mechanical DVT prophylaxis, with a&#xD;
      mobile device absent of tubes and pumps, stays in place during ambulation, is lightweight and&#xD;
      comfortable for continuous wear, and is designed to improve compliance with recommended use.&#xD;
      The hypothesis for Phase II is that IPC using the RF1400 will result in improved compliance,&#xD;
      support early mobility and result in significantly higher functional mobility after TJR as&#xD;
      compared to standard of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research team will conduct a randomized comparative study of DVT prophylaxis using either&#xD;
      standard IPC (Group 1) or the RF1400 (Group 2) in 300 patients after TJR surgery. Dr. Karen&#xD;
      Giuliano of the University of Massachusetts Amherst will serve as the overall PI for efforts&#xD;
      associated with the study sites. This study will include an inpatient phase and an outpatient&#xD;
      phase with patients at two clinical sites: Tufts Medical Center and Indiana University School&#xD;
      of Medicine, with each site enrolling 150 patients (75 control/75 experimental).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall goal of Phase II is to demonstrate that compliance with perscribed use, comfort,&#xD;
      and ease-of-use is significantly higher with the RF1400 than with DVT prophylaxis using&#xD;
      either standard IPC (in-hospital) or standard-of-care (at-home) in preparation for full&#xD;
      commercialization in the TJR market during Phase III. The DVT therapy market is expected to&#xD;
      hit $3.8B by 2021, and the US accounts for over 50% of the global market. With the current&#xD;
      risk of bleeding from anticoagulant DVT prophylaxis at 5.6%, the commercial impact of this&#xD;
      research is that improved patient compliance with the RF1400 DVT prophylaxis will improve&#xD;
      postoperative mobility and provide an effective alternative to anticoagulation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 1, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This study will have 2 groups, intervention (RF MAC-group 2) and control (usual care for DVT prevention and mobility-group 1) in postoperative total joint replacement patients at two hospitals.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance to prescribed use</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Compare patient compliance (measured as percent of time used per 24-hour period) between the standard of care sequential compression device and the Recovery Force Mobility and Compression (MAC) system in a group of total joint replacement patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported comfort</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Compare patient-reported comfort (using the comfort rating scale) between the standard of care sequential compression device and the Recovery Force Mobility and Compression (MAC) system in a group of total joint replacement patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient-reported ease-of-use</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Compare patient-reported ease-of-use (using the System Usability Scale) between the standard of care sequential compression device and the Recovery Force Mobility and Compression (MAC) system in a group of total joint replacement patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Orthopedic Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive DVT prophylaxis using standard intermittent pneumatic compression during postoperative care after total joint replacement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Recovery Force MAC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive DVT prophylaxis using the RF Health MAC during postoperative care after total joint replacement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>RF Health MAC</intervention_name>
    <description>The RF Health MAC is a novel device that is applied to the lower legs of patients that provides intermittent active compressions to the calf muscles which results in increased blood flow in the veins, moving blood towards the direction of the heart and reducing the risk of clot formation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Recovery Force MAC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  adult patients (age 40-85)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  first elective total hip replacement (THR) or first or second (opposite knee) elective&#xD;
             total knee replacement (TKA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  speak English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  expected to have a hospital stay of two days or less&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  discharge to home from hospital (not a rehabilitation facility)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  must be able to perform self-care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI between 18 and 39&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  calf circumference between 11 and 24.5 inches&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  partial joint replacement, TJR revisions, emergency surgeries&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  calf deformities that would not allow proper fit for external compression device&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  non-ambulatory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  clinically malnourished or frail/deconditioned&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  vulnerable patients (pregnant women, prisoners, homeless and cognitively impaired)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  do not speak English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Karen K Giuliano, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>2247250270</phone>
    <email>kkgiuliano@umass.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kristen Parmelee</last_name>
    <phone>3174915051</phone>
    <email>kparmelee@parmeleeconsulting.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Musculoskeletal Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

