<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04990076</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>s62497</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04990076</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ultrasound Evaluation of the Myometrium Using the MUSA Terminology Comparison With Histology</brief_title>
  <acronym>MUSA1</acronym>
  <official_title>Ultrasound Evaluation of the Myometrium Using the MUSA Terminology, Comparison With Histology.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitaire Ziekenhuizen Leuven</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective is to evaluate the diagnostic accuracy of the MUSA terms and definitions,&#xD;
      as defined in the paper by Van den Bosch T, Dueholm M, ea. in 2015, to differentiate between&#xD;
      different types of myometrial lesions of more than 1 cm. The primary aim is the diagnostic&#xD;
      accuracy of the MUSA terms and definitions and the secondary aim the development of a&#xD;
      prediction model.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Primary aim: Diagnostic accuracy of the MUSA terms and definitions&#xD;
&#xD;
      Every patient planned for hysterectomy for myometrial pathology (e.g. benign fibroid, benign&#xD;
      adenomyoma or malignant uterine sarcoma) will undergo a systematic preoperative ultrasound&#xD;
      scan. Around 50 ultrasound characteristics (described in Addendum 1) will be assess as to&#xD;
      diagnostic accuracy as predictors (Prospective evaluation of MUSA terms and definitions).&#xD;
      Figure 1 shows the different histological endpoint with expected prevalence in our study&#xD;
      population and table 1 further differentiate those histological endpoints. The estimation for&#xD;
      sarcomas is based on preliminary and unpublished results from an ongoing prospective study&#xD;
      led by prof dr Antonia Testa from the Università Cattolica di Sacro Cuore Largo Agostino&#xD;
      Gemelli in Rome showing an incidence of 4.9% for uterine sarcomas amongst women with a&#xD;
      myometrial lesion referred to their tertiary center (Antonia Testa, personal communication).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary aim: Development of prediction model&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Secondary aim is to build predictive models to differentiate between benign myometrial&#xD;
      lesions (e.g. adenomyosis and fibroid) and malignant myometrial lesion (e.g. uterine&#xD;
      sarcoma). Because of the small number of cases with malignant myometrial lesion (expected to&#xD;
      be 5% of the study population or around 75 women), we will limit the number of variables to&#xD;
      be tested in order to avoid overfitting. Based on current literature, we preselected&#xD;
      following characteristics for development of a prediction model:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Outer contour: regular of irregular&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Echogenicity of uterine lesion: uniform (homogeneous) or non-uniform (mixed)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Colour score: 1 to 4&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Presence of central necrosis&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Maximal diameter of the lesion (in mm)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Presence of acoustic shadows&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 11, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diagnostic accuracy of the MUSA terms and definitions</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>Around 50 ultrasound characteristics will be assess as to diagnostic accuracy as predictors (Prospective evaluation of MUSA terms and definitions).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Development of prediction model</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>predictive models to differentiate between benign myometrial lesions (e.g. adenomyosis and fibroid) and malignant myometrial lesion (e.g. uterine sarcoma).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1500</enrollment>
  <condition>Myoma;Uterus</condition>
  <condition>Sarcoma Uterus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients planned for hysterectomy with a myometrial lesion of more than 1 cm.</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hysterectomy</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgery includes different types of hysterectomy: vaginal hysterectomy, total abdominal hysterectomy and laparoscopic or Robotic hysterectomy. The type of hysterectomy does not influence histological outcome, as long as the uterus is removed in one part (no power morcellation). Indications for surgery and the type of surgery are according to the departments' protocols. If the patient is deemed to be inoperable due to the extent of the disease, a representive biopsy (e.g. trucut biopsy) will be accepted if sufficiently motivated by the oncology team.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients planned for hysterectomy with a myometrial lesion of more than 1 cm.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients planned for hysterectomy with a myometrial lesion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Consecutive patients planned to undergo hysterectomy for myometrial pathology of more then&#xD;
        1cm (e.g. fibroid, focal adenomyosis, uterine sarcoma).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient's refusal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Polymyomatous uterus&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Myometrial lesion with a diameter less then 10mm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients currently treated for another cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ovarian pathology, endometrial pathology of cervical pathology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Power morcellation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dirk Timmerman, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UZ Leuven</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christine De Bruyn, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+32 16 345125</phone>
    <email>christine.debruyn@uzleuven.be</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UZ Leuven</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leuven</city>
        <zip>300</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christine De Bruyn, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+32 16 345125</phone>
      <email>christine.debruyn@uzleuven.be</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Dirk Timmerman, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thierry Van den Bosch, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ben Van Calster, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christine De Bruyn, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Van den Bosch T, Dueholm M, Leone FP, Valentin L, Rasmussen CK, Votino A, Van Schoubroeck D, Landolfo C, Installé AJ, Guerriero S, Exacoustos C, Gordts S, Benacerraf B, D'Hooghe T, De Moor B, Brölmann H, Goldstein S, Epstein E, Bourne T, Timmerman D. Terms, definitions and measurements to describe sonographic features of myometrium and uterine masses: a consensus opinion from the Morphological Uterus Sonographic Assessment (MUSA) group. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2015 Sep;46(3):284-98. doi: 10.1002/uog.14806. Epub 2015 Aug 10.</citation>
    <PMID>25652685</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ludovisi M, Moro F, Pasciuto T, Di Noi S, Giunchi S, Savelli L, Pascual MA, Sladkevicius P, Alcazar JL, Franchi D, Mancari R, Moruzzi MC, Jurkovic D, Chiappa V, Guerriero S, Exacoustos C, Epstein E, Frühauf F, Fischerova D, Fruscio R, Ciccarone F, Zannoni GF, Scambia G, Valentin L, Testa AC. Imaging in gynecological disease (15): clinical and ultrasound characteristics of uterine sarcoma. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2019 Nov;54(5):676-687. doi: 10.1002/uog.20270. Epub 2019 Oct 7.</citation>
    <PMID>30908820</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leiomyoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myofibroma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

