<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04994145</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PD-612416</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04994145</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Post-Market Clinical Investigation on Mepilex Border Post-Op</brief_title>
  <acronym>ARCTIS</acronym>
  <official_title>A Retrospective, Observational, Post-Market Clinical Investigation on Safety and Performance of Mepilex Border Post-Op for Post-Operative Wounds</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Molnlycke Health Care AB</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Molnlycke Health Care AB</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a retrospective, observational (non-interventional), single-arm, single-centre,&#xD;
      post-market clinical investigation designed to verify clinical performance and safety of&#xD;
      Mepilex Border Post-Op when used according to clinical practice for post-operative wounds in&#xD;
      a large and broad population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical investigation will consist of a retrospective medical record review, which will&#xD;
      be completed with data from up to 450 female and male adult subjects who were treated with&#xD;
      Mepilex Border Post-Op following elective hip or knee replacement at one clinic in Belgium&#xD;
      between January 2016 and February 2021.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Mepilex Border Post-Op is a CE-marked class IIa medical device developed, manufactured and&#xD;
      marketed by Mölnlycke Health Care AB. This is a retrospective, observational&#xD;
      (non-interventional), single-arm, single-centre, post-market clinical investigation designed&#xD;
      to verify clinical performance and safety of Mepilex Border Post-Op when used according to&#xD;
      clinical practice for post-operative wounds in a large and broad population. The overall&#xD;
      objective of this investigation is to confirm the clinical performance of Mepilex Border&#xD;
      Post-Op for post-operative wounds when used according to clinical practice, by assessing&#xD;
      dressing wear time from day of surgery to end of dressing use.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The clinical investigation will consist of a retrospective medical record review, which will&#xD;
      be completed with data from up to 450 female and male adult subjects who were treated with&#xD;
      Mepilex Border Post-Op following elective hip or knee replacement at one clinic in Belgium&#xD;
      between January 2016 and February 2021. The data collected for each subject will include&#xD;
      those generated in relation to the surgery itself as well as the pre- and post-surgery&#xD;
      phases. There is no available data for subjects treated with an alternative to Mepilex Border&#xD;
      Post-Op to use as a control group, however, the pre-surgery data will serve as control for&#xD;
      some endpoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The treatment the subjects received at the clinic included pre-surgery visits, the surgery&#xD;
      itself, a short in-patient stay following surgery, and post-surgery follow-up visits at&#xD;
      approximately 14 days, 1.5 months, 3 months, 6 months, and 1 year. In addition, the subjects&#xD;
      used the commercially available mobile health application moveUP Therapy to support their&#xD;
      rehabilitation. The subjects' rehabilitation was tracked and aided with moveUP Therapy as it&#xD;
      allows (1) subjects to answer a number of questionnaires; (2) subjects to communicate with&#xD;
      their surgeon and physical therapist via a chat function in the app; and (3) subject-specific&#xD;
      log entries by the surgeon and physical therapist. The data to be used in this retrospective&#xD;
      investigation will be extracted exclusively from moveUP Therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible subjects/medical records will be identified by site personnel through screening&#xD;
      moveUP Therapy. Only data from subjects who have consented to the use of their data related&#xD;
      to the surgery in an anonymous way for medical research and scientific publications will be&#xD;
      extracted.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigational device, Mepilex Border Post-Op, was applied as part of the surgery. In&#xD;
      the rare event that a dressing change would be required, the subjects were provided with&#xD;
      spare dressings and instructions for how to do the change by the treating surgeon or clinic&#xD;
      nurse. These instructions included only changing the dressing once at least three corners of&#xD;
      the dressing were stained with blood, and to consult the treating surgeon or clinic nurse by&#xD;
      sending a moveUP Therapy chat message with a picture of the dressing requesting advice on&#xD;
      whether to change or not.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dressing wear time will be derived from up to three sources:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. how frequently the subjects have answered the question &quot;Is the dressing dry?&quot; with &quot;Yes,&#xD;
           it was changed today&quot;;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. review of potential Health Care Professional log entries for evidence of dressing&#xD;
           change(s); and&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. review of potential moveUP Therapy chat messages, including photographs, for evidence of&#xD;
           dressing change(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Total number of dressings per subject will be derived from the same information as dressing&#xD;
      wear time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dressing wear time</measure>
    <time_frame>From day of surgery to end of dressing use (up to one month)</time_frame>
    <description>Dressing wear time from day of surgery to end of dressing use</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total number of dressings per subject</measure>
    <time_frame>From day of surgery to end of dressing use (up to one month)</time_frame>
    <description>Total number of dressings/subject from day of surgery to end of dressing use</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to dressing strikethrough</measure>
    <time_frame>From day of surgery to end of dressing use (up to one month)</time_frame>
    <description>Time to dressing strikethrough from day of surgery to end of dressing use</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in physical activity level</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-surgery to end of dressing use (up to one month)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in physical activity level (daily step count) pre-surgery to end of dressing use</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the EQ-5D</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-surgery to day 83 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in the EQ-5D results pre-surgery to day 83.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in KOOS or HOOS pain subscale score</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in the KOOS or HOOS pain subscale score pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in KOOS or HOOS symptoms subscale score</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in the KOOS or HOOS symptoms subscale score pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in KOOS or HOOS activities of daily living subscale score</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in the KOOS or HOOS activities of daily living subscale score pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in KOOS or HOOS sport and recreation function subscale score</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in the KOOS or HOOS sport and recreation function subscale score pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in KOOS or HOOS joint-related quality of life subscale score</measure>
    <time_frame>pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83 post surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage and absolute change in the KOOS or HOOS joint-related quality of life subscale score pre-surgery to day 42 and day 83</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dressing showerability</measure>
    <time_frame>From day of surgery to end of dressing use (up to one month)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of incidences (percentage and absolute) of dressing detachment due to subject showering or using water in other ways for personal hygiene reasons</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">450</enrollment>
  <condition>Surgical Wound</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Eligible subjects/medical records will be identified from a population of adults patients&#xD;
        who have had elective hip or knee replacement surgery at the Medisch Centrum Latem,&#xD;
        Belgium.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Underwent elective knee or hip surgery between January 2016 and February 2021 at the&#xD;
             Medisch Centrum Latem, Belgium.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Post-operative wound treated with Mepilex Border Post-Op&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Documented consent in moveUP Therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Documented consent at Medisch Centrum Latem during pre-op consultation&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Subject missing all answers to the moveUP Therapy question &quot;Is the dressing dry?&quot;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Camilla Fardell, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>+46317223402</phone>
    <email>camilla.fardell@molnlycke.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medisch Centrum Latem</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sint-Martens-Latem</city>
        <zip>9830</zip>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wouter Van Lysebettens</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Medical Device</keyword>
  <keyword>Mepilex Border Post-Op</keyword>
  <keyword>Knee replacement</keyword>
  <keyword>Hip replacement</keyword>
  <keyword>Surgical wound</keyword>
  <keyword>Dressing</keyword>
  <keyword>Wear time</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Surgical Wound</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

