<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04997655</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KonyaCityH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04997655</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Upper Transabdominal Plain Block on Diaphragm Thickness</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Upper Transabdominal Plain Block on Diaphragm Thickness in Adult Patients After Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy Operation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Konya City Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Konya City Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the study, patients of both sexes between the ages of 18 and 60 who will undergo&#xD;
      laparoscopic cholecystectomy will be examined. In this patient group, the change in the&#xD;
      inspiratory and expiratory diaphragmatic thickness before and after laparoscopic&#xD;
      cholecystectomy operation in the upper transabdominal block group will be examined.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The use of ultrasonography (USG) in operating rooms is increasing day by day. Diaphragm&#xD;
      thickness can be evaluated by ultrasonography and is used as a bedside method studies have&#xD;
      proven that the evaluation of diaphragmatic thickness contributes to the observation of&#xD;
      diaphragmatic function and the evaluation of respiratory workload. Measurement of&#xD;
      diaphragmatic thickness is a method used in operating rooms and intensive care units to make&#xD;
      the decision to wean from mechanical ventilation and extubation. Laparoscopic gallbladder&#xD;
      operations are a very common operation in the adult age group in the operating room. In these&#xD;
      cases who were intubated and extubated at the end of the operation, regression in respiratory&#xD;
      function is observed, especially due to right upper quadrant pain appropriate to the location&#xD;
      of the liver. For this reason, the respiratory functions of patients who will have&#xD;
      gallbladder surgery will be routinely evaluated before and after gallbladder surgery in our&#xD;
      clinic with the help of USG and routinely apply analgesic methods, including peripheral nerve&#xD;
      blocks, to patients with pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, it will be planned to observe the effect of upper transabdominal area block,&#xD;
      which is routinely performed post-operatively in laparoscopic gallbladder operations, on&#xD;
      diaphragmatic thickness and therefore on respiratory capacity, and observationally evaluating&#xD;
      diaphragmatic thickness measurements by USG, which is routinely performed post-operatively&#xD;
      and the measurement records are noted.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 12, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 12, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 12, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diaphragm Thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes before general anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The measurement of Diaphragm Thickness by USG</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diaphragm Thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The measurement of Diaphragm Thickness by USG</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Diaphragm Thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>5 minutes after upper abdominal plane block</time_frame>
    <description>The measurement of Diaphragm Thickness by USG</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oxygen saturation</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the anesthesia, after anesthesia and after 30 minutes in the post operative care unit.</time_frame>
    <description>Oxygen saturation separately for each primary outcome stage</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Visual analogue scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Before the anesthesia, after anesthesia and after 30 minutes in the post operative care unit.</time_frame>
    <description>The patient's pain will be asked in a scale from 1 to 10.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">68</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia, General</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Upper Transabdominal Plain Block</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients in this group are routinely administered general anesthesia. After extubation, the subcostal transverse abdominis area block was directed laterally along the rectus abdominis muscle by finding the linea alba under the xiphoid region under ultrasound guidance with a 22G echogenic block needle, and 20 ml (8 ml 0.5% bupivacaine, 7 ml prilocaine) into the fascia between the rectus abdominis and transverse abdominis muscles. , 5 ml of saline) drug mixture will be performed by the anesthesiologist in charge of that day, who is not aware of the observational measurement to be made, if there is an indication, as a blind practitioner.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Opioid analgesia</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients in this group are routinely administered general anesthesia. Apart from this, in the other group, which does not have peripheral nerve block and only routine opioid analgesia is considered sufficient, only routine peroperative USG diaphragm measurements will be recorded observationally.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ultrasound measurement</intervention_name>
    <description>In the patient group who will undergo elective laparoscopic cholecystectomy, the diaphragmatic thickness values measured and recorded routinely at the pre-operative, post-extubation and post-operative 30th minute, at the end of inspiration and expiration, and the inspiratory amplitude in m-mode in the ultrasound measured from the right anterior axillary line subcostal area were observed as observational data. will be saved in our file.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Opioid analgesia</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Upper Transabdominal Plain Block</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        With the calculated sample size values, we will need to include at least 68 patients in our&#xD;
        study at 0.5 sensitivity and 0.95 power.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients between the ages of 18-60&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both sexes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patiets are evaluated as ASA 1 and ASA 2 anesthesia risk, will be examined.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Under 18 years old, over 60 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI&gt;35 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bleeding diathesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Local anesthetic allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infection in the area of TAP (Trans abdominal plane) block application&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Illiteracy, communication problem&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous upper abdomen operation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Transition to open surgery Cases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe chronic respiratory disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neuromuscular disorders.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Patients between the ages of 18-60, of both sexes, who will undergo laparoscopic cholecystectomy, which are evaluated as ASA 1 and ASA 2 anesthesia risk, will be examined.</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yasin Tire</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Konya City Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yasin Tire</last_name>
    <phone>+905055367970</phone>
    <email>dryasintire@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sami Uyar</last_name>
    <phone>+903323100500</phone>
    <email>uyarsami111191@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=tr&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=G%C3%BCllero%C4%9Flu%2C+Aykan%2C+et+al.+%22Laparoskopik+kolesistektomi+operasyonlar%C4%B1nda+kar%C4%B1n+i%C3%A7i+bas%C4%B1n%C3%A7+art%C4%B1%C5%9F%C4%B1n%C4%B1n+solunum+mekani%C4%9Fi%2C+hemodinami+ve+metabolizma+%C3%BCzerindeki+etkileri.%22+Ok+Meydan%C4%B1+E%C4%9Fitim+ve+Ara%C5%9Ft%C4%B1rma+Hastanesi+Anesteziyoloji+ve+Reanimasyon+Klini%C4%9Fi+Uzmanl%C4%B1k+Tezi+%282008%29.&amp;btnG=</url>
    <description>Gülleroğlu, Aykan, et al. &quot;Laparoskopik kolesistektomi operasyonlarında karın içi basınç artışının solunum mekaniği, hemodinami ve metabolizma üzerindeki etkileri.&quot; Ok Meydanı Eğitim ve Araştırma Hastanesi Anesteziyoloji ve Reanimasyon Kli</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://scholar.google.com/scholar?hl=tr&amp;as_sdt=0%2C5&amp;q=And%C4%B1%C3%A7%2C+K.+D.%2C+N.+G%C3%B6%C4%9F%C3%BC%C5%9F%2C+and+Ay%C5%9Fe+Lafc%C4%B1.+%22Laparoskopik+Kolesistektomi+Ge%C3%A7iren+Hastalarda+Ultrasonografi+E%C5%9Fli%C4%9Finde+Uygulanan+Transversus+Abdominis+Plan+Blo%C4%9Fun+Perioperatif+Analjezi+ve+Hasta+Konforuna+Katk%C4%B1s%C4%B1.%22+%282021%29.&amp;btnG=</url>
    <description>Andıç, K. D., N. Göğüş, and Ayşe Lafcı. &quot;Laparoskopik Kolesistektomi Geçiren Hastalarda Ultrasonografi Eşliğinde Uygulanan Transversus Abdominis Plan Bloğun Perioperatif Analjezi ve Hasta Konforuna Katkısı.&quot; (2021).</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vivier E, Muller M, Putegnat JB, Steyer J, Barrau S, Boissier F, Bourdin G, Mekontso-Dessap A, Levrat A, Pommier C, Thille AW. Inability of Diaphragm Ultrasound to Predict Extubation Failure: A Multicenter Study. Chest. 2019 Jun;155(6):1131-1139. doi: 10.1016/j.chest.2019.03.004. Epub 2019 Mar 23.</citation>
    <PMID>30910636</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>DiNino E, Gartman EJ, Sethi JM, McCool FD. Diaphragm ultrasound as a predictor of successful extubation from mechanical ventilation. Thorax. 2014 May;69(5):423-7. doi: 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2013-204111. Epub 2013 Dec 23.</citation>
    <PMID>24365607</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Dres M, Demoule A. Monitoring diaphragm function in the ICU. Curr Opin Crit Care. 2020 Feb;26(1):18-25. doi: 10.1097/MCC.0000000000000682. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31876624</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Konya City Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yasin Tire, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assoc. Prof. Dr. Yasin Tire</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Laparoscopic Cholecystectomy Operation</keyword>
  <keyword>Diaphragm Thickness</keyword>
  <keyword>Upper Transabdominal Plain Block</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>I plan to make individual participant data (IPD) available to only responsible researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

