<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04995887</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CIP-05 v1.0</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>Protocol No. PPH-05</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04995887</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>RUBY Post-Market Registry on the Jada® System</brief_title>
  <acronym>RUBY</acronym>
  <official_title>RUBY: Treating Abnormal Postpartum Uterine Bleeding or Postpartum Hemorrhage With the Jada® System - A Post-Market Registry</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Alydia Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Alydia Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The RUBY Study is a multicenter, observational, post-market registry designed to collect&#xD;
      observational data on patients treated with the Jada System in the post-market setting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this registry is to collect observational data on patients treated with the&#xD;
      Jada System in the post-market setting. Data collection will include observations of&#xD;
      effectiveness and safety of the device. Additional outcome data related to resource&#xD;
      utilization will also be included.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Efficacy: Cessation of PPH</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with atony-related abnormal postpartum uterine bleeding or PPH successfully treated with the Jada System. Treatment success is defined as the avoidance of escalated non-surgical or surgical intervention to control abnormal postpartum uterine bleeding or PPH after the Jada System was used.&#xD;
Note: Concomitant treatment with uterotonics or uterine compression sutures does not constitute escalation (i.e., failure). However, if the Jada treatment was aborted to instead administer treatment with compression sutures for ongoing bleeding, then the event does meet the escalation (i.e., failure) definition.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety: device-related Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours through time of discharge.</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of procedure- and device-related adverse events.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of non-surgical or surgical procedures other than Jada</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of non-surgical or surgical procedures other than Jada for atony-related bleeding after Jada was used</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Transfusion rates</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours through time of discharge.</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of blood transfusions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In-dwelling time of Jada during treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>In-dwelling time (i.e., insertion of Jada to removal of Jada)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time spent in care settings</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours through time of discharge.</time_frame>
    <description>Time spent in care settings (e.g., L&amp;D, OR, Delivery Room, Postpartum Room, ICU, Other) from Jada treatment through discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours through time of discharge.</time_frame>
    <description>Length of stay (LOS) from delivery to discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1000</enrollment>
  <condition>Postpartum Hemorrhage</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>C-Section Delivery with EBL ≥ 1500 mL</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with ≥ 1500 mL estimated blood loss (EBL) at time of Jada insertion for cesarean delivery; data collection will continue until a minimum of 100 patients are enrolled in each group/category or until March 31, 2022 (whichever occurs first).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>C-Section Delivery with EBL &lt; 1500 mL</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with &lt; 1500 mL EBL at time of Jada insertion for cesarean delivery; data collection will continue until a minimum of 100 patients are enrolled in each group/category or until March 31, 2022 (whichever occurs first).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaginal Delivery with EBL ≥ 1000 mL</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with ≥ 1000 mL EBL at time of Jada insertion for vaginal delivery; data collection will continue until a minimum of 100 patients are enrolled in each group/category or until March 31, 2022 (whichever occurs first).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Vaginal Delivery with EBL &lt; 1000 mL</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with &lt; 1000 mL EBL at time of Jada insertion for vaginal delivery; data collection will continue until a minimum of 100 patients are enrolled in each group/category or until March 31, 2022 (whichever occurs first).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Jada® System</intervention_name>
    <description>The Jada® System is intended to provide control and treatment of abnormal postpartum uterine bleeding or hemorrhage when conservative management is warranted. It is a teardrop-shaped, soft silicone ring that is placed into the uterus, where gentle suction is applied to cause the uterus to contract and shrink in size, compressing the blood vessels so the bleeding stops.</description>
    <arm_group_label>C-Section Delivery with EBL &lt; 1500 mL</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>C-Section Delivery with EBL ≥ 1500 mL</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vaginal Delivery with EBL &lt; 1000 mL</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Vaginal Delivery with EBL ≥ 1000 mL</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Vacuum-induced Hemorrhage Control</other_name>
    <other_name>Obstetric-Gynecologic Specialized Manual Instrument</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients included are all identified through review of the medical charts as having&#xD;
        received Jada treatment starting from the center's first commercial use of the Jada System.&#xD;
        This chart review will be ongoing until the specified date or until a minimum of 100&#xD;
        patients are enrolled in each of the groups described below (whichever occurs first):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. ≥ 1500 mL estimated blood loss (EBL) at time of Jada insertion (C-S)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. &lt; 1500 mL EBL at time of Jada insertion (C-S)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. ≥ 1000 mL EBL at time of Jada insertion (vaginal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. &lt; 1000 mL EBL at time of Jada insertion (vaginal)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Up to a maximum of 50 sites can be included in this registry. Each IRB approval constitutes&#xD;
        a &quot;site.&quot;&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Use of the Jada System (inserted into the patient and connected to vacuum).&#xD;
&#xD;
        NOTE: There is no Exclusion Criteria in this protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Conditions treated occur only in females of childbearing age (i.e., postpartum hemorrhage or abnormal postpartum uterine bleeding).</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dena Goffman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Columbia University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Ohio State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Columbus</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>43210</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gülmezoglu AM, Lawrie TA, Hezelgrave N, Oladapo OT, Souza JP, Gielen M, Lawn JE, Bahl R, Althabe F, Colaci D, Hofmeyr GJ. Interventions to Reduce Maternal and Newborn Morbidity and Mortality. In: Black RE, Laxminarayan R, Temmerman M, Walker N, editors. Reproductive, Maternal, Newborn, and Child Health: Disease Control Priorities, Third Edition (Volume 2). Washington (DC): The International Bank for Reconstruction and Development / The World Bank; 2016 Apr 5. Chapter 7.</citation>
    <PMID>27227224</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Callaghan WM, Kuklina EV, Berg CJ. Trends in postpartum hemorrhage: United States, 1994-2006. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2010 Apr;202(4):353.e1-6. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2010.01.011.</citation>
    <PMID>20350642</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mulic-Lutvica A, Bekuretsion M, Bakos O, Axelsson O. Ultrasonic evaluation of the uterus and uterine cavity after normal, vaginal delivery. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2001 Nov;18(5):491-8. Erratum in: Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2008 Aug;29(8):1215.</citation>
    <PMID>11844171</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Andersen HF, Hopkins MP. Chapter 80: postpartum hemorrhage. In: Sciarra JJ, editor. Gynecology and obstetrics, volume 2. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2004.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lyon DS. Chapter 90: postpartum care. In: Sciarra JJ, editor. Gynecology and obstetrics, volume 2. Philadelphia, PA: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2004.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baskett TF. A flux of the reds: evolution of active management of the third stage of labour. J R Soc Med. 2000 Sep;93(9):489-93.</citation>
    <PMID>11089490</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Main EK, Goffman D, Scavone BM, Low LK, Bingham D, Fontaine PL, Gorlin JB, Lagrew DC, Levy BS; National Partnership for Maternal Safety; Council on Patient Safety in Women's Health Care. National Partnership for Maternal Safety: Consensus Bundle on Obstetric Hemorrhage. Obstet Gynecol. 2015 Jul;126(1):155-62. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000000869. Erratum in: Obstet Gynecol. 2015 Nov;126(5):1111. Obstet Gynecol. 2019 Jun;133(6):1288.</citation>
    <PMID>26241269</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goffman D, Ananth CV, Fleischer A, D'Alton M, Lavery JA, Smiley R, Zielinski K, Chazotte C; Safe Motherhood Initiative Obstetric Hemorrhage Work Group. The New York State Safe Motherhood Initiative: Early Impact of Obstetric Hemorrhage Bundle Implementation. Am J Perinatol. 2019 Nov;36(13):1344-1350. doi: 10.1055/s-0038-1676976. Epub 2019 Jan 4.</citation>
    <PMID>30609429</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shields LE, Smalarz K, Reffigee L, Mugg S, Burdumy TJ, Propst M. Comprehensive maternal hemorrhage protocols improve patient safety and reduce utilization of blood products. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Oct;205(4):368.e1-8. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2011.06.084. Epub 2011 Jun 29.</citation>
    <PMID>22083059</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rossen J, Okland I, Nilsen OB, Eggebø TM. Is there an increase of postpartum hemorrhage, and is severe hemorrhage associated with more frequent use of obstetric interventions? Acta Obstet Gynecol Scand. 2010 Oct;89(10):1248-55. doi: 10.3109/00016349.2010.514324.</citation>
    <PMID>20809871</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Della Torre M, Kilpatrick SJ, Hibbard JU, Simonson L, Scott S, Koch A, Schy D, Geller SE. Assessing preventability for obstetric hemorrhage. Am J Perinatol. 2011 Dec;28(10):753-60. doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1280856. Epub 2011 Jun 22.</citation>
    <PMID>21698554</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists. ACOG Practice Bulletin: Clinical Management Guidelines for Obstetrician-Gynecologists Number 76, October 2006: postpartum hemorrhage. Obstet Gynecol. 2006 Oct;108(4):1039-47.</citation>
    <PMID>17012482</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zelop CM. Postpartum hemorrhage: becoming more evidence-based. Obstet Gynecol. 2011 Jan;117(1):3-5. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0b013e318202ec9a.</citation>
    <PMID>21173639</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Purwosunu Y, Sarkoen W, Arulkumaran S, Segnitz J. Control of Postpartum Hemorrhage Using Vacuum-Induced Uterine Tamponade. Obstet Gynecol. 2016 Jul;128(1):33-36. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000001473.</citation>
    <PMID>27275795</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>D'Alton ME, Rood KM, Smid MC, Simhan HN, Skupski DW, Subramaniam A, Gibson KS, Rosen T, Clark SM, Dudley D, Iqbal SN, Paglia MJ, Duzyj CM, Chien EK, Gibbins KJ, Wine KD, Bentum NAA, Kominiarek MA, Tuuli MG, Goffman D. Intrauterine Vacuum-Induced Hemorrhage-Control Device for Rapid Treatment of Postpartum Hemorrhage. Obstet Gynecol. 2020 Nov;136(5):882-891. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000004138.</citation>
    <PMID>32909970</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 13, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Vacuum-Induced Hemorrhage-Control (VHC)</keyword>
  <keyword>Jada</keyword>
  <keyword>Postpartum Hemorrhage</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Postpartum Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>It is not yet known if there will be a plan to make IPD available.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

