<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04997200</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Version 1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04997200</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Sleep Deprivation on Breathlessness and Exercise Capacity in COPD</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Sleep Deprivation on Breathlessness and Exercise Capacity in COPD: a Randomized Crossover Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Skane University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Blekinge County Council Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Skane University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized controlled cross-over trial designed to measure the effect of one&#xD;
      night's sleep deprivation on exercise endurance, ventilation and breathlessness in&#xD;
      outpatients with COPD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is a major cause of morbidity and mortality in&#xD;
      the world. Breathlessness and exercise limitation are cardinal symptoms in COPD with grave&#xD;
      consequences for the patient. Even with optimal COPD treatment a large number of these&#xD;
      patients experience a breathlessness which limits their everyday life. Physical activity is&#xD;
      the main trigger of breathlessness in daily life, but knowledge is limited on how other&#xD;
      factors may affect exercise performance, breathing and exertional breathlessness in patients&#xD;
      with COPD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sleep deprivation is common in the population in patients with COPD, and especially in&#xD;
      patients with worsening health status and during hospitalizations. As many as 40-45% of&#xD;
      patients older than 70 experience sleep deprivation during hospitalization. As many as 21 %&#xD;
      of patients with COPD have a disturbed sleep. A recent study on healthy young males who&#xD;
      breathed against an inspiratory resistance showed that one night's sleep deprivation&#xD;
      significantly reduced their respiratory endurance and induced worse and more disturbing&#xD;
      breathlessness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Little is known how sleep loss affects patients with COPD in an outpatient setting. Several&#xD;
      studies have evaluated the effect of sleep deprivation on exercise capacity in young healthy&#xD;
      adults. However, very few studies have examined the effect of sleep deprivation on the&#xD;
      exercise capacity or exertional breathlessness in patients with COPD; most data pertain to&#xD;
      observational studies where no intervention took place and data from a randomized controlled&#xD;
      trial (RCT) is needed. The presence of disturbed sleep in patients with COPD - and especially&#xD;
      in relation to worsenings and hospitalizations, could have a marked detrimental effect on&#xD;
      their breathing, increase suffering from distressing breathlessness and potentially increase&#xD;
      the risk of adverse health outcomes and worse prognosis. Directed actions to improve sleeping&#xD;
      in these settings could in that case improve the patients' outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To test the effect of one sleepless night on breathlessness, exercise endurance and&#xD;
      ventilation in patients with COPD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Method:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is a randomized (ratio 1:1), controlled, crossover trial of the effect of one night's&#xD;
      sleep deprivation vs. normal sleep on exercise endurance, ventilation and breathlessness in&#xD;
      outpatients with COPD. The study will not be blinded for participants and staff (due to the&#xD;
      nature of the intervention) but will be blinded for the analyst.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intervention is one night without sleep, and the control is one night with normal sleep.&#xD;
      The test is a bicycle test (exercise test on a bike with continuous analysis of ventilation&#xD;
      and gaseous exchange) carried out as a sub-max test at 75% of maximum capacity until the test&#xD;
      person cannot go on.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study consists of three visits. At the first visit, informed consent is collected, and&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria are evaluated. Also, information is collected regarding the&#xD;
      person's COPD-diagnosis, medication, and other illnesses. Specific surveys are Pittsburgh&#xD;
      Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), COPD Assessment Test (CAT), modified Medical Research Council&#xD;
      (mMRC) scale, 7-point Global Impression of Change (GIC) scale, Experienced sleep quality&#xD;
      (Likert scale), Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile (MDP) to assess the person's sleep and&#xD;
      respiration. Baseline values for dynamic spirometry, saturation, and blood pressure are also&#xD;
      measured during the first visit. Afterwards, a bicycle test is carried out according to&#xD;
      normal clinical standards. This involves increasing the resistance (in Watts) according to a&#xD;
      set protocol until the test person is unable to continue. This takes roughly 6-10 minutes and&#xD;
      provides a maximum performance value for the individual. This maximum value is used for visit&#xD;
      number two and three. After this first visit the order of the sleepless night is randomized&#xD;
      for either visit two or three.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the second and third visit spirometry, saturation and blood pressure are once more&#xD;
      measured. The person is evaluated for contraindications. Then a new bicycle test is carried&#xD;
      out at 75% of the maximum W achieved at the first visit. The test takes around 10 minutes,&#xD;
      and continues until the person is unable to continue. During this test, ventilation is&#xD;
      measured as respiratory rate (RR), minute ventilation (MV), oxygen consumption (VO2), carbon&#xD;
      dioxide consumption (VCO2), the respiratory quotient (VCO2/VO2), inspiratory capacity&#xD;
      manoeuvre (IC), dynamic hyperinflation, ventilatory reserve capacity, ventilation efficiency&#xD;
      (MV/VCO2-curve) and the anaerobic threshold. During the test the person is also assessed for&#xD;
      how difficult the breathing feels (0-19 Borg CR10), how tired the legs feels (Borg CR10), how&#xD;
      uncomfortable the breathing feels (mBorg 0-10) every two minutes and at the end of the test.&#xD;
      At the end of the test the test person is asked about the reason for ending the test, how the&#xD;
      breathing was experienced (Multidimensional Dyspnea Profile, MDP), and how motivated they&#xD;
      were to carry out the test (0-10 NRS). The person is also monitored with EKG during the test,&#xD;
      and the blood pressure is measured every two minutes. The results are then compared between&#xD;
      the test where the person had a normal night's sleep, and the test where the person was awake&#xD;
      the whole night before.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The normal night's sleep is assessed using some simple questions, such as: &quot;How did you sleep&#xD;
      tonight&quot; and &quot;How satisfied are you with the night's sleep?&quot;. It is also evaluated using an&#xD;
      Actigraph bracelet that measures movement when worn. The bracelet is worn for 48 hours&#xD;
      preceding both tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The night when the person is going to be awake is spent at the test lab, after eating a&#xD;
      normal dinner at home. They then spend an entire night in a room where they can watch TV, use&#xD;
      a phone or tablet or read books and magazines. They will be monitored by staff to help them&#xD;
      stay awake during the night. They cannot eat, drink or smoke anything not usually consumed&#xD;
      during the night (other than water). They then eat a normal breakfast of their choosing, and&#xD;
      the test is carried out just like the one where they slept normally.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Performed in randomized order on two separate days, at least seven days apart and no more than six weeks apart.&#xD;
Intervention: A night without sleep. No daytime sleeping the day before the test. Participants are observed by staff at the trial unit during the night before the test.&#xD;
Control: Normal night's sleep (at least six hours of sleep) in the patient's home.&#xD;
The participants wear an actigraph during 48 hours before the test to ensure adherence to the allocated condition (sleep deprivation or control).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>The analyst analyzing the data will be blinded.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in breathlessness intensity (Borg CR10) between control and intervention at iso-time</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention exercise tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Change between conditions in breathlessness intensity using the Borg Category Ratio scale (Borg CR10), where 0 indicates no exertion and 10 indicates maximum exertion, at iso-time (defined as the time of the latest similar time point during both conditions (control and intervention) during a constant rate cycle cardiopulmonary exercise test (CPET).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in breathlessness unpleasantness (Borg CR10) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived unpleasantness from breathlessness, measured with the Borg CR10 scale, where 0 indicates no exertion and 10 indicates maximum exertion. Compared at end exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in time to the limit of tolerance (tLIM) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>For how long the test person can continue the test, measured in seconds.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in oxygen consumption between control and intervention (absolute)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using 7V'O2 (aerobic exercise capacity), in absolute numbers. Compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in oxygen consumption between control and intervention (%pred)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Measured using V'O2, (aerobic exercise capacity), in percent of predicted (%pred). Compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in workload (W) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum workload achieved, measured in Watts, in absolute numbers.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in workload (%pred) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum workload achieved, measured in percent of predicted (%pred).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Minute ventilation (VE) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Minute ventilation is measured and compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in tidal volume (VT) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Tidal volume measured and compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in ventilatory reserve, (MVV) - (VE) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Ventilatory reserve defined as maximum voluntary ventilation (MVV) - (VE). Compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in cardiac reserve between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Cardiac reserve is evaluated using the predicted peak heart rate. Compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in dynamic hyperinflation and inspiratory capacity (IC) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>This includes measures of constrained ventilatory expansion such as the inspiratory reserve volume (IRV). Compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in breathing frequency between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Breathing frequency is measured, and compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in breathlessness intensity at peak exercise (Borg CR10) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived breathlessness intensity at peak exercise is evaluated using the Borg CR10 scale, where 0 indicates no exertion and 10 indicates maximum exertion, and compared between the tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in leg discomfort (Borg CR10) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived leg discomfort is evaluated using the Borg CR10 scale, where 0 indicates no exertion and 10 indicates maximum exertion, and compared between the tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in timing of the anaerobic threshold (AT) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>At the anaerobic threshold, timing is registered, and compared between the tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in V'O2 of the anaerobic threshold (AT) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>At the anaerobic threshold, V'O2 is registered, and compared between the tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in efficacy of ventilation (VE/V'CO2-slope and ratio at the AT) between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>VE/V'CO2-slope and ratio are evaluated at the anaerobic threshold, and compared between the tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in respiratory exchange ratio (RER), defined as V'CO2/V'O2 between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Measured during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Respiratory exchange ratio is calculated using V'CO2/V'O2, and compared between the tests at peak exercise and at iso-time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in causes for stopping the test between control and intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>The test person's reason for discontinuing the test is recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in any adverse events during the control and intervention tests</measure>
    <time_frame>Evaluated during post-control and post-intervention tests, spaced 7 days to 6 weeks apart</time_frame>
    <description>Any adverse events during the tests are recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>COPD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention: One night's sleeplessness</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>A night without sleep. No daytime sleeping the day before the test. Participants are observed by staff at the trial unit during the night before the test.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control: One night's normal sleep</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>A normal night's sleep (at least six hours) in the patient's home.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>One night's sleeplessness</intervention_name>
    <description>A night without sleep. No daytime sleeping the day before the test. Participants are observed by staff at the trial unit during the night before the test.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention: One night's sleeplessness</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: (All required)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COPD diagnosed by physician in accordance with Global Initiative For Chronic&#xD;
             Obstructive Lung Disease (GOLD) guidelines (GOLD 2021), with a spirometric ratio of&#xD;
             the forced expired volume in one second (FEV1) / forced vital capacity (FVC) &lt; 0.7 and&#xD;
             a FEV1 &lt; 80% of predicted post bronchodilator at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Self-reported average sleep time of six hours or longer during a normal night.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No regular treatment with sleep medication or anxiolytics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to cycle&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to talk and write Swedish well enough to participate in the study procedures, as&#xD;
             judged by the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resting peripheral oxygen saturation (SpO2) &lt; 92%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Night shift worker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalization or clinical instability during the last four weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with supplementary oxygen at rest or during exercise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sleep disturbance, defined as a Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index &gt;5 at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to exercise testing in accordance with clinical practice guidelines&#xD;
             (ATS/ACCP Statement on cardiopulmonary exercise testing. Am J Respir Crit Care Med&#xD;
             2003; 167:211-277)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected survival shorter than six months as judged by the Investigator.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Magnus Ekström, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46455731000</phone>
    <email>pmekstrom@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lars Ekman, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+46455731000</phone>
    <email>larsstyrbjorn13@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Clinical Physiology, Blekinge Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Karlskrona</city>
        <state>Blekinge</state>
        <zip>SE-37185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Magnus Ekström, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0046455731000</phone>
      <email>pmekstrom@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Lars Ekman, MD</last_name>
      <phone>0046455731000</phone>
      <email>larsstyrbjorn13@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://goldcopd.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/11/GOLD-REPORT-2021-v1.1-25Nov20_WMV.pdf</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>O'Donnell DE, Banzett RB, Carrieri-Kohlman V, Casaburi R, Davenport PW, Gandevia SC, Gelb AF, Mahler DA, Webb KA. Pathophysiology of dyspnea in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease: a roundtable. Proc Am Thorac Soc. 2007 May;4(2):145-68. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17494725</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Agusti A, Edwards LD, Celli B, Macnee W, Calverley PM, Müllerova H, Lomas DA, Wouters E, Bakke P, Rennard S, Crim C, Miller BE, Coxson HO, Yates JC, Tal-Singer R, Vestbo J; ECLIPSE Investigators. Characteristics, stability and outcomes of the 2011 GOLD COPD groups in the ECLIPSE cohort. Eur Respir J. 2013 Sep;42(3):636-46. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00195212. Epub 2013 Jun 13.</citation>
    <PMID>23766334</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Simon ST, Bausewein C, Schildmann E, Higginson IJ, Magnussen H, Scheve C, Ramsenthaler C. Episodic breathlessness in patients with advanced disease: a systematic review. J Pain Symptom Manage. 2013 Mar;45(3):561-78. doi: 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2012.02.022. Epub 2012 Aug 24. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22921180</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dharmarajan K, Swami S, Gou RY, Jones RN, Inouye SK. Pathway from Delirium to Death: Potential In-Hospital Mediators of Excess Mortality. J Am Geriatr Soc. 2017 May;65(5):1026-1033. doi: 10.1111/jgs.14743. Epub 2016 Dec 30.</citation>
    <PMID>28039852</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rault C, Sangaré A, Diaz V, Ragot S, Frat JP, Raux M, Similowski T, Robert R, Thille AW, Drouot X. Impact of Sleep Deprivation on Respiratory Motor Output and Endurance. A Physiological Study. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2020 Apr 15;201(8):976-983. doi: 10.1164/rccm.201904-0819OC.</citation>
    <PMID>31810378</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chen R, Tian JW, Zhou LQ, Chen X, Yan HY, Zeng B, Zhang MS. The relationship between sleep quality and functional exercise capacity in COPD. Clin Respir J. 2016 Jul;10(4):477-85. doi: 10.1111/crj.12249. Epub 2015 Jan 15.</citation>
    <PMID>25515647</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schulz KF, Altman DG, Moher D; CONSORT Group. CONSORT 2010 statement: updated guidelines for reporting parallel group randomized trials. Ann Intern Med. 2010 Jun 1;152(11):726-32. doi: 10.7326/0003-4819-152-11-201006010-00232. Epub 2010 Mar 24.</citation>
    <PMID>20335313</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hedenström H, Malmberg P, Fridriksson HV. Reference values for lung function tests in men: regression equations with smoking variables. Ups J Med Sci. 1986;91(3):299-310.</citation>
    <PMID>3811032</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Skane University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Magnus Ekström</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, PhD, Associate professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dyspnea</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiration Disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>Respiratory Tract Diseases</keyword>
  <keyword>Signs and Symptoms, Respiratory</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dyspnea</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sleep Deprivation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

