<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04995809</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21_DOG_32</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04995809</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Pelvic Radiotherapy on the Intestinal Microbiome and Metabolome</brief_title>
  <acronym>EPRIMM</acronym>
  <official_title>Investigating the Effect of Pelvic Radiotherapy on the Intestinal Microbiome and Metabolome to Improve the Detection and Management of Gastrointestinal (GI) Toxicity.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Christie NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Liverpool</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Manchester</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Wythenshawe Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Christie NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Eight in ten patients will develop bowel problems during radiotherapy, eg diarrhoea, pain and&#xD;
      incontinence, half will develop difficult long-term bowel problems. It is not known why some&#xD;
      people get bowel problems and others do not and there is no test to predict who will develop&#xD;
      bowel problems following their treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is a link between the changes in the number and type of gut bacteria (the microbiome)&#xD;
      in some bowel conditions and it is possible to test for these different bacteria in a simple&#xD;
      stool sample using genetic testing. Also gut bacteria produce different gases in the stool&#xD;
      called &quot;volatile organic compounds&quot; (VOCs), which can be measured in stool samples. Specific&#xD;
      VOC patterns have been seen in other bowel conditions and small studies suggesting that there&#xD;
      are specific VOC and gut bacteria patterns in the stool of those undergoing pelvic&#xD;
      radiotherapy which may help to identify people who will get difficult bowel problems. Diet&#xD;
      can change the microbiome/VOCs so diet change could improve bowel symptoms after&#xD;
      radiotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators would like to test stool samples of patients with womb, cervix or bladder&#xD;
      cancer having pelvic radiotherapy to see if there are differences in the number/type of gut&#xD;
      bacteria and VOCs between those who get severe bowel symptoms compared to those with mild&#xD;
      bowel symptoms. They also want to see whether these differences in VOCs or gut bacteria can&#xD;
      tell who will develop severe bowel symptoms during or after radiotherapy and determine the&#xD;
      effect of diet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first step is to run the study on a small scale to confirm that a larger study would&#xD;
      work. This will make sure the investigators can recruit and consent people safely and will&#xD;
      test the best ways of measuring bowels symptoms using several questionnaire options. They&#xD;
      will collect the information needed to work out how many people would be needed in a large&#xD;
      trial to fully test the theory. Ultimately, the investigators would like to use differences&#xD;
      in the number/type of gut bacteria and VOCs to find ways to better prevent and treat bowel&#xD;
      problems after pelvic radiotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background 80% of patients develop GI-toxicity during pelvic radiotherapy and half develop&#xD;
      chronic GI-toxicity. This manifests as diarrhoea, pain, bleeding and incontinence. Unlike&#xD;
      many diseases, the triggering event, i.e. radiotherapy, is known, enabling the identification&#xD;
      of specific pathophysiological changes. The metabolomic and microbiomic profile of patients&#xD;
      undergoing pelvic radiotherapy and the link with GI-toxicity has not been fully explored.&#xD;
      Studies suggest radiation alters the gut microbiome, altering microbial diversity. Higher&#xD;
      pre-radiotherapy diversity has been seen in those with no GI symptoms with reducing diversity&#xD;
      as GI-toxicity increases and an association between low microbial diversity and severity of&#xD;
      chronic GI-toxicity. Dietary change can alter microbial composition. Faecal VOCs are&#xD;
      chemicals that exist in the gaseous phase at ambient temperature and form the faecal&#xD;
      metabolome, the result of the interaction between the gut microbiota and cell metabolism.&#xD;
      VOCs can be identified using established techniques and unique VOCs patterns have been&#xD;
      identified in specific GI diseases. Early data suggest differences in VOCs between patients&#xD;
      with high vs low levels of GI-toxicity. Metabolomic and microbiomic profiling and&#xD;
      manipulation has the potential to advance understanding of disease-related pathways to&#xD;
      predict, prevent and treat GI-toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale GI-toxicity is a significant cause of morbidity both during and after pelvic&#xD;
      radiotherapy to the extent that it adversely affects quality of life. There is a paucity of&#xD;
      research into this condition. The metabolomic and microbiomic profile of patients undergoing&#xD;
      pelvic radiotherapy and the link with GI-toxicity has not been fully explored. Studies&#xD;
      suggest radiation alters the gut microbiome, altering microbial diversity. Higher&#xD;
      pre-radiotherapy diversity has been seen in those with no GI symptoms with reducing diversity&#xD;
      as GI-toxicity increases and an association between low microbial diversity and severity of&#xD;
      chronic GI-toxicity. Dietary change can alter microbial composition. Unique VOCs patterns&#xD;
      have been identified in specific GI diseases. Early data suggest differences in VOCs between&#xD;
      patients with high vs low levels of GI-toxicity. Metabolomic and microbiomic profiling and&#xD;
      manipulation has the potential to advance understanding of disease-related pathways to&#xD;
      predict, prevent and treat GI-toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      By comparing samples collected pre and post radiotherapy the investigators aim to identify&#xD;
      potential biomarkers. They are going to integrate metadata indicating a negative GI response&#xD;
      to the therapy, i.e. GI toxicity symptoms from validated questionnaires, with microbial&#xD;
      community data and VOCs data in order to identify markers (VOCs or bacteria) that increase&#xD;
      with symptoms. They will also identify which species make patients more susceptible to&#xD;
      negative outcomes by analysing the community pre-treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous literature using culture based methods showed an increase in E. coli and&#xD;
      Staphylococcus spp. and the investigators will determine whether they can confirm this. In&#xD;
      terms of VOCs, they will look for markers of inflammation, e.g. aldehydes. It has been&#xD;
      proposed that there are similarities between radiation-induced GI-toxicity and IBD,&#xD;
      particularly Crohn's disease, therefore it would be interesting to see whether there is a&#xD;
      similar dysbiosis of the microbial community and VOCs profile to that observed in Crohn's&#xD;
      disease, i.e. whether decreased species diversity, increased Bacteroides species and&#xD;
      Enterobacteriaceae coupled with a decrease in Faecal bacterium are also observed in patients&#xD;
      with severe GI toxicity symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential interventions to modify the gut microbiome, e.g. diet, pre/probiotics, synthetic&#xD;
      faecal microbiota transplantation, are in wide clinical research use currently in other&#xD;
      related clinical areas, e.g. inflammatory bowel disease, and would be the types of&#xD;
      interventions that may be indicated by information from this work and the subsequent&#xD;
      definitive study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives of the subsequent definitive study are as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine the differences in VOC profile/microbiome in patients with the most severe vs&#xD;
           least severe GI-toxicity at 4 weeks and 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Determine the differences in VOC profile/microbiome at baseline in patients who develop&#xD;
           the most severe vs least severe GI-toxicity at 4 weeks and 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Characterise disease-related pathways for GI-toxicity to identify potential therapeutic&#xD;
           targets, including dietary.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 13, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 13, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of recruitment</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Recruitment rates: can we achieve sufficient recruitment to the study? Are patients willing to participate?</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of recruitment</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability of recruitment process to patient cohort measured using internally generated non-validated questionnaire led by the research nurse</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient experience of study</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Experience of the study process by patient cohort measured using internally generated non-validated questionnaire led by the research nurse</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stool sample collection</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Practicality and acceptability of obtaining stool samples for patient cohort measured using internally generated non-validated questionnaire led by the research nurse</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Attrition rates</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of patient leaving the study before completing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reason for attrition</measure>
    <time_frame>18 months</time_frame>
    <description>Reason for patient leaving the study before completing</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of questionnaires/food diaries</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability of questionnaires and food diaries to patient cohort measured using internally generated non-validated questionnaire led by the research nurse</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Completion of information</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients who complete the study eg rate of attrition of patients and rate of missing data items</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of participants required to take part in a larger multicentre trial which will identify microbiome/VOC profiles which confer risk of GI toxicity</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To identify microbiome (diversity or composition) or VOCs profile that confers risk of GI-toxicity and that is associated with participants greater severity of GI-toxicity in response in response to radiotherapy in the acute and chronic phases</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The number of participants required to take part in a larger multicentre trial which will identify potential therapeutic targets from metabolomic and microbiomic profiling</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To use metabolomic and microbiomic profiling to further understand the pathophysiology of GI-toxicity to identify potential therapeutic targets for treatment and/or prevention, including dietary targets</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiome data (DNA reads)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Obtain initial data regarding microbiome (diversity or composition) associated with risk of GI-toxicity and that is associated with greater severity of GI-toxicity in response in response to radiotherapy in the acute and chronic phases</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>VOC profile by solid-phase microextraction followed by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry SPME-GC/MS</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Obtain initial data (peak area/metabolite(VOC)/sample) regarding VOCs profile associated with risk of GI-toxicity and that is associated with greater severity of GI-toxicity in response in response to radiotherapy in the acute and chronic phases.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Metabolomic profiling by SPME-GC/MS</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To use metabolomic profiling to further understand the pathophysiology of GI-toxicity to identify potential therapeutic targets for treatment and/or prevention, including dietary targets</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiomic profiling by bacterial 16S rRNA metabarcoding sequencing</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>To use microbiomic profiling ( data table containing number of reads/species/sample) to further understand the pathophysiology of GI-toxicity to identify potential therapeutic targets for treatment and/or prevention, including dietary targets</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</condition>
  <condition>Endometrial Neoplasms</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>EPRIMM study participants</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Eligible patients will be identified from new patient referrals to oncology clinics for&#xD;
        pelvic radiotherapy to treat cervix, endometrial or bladder cancer&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pelvic radiotherapy-cervix/endometrial/bladder cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to complete questionnaires.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing GI disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abdominopelvic surgery within preceding 4 weeks&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Caroline Henson, MBBS FRCP PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Christie NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wes Dale</last_name>
    <phone>01619187902</phone>
    <email>wes.dale@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Louise James, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>01619182150</phone>
    <email>louise.james22@nhs.net</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Louise James</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <zip>M20 4GJ</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Louise James</last_name>
      <phone>01614468437</phone>
      <email>louise.james22@nhs.net</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wedlake L, Thomas K, McGough C, Andreyev HJ. Small bowel bacterial overgrowth and lactose intolerance during radical pelvic radiotherapy: An observational study. Eur J Cancer. 2008 Oct;44(15):2212-7. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2008.07.018. Epub 2008 Aug 27.</citation>
    <PMID>18760593</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Andreyev J. Gastrointestinal symptoms after pelvic radiotherapy: a new understanding to improve management of symptomatic patients. Lancet Oncol. 2007 Nov;8(11):1007-17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17976611</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gami B, Harrington K, Blake P, Dearnaley D, Tait D, Davies J, Norman AR, Andreyev HJ. How patients manage gastrointestinal symptoms after pelvic radiotherapy. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2003 Nov 15;18(10):987-94.</citation>
    <PMID>14616164</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nam YD, Kim HJ, Seo JG, Kang SW, Bae JW. Impact of pelvic radiotherapy on gut microbiota of gynecological cancer patients revealed by massive pyrosequencing. PLoS One. 2013 Dec 18;8(12):e82659. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0082659. eCollection 2013.</citation>
    <PMID>24367534</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lam V, Moulder JE, Salzman NH, Dubinsky EA, Andersen GL, Baker JE. Intestinal microbiota as novel biomarkers of prior radiation exposure. Radiat Res. 2012 May;177(5):573-83. Epub 2012 Mar 23.</citation>
    <PMID>22439602</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim YS, Kim J, Park SJ. High-throughput 16S rRNA gene sequencing reveals alterations of mouse intestinal microbiota after radiotherapy. Anaerobe. 2015 Jun;33:1-7. doi: 10.1016/j.anaerobe.2015.01.004. Epub 2015 Jan 16.</citation>
    <PMID>25600706</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Manichanh C, Varela E, Martinez C, Antolin M, Llopis M, Doré J, Giralt J, Guarner F, Malagelada JR. The gut microbiota predispose to the pathophysiology of acute postradiotherapy diarrhea. Am J Gastroenterol. 2008 Jul;103(7):1754-61. doi: 10.1111/j.1572-0241.2008.01868.x. Epub 2008 Jun 28.</citation>
    <PMID>18564125</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Goudarzi M, Mak TD, Jacobs JP, Moon BH, Strawn SJ, Braun J, Brenner DJ, Fornace AJ Jr, Li HH. An Integrated Multi-Omic Approach to Assess Radiation Injury on the Host-Microbiome Axis. Radiat Res. 2016 Sep;186(3):219-34. doi: 10.1667/RR14306.1. Epub 2016 Aug 11.</citation>
    <PMID>27512828</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wang A, Ling Z, Yang Z, Kiela PR, Wang T, Wang C, Cao L, Geng F, Shen M, Ran X, Su Y, Cheng T, Wang J. Gut microbial dysbiosis may predict diarrhea and fatigue in patients undergoing pelvic cancer radiotherapy: a pilot study. PLoS One. 2015 May 8;10(5):e0126312. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0126312. eCollection 2015.</citation>
    <PMID>25955845</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reis Ferreira M, Andreyev HJN, Mohammed K, Truelove L, Gowan SM, Li J, Gulliford SL, Marchesi JR, Dearnaley DP. Microbiota- and Radiotherapy-Induced Gastrointestinal Side-Effects (MARS) Study: A Large Pilot Study of the Microbiome in Acute and Late-Radiation Enteropathy. Clin Cancer Res. 2019 Nov 1;25(21):6487-6500. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.CCR-19-0960. Epub 2019 Jul 25.</citation>
    <PMID>31345839</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cui M, Xiao H, Li Y, Zhou L, Zhao S, Luo D, Zheng Q, Dong J, Zhao Y, Zhang X, Zhang J, Lu L, Wang H, Fan S. Faecal microbiota transplantation protects against radiation-induced toxicity. EMBO Mol Med. 2017 Apr;9(4):448-461. doi: 10.15252/emmm.201606932.</citation>
    <PMID>28242755</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>David LA, Maurice CF, Carmody RN, Gootenberg DB, Button JE, Wolfe BE, Ling AV, Devlin AS, Varma Y, Fischbach MA, Biddinger SB, Dutton RJ, Turnbaugh PJ. Diet rapidly and reproducibly alters the human gut microbiome. Nature. 2014 Jan 23;505(7484):559-63. doi: 10.1038/nature12820. Epub 2013 Dec 11.</citation>
    <PMID>24336217</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reade S, Mayor A, Aggio R, Khalid T, Pritchard DM, Ewer AK, et al. Optimisation of Sample Preparation for Direct SPME-GC-MS Analysis of Murine and Human Faecal Volatile Organic Compounds for Metabolomic Studies. J Anal Bioanal Tech. 2014;5(2).</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Xu X, Xu P, Ma C, Tang J, Zhang X. Gut microbiota, host health, and polysaccharides. Biotechnol Adv. 2013 Mar-Apr;31(2):318-37. doi: 10.1016/j.biotechadv.2012.12.009. Epub 2012 Dec 30. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23280014</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hough R, Archer D, Probert C. A comparison of sample preparation methods for extracting volatile organic compounds (VOCs) from equine faeces using HS-SPME. Metabolomics. 2018;14(2):19. doi: 10.1007/s11306-017-1315-7. Epub 2018 Jan 4.</citation>
    <PMID>29367839</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mikami T, Aoki M, Kimura T. The application of mass spectrometry to proteomics and metabolomics in biomarker discovery and drug development. Curr Mol Pharmacol. 2012 Jun;5(2):301-16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22122469</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Probert CS. Role of faecal gas analysis for the diagnosis of IBD. Biochem Soc Trans. 2011 Aug;39(4):1079-80. doi: 10.1042/BST0391079.</citation>
    <PMID>21787351</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Probert CS, Ahmed I, Khalid T, Johnson E, Smith S, Ratcliffe N. Volatile organic compounds as diagnostic biomarkers in gastrointestinal and liver diseases. J Gastrointestin Liver Dis. 2009 Sep;18(3):337-43. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19795029</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Probert CS, Jones PR, Ratcliffe NM. A novel method for rapidly diagnosing the causes of diarrhoea. Gut. 2004 Jan;53(1):58-61.</citation>
    <PMID>14684577</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Covington JA, Wedlake L, Andreyev J, Ouaret N, Thomas MG, Nwokolo CU, Bardhan KD, Arasaradnam RP. The detection of patients at risk of gastrointestinal toxicity during pelvic radiotherapy by electronic nose and FAIMS: a pilot study. Sensors (Basel). 2012 Sep 26;12(10):13002-18. doi: 10.3390/s121013002.</citation>
    <PMID>23201982</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sokol H, Adolph TE. The microbiota: an underestimated actor in radiation-induced lesions? Gut. 2018 Jan;67(1):1-2. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2017-314279. Epub 2017 May 4.</citation>
    <PMID>28473631</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stringer AM, Al-Dasooqi N, Bowen JM, Tan TH, Radzuan M, Logan RM, Mayo B, Keefe DM, Gibson RJ. Biomarkers of chemotherapy-induced diarrhoea: a clinical study of intestinal microbiome alterations, inflammation and circulating matrix metalloproteinases. Support Care Cancer. 2013 Jul;21(7):1843-52. doi: 10.1007/s00520-013-1741-7. Epub 2013 Feb 10.</citation>
    <PMID>23397098</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferreira MR, Muls A, Dearnaley DP, Andreyev HJ. Microbiota and radiation-induced bowel toxicity: lessons from inflammatory bowel disease for the radiation oncologist. Lancet Oncol. 2014 Mar;15(3):e139-47. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(13)70504-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24599929</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pelvic radiotherapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Microbiota</keyword>
  <keyword>Metabolome</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastrointestinal toxicity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Uterine Cervical Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

