<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04993924</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0024-21-ASF</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04993924</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>GnRH Antagonist Pre-treatment in the Early Follicular Phase for Resolution of a Baseline Functional Ovarian Cyst</brief_title>
  <official_title>GnRH Antagonist Pre-treatment in the Early Follicular Phase for Resolution of a Baseline Functional Ovarian Cyst - A Proof-of-concept Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assaf-Harofeh Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assaf-Harofeh Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this study we would like to examine the effect of GnRH antagonist administration at the&#xD;
      beginning of the follicular phase in patient presenting with a simple ovarian cyst 25-50 mm.&#xD;
      The aim of this intervention is to allow a spontaneous regression of the ovarian cyst (if in&#xD;
      nature) while ensuring a pituitary downregulation to prevent the beginning of a leading&#xD;
      follicle recruitment. As previous studies using GnRH antagonist pre-treatment prior to GT&#xD;
      initiation for other purposes demonstrated positive results (including different patient&#xD;
      population) , no deleterious effects are expected.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Reports on the effect of a baseline ovarian cyst on IVF cycle cancellation and outcome are&#xD;
      scare and inconsistent. A cystic structure of the ovary may be functional or non-functional.&#xD;
      Functional ovarian cysts are usually created by disruption of normal ovulation with the&#xD;
      accumulation of intrafollicular fluid. Hormonal dysfunction prior to ovulation results in&#xD;
      expansion of the follicular antrum with serous fluid. These cysts may be more frequent using&#xD;
      Progesterone only contraceptives, Levonogetstrel-containing intrauterine device and following&#xD;
      controlled ovarian stimulation during fertility treatments . Most functional cysts regress&#xD;
      spontaneously within the first few days of menstruation or within the first 1-2 cycles and up&#xD;
      to 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An ovarian cystic structure, even if hormonally inactive, may interfere with ovarian function&#xD;
      during ovulation induction. These cysts may have a mechanical effect by reducing the space&#xD;
      for growing follicles or by impairing ovarian blood supply. This may result in a lower number&#xD;
      of oocytes and poor embryo quality, or utilization of higher doses of gonadotropins(GT) to&#xD;
      reach the same oocyte yield.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Several studies have investigated the outcome of GnRH antagonist supplementation at the&#xD;
      beginning of the menstrual cycle prior to GT stimulation mainly for the purpose of&#xD;
      synchronization of antral follicles preventing a premature follicular recruitment. The&#xD;
      delayed start protocol which combines estradiol priming followed by GnRH antagonist for 7&#xD;
      days at the beginning of menses prior to GT administration to further synchronize antral&#xD;
      follicles improved ovarian response in poor responders and reduced cycle cancellation rate&#xD;
      with no significant effect on pregnancy rates. A preliminary study investigated the effect of&#xD;
      three day administration of GnRH antagonist at the beginning of the follicular phase prior to&#xD;
      GT stimulation in normal responders regardless of baseline hormonal levels and found a trend&#xD;
      towards increase in clinical pregnancy rate, and similar profiles of early embryo&#xD;
      development, compared to standard fixed GnRH antagonist protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receiving an antagonist protocol usually start their stimulation on day 2-3 of&#xD;
      menses. A baseline US and hormonal blood test are performed to determine adequacy of cycle&#xD;
      start.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients presenting with a simple ovarian cyst larger then 25-30 mm in our unit, even in the&#xD;
      presence of normal baseline estradiol levels are deferred to start their treatment in the&#xD;
      following menstrual cycle as these structures may negatively affect treatment outcome. It is&#xD;
      possible that these cystic structures, most being remnants of previous cycle, would have&#xD;
      resolved spontaneously within a few days, but since GT treatment is to be started on the 2-3&#xD;
      day of the cycle to prevent leading follicle recruitment, we cannot wait to find out whether&#xD;
      cyst has resolved and are inclined to postpone treatment to the following menstrual cycle.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study aims: In this study we would like to examine the effect of GnRH antagonist&#xD;
      administration at the beginning of the follicular phase in patient presenting with a simple&#xD;
      ovarian cyst 25-50 mm. The aim of this intervention is to allow a spontaneous regression of&#xD;
      the ovarian cyst (if in nature) while ensuring a pituitary downregulation to prevent the&#xD;
      beginning of a leading follicle recruitment. As previous studies using GnRH antagonist&#xD;
      pre-treatment prior to GT initiation for other purposes demonstrated positive results&#xD;
      (including different patient population) , no deleterious effects are expected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and Methods: This is a proof-of-concept pilot study. Patients will be recruited at&#xD;
      the reproductive medicine unit of Shamir Medical Center, Israel.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population: Patients undergoing controlled ovarian hyper stimulation at the IVF unit,&#xD;
      Shamir medical center. Planned recruitment of 15 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size: This is a proof-of-concept pilot study to evaluate the feasibility and potential&#xD;
      effectiveness of the intervention. A sample size of 15 patients will allow detecting the&#xD;
      potential for use of cycles that would have been cancelled using standard protocols. As the&#xD;
      comparator is mandatory cancellation, i.e. 0% use of cycles, this sample size is sufficient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study protocol:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients treated at the IVF unit at Shamir Medical Center planned for an antagonist cycle&#xD;
      will undergo blood test and US exam at day 2-3 of their menstrual cycle. Patients will be&#xD;
      recruited if a simple ovarian cyst &gt; 25mm and &lt; 50 mm is demonstrated upon US exam in the&#xD;
      presence of E2 &lt; 220 pmol/L. Following the initial US exam in the morning, if a simple cyst&#xD;
      25-50 mm will be demonstrated, the patient will receive a form explaining that her protocol&#xD;
      may be changed according to blood test results with three possible options: 1. Continuation&#xD;
      with the original protocol 2. Cancellation 3. Change in protocol as part of a research if she&#xD;
      agrees to participate. As patients undergo blood draws in the morning, with results available&#xD;
      in the afternoon, the initial recruitment will be performed over the phone with a verbal&#xD;
      informed consent documented in the patients' medical file. A signed informed consent received&#xD;
      at the following clinic visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will receive a verbal explanation over the phone and following consent will start&#xD;
      GnRH antagonist injections [Cetrotide (cetrolix) or Orgalutran (ganirelix) - depending on&#xD;
      their primary prescription] for 3 days by which time a second blood test (for estradiol,&#xD;
      progesterone, LH and FSH) and US exam will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If cyst size has decreased to &lt; 25 mm, and estradiol levels have remained &lt; 220 pmol/L&#xD;
           then GT stimulation will be started according to the original protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If cyst size has decreased in more than 10 mm mm but is still above 25mm, and estradiol&#xD;
           levels have remained &lt; 220 pmol/L additional 3 days treatment with Cetrotide (cetrolix)&#xD;
           or Orgalutran (ganirelix) will be given.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In case of no change/increase, the cycle will be cancelled. The patient will receive&#xD;
           oral contraceptives for 2-3 weeks to time the next cycle and will start a new cycle once&#xD;
           the current cyst resolves. The time to cyst resolution will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When treatment is continued, the remnant of the cystic structure will be separately followed.&#xD;
      Treatment outcomes will be recorded, including the number of follicles on both ovaries,&#xD;
      number of mature oocytes of expected mature oocytes and number of embryos. Cystic outcome (if&#xD;
      aspirated as part of the ovum pickup) will be recorded separately. In patients with a&#xD;
      previous or a subsequent cycle with similar GT dosages, cycle outcomes will be compared to&#xD;
      the cycle with the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks to subjects: No anticipated risks over regular stimulation protocol side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analyses: Descriptive statistics will be used.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cyst resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of participants with a resolution/decrease in size of the cystic structure following GnRH antagonist.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of oocytes retrieved</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>cycle outcome - number of oocytes retrieved, of participants following the administration of the GnRH antagonist</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients which had an oocyte in the aspirated cystic content.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>cystic content</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of cycle outcome - oocyte number compared to a previous/future cycle cycle outcome compared to a previous cycle</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison to a similar cycle of the same patients using similar GT dosages - number of oocytes retrieved.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>IVF</condition>
  <condition>Ovarian Cysts</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Participants</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will start GnRH antagonist injections [Cetrotide (cetrolix) or Orgalutran (ganirelix) - depending on their primary prescription] for 3-6 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cetrorelix Acetate, Ganerelix Acetate</intervention_name>
    <description>3-6 days of 0.25 mg starting on day 2-3 of the menstrual cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Participants</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Antagonist protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Presentation for cycle initiation on day 2-3 of the menstrual cycle with a simple&#xD;
             ovarian cyst &gt;25 mm and &lt; 50mm, and estradiol levels &lt; 220 pmol/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Inability to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Oocyte donor&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Michal Youngster, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972506430111</phone>
    <email>michalyo@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ariel Hourvitz, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972526666063</phone>
    <email>ariel@hourvitz.co.il</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shamir Medical center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Be'er Ya'aqov</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michal youngster, MD</last_name>
      <phone>972-506430111</phone>
      <email>michalyo@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Ariel Hourvitz, MD</last_name>
      <phone>972-526666063</phone>
      <email>ariel@Hourvitz.co.il</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assaf-Harofeh Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Assaf Harofeh MC</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Medical Center</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cysts</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ovarian Cysts</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cetrorelix</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

