<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04993976</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Rec/00980 Wajeeha Sahar</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04993976</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prehabilitation and Coronary Artery Bypass Grafting</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Resistance Training in Mild to Moderate Clinically Frail Patients Awaiting Coronary Artery Bypass Graft.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the effects of Prehabilitation Resistance training on frailty and functional&#xD;
      capacity in mild to moderate clinically frail patients awaiting Coronary Artery Bypass&#xD;
      Grafting) CABG. This study will contribute to describing the effect of resistance training in&#xD;
      mild to moderate frails patients and were directed to be the part of cardiac rehabilitation&#xD;
      and define the effects of cardiac prehabilitation and to check whether the effects of&#xD;
      resistance training or routine training is similar for quality of recovery in mild to&#xD;
      moderate frails patients which undergone CABG.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In literature, Coronary Artery Bypass Graft (CABG) is a form of heart surgery that redirects&#xD;
      blood around clogged arteries to increase blood flow and oxygen to the heart. During CABG&#xD;
      surgery, the surgeon uses a portion of a healthy vessel (either an artery or vein) from the&#xD;
      leg, chest, or arm to create a bypass around the clogged artery. During CABG surgery with&#xD;
      cardiopulmonary bypass, a heart-lung machine artificially maintains circulation blood and&#xD;
      oxygenation while the surgeon operates on the heart. It includes exercise, lifestyle changes,&#xD;
      education, and emotional support. It can help improve patient's health and enable them to&#xD;
      live a more active life after the patient has had a heart attack or heart surgery or if the&#xD;
      patient has long-term heart problems such as heart failure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The time spent waiting for cardiac surgery to be scheduled is a period of great uncertainty&#xD;
      for a patient. There appears to be heightened anxiety regarding the inclusion of physical&#xD;
      activity in this time period, mainly as a result of their current cardiac condition or&#xD;
      diagnosis&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frailty</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It is a scale ranges from 1 (very fit) to 9 (terminally ill). with common cut-off categories classified as non-frail (scores 1-3), vulnerable/ pre-frail (score 4) and frailty (scores 5-9). it is a simple, quick and highly predictive semi-quantitative tool.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Functional capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>It is measured through six minute walk test which is a sub-maximal exercise test used to assess aerobic capacity and endurance. The distance covered over a time of 6 minutes is used as the outcome by which to compare changes in performance capacity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">74</enrollment>
  <condition>Coronary Artery Bypass Graft</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prehabilitation group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Strength training along with warm-up and cool down for 8 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Supervised Standard care plan for 8 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resistant training (Prehabilitation)</intervention_name>
    <description>Resistance training (10-15 repetitions: major muscle groups of upper and lower limbs [eg, shoulder overhead press, biceps curl, knee lift, and quadriceps extension in sitting and hamstrings curl exercises], one to three sets each) for 20-60 minutes five days a week.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prehabilitation group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Active Comparator: Control group</intervention_name>
    <description>Conventional physiotherapy group followed basic pre-operative respiratory physiotherapy including deep breathing exercises, instructions in coughing techniques, mobilization, and active exercises of the upper limbs and thorax. Walk 30 m in the hospital ward.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing elective primary isolated coronary artery bypass grafting,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with double and triple-vessel coronary artery disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mild to moderately frail patients with a clinical frailty score of 5 -6 at the&#xD;
                  time of accepting surgery at the outpatient cardiothoracic surgical clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with musculoskeletal disability and neurological disability affecting&#xD;
             respiratory rate.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient with renal dysfunction requiring dialysis, use of immunosuppressive&#xD;
                  treatments during the 30-day period before surgery,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Left ventricular ejection fraction &lt;30%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  concomitant valve disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patient having dysrhythmias or pacemaker dependent&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Those patients who are severely frail (CFS 7-9)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mehwish Waseem, MSPT(CPPT)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Riphah International University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Imran Amjad, Phd</last_name>
    <phone>03324390125</phone>
    <email>imran.amjad@riphah.edu.pk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faisalabad Institute of Cardiology.</name>
      <address>
        <city>Faisalābad</city>
        <state>Punjab</state>
        <zip>38000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mehwish Waseem, MSPT(CPPT)</last_name>
      <phone>0331-5309015</phone>
      <email>mehwish.waseem@riphah.edu.pk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Wajeeha Sahar, MSPT(CPPT*)</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Afilalo J, Lauck S, Kim DH, Lefèvre T, Piazza N, Lachapelle K, Martucci G, Lamy A, Labinaz M, Peterson MD, Arora RC, Noiseux N, Rassi A, Palacios IF, Généreux P, Lindman BR, Asgar AW, Kim CA, Trnkus A, Morais JA, Langlois Y, Rudski LG, Morin JF, Popma JJ, Webb JG, Perrault LP. Frailty in Older Adults Undergoing Aortic Valve Replacement: The FRAILTY-AVR Study. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017 Aug 8;70(6):689-700. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2017.06.024. Epub 2017 Jul 7.</citation>
    <PMID>28693934</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sepehri A, Beggs T, Hassan A, Rigatto C, Shaw-Daigle C, Tangri N, Arora RC. The impact of frailty on outcomes after cardiac surgery: a systematic review. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2014 Dec;148(6):3110-7. doi: 10.1016/j.jtcvs.2014.07.087. Epub 2014 Aug 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25199821</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stammers AN, Kehler DS, Afilalo J, Avery LJ, Bagshaw SM, Grocott HP, Légaré JF, Logsetty S, Metge C, Nguyen T, Rockwood K, Sareen J, Sawatzky JA, Tangri N, Giacomantonio N, Hassan A, Duhamel TA, Arora RC. Protocol for the PREHAB study-Pre-operative Rehabilitation for reduction of Hospitalization After coronary Bypass and valvular surgery: a randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open. 2015 Mar 9;5(3):e007250. doi: 10.1136/bmjopen-2014-007250.</citation>
    <PMID>25753362</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Afilalo J, Kim S, O'Brien S, Brennan JM, Edwards FH, Mack MJ, McClurken JB, Cleveland JC Jr, Smith PK, Shahian DM, Alexander KP. Gait Speed and Operative Mortality in Older Adults Following Cardiac Surgery. JAMA Cardiol. 2016 Jun 1;1(3):314-21. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2016.0316.</citation>
    <PMID>27438112</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>CABG</keyword>
  <keyword>Fraility</keyword>
  <keyword>Prehabilitation</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

