<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04995575</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EORTC-1550-BCG</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04995575</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Dissecting the Pathways of Therapy Resistance in Early Breast Cancer</brief_title>
  <acronym>MINDACTRelapse</acronym>
  <official_title>Dissecting the Pathways of Therapy Resistance in Early Breast Cancer: A Sub-study of the EORTC 10041/BIG 3-04 MINDACT Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer - EORTC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Within the 1st step MINDACT patients who have already relapsed will be asked to participate.&#xD;
      For these patients a biopsy of the metastasis should have been taken. A molecular analysis of&#xD;
      the stored primary tumor sample and of the metastatic sample, using new technologies, will be&#xD;
      performed, and the characteristics of both samples will be compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within the 2nd step a prospective collection of the metastasis samples will be implemented&#xD;
      and analysis of biological material from relapsing MINDACT patients is foreseen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This process will provide insights on the biology of breast cancer and allow us to better&#xD;
      understand mechanisms of resistance to therapies, contributing to overcoming this important&#xD;
      problem.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of enrolled patients per year with adequate clinicopathologically annotated biological material and clinical data.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after FPI</time_frame>
    <description>Collection of tissue from the first site of relapse or new primary breast cancer, and blood samples for patients still alive that have relapsed (retrospective collection) or will relapse (prospective collection)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease progression</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after FPI</time_frame>
    <description>Characterization of disease progression using molecular characterization of tumour and germline molecular markers in tissue and blood.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment resistance</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years after FPI</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment resistance studies aiming to verify if a given mechanism is responsible for the relapse after exposure to anticancer agents will be performed using molecular characterization of tumour and germline molecular markers in tissue and blood..</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>all MINDACT patients who relapse</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>collection of the biopsy, blood samples</intervention_name>
    <description>for the patients recruited retrospectively collection of biopsy is not considered intervention, as the relapse samples were collected according to standard of care in the participating hospitals.&#xD;
For the prospective collection of samples, the relapsed patients will be asked to donate tissue and blood samples</description>
    <arm_group_label>all MINDACT patients who relapse</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      tumor tissue, whole blood, plasma&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        please see eligibility criteria as this is a 1 cohort study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Retrospective part (part I):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent of agreement for participating in the research project.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have been enrolled in the MINDACT study and received randomized or&#xD;
             non-randomized treatment within the study, of any type and any duration and have&#xD;
             consented for future research or are willing to provide consent for use of the primary&#xD;
             tumour sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a local, regional or distant breast cancer relapse or new primary&#xD;
             breast cancer lesion and have undergone a bioptic/excision procedure of the new, not&#xD;
             previously irradiated, lesion as part of routine clinical practice before initiation&#xD;
             of a subsequent line of systemic treatment (any line).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one Formalin-Fixed Paraffin-embedded (FFPE) tissue block or fresh frozen&#xD;
             tissue (FFT) from the biopsy or from the resection specimen of the relapsed or new&#xD;
             primary disease site, available for translational research purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If blood or normal tissue (e.g. non tumoral) is available in the hospital, it will be&#xD;
             collected as well. For clarity, if normal tissue is not available, patients remain&#xD;
             eligible for the research project but will not be prioritized for the molecular&#xD;
             analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsies of bone lesions are accepted if no other metastatic lesions are available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with brain metastases are accepted if brain-tissue is provided through&#xD;
             surgical excision as part of the routine clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prospective part (part II):&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent of agreement for participating in the research project.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have been enrolled in the MINDACT study and received randomized or&#xD;
             non-randomized treatment within the study, of any type and any duration and have&#xD;
             consented for future research or are willing to provide consent for use of the primary&#xD;
             tumour sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a new diagnosis of local, regional or distant breast cancer relapse&#xD;
             or new primary breast cancer lesion based on physical, radiological and/or laboratory&#xD;
             evaluation and will undergo a biopsy of this new, not previously irradiated, lesion as&#xD;
             part of routine clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The biopsy of the local, regional or distant breast cancer relapse or new primary&#xD;
             breast cancer lesion must be conducted either at the initial diagnosis of the breast&#xD;
             cancer (BC) relapse or at the first disease progression upon any line of systemic&#xD;
             treatment received. Of note, the biopsy of the metastatic lesion must be conducted&#xD;
             before initiation of a subsequent line of systemic treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one FFPE tissue block or FFT from the biopsy or from the resection specimen&#xD;
             of the relapsed or new primary disease site, available for translational research&#xD;
             purposes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsies of bone lesions are accepted if no other metastatic lesions are available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with brain metastases are accepted if brain-tissue is provided through&#xD;
             surgical excision as part of the routine clinical practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) Performance Status 0-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient agrees to provide blood samples at enrolment in research project and at&#xD;
             the time of new disease progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The patient is eligible if she has not received palliative radiotherapy prior to the&#xD;
             biopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who participated in the retrospective part are allowed to participate in the&#xD;
             prospective part as long as there is another new breast cancer lesion (local, regional&#xD;
             or distant relapse or new primary breast tumour) identified which has not been&#xD;
             irradiated previously that will be biopsied by the site. The biopsy and blood draw&#xD;
             should be performed prior to the start of next line of treatment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>EORTC</last_name>
    <phone>+32 2 774 16 97</phone>
    <email>eortc@eortc.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Onze Lieve Vrouw Ziekenhuis</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aalst</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Adelheid Roelstraete, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institut Jules Bordet-Hopital Universitaire ULB</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brussels</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Martine Piccart, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hopital De Jolimont</name>
      <address>
        <city>Haine-Saint-Paul</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carine Mitine, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU-UCL Namur - CHU Site Sainte-Elisabeth-UCL Namur</name>
      <address>
        <city>Namur</city>
        <country>Belgium</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Stephanie A. Henry, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ziekenhuisgroep Twente - Twenteborg Ziekenhuis (3)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Almelo</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>E.A. Kouwenhoven</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Belgium</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 7, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>breast cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>MINDACT</keyword>
  <keyword>relapses</keyword>
  <keyword>metastasis</keyword>
  <keyword>molecular analysis</keyword>
  <keyword>sequencing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Breast Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The access to the data collected within this study, upon study completion could be requested by filling in the request form on EORTC website.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

