<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04991467</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-12561</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01MH126821</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04991467</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multimodal CARES Intervention</brief_title>
  <acronym>CARE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multimodal Parent-focused Intervention for Vulnerable Populations in the Bronx</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Albert Einstein College of Medicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Albert Einstein College of Medicine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      For caregivers in the Bronx, the pandemic has caused unprecedented psychological distress; in&#xD;
      addition to combating social determinants of health (SDOH), these families now face greater&#xD;
      financial insecurity and challenges related to their school-aged children. Furthermore,&#xD;
      social distancing requirements and limited telehealth resources for Bronx families have posed&#xD;
      greater barriers to healthcare. Such parental distress contributes to heightened risk of&#xD;
      transgenerational cycles of psychological stress, trauma and maltreatment. The social and&#xD;
      economic impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic have had significant consequences for family&#xD;
      well-being, putting parents at higher risk of experiencing distress and potentially impairing&#xD;
      their ability to provide supportive care to their children. Although children may be less&#xD;
      susceptible to the most damaging physical consequences of COVID-19, there are growing&#xD;
      concerns regarding the short-and long-term impacts of pandemic-related stressors on children.&#xD;
      The marked upheaval of family life over an extended period may make children vulnerable to&#xD;
      mental health consequences associated with the public health crisis and infection mitigation&#xD;
      efforts. School and childcare closures, unstable financial circumstances, social isolation&#xD;
      and lack of support have a disproportionate, cumulative impact on parents and may undermine&#xD;
      their capacities to provide support for their children. Importantly, a large body of evidence&#xD;
      suggests that parental stress during times of disasters induces psychopathologies in family&#xD;
      members including children. Further, high anxiety and depressive symptoms in parents during&#xD;
      the pandemic have been associated with higher child abuse potential, whereas greater parental&#xD;
      support was associated with lower perceived stress and child abuse potential. In addition to&#xD;
      psychological impacts, stress associated with caregiving can interfere with parents' ability&#xD;
      to maintain their own health. This multimodal study addresses key strategies to mitigate the&#xD;
      psychological and health impact of COVID-19 in parents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Design&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Objectives We hypothesize that both the CARE program and the Valera Health app will&#xD;
           mitigate the psychological effects of COVID-19 while enhancing access to healthcare in&#xD;
           the Bronx. The study will take place at Montefiore Medical Center (MMC), the largest&#xD;
           health system in the Bronx, serving predominantly racial and ethnic minority individuals&#xD;
           from underserved families. We will focus on three vulnerable caregiver cohorts&#xD;
           presenting with moderate stress: a) caregivers of children with psychiatric conditions&#xD;
           (N=130); b) caregivers of children with autoimmune illnesses (N=130); c) caregivers who&#xD;
           are frontline healthcare workers at MMC (N=130). While the latter may have more&#xD;
           favorable SDOH than families treated at MMC, this cohort has faced unprecedented stress&#xD;
           during the pandemic. A RCT (Stage III, NIH model) with 3 arms will test our hypothesis:&#xD;
           a) CARE program alone; b) Valera Health app; c) CARE program and Valera Health app;&#xD;
           Study procedures will include four surveys: at study enrollment, 6-, 12- and 24-weeks&#xD;
           and will assess parental stress (primary outcome), reflective functioning (RF), access&#xD;
           to healthcare, mood and anxiety and additional parent and child clinical measures.&#xD;
           Smartphones and connectivity will be provided as needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Aim 1. To examine the efficacy of the 12-week CARE program on caregivers' emotional&#xD;
           health and RF. Hyp. 1. (a) Compared to the Valera Health app arm at 12- and 24-week&#xD;
           follow-up, participation in the CARE program will result in decreased caregiver's&#xD;
           perceived stress, increased RF, and improved caregiver's mood and anxiety symptoms. (b)&#xD;
           Therapeutic improvements in Hyp. 1a will be mediated by RF, as it reflects mentalizing&#xD;
           capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Aim 2: To examine the efficacy of the 12-week Valera Health app on caregivers' emotional&#xD;
           health and access to healthcare. Hyp. 2. (a), The Valera Health app, will result in&#xD;
           decreased caregiver's perceived stress, increased access to healthcare, and increased&#xD;
           adherence to and engagement in treatment. (b) CARE program + Valera Health app arm will&#xD;
           be superior to CARE or Valera Health app alone on all outcome measures.&#xD;
&#xD;
           Exploratory Aim: (a) We will also explore the effects on outcome of providing technology&#xD;
           and connectivity to families who lack them during the study period. (b) We will explore&#xD;
           the relative effectiveness of our intervention among the 3 vulnerable cohorts. (c) We&#xD;
           will also utilize machine learning approaches to explore complex patterns as predictors&#xD;
           of outcome including COVID-19 illness/deaths, medical comorbidity, psychopathology,&#xD;
           housing, poverty, children's school status, age, family functioning, and trauma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Study Timelines&#xD;
&#xD;
      Individual Subject Timeline:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in this research will last about 24 weeks. Participants will partake in 12 one&#xD;
      hour group sessions that meet once per week. Participants will complete several surveys when&#xD;
      enrolled in the study and then after 6 weeks, after 12 weeks, and after 24 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Overall Timeline:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Because Investigators intend to rely on a pre-existing clinical infrastructure, Investigators&#xD;
      anticipate to be able to begin enrollment within the first six months of the study.&#xD;
      Participants will return for 6-month follow-ups. Data analysis will occur throughout the&#xD;
      duration of the study, along with publications and conference presentations. The likelihood&#xD;
      that this study will be carried out as planned is very high, as all methods and&#xD;
      collaborations are already in place.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>2x2</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Stress</measure>
    <time_frame>week 0</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Stress Questionnaire</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Stress</measure>
    <time_frame>weeks 6</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Stress Questionnaire Change</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Stress</measure>
    <time_frame>week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Stress Questionnaire Change</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Perceived Stress</measure>
    <time_frame>week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Stress Questionnaire Change</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental Reflective Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>week 0</time_frame>
    <description>Parental Reflective Functioning Questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental Reflective Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>week 6</time_frame>
    <description>Parental Reflective Functioning Questionnaire Change</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental Reflective Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Parental Reflective Functioning Questionnaire Change</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parental Reflective Functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>week 24</time_frame>
    <description>Parental Reflective Functioning Questionnaire Change</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">360</enrollment>
  <condition>Parenting</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children receiving mental health treatment at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will either CARE program alone; b) Valera Health app; c) CARE program and Valera Health app .</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children being treated for autoimmune disorders at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will either CARE program alone; b) Valera Health app; c) CARE program and Valera Health app.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare workers at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will either CARE program alone; b) Valera Health app; c) CARE program and Valera Health app.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CARE Program and Valera Application with care manager functionality</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will take part in 12 week CARE program and receive the Valera health application which will provide parent education materials as well as the ability to connect to their child's treatment team via care manager.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children being treated for autoimmune disorders at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children receiving mental health treatment at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Valera Application with care manager functionality</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will receive the Valera health application which will provide parent education materials and the ability to connect to their child's treatment team via care manger.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children being treated for autoimmune disorders at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children receiving mental health treatment at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CARE Program</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will take part in 12 week CARE program.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare workers at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children being treated for autoimmune disorders at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Parents of children receiving mental health treatment at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Valera Application</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will receive the Valera health application which will provide parent education materials.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare workers at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CARE Program and Valera Application</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant will take part in 12 week CARE program and receive the Valera health application which will provide parent education materials.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthcare workers at Montefiore</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All participants will be primary caregivers who present with moderate level of stress&#xD;
             by meeting a severity score of ≥ 14 on the Perceived Stress Scale (PSS22).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Investigators will allow primary caregivers (e.g., grandmothers and aunts) as it is&#xD;
             common in our patient population.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical cohorts will be active patients in the psychiatric and rheumatology clinics&#xD;
             in Montefiore Medical Center (MMC).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Frontline health care providers will be those who are required to work on site at&#xD;
             Montefiore Medical Center (MMC).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious psychiatric or substance use difficulty that, in the judgement of the PI,&#xD;
             would preclude meaningful participation in a parent intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active child abuse/maltreatment cases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neurocognitive conditions that may prevent participants from accessing telehealth&#xD;
             services.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary language other than Spanish or English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Utilized a smartphone health platform similar to the Valera app.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vilma Gabbay, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Albert Einstein College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer Alexander, BA</last_name>
    <phone>929-429-5644</phone>
    <email>jealexan@montefiore.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sherry Simkovic, BA</last_name>
    <phone>718-839-7504</phone>
    <email>sherry.simkovic@einsteinmed.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Albert Einstein College of Medicine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vilma Gabbay</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID</keyword>
  <keyword>Parental Stress</keyword>
  <keyword>Social Determinants of Health</keyword>
  <keyword>Valera</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

