<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04993001</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21.126</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04993001</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of an Open Lung Extubation Strategy on Postoperative Pulmonary Complications</brief_title>
  <official_title>Impact of an Open Lung Extubation Strategy on Postoperative Pulmonary Complications Compared to a Conventional Extubation Strategy: a Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Perioperative respiratory complications are a major source of morbidity and mortality.&#xD;
      Postoperative atelectasis plays a central role in their development. Protective &quot;open lung&quot;&#xD;
      mechanical ventilation aims to minimize the occurrence of atelectasis during the&#xD;
      perioperative period. Randomized controlled studies have been performed comparing various&#xD;
      &quot;open lung&quot; ventilation protocols, but these studies report varying and conflicting effects.&#xD;
      The interpretation of these studies is complicated by the absence of imagery supporting the&#xD;
      pulmonary impact associated with the use of different ventilation strategies. Imaging studies&#xD;
      suggest that the gain in pulmonary gas content in &quot;open lung&quot; ventilation regimens disappears&#xD;
      within minutes after the extubation. Thus, the potential benefits of open-lung ventilation&#xD;
      appear to be lost if, at the time of extubation, no measures are used to keep the lungs well&#xD;
      aerated. Recent expert recommendations on good mechanical ventilation practices in the&#xD;
      operating room conclude that there is actually no quality study on extubation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Extubation is a very common practice for anesthesiologists as part of their daily clinical&#xD;
      practice. It is therefore imperative to generate evidence on good clinical practice during&#xD;
      anesthetic emergence in order to potentially identify an effective extubation strategy to&#xD;
      reduce postoperative pulmonary complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to establish the feasibility of a multicenter randomized controlled&#xD;
      clinical trial comparing two clinical strategies called &quot;open lung&quot; and &quot;conventional&quot; during&#xD;
      extubation. The investigators also aim to estimate the rates of postoperative pulmonary&#xD;
      complications in the two intervention groups and verify the hypothesis that the &quot;open lung&quot;&#xD;
      extubation strategy improves postoperative lung aeration as measured by the quantitative Lung&#xD;
      Ultrasound Score compared to a conventional extubation strategy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      A pilot, prospective, randomized and controlled triple-blind study. Sixty-nine patients&#xD;
      scheduled to undergo elective surgery at the CHUM and at moderate or high risk of&#xD;
      postoperative pulmonary complications according to the ARISCAT score will be recruited.&#xD;
      Following the administration of standardized mechanical ventilation and after obtaining&#xD;
      consent, participants will be randomly assigned to two groups: Intervention group, &quot;open&#xD;
      lung&quot; extubation strategy and Control group, &quot;conventional&quot; extubation strategy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Pilot, single-center, randomized, triple-blind controlled study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Protocol adherence rate</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of the surgery</time_frame>
    <description>During emergence from general anesthesia, a research assistant will observe the adherence to the protocol. The adherence rate will be defined as the number of extubations performed according to the protocol and the patient assigned group divided by the total number of awakenings. In the event of a breach of the protocol, the specific elements that led to the deviation will be noted as well as the reasons given by the treating anesthesiologist to justify it.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of eligible patients per week</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of consent to participate in the protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of missing values</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated baseline rates of postoperative respiratory complications in the two intervention groups</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days following the patient enters the recovery room</time_frame>
    <description>Postoperative pulmonary complications will be defined using the definition recommended by the StEP group. These will be compiled from the patient's arrival in the recovery room until the 7th postoperative day or, if earlier, until discharge from hospital. Adjudication of complications will be performed by 2 investigators blinded to the treatment group. Any disagreement will be resolved by discussion between the two reviewers.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of pulmonary aeration using the qLUS score in the two intervention groups</measure>
    <time_frame>15 minutes after the patient enters the recovery room</time_frame>
    <description>A lung ultrasound will be performed on each patient during pre-emergence preparations and 15 minutes after the patient arrives in the recovery room. The quantitative Lung Ultrasound Score will be calculated for each ultrasound examination. The physician performing the ultrasound examinations will be kept blind from the intervention group.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Re-intubation rate in the operating room</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of the surgery</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">69</enrollment>
  <condition>Anesthesia</condition>
  <condition>Pulmonary Atelectasis</condition>
  <condition>Complication of Anesthesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Emergence from general anesthesia with an open lung extubation strategy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Emergence from general anesthesia with a conventional extubation strategy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Open lung extubation</intervention_name>
    <description>Before starting emergence from anesthesia, the patient will be transferred to their hospital bed or stretcher and seated at 30 degrees. Secretions from the patients' oropharynx will be suctioned. To prevent the patient from coughing, the anesthetic gas or intravenous agent will be stopped after the transfer and suction procedure are completed. The FiO2 will be maintained at the same level or increased to 50% (minimum FiO2) with a fresh gas flow rate greater than or equal to 10 L.min-1. The ventilation mode will be changed to pressure support. The level of pressure support will be modified by the anesthesiologist to generate the same volumes as with controlled ventilation. The PEEP will be maintained at the same level. The minimum respiratory rate will be reduced by 4 min-1. The inspiratory flow for triggering will be 2 L.min-1.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emergence from general anesthesia with an open lung extubation strategy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conventional extubation</intervention_name>
    <description>Before starting emergence from anesthesia, the patient will be transferred to his hospital bed or stretcher and kept in the supine position. Secretions from the patients' oropharynx will be suctioned. To prevent the patient from coughing, the anesthetic gas or intravenous agent will be stopped after the transfer and suction procedure are completed. The FiO2 will be increased to 100% with a fresh gas flow rate greater than or equal to 10 L.min-1. The ventilator will be stopped with the APL valve open to atmosphere. The patient will be manually ventilated with the reservoir bag until spontaneous ventilation resumes. Then, the patient may be manually assisted if the treating anesthesiologist deems it necessary.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emergence from general anesthesia with a conventional extubation strategy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients over 18 years of age requiring elective surgery under general anesthesia and&#xD;
             hospitalization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a moderate or high risk of postoperative pulmonary complication&#xD;
             according to the ARISCAT score (score of 26 or more)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected or known difficult intubation according to the treating anesthesiologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Postoperative mechanical ventilation (planned or unplanned)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neuromuscular disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intrathoracic surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Respiratory failure, sepsis or mechanical ventilation in the month preceding&#xD;
             anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient refusal&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ultrasound sub-study:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Body mass index greater than 40 kg.m-2&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Extensive postoperative chest dressings&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinician's refusal to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Martin Girard, MD, FRCPC</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Martin Girard, MD, FRCPC</last_name>
    <phone>5148908000</phone>
    <phone_ext>12132</phone_ext>
    <email>martin.girard@umontreal.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Monique Ruel, RN</last_name>
    <phone>5148908000</phone>
    <phone_ext>12171</phone_ext>
    <email>monique.m.ruel.chum@ssss.gouv.qc.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre hospitalier de l'Université de Montréal (CHUM)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montréal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H2X 3E4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Monique Ruel, RN</last_name>
      <phone>5148908000</phone>
      <phone_ext>12171</phone_ext>
      <email>monique.m.ruel.chum@ssss.gouv.qc.ca</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Julie Desroches, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>5148908000</phone>
      <phone_ext>12172</phone_ext>
      <email>julie.desroches.chum@ssss.gouv.qc.ca</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Martin Girard, MD, FRCPC</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Open lung extubation strategy</keyword>
  <keyword>Postoperative pulmonary complications</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Atelectasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

