<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04994340</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020/01/007</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04994340</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Physical Activity Observatory of Castilla-La Mancha</brief_title>
  <acronym>OBAFIT</acronym>
  <official_title>Physical Activity Observatory of Castilla-La Mancha</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Castilla-La Mancha</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Consejería de Educación, Cultura y Deportes de Castilla-La Mancha</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dirección General de Juventud y Deportes de Castilla-La Mancha</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Castilla-La Mancha</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The OBAFIT project aims to examine the patterns of physical activity, sedentary activity and&#xD;
      health-related physical fitness of the boys and girls enrolled in schools of Primary&#xD;
      Education and Secondary Education in Castilla-La Mancha (Spain). The design of the project is&#xD;
      observational/cross-sectional. Through an epidemiological orientation, it proposes a&#xD;
      representative sampling of a multistage type of the Castilian-La Mancha population aged 6 to&#xD;
      16 years. The subjects that will make up the sample will be selected from among the 724&#xD;
      Castilian-La Mancha schools with teachings in the Primary Education stage, and among 373&#xD;
      Secondary Education schools. To ensure the heterogeneity of the population, both public and&#xD;
      private centers will be selected, and proportionally between centers that have Healthy School&#xD;
      Programs (PES) from those that do not. The sample will be multistage, randomized and&#xD;
      stratified according to province (Albacete, Ciudad Real, Cuenca, Guadalajara and Toledo),&#xD;
      area (urban, semi-urban, rural), sex (men, women) and age (one group for each age group).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The OBAFIT project was designed to provide a public tool where PA habits, sedentary behaviors&#xD;
      and the health-related physical fitness of school children from Castilla-La Mancha (a Spanish&#xD;
      region) could be visualized. OBAFIT also allows physical education teachers at participating&#xD;
      schools to monitor and observe the evolution of these variables in their students.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this, the schooling data provided by the Consejería de Educación, Cultura y Deportes de&#xD;
      la Junta de Comunidades de Castilla-La Mancha (Ministry of Education, Culture and Sports of&#xD;
      the Community Board of Castilla-La Mancha) are considered: the population enrolled in the&#xD;
      region from the first to the sixth year of Primary Education amounts to 131,903 students&#xD;
      (63,488 girls; 68,415 boys) distributed in the five provinces (Albacete 24,143; Ciudad Real&#xD;
      31,053; Cuenca 11,001; Guadalajara 17,560; Toledo 48,146) both in public (106,366) and&#xD;
      private (25,537) schools.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the case of Secondary Education and the first year of high school, the number of students&#xD;
      stands at 98,745 (50,807 men and 49,267 women) from the five provinces of the region&#xD;
      (Albacete 19,016; Ciudad Real 23,599; Cuenca 8,971; Guadalajara 12,827; Toledo 34,332) of&#xD;
      public centers (80,996) and private (19,078).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size, calculated through the Edidat 4.2 software, is 631 subjects for the Primary&#xD;
      sample and 631 for the Secondary sample (assuming normal distribution). A confidence level of&#xD;
      95% and a margin of error of 3% have been considered, and the CVR associated with low CRC&#xD;
      with a prevalence of 18% is assumed as the parameter of greater variance. If the same level&#xD;
      of confidence and margin of error for both sexes are considered, the sample would amount to&#xD;
      1,262 for each educational level. Assuming a non-response rate of 30%, the final sample size&#xD;
      is estimated at 1640 students in Primary Education and 1640 for Secondary Education.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participants that will make up the sample will be selected from the 724 Castilian-La&#xD;
      Mancha schools with education in the Primary Education stage, and from 373 Secondary&#xD;
      Education centers. Both public and private centers will be selected. The sample will be&#xD;
      multistage, randomized and stratified according to province (Albacete, Ciudad Real, Cuenca,&#xD;
      Guadalajara and Toledo), area (urban, semi-urban, rural), gender (men, women) and age (one&#xD;
      group for each section of age).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the sample size has been determined, a lottery of schools classified based on the&#xD;
      aforementioned criteria is carried out, considering in all cases the proportionality in the&#xD;
      number of students. For this, a multistage method with proportional probability will be used&#xD;
      using SPSS 24.0 software. Approximately 48 centers for Primary Education and 55 for Secondary&#xD;
      Education will be selected, taking into account that there are 6 Primary courses and 4 in&#xD;
      E.S.O. (Spanish system) in addition to 1st year of high school In the selected schools, three&#xD;
      boys and three girls will be randomly chosen per group-class and level, on which the&#xD;
      different instruments will be applied. A priori, due to pedagogical and operational issues in&#xD;
      the administration, proportional age preselection will not be carried out (for the same&#xD;
      group-class). Since all students in the same class-group will have the same probability of&#xD;
      being selected, the age and sex quotas will be corrected at the end of data collection by a&#xD;
      weighting system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 8, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 23, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 23, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Subjective physical activity levels</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Physical activity assessed by self-report (PAQ-C or PAQ-A). The scales ranged from 0 to 5, where higher values indicate greater levels of physical activity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Device-measured physical activity levels</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Physical activity assessed by accelerometer (Measure carried out only in those schools that give consent)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sedentary behavior</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Sedentary behavior assessed by self-report (YLSBQ)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sedentary behavior</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Adolescents' sedentary behaviors assessed by self-report (ASAQ)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Health-related physical fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related physical fitness assessed by the ALPHA-FITNESS test battery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Socioeconomic status</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Socioeconomic status assessed by the Family Affluence Scale III. The scale ranged from 0 to 13, where higher values indicate a greater socioeconomic status.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Age</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Age assessed by self-report</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Gender</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Gender assessed by self-report</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Body mass index</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Body mass calculated through height and weight measurements</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Type of school</measure>
    <time_frame>2017/2018 to 2021/2022</time_frame>
    <description>Public/private schools or urban/semirural/rural schools extracted from the registry of Castilla-La Mancha</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3280</enrollment>
  <condition>Sedentary Behavior</condition>
  <condition>Exercise</condition>
  <condition>Physical Fitness</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Children</arm_group_label>
    <description>From a cross-sectional perspective, children will fill out questionnaires related to their subjective physical activity levels (PAQ-C), levels of sedentary activity (YLSBQ), and socio-economic status (Family Affluence Scale III) during school hours. Two sessions of physical education will be used to measure the health-related physical fitness of children through the ALPHA-Fitness battery test. The sequence to administer this battery will be: 1. Weight and height (BMI); 2. Waist circumference; 3. Skin folds; 4. Hand grip strength, long jump with feet together, and 4x10 m shuttle run test (these tests could be carried out alternately or simultaneously since there will always be 2 or more evaluators); 5. 20 m Course Navette test.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adolescents</arm_group_label>
    <description>From a cross-sectional perspective, adolescents will fill out questionnaires related to their subjective physical activity levels (PAQ-A), levels of sedentary activity (YLSBQ), and socio-economic status (Family Affluence Scale III) during school hours. Two sessions of physical education will be used to measure the health-related physical fitness of adolescents through the ALPHA-Fitness battery test. The sequence to administer this battery will be: 1. Weight and height (BMI); 2. Waist circumference; 3. Skin folds; 4. Hand grip strength, long jump with feet together, and 4x10 m shuttle run test (these tests could be carried out alternately or simultaneously since there will always be 2 or more evaluators); 5. 20 m Course Navette test.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Boys and girls aged 6 to 16 years enrolled in Primary and Secondary Education schools in&#xD;
        Castilla La Mancha.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Be enrolled in any school in Castilla-La Mancha (primary or secondary, public or private,&#xD;
        rural or urban).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Temporary injury or disability that prevents physical testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical diagnosis of diabetes or diseases not related to nutrition.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Javier Valenciano, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Castilla-La Mancha</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan Gregorio Fernández-Bustos, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Castilla-La Mancha</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Javier Valenciano, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>925268800</phone>
    <phone_ext>+34</phone_ext>
    <email>javier.valenciano@uclm.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alejandro Jiménez-Loaisa, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>648622088</phone>
    <phone_ext>+34</phone_ext>
    <email>alejandro.jloaisa@uclm.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universidad Castilla-La Mancha</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toledo</city>
        <zip>45004</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Javier Valenciano, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>925268800</phone>
      <phone_ext>+34</phone_ext>
      <email>javier.valenciano@uclm.es</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alejandro Jiménez-Loaisa</last_name>
      <phone>648622088</phone>
      <phone_ext>+34</phone_ext>
      <email>alejandro.jloaisa@uclm.es</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://obafi.es/</url>
    <description>OBAFIT website</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Poitras VJ, Gray CE, Borghese MM, Carson V, Chaput JP, Janssen I, Katzmarzyk PT, Pate RR, Connor Gorber S, Kho ME, Sampson M, Tremblay MS. Systematic review of the relationships between objectively measured physical activity and health indicators in school-aged children and youth. Appl Physiol Nutr Metab. 2016 Jun;41(6 Suppl 3):S197-239. doi: 10.1139/apnm-2015-0663. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27306431</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Biddle SJ, Gorely T, Pearson N, Bull FC. An assessment of self-reported physical activity instruments in young people for population surveillance: Project ALPHA. Int J Behav Nutr Phys Act. 2011 Jan 2;8:1. doi: 10.1186/1479-5868-8-1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21194492</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Benítez-Porres J, López-Fernández I, Raya JF, Álvarez Carnero S, Alvero-Cruz JR, Álvarez Carnero E. Reliability and Validity of the PAQ-C Questionnaire to Assess Physical Activity in Children. J Sch Health. 2016 Sep;86(9):677-85. doi: 10.1111/josh.12418.</citation>
    <PMID>27492937</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cain KL, Sallis JF, Conway TL, Van Dyck D, Calhoon L. Using accelerometers in youth physical activity studies: a review of methods. J Phys Act Health. 2013 Mar;10(3):437-50. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23620392</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hidding LM, Chinapaw MJM, van Poppel MNM, Mokkink LB, Altenburg TM. An Updated Systematic Review of Childhood Physical Activity Questionnaires. Sports Med. 2018 Dec;48(12):2797-2842. doi: 10.1007/s40279-018-0987-0.</citation>
    <PMID>30298479</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ortega FB, Ruiz JR, Castillo MJ, Moreno LA, González-Gross M, Wärnberg J, Gutiérrez A; Grupo AVENA. [Low level of physical fitness in Spanish adolescents. Relevance for future cardiovascular health (AVENA study)]. Rev Esp Cardiol. 2005 Aug;58(8):898-909. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>16053823</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ruiz JR, España Romero V, Castro Piñero J, Artero EG, Ortega FB, Cuenca García M, Jiménez Pavón D, Chillón P, Girela Rejón MJ, Mora J, Gutiérrez A, Suni J, Sjöstrom M, Castillo MJ. [ALPHA-fitness test battery: health-related field-based fitness tests assessment in children and adolescents]. Nutr Hosp. 2011 Nov-Dec;26(6):1210-4. doi: 10.1590/S0212-16112011000600003. Spanish.</citation>
    <PMID>22411362</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marasso D, Lupo C, Collura S, Rainoldi A, Brustio PR. Subjective versus Objective Measure of Physical Activity: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of the Convergent Validity of the Physical Activity Questionnaire for Children (PAQ-C). Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2021 Mar 25;18(7). pii: 3413. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18073413. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33806106</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Castilla-La Mancha</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Javier Valenciano</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Childhood</keyword>
  <keyword>Physical activity</keyword>
  <keyword>Health</keyword>
  <keyword>School</keyword>
  <keyword>Surveillance</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

