<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04998240</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IVI-ECOVA-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04998240</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mix and Match Heterologous Prime-Boost Study Using Approved COVID-19 Vaccines in Mozambique</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Observer-blind, Randomized Study to Assess the Safety and Immunogenicity of Heterologous Prime-boost COVID-19 Vaccines Regimens in Healthy Adults Aged 18 to 65 Years in Mozambique</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>International Vaccine Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Instituto Nacional de Saúde (INS), Mozambique</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Antananarivo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>International Centre for Diarrhoeal Disease Research, Bangladesh</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Harvard University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Heidelberg University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>International Vaccine Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an observer-blind, randomized study which aims to assess the immune response and the&#xD;
      safety of two different approved vaccines for first and second dose in healthy adults in&#xD;
      Mozambique.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a phase 2, observer-blind, randomized study to assess the safety and the&#xD;
      immunogenicity of heterologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens in healthy adults aged&#xD;
      18 to 65 years in Mozambique using two approved vaccines (BBIBP-CorV and AZD1222). AZD1222 is&#xD;
      the first option as second vaccine to be used in this study. However, this may be subject to&#xD;
      replacement by another approved COVID-19 vaccine according to its availability for trial&#xD;
      purpose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will consist of 2 cohorts, one for main immunology endpoints (N=260, 65 per study&#xD;
      arm) and one for more detailed immunological assessment (N=100, 25 per study arm). Two doses&#xD;
      of vaccine will be administered intramuscularly 4 week apart. All the study participants will&#xD;
      be follow-up for 12 months from the administration of first vaccine dose&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The randomization of study participants will be stratified into two cohorts including the general and immunology subset cohorts. The general cohort (N=260) for main immunology endpoints will be randomized in 1:1:1:1 ratio to the following arms: Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (GA1), Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GA2), Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GB1) and Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (GB2). The participants in the immunology subset cohort (n=100) will be randomized in 1:1:1:1 ratio to the following arms: Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (SA1), Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SA2), Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SB1), and Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (SB2). This immunology cohort will enable to further characterize the cellular and humoral immune response.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>This is an observer-blind study. So in this study only the outcome assessors should be blinded namely the clinical staff in charge of the clinical outcomes assessment and the laboratory analysts.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers (GMTs) of anti-SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies</measure>
    <time_frame>Four Weeks after second dose</time_frame>
    <description>Geometric Mean Titers (GMTs) of anti-SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies using a neutralization assay four weeks after the second dose, in COVID-19 seronegative participants following immunization with heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of SAEs and AESI observed at any time point during the entire study period</measure>
    <time_frame>Till 12 months follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of SAEs and AESI observed at any time point during the entire study period, among all study participants of heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of solicited reactions within 7 days (local reactions) and 14 days (systemic reactions)</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 7 days (local reactions) and 14 days (systemic reactions) following each vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of solicited reactions within 7 days (local reactions) and 14 days (systemic reactions) following each vaccination in all study participants of heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of unsolicited adverse events that are within 28 days after each vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 28 days after each vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of unsolicited adverse events that are within 28 days after each vaccination in all study participants of heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of changes in laboratory safety measures from baseline to day 28 after each vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 28 days after each vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of changes in laboratory safety measures from baseline to day 28 after each vaccination, in all study participants of heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers (GMTs) and Geometric Mean Fold Rise (GMFR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Till 12 months follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>GMTs of anti-SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies as measured by neutralization assay at Day 0, Day 28, Day 196, Day 364&#xD;
GMFR from baseline of anti-SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies as measured by neutralization assay at Day 0, Day 28, Day 196, Day 364&#xD;
Percentage of participants achieving 4-fold or more rise from baseline of anti-SARS-CoV-2 neutralizing antibodies as measured by neutralization assay at Day 0, Day 28, Day 196, Day 364</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Geometric Mean Titers (GMTs) and Geometric Mean Fold Rise (GMFR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Till 12 months follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>GMTs of anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-spike IgG as measured by Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA), anti-SARS-CoV-2 pseudoneutralizing antibodies as measured by pseudo-neutralization assay, and anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-nucleocapsid IgG at Day 0, Day 28, Day 56, Day 196, Day 364&#xD;
GMFR from baseline of anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-spike IgG as measured by Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA), anti-SARS-CoV-2 pseudo-neutralizing antibodies as measured by pseudo-neutralization assay, and anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-nucleocapsid IgG at Day 0, Day 28, Day 56, Day 196, Day 364&#xD;
Percentage of participants achieving 4-fold or more rise from baseline for anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-spike IgG as measured by Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay (ELISA), anti-SARS-CoV-2 pseudoneutralizing antibodies as measured by pseudo-neutralization assay, and anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-nucleocapsid IgG at Day 0, Day 28, Day 56, Day 196, Day 364</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Cellular immune responses against SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>Till 12 months follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>Cellular immune responses against SARS-CoV-2 by ELISpot and by Intracellular Cytokine Staining (ICS) (Th1/Th2) at days 0, 14, 28, 42, 56, 196, 364, following immunization with heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens, in the participants of immunology cohort.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>GMTs, GMFR from baseline</measure>
    <time_frame>Till 12 months follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>GMTs of anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-spike IgG, anti-nucleocapsid IgG against SARS-CoV-2, nAbs and pnAbs against SARS-CoV-2, cellular immune response against SARS-CoV-2, post prime or boost dose, and within one week in all participants being found to be SARS-CoV-2 positive by testing.&#xD;
GMFR from baseline of anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-spike IgG, anti-nucleocapsid IgG against SARS-CoV-2, nAbs and pnAbs against SARS-CoV-2, cellular immune response against SARS-CoV-2, post prime or boost dose, and within one week in all participants being found to be SARS-CoV-2 positive by testing.&#xD;
Percentage of participants achieving 4-fold or more rise from baseline for anti-SARS-CoV-2 anti-spike IgG, anti-nucleocapsid IgG against SARS-CoV-2, nAbs and pnAbs against SARS-CoV-2, cellular immune response against SARS-CoV-2, post prime or boost dose, and within one week in all participants being found to be SARS-CoV-2 positive by testing.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Genome sequencing of SARS-CoV-2 viruses isolated post prime or booster dose</measure>
    <time_frame>Within one week of diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection</time_frame>
    <description>Genome sequencing of SARS-CoV-2 viruses isolated post prime or boost, within one week of diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection, in all study participants of heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Profile of vaccine-induced humoral response against SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>Till 12 months follow-up visit</time_frame>
    <description>Profile of vaccine-induced humoral response against SARS-CoV-2 using systems serology at days 0, 14, 28, 42, 196, 364, in study participants of immunology cohort, following immunization with heterologous and homologous prime-boost COVID-19 vaccines regimens.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>8</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">360</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (GA1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In general cohort (N=260), the randomization of study participants will be stratified into two cohorts in which the first arm will receive Prime BBIBP-CorV vaccine followed by Booster dose of AZD1222 vaccine (GA1)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GA2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In general cohort (N=260), the randomization of study participants will be stratified into two cohorts in which the second arm will receive Prime BBIBP-CorV vaccine followed by Booster dose of BBIBP-CorV vaccine (GA2)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GB1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In general cohort (N=260), the randomization of study participants will be stratified into two cohorts in which the third arm will receive Prime AZD1222 vaccine followed by Booster dose of BBIBP-CorV vaccine (GB1)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (GB2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In general cohort (N=260), the randomization of study participants will be stratified into two cohorts in which the fourth arm will receive Prime AZD1222 vaccine followed by Booster dose of AZD1222 vaccine (GB2)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (SA1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the immunology subset cohort (n=100), participants will receive Prime BBIBP-CorV vaccine followed by Booster dose of AZD1222 vaccine (SA1)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SA2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the immunology subset cohort (n=100), participants will receive Prime BBIBP-CorV vaccine followed by Booster dose of BBIBP-CorV vaccine (SA2)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SB1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the immunology subset cohort (n=100), participants will receive Prime AZD1222 vaccine followed by Booster dose of BBIBP-CorV vaccine (SB1)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (SB2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the immunology subset cohort (n=100), participants will receive Prime AZD1222 vaccine followed by Booster dose of Boost AZD1222 vaccine (SB2)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BBIBP-CorV - Inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccine (Vero cell)</intervention_name>
    <description>The Inactivated SARS-CoV-2 vaccine (Vero cell)- BBIBP-CorV manufactured by Beijing Institute of Biological Products (BIBP), China National Biotec Group (CNBG), Sinopharm, Beijing, People's Republic of China&#xD;
Dose formulation: A liquid formulation containing 4μg total protein with aluminum hydroxide adjuvant (0·45 mg/mL) per 0·5 mL (2-dose schedule followed by a booster dose).&#xD;
Mode of Administration:&#xD;
Intramuscular&#xD;
Storage Conditions: 2 to 8' C</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (GB2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (SB2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GB1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SB1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (GA1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (SA1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GA2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SA2)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AZD1222 (replication-deficient Ad type 5 vector expressing full-length spike protein)</intervention_name>
    <description>AZD1222 (replication-deficient Ad type 5 vector expressing full-length spike protein), manufactured by Oxford University-AstraZeneca in United Kingdom&#xD;
Dose formulation: One dose (0.5ml) contains 5 x 1010 ChAdOx1-S (recombinant) viral particles. .&#xD;
Mode of administration: Intramuscular&#xD;
Storage Conditions: 2 to 8' C</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (GB2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost AZD1222 (SB2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GB1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime AZD1222, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SB1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (GA1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost AZD1222 (SA1)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (GA2)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prime BBIBP-CorV, Boost BBIBP-CorV (SA2)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy female and male adults 18 to 65 years old at the time of consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residing within the Maputo health region and planning to stay for the study duration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV negative test result on the day of screening (for those who do not have a&#xD;
             documented HIV test results in the last three months of screening).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female volunteers of childbearing potential with a negative pregnancy test on the&#xD;
             day(s) of screening and vaccination, practicing/willing to practice continuous&#xD;
             effective contraception recommended by the national health system up to 12 weeks after&#xD;
             the booster vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agreement to refrain from blood donation during the course of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to comply with all study requirements, , based on the assessment of&#xD;
             the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to provide written informed consent before any trial procedure&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy, lactation, or intention to become pregnant during the vaccination phase&#xD;
             through three months after the booster dose.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior receipt/ planned receipt of any vaccine other than the study intervention within&#xD;
             28 days before and after each study vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous participation in any COVID-19 vaccination trial or vaccination campaign.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administration of immunoglobulins and/ or any blood products within the three months&#xD;
             preceding the administration of the study vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known infection with hepatitis B, C virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of allergy or anaphylaxis to study vaccine components and/or excipients&#xD;
             or other medications, or any other allergies deemed by the investigator to increase&#xD;
             the risk of an adverse reaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of bleeding disorder (e.g., factor deficiency, coagulopathy or platelet&#xD;
             disorder), or prior history of significant bleeding or bruising following IM&#xD;
             injections or venipuncture.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Continuous use of the anticoagulants, such as coumarins and related anticoagulants.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe and/or uncontrolled cardiovascular disease, respiratory disease,&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disease, renal disease, liver disease, endocrine disorders, and&#xD;
             neurological illness (mild/moderate well controlled comorbidities are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant abnormal finding on screening as judged by the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of laboratory confirmed COVID-19 illness prior to enrollment (History of&#xD;
             SARS-Cov-2 detection by PCR or antibody to SARS-CoV-2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SARS-CoV-2 seropositivity at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any confirmed or suspected immunosuppressive or immunodeficient state, asplenia,&#xD;
             recurrent severe infections and chronic use (more than 14 days) immunosuppressant&#xD;
             medication within 3 months prior to recruitment (topical steroids are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any other finding which in the opinion of the investigators would increase the risk of&#xD;
             an adverse outcome from participation in the trial or result in incomplete or&#xD;
             poor-quality data.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Florian Marks, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>International Vaccine Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ilesh Jani, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Saúde</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Florian Marks, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+821087033813</phone>
    <email>fmarks@ivi.int</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Birkneh Tilahun Tadesse, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+821098041348</phone>
    <email>birkneh.tadesse@ivi.int</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centro de Investigação e Treino em Saúde da Polana Caniço - Instituto Nacional de Saúde</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maputo</city>
        <country>Mozambique</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ilesh Jani, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+258825802221</phone>
      <email>ilesh.jani@ins.gov.mz</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Mozambique</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://covid19.who.int/region/afro/country/mz</url>
    <description>Description Mozambique COVID-19 Situation</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2, Vaccines, Mix and Match Trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myeloma Proteins</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Paraproteins</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

