<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04995731</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AssiutNT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04995731</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Risk Assessment of Endometrial Hyperplasia and Endometrial Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Risk Assessment of Endometrial Hyperplasia and Endometrial Cancer: Development and Validation of Clinical-ultrasound Based Scoring System(A Cross Sectional -Validation Study)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Abnormal uterine bleeding (AUB) represents common diagnostic challenge in everyday&#xD;
      gynecological practice. However, abnormal bleeding is a common symptom of many benign&#xD;
      diseases and only indicates the presence of EC in 9% of postmenopausal women and 1% to 2% of&#xD;
      premenopausal women, suggesting that many women at low risk undergo unnecessary invasive&#xD;
      procedures to rule out cancer. The aim of the study is to create a risk-scoring model of&#xD;
      endometrial hyperplasia and endometrial cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Approximately 90% of endometrial cancer (EC) cases are preceded by AUB in premenopausal or&#xD;
      perimenopausal women or post-menopausal bleeding (PMB).Transvaginal ultrasonography(TVS) has&#xD;
      become the first step diagnostic tool of AUB. The main advantage of ultrasound imaging is&#xD;
      that it has high accuracy for the preoperative classiﬁcation of intra and extra uterine&#xD;
      lesions, both benign and malignant. If increased endometrial thickness (ET) is found in women&#xD;
      with PMB, the risk of EC increases. However, in women with type II EC, ET below 3-4 mm might&#xD;
      also be found. Because of these limitations, ET should not be the only factor for cancer risk&#xD;
      estimation in women with AUB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Three-dimensional sonography and blood ﬂow vascular indices improve the diagnostic precision&#xD;
      of the sonographic estimation of endometrial lesions. Several scoring systems using different&#xD;
      ultrasound image characteristics were proposed to estimate the risk of EC in women with AUB&#xD;
      including the recently proposed system&quot; Risk of Endometrial Cancer scoring model &quot;(REC).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Existing guidelines recommend considering clinical risk factors such as BMI, age, obesity,&#xD;
      type II diabetes, polycystic ovary syndrome(PCOS) and use of unopposed estrogen when&#xD;
      evaluating AUB. However, only few clinical risk prediction models have been developed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the important role of ultrasound imaging in assessment of endometrial lesions, one&#xD;
      wonders if clinical variables can improve the diagnostic performance of risk prediction&#xD;
      models.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to create a risk-scoring model of endometrial hyperplasia and&#xD;
      endometrial cancer using patient clinical characteristics and ultrasound image&#xD;
      characteristics among women with abnormal uterine bleeding, and to validate the diagnostic&#xD;
      performance of our model and to compare it's predictive value with the recently proposed REC&#xD;
      score for EC risk stratiﬁcation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>prevalence of endometrial cancer, endometrial hyperplasia</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Magnitude and prevalence of endometrial cancer, endometrial hyperplasia using a practical clinical-ultrasound based scoring system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>prevalence of endometrial benign lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>calculate absolute risks (prevalent risk) of endometrial benign lesions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">328</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometrial Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Women with pre or peri-menopausal abnormal uterine bleeding or post menopausal bleeding</arm_group_label>
    <description>Eligible women presenting to Women's Health hospital with pre or peri-menopausal AUB or PMB will be prospectively enrolled after obtaining their informed consent. AUB will be deﬁned by symptoms of heavy menstrual bleeding, inter-menstrual bleeding, meno-metrorrhagia, irregular menses, or other AUB among women aged ≥40 years who are not in menopause. Peri-menopausal bleeding will be defined as vaginal bleeding after 6 months of menopause after the age of 40 years. Postmenopausal status will be defined as the absence of menstruation for at least 12 months after the age of 40 years, where any pathological condition of amenorrhea is excluded.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Information about clinical risk factors for endometrial cancer and endometrial hyperplasia (EH)</intervention_name>
    <description>Bleeding type, age, race, parity, early menarche or late menopause, body mass index, body composition, hypertension, type II diabetes, anovulation, polycystic ovary syndrome and smoking history. Other epidemiologic risk factors including tamoxifen exposure, history of breast cancer, current hormone therapy use, anticoagulant use, oral contraception use, family history of endometrial, breast or colon cancer.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Women with pre or peri-menopausal abnormal uterine bleeding or post menopausal bleeding</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>transvaginal ultrasound examination</intervention_name>
    <description>All patients will undergo a standard transvaginal ultrasound examination followed by power Doppler endometrial vascularity assessment. After ultrasound examination, all patients will undergo endometrial sampling either through hysteroscopy or dilatation and curettage operation (D, C) or will have histopathological evaluation of biopsy specimens obtained by hysterectomy. Histopathological evaluation will serve as a gold standard for the ﬁnal diagnosis.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Women with pre or peri-menopausal abnormal uterine bleeding or post menopausal bleeding</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>power Doppler endometrial vascularity assessment</other_name>
    <other_name>endometrial sampling</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Endometrial sampling either through hysteroscopy or dilatation and curettage operation (D, C)&#xD;
      or histopathological evaluation of biopsy specimens obtained by hysterectomy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Eligible women presenting to Women's Health hospital with pre or peri-menopausal abnormal&#xD;
        uterine bleeding(AUB )or Postmenopausal (PMB)will be prospectively enrolled after obtaining&#xD;
        their informed consent. Abnormal uterine bleeding will be deﬁned by symptoms of heavy&#xD;
        menstrual bleeding, inter-menstrual bleeding, meno-metrorrhagia, irregular menses, or other&#xD;
        AUB among women aged ≥40 years who are not in menopause. Peri-menopausal bleeding will be&#xD;
        defined as vaginal bleeding after 6 months of menopause after the age of 40 years.&#xD;
        Postmenopausal status will be defined as the absence of menstruation for at least 12 months&#xD;
        after the age of 40 years, where any pathological condition of amenorrhea is excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        women ≥40 years with pre- or perimenopausal AUB or PMB presenting to Women's Health&#xD;
        Hospital, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Faculty of medicine, Assiut University,&#xD;
        Assiut, Egypt.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with a vaginal bleeding arising from a cervical, vaginal or vulvar disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cervical cancer or uterine metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of prior hysterectomy, prior pelvic radiation, endometrial sampling within the&#xD;
             past 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of existing pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with inadequate endometrial sampling or with no histopathological diagnosis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Norhan T Sayed, Masters</last_name>
    <phone>+201032747426</phone>
    <email>norhantareq@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>71515</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Norhan T Sayed, Masters</last_name>
      <phone>01032747426</phone>
      <email>norhantareq@yahoo.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clarke MA, Long BJ, Del Mar Morillo A, Arbyn M, Bakkum-Gamez JN, Wentzensen N. Association of Endometrial Cancer Risk With Postmenopausal Bleeding in Women: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. JAMA Intern Med. 2018 Sep 1;178(9):1210-1222. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.2820.</citation>
    <PMID>30083701</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Matteson KA, Robison K, Jacoby VL. Opportunities for Early Detection of Endometrial Cancer in Women With Postmenopausal Bleeding. JAMA Intern Med. 2018 Sep 1;178(9):1222-1223. doi: 10.1001/jamainternmed.2018.2819.</citation>
    <PMID>30083765</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pennant ME, Mehta R, Moody P, Hackett G, Prentice A, Sharp SJ, Lakshman R. Premenopausal abnormal uterine bleeding and risk of endometrial cancer. BJOG. 2017 Feb;124(3):404-411. doi: 10.1111/1471-0528.14385. Epub 2016 Oct 20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27766759</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Du J, Li Y, Lv S, Wang Q, Sun C, Dong X, He M, Ulain Q, Yuan Y, Tuo X, Batchu N, Song Q, Li Q. Endometrial sampling devices for early diagnosis of endometrial lesions. J Cancer Res Clin Oncol. 2016 Dec;142(12):2515-2522. Epub 2016 Aug 11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27515060</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Szubert S, Szpurek D, Wójtowicz A, Żywica P, Stukan M, Sajdak S, Jabłonski S, Wicherek Ł, Moszyński R. Performance of Selected Models for Predicting Malignancy in Ovarian Tumors in Relation to the Degree of Diagnostic Uncertainty by Subjective Assessment With Ultrasound. J Ultrasound Med. 2020 May;39(5):939-947. doi: 10.1002/jum.15178. Epub 2019 Nov 29.</citation>
    <PMID>31782548</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gull B, Karlsson B, Milsom I, Granberg S. Can ultrasound replace dilation and curettage? A longitudinal evaluation of postmenopausal bleeding and transvaginal sonographic measurement of the endometrium as predictors of endometrial cancer. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2003 Feb;188(2):401-8.</citation>
    <PMID>12592247</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dueholm M, Hjorth IM. Structured imaging technique in the gynecologic office for the diagnosis of abnormal uterine bleeding. Best Pract Res Clin Obstet Gynaecol. 2017 Apr;40:23-43. doi: 10.1016/j.bpobgyn.2016.09.010. Epub 2016 Oct 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>27818130</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dueholm M, Hjorth IMD, Dahl K, Pedersen LK, Ørtoft G. Identification of endometrial cancers and atypical hyperplasia: Development and validation of a simplified system for ultrasound scoring of endometrial pattern. Maturitas. 2019 May;123:15-24. doi: 10.1016/j.maturitas.2019.01.017. Epub 2019 Feb 1.</citation>
    <PMID>31027672</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Burbos N, Musonda P, Duncan TJ, Crocker SG, Morris EP, Nieto JJ. Estimating the risk of endometrial cancer in symptomatic postmenopausal women: a novel clinical prediction model based on patients' characteristics. Int J Gynecol Cancer. 2011 Apr;21(3):500-6. doi: 10.1097/IGC.0b013e31820c4cd6.</citation>
    <PMID>21436697</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Norhan Tarek Sayed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>assistant lecturer of obstetrics and gynecology, Faculty of medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>endometrial hyperplasia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Endometrial Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

