<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00373139</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>03/08/VA11</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00373139</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Accuracy of Whole-Blood Testing for Rapid Detection of Pregnancy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Accuracy of Whole-Blood Testing for Rapid Detection of Pregnancy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Antonios Likourezos</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maimonides Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is common practice in the emergency medicine department to rapidly assess pregnancy status&#xD;
      through the use of either urine or serum in pregnancy tests. Using whole blood instead of&#xD;
      urine would facilitate a much more rapid emergency department identification of pregnancy&#xD;
      status. No study to date has utilized whole blood for rapid detection of pregnancy status.&#xD;
      Set in the busy adult emergency room at Maimonides Medical Center, this study will recruit a&#xD;
      sample of women of reproductive age (18-55), who fit the inclusion criteria of being healthy&#xD;
      and in need of a pregnancy test for own purpose or diagnostic testing/treatment. Blood&#xD;
      samples will be taken from the participants and used in the hCG kits and the remaining blood&#xD;
      was sent to the chemistry laboratory to perform the reference gold standard. The reference&#xD;
      gold standard for a positive test is an hCG level &gt;25mlU/ml. The research investigators and&#xD;
      lab will be blinded to each other's results. Kappa statistics will be done for the&#xD;
      measurement agreement between urine pregnancy results and whole blood pregnancy results, and&#xD;
      whole blood results with laboratory results.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background and Significance:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Point-of-Care testing to rapidly detect pregnancy in women of reproductive age is common&#xD;
      practice in Emergency Medicine departments. The patient history may not always reliably&#xD;
      identify the possibility of pregnancy1, and a large proportion of these patients are exposed&#xD;
      to potential teratogens because of their emergency department visit. In one study, 33% of&#xD;
      such patients received a radiographic evaluation and 75% were prescribed a medication2.&#xD;
      Additionally, a pregnancy test is required as the first step in the evaluation of a&#xD;
      suspected, potentially life threatening, ectopic pregnancy3.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Commercially available rapid immunochemical assays detect human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)&#xD;
      concentrations &gt;25 mlU/ml, and yield results at 3 minutes using urine and at 5 minutes using&#xD;
      serum4-6. However, in clinical practice these tests may take much longer to perform due to&#xD;
      significant delays in obtaining urine specimens from patients, or time delays required for&#xD;
      separating serum from whole blood. By prolonging patient waiting time for further diagnostic&#xD;
      testing and treatment, these delays may adversely impact on patient outcomes, emergency&#xD;
      department crowding, and patient satisfaction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using whole blood for hCG immunoassay, instead of urine or serum, would facilitate much more&#xD;
      rapid emergency department identification of pregnant patients. Whole blood can be obtained&#xD;
      immediately during intravenous insertion of phlebotomy, or by finger stick puncture using a&#xD;
      lancet in a manner similar to obtaining blood for bedside glucose determination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Previous study of hCG immunoassays (which were less rapid than the immunoassays which are now&#xD;
      commercially available and in use today) utilized whole blood as well as urine and serum,&#xD;
      with equal sensitivities7. However, the accuracy of whole blood identifying pregnancy using&#xD;
      presently available rapid immunochemical hCG test kits has not been validated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate the sensitivity and specificity of a commercially available rapid immunochemical&#xD;
      hCG assay kit to detect pregnancy using whole blood specimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material &amp; Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: A prospective, blinded study for validation of a diagnostic test&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting: Two Clinical Sites:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Primary Care Women's Center of the Maimonides Medical Center, located at 5008 Fort&#xD;
           Hamilton Parkway, Brooklyn, New York.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Adult Emergency Department of Maimonides Medical Center, located at Fort Hamilton&#xD;
           Parkway and 49th Street, Brooklyn, New York.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A convenience sample of healthy women from the above two settings, who meet the following&#xD;
      inclusion and exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Healthy adult women of child bearing age.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Who either request a pregnancy test, or require a pregnancy test for diagnostic studies&#xD;
           or treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Minors&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Adults who are unable to independently give consent for study&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Known pregnancy (i.e. - patient appears obviously pregnant)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Hemodynamically unstable.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Moderately to severely ill-appearing or in moderate to severe pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Technically not possible to obtain blood from the study subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If we consider the quantitative hCG as the parameter for the final outcome: A sample of 279&#xD;
      from the positive group and 279 from the negative group achieve 80% power to detect a&#xD;
      difference of 0.0500 between the area under the ROC (receiver operating characteristic) curve&#xD;
      (AUC) under the null hypothesis of 0.8500 and an AUC under the alternative hypothesis of&#xD;
      0.9000 using a two-sided z-test at a significance level of 0.0500. The data are discrete&#xD;
      (rating scale) responses. The AUC is computed between false positive rates of 0.000 and&#xD;
      1.000. The ration of the standard deviation of the responses in the negative group to the&#xD;
      standard deviation of the responses in the positive group is 1.000.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If we consider a dichotomous outcome for the qualitative result of hCG, instead of testing a&#xD;
      hypothesis: A sample size of 384 from each (Positive and Negative test) group will be&#xD;
      required to be 95% confident that the results would be within a true population parameter&#xD;
      using the following formula:&#xD;
&#xD;
      (Py)(Pn)&#xD;
&#xD;
      = N Std Error2 Py and Pn represent the proportion of people responding to each of the&#xD;
      categories in a dichotomous variable and N represent the sample size. We assumed a 50/50&#xD;
      split approach to maximize the variation (i.e. Py = 0.5 and Pn = 0.5) and a Type l error =&#xD;
      .05 to obtain a confidence interval of 95 percent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to enrollment in this study, written informed consent will be obtained from all&#xD;
      subjects. After valid consent is granted, subjects will complete a brief standardized data&#xD;
      collection sheet to determine whether they meet eligibility criteria for participation in&#xD;
      this study. Study investigators will review this data. Subjects who meet eligibility criteria&#xD;
      and agree to participate in this study will be enrolled as participants. Each participant&#xD;
      will submit 5ml of whole blood to be used exclusively for this research study. This blood&#xD;
      specimen will be dram from an antecubital or other large upper extremity vein by a physician,&#xD;
      nurse, or professional phlebotomist. Each blood sample will be labeled with a unique&#xD;
      identification number. One or two drops from each blood sample will be used immediately by&#xD;
      the study investigator to perform an ICON 25 rapid hCG immunoassay test (Beckman Coulter,&#xD;
      Miami, Florida). The result will be read at 3 and 5 minutes and the specimen identification&#xD;
      number and corresponding result recorded in a log. The remainder of each whole blood specimen&#xD;
      will be sent to the Maimonides Medical Center chemistry laboratory and processed to perform&#xD;
      the reference gold standard test, a quantitative serum total hCG (ADVIA Centaur® System total&#xD;
      hCG chemiluminometric immunoassay; Bayer Corporation, Tarrytown, New York) The Beckman&#xD;
      Coulter ICON 25 kits is 100% sensitive and 100% specific at hCG values &gt; 25mlU/ml. Therefore,&#xD;
      the reference gold standard for a positive pregnancy test will be a quantitative serum hCG &gt;&#xD;
      25 mlU/ml. Investigators who perform the whole blood pregnancy test and laboratory&#xD;
      technicians performing reference gold standard testing of serum will be blinded to one&#xD;
      another's results.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Confidentiality:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is not intended to evaluate the performance of any individual resident. Date from&#xD;
      this study will be used only for the statistical analysis for this study. The participant's&#xD;
      privacy will be maintained by giving each a unique ID number in the database for analysis.&#xD;
      Access to the database file will be protected by encryption and a password. All data forms&#xD;
      will be secured in a locked file cabinet and access will be limited to the investigators&#xD;
      only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Analysis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be initially entered and analyzed via SPSS. Sensitivity and specificity will&#xD;
      also be estimated using 2X2 table.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>July 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Detection of Pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Blood will be assessed in a pregnancy kit to assess the sensitivity and specificity of detecting whether or not the patient is pregnant. The laboratory results will be the gold standard.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">633</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Healthy ED adult women of child bearing age.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy adult women of child bearing age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Who either request a pregnancy test, or require a pregnancy test for diagnostic&#xD;
             studies or treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Minors&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Adults who are unable to independently give consent for study&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Known pregnancy (i.e. - patient appears obviously pregnant)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Hemodynamically unstable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Moderately to severely ill-appearing or in moderate to severe pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Technically not possible to obtain blood from the study subject.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christian Fromm, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Maimonides Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Maimonides Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brooklyn</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>11219</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 6, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 6, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 7, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 27, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 27, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 30, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Maimonides Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Antonios Likourezos</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Research Manager</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Pregnancy,</keyword>
  <keyword>Screening,</keyword>
  <keyword>Whole Blood</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

