<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00375050</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>13175</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00375050</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Refractory Schizophrenia With Riluzole</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neuroprotective Treatment of Refractory Schizophrenia With Riluzole 01T-432</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Yale University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Stanley Medical Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Yale University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The proposed study would evaluate the benefits of riluzole add-on treatment to patients with&#xD;
      schizophrenia who are already receiving medications, but still experience symptoms.&#xD;
      Neuroprotective medication riluzole is currently approved for treatment of amyotrophic&#xD;
      lateral sclerosis (Lou Gehrig's disease), a severe neurological illness. Due to its unique&#xD;
      mechanism of action, riluzole, if effective in helping the symptoms of schizophrenia, would&#xD;
      open novel directions in treatment of schizophrenia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Schizophrenia is perhaps one of the most debilitating illnesses. Over the past years there&#xD;
      has been limited improvement in the efficacy of the medications used to treat this disorder.&#xD;
      In particular, the currently available antipsychotic drugs have small efficacy against&#xD;
      negative symptoms and cognitive impairment associated with schizophrenia. This is critical&#xD;
      considering that both negative symptoms and cognitive deficits contribute significantly to&#xD;
      social and vocational impairment in schizophrenic patients. Furthermore, current treatment&#xD;
      can not always provide satisfactory control of positive symptoms. While various extracellular&#xD;
      neurotransmitter systems (dopamine, 5HT, GABA, etc. ) have been explored as targets for&#xD;
      antipsychotic treatment, a substantial body of evidence suggests that neurodegenerative&#xD;
      intracellular processes might be responsible for some of the symptoms of schizophrenia,&#xD;
      resulting in cytopathic effects or inadequate cellular functioning. Some of these processes&#xD;
      may be triggered by excitotoxic influence of neurotransmitters (i.e. glutamate). As many&#xD;
      neuroleptic agents currently in use have some neuroprotective properties it is possible to&#xD;
      speculate that medications with primarily neuroprotective mode of action might be of&#xD;
      additional help in treatment of schizophrenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Huntington's disease patients who in its advanced form exhibit some symptoms similar to that&#xD;
      of psychotic illness, have, in a recent small (n=9) open label study with a neuroprotective&#xD;
      drug riluzole, shown a temporary improvement in not only motor function, but also cognitive,&#xD;
      and behavioral functioning (Seppi 2001).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on all of the above, it seems possible to expect improvement in symptoms of&#xD;
      schizophrenia with neuroprotective agents such as riluzole.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Riluzole is the only effective medication approved for use in ALS (amyotrophic lateral&#xD;
      sclerosis, Lou Gehrig's disease) which is one of the most severe and rapidly progressing&#xD;
      neurodegenerative illnesses that affects motor neurons in the brain and spinal cord. A subset&#xD;
      of ALS is inherited and involves more than 70 different mutations in the antioxidant enzyme&#xD;
      superoxide dismutase (SOD) thereby contributing to reduced antioxidative defense against&#xD;
      oxidative injury. This results in increased reactive oxygen species level in several&#xD;
      organs/tissues while the bulk of symptomatology is related to degeneration in the subset of&#xD;
      CNS neurons. Although riluzole is effective in both humans and the transgenic mouse model of&#xD;
      familial ALS where it slows decrease in motor power, its exact neuroprotective mechanism of&#xD;
      action is not known. Various studies suggest that riluzole might exert some of its beneficial&#xD;
      effect by inhibition of glutamate release, inhibition of voltage-gated Na+ channels, but also&#xD;
      intracellularly by inhibiting of protein kinase C (PKC), enzyme that was linked to oxidative&#xD;
      neuronal injury. Although riluzole is generally well tolerated, side effects can occur and&#xD;
      are mostly related to gastrointestinal problems, hepatotoxicity and asthenia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This 14 week study would evaluate the benefits of riluzole add-on treatment to patients with&#xD;
      schizophrenia on neuroleptics with refractory symptoms.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 2002</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 29, 2006</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 29, 2006</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PANSS (Positive and Negative Syndrome Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SANS (Scale for the Assessment of Negative Symptoms)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CGI- Clinical Global Impression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Calgary Depression Scale: To assess mood symptoms in psychotic patients</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neuropsychological tests:</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Computerized Working Memory Task</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Verbal Fluency</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>HVLT-Hopkins Verbal Learning Test</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>DSST-Digit Symbol Substitution Test</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Continuous performance test</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CANTAB- Cambridge Neuropsychological Test Automated Battery</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AIMS (abnormal involuntary movement scale), EPS (extrapyramidal symptom) assessment, Barnes akathisia scale, Simpson Angus scale</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">34</enrollment>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <condition>Schizoaffective</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Riluzole</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Riluzole</intervention_name>
    <arm_group_label>Riluzole</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rilutek</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men or women with a diagnosis of schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder as defined&#xD;
             by DSM- IV criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age between 18 and 65. Special attention will be placed on selective enrolling of&#xD;
             patients 18-25 to assess that they have been exposed to adequate medication trials&#xD;
             (minimum two medications) for sufficient length of time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  During the 3 months prior to study entry, the patient must not have been an inpatient&#xD;
             in a hospital for longer than 4 weeks (cumulative hospitalizations) due to worsening&#xD;
             of psychiatric illness (although could have been participating in an inpatient&#xD;
             research protocol).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients able to comprehend and satisfactorily comply with the protocol requirements;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a PANSS total score of 60 or higher and a score of 4 (moderate) or&#xD;
             higher on two or more of the following PANSS items: delusions, hallucinatory behavior,&#xD;
             conceptual disorganization or suspiciousness.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CGI scale rating of at least mildly ill, but not greater than severely ill.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For women only: The patient must be non-pregnant, non-lactating, or has undergone&#xD;
             tubal ligation, bilateral oophorectomy or hysterectomy; or the patient must be at&#xD;
             least one year post menopausal; or the patient a) has negative urine or serum&#xD;
             pregnancy test (Beta HCG) and b) agrees to reliably practice contraception throughout&#xD;
             the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary psychiatric diagnosis other than schizophrenia or schizoaffective disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had psychosurgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recent (&lt; 3 weeks) change in antipsychotic regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of clinically significant somatic disease that requires frequent changes in&#xD;
             medications or that could be aggravated by taking riluzole (i.e. severe liver illness)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently receiving treatment with potentially hepatotoxic drugs (e.g. allopurinol,&#xD;
             methyldopa, sulfasalazine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  HIV positive, as assessed by blood testing (in part to avoid subjects with possible&#xD;
             brain HIV infection and to avoid rare complications of rarely occurring riluzole&#xD;
             induced neutropenia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who pose immediate or significant enough risk for suicide or harm for others&#xD;
             as assessed by the study MD.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or nursing women, or women of childbearing potential who do not use adequate&#xD;
             contraception or who are judged to be unreliable in their use of contraception&#xD;
             (because there is not enough experience with riluzole use in nursing or pregnant&#xD;
             women)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Zoran Zimolo, MD, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Yale University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yale Department of Psychiatry</name>
      <address>
        <city>New Haven</city>
        <state>Connecticut</state>
        <zip>06519</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>December 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 8, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 8, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 12, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 6, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 6, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">December 9, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Riluzole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

