<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00371241</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HSC-MS-06-0122</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00371241</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Antibody Secreting Cell and Cyotokine Profiles in Neonates on ECMO</brief_title>
  <official_title>Antibody Secreting Cell (ASC) and Immunoactive Protein Profiles in Neonates on Extracorporeal Membrane Oxygenation (ECMO)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Memorial Hermann Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The University of Texas Health Science Center, Houston</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Infants are placed on ECMO for correction of reversible respiratory failure. Often, because a&#xD;
      few of the reasons for respiratory failure show us similar things in the baby, it is&#xD;
      difficult to determine exactly which is causing the biggest problem. We are now capable of&#xD;
      measuring certain cells and proteins in these infants that may help us more accurately&#xD;
      diagnose the exact problem. We hypothesize that infants placed on ECMO will show unique&#xD;
      antibody-secreting cells responses and patterns of cytokine and chemokine (protein) response&#xD;
      to illness and to the ECMO circuit. If we find unique patterns to these cells or proteins,&#xD;
      they may be able to predict outcomes or guide treatment of these infants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Specific Aims Primary Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Determine the rise, peak, and fall of immunoglobulin isotype-specific ASC's, and&#xD;
      immunoactive proteins (cytokines and chemokines) from sequential samples of peripheral blood&#xD;
      from infants on ECMO.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Determine the most appropriate time to sample blood from infants with suspected sepsis&#xD;
           for ASC diagnostic assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Characterize the incidence of culture-negative sepsis that leads to ECMO.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Determine immunoglobulin isotype-specific levels of ASC in infants with and without&#xD;
           infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Establish an archive of mononuclear cells and plasma to use in development of pathogen&#xD;
           specific ASC assays.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis Infants on ECMO will have a high ASC response and unique cytokine/chemokine&#xD;
      patterns due to possible underlying infection and exposure to many foreign antigens (blood&#xD;
      products, ECMO circuit). A significant portion of these will have ASC's with specificity for&#xD;
      common causes of neonatal sepsis that is not detected by routine blood culture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Residual samples will be collected from those used in routine procedures for infants on ECMO.&#xD;
      The approximate volume/sample will be 0.5-0.8ml. Specimens will be processed using methods&#xD;
      well established in our laboratory. Briefly, PBMC's will be isolated via Ficoll gradient and&#xD;
      archived in liquid nitrogen at -80C. Batch analysis of ASC levels and lymphocyte&#xD;
      proliferation activity will be performed when sufficient number of specimens are accumulated.&#xD;
      A detailed profile and quantification of immune cells will be determined by Fluorescent&#xD;
      Activated Cell Sorter (FACS) staining for CD3, CD4, CD8, CD27, CD38, CD45, and HLA-DR. A bead&#xD;
      micro-array will be used to detect levels of immunoactive molecules, also done on the FACS.&#xD;
      The proteins detected will include, but may not be limited to, the following: IL1β, IL2, IL4,&#xD;
      IL5, IL6, IL7, IL8, IL10, IL12p70, IL13, IL17, GCSF, GMCSF, IFN-γ, MCP-1, MIP-1β, TNFα. The&#xD;
      ASC procedure be that established by Van de Verg modified to use membrane surface&#xD;
      microculture plates in place of agar with outcomes read by CTL analyzer in place of manual&#xD;
      count. LPA assays will use long established techniques.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>September 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2007</completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment type="Actual">12</enrollment>
  <condition>Persistent Fetal Circulation Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Diaphragmatic Hernia</condition>
  <condition>Meconium Aspiration</condition>
  <condition>Sepsis</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Plasma and whole blood&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Infants requiring ECMO&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1) term newborn infants &gt;24 hours and ≤ 30 days old 2) Placed on ECMO in the NICU at&#xD;
             MHCH 3) Parental consent obtained within 48 hours of being placed on ECMO&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  1) Infant &gt; 30 days old 2) Infant NOT on ECMO 3) Withdrawal of parental consent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>30 Days</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>James M Murpy, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston- Division of Infectious Diseases</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Memorial Hermann Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stoll BJ, Lee FK, Hale E, Schwartz D, Holmes R, Ashby R, Czerkinsky C, Nahmias AJ. Immunoglobulin secretion by the normal and the infected newborn infant. J Pediatr. 1993 May;122(5 Pt 1):780-6.</citation>
    <PMID>8496761</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stoll BJ, Lee FK, Larsen S, Hale E, Schwartz D, Rice RJ, Ashby R, Holmes R, Nahmias AJ. Clinical and serologic evaluation of neonates for congenital syphilis: a continuing diagnostic dilemma. J Infect Dis. 1993 May;167(5):1093-9.</citation>
    <PMID>8486942</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baqar S, Nour El Din AA, Scott DA, Bourgeois AL, Mourad AS, Kleinosky MT, Oplinger MJ, Murphy JR. Standardization of measurement of immunoglobulin-secreting cells in human peripheral circulation. Clin Diagn Lab Immunol. 1997 May;4(3):375-9.</citation>
    <PMID>9144380</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Küster H, Weiss M, Willeitner AE, Detlefsen S, Jeremias I, Zbojan J, Geiger R, Lipowsky G, Simbruner G. Interleukin-1 receptor antagonist and interleukin-6 for early diagnosis of neonatal sepsis 2 days before clinical manifestation. Lancet. 1998 Oct 17;352(9136):1271-7.</citation>
    <PMID>9788457</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 30, 2006</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 1, 2006</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">September 4, 2006</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 3, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 3, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 5, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <name_title>James R. Murphy</name_title>
    <organization>The University of Texas Health Science Center, HoustonU</organization>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>ECMO</keyword>
  <keyword>extracorporeal membrane oxygenation</keyword>
  <keyword>cytokines</keyword>
  <keyword>chemokines</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Meconium Aspiration Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Persistent Fetal Circulation Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hernias, Diaphragmatic, Congenital</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hernia, Diaphragmatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

