<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03369678</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>H17-01548</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03369678</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>EQUIP Emergency: Promoting Health Equity for Indigenous and Non-Indigenous People in Emergency Departments</brief_title>
  <official_title>Promoting Health Equity for Indigenous and Non-Indigenous People in Emergency Departments</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of British Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Canadian Institutes of Health Research (CIHR)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of British Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Emergency Departments (EDs) in Canada often operate over-capacity and are under significant&#xD;
      pressures. In this environment, particular groups of people experience inadequate and&#xD;
      inequitable treatment in EDs, including Indigenous people, racialized newcomers, people with&#xD;
      mental illnesses, those living in unstable housing or facing homelessness, experiencing&#xD;
      interpersonal violence or using substances, and people involved in sex work. Stigma and&#xD;
      discrimination in health care deter people from accessing care, interfering with effective&#xD;
      care delivery, increasing reliance on EDs, and increasing human and financial costs. This&#xD;
      project will develop and test a framework for health equity interventions to promote the&#xD;
      provision of equity-oriented care in EDs.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study examines the feasibility, process, and impacts of implementing an&#xD;
      evidence-informed framework for interventions to enhance the capacity of Emergency&#xD;
      Departments to provide high-quality care to people at greatest risk of experiencing health&#xD;
      and health care inequities. The framework integrates evidence-based strategies to mitigate&#xD;
      discrimination and racism experienced by Indigenous people, and stigma and discrimination&#xD;
      faced by people of all ethnicities related to substance use, housing instability, sex work,&#xD;
      gender, or mental illnesses. The study tests organizational interventions that incorporate&#xD;
      principles of equity-oriented care, trauma- and violence-informed care, harm reduction, and&#xD;
      cultural safety to optimize care first for Indigenous people, and then for a range of people&#xD;
      who commonly face stigma and discrimination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approaching EDs as complex adaptive systems, the study aims to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Engage EDs in a participatory process to enhance capacity for equity-oriented care&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Examine impacts of equity-oriented interventions on processes of care, patient&#xD;
           experiences of care and short-term outcomes, staff attitudes, confidence, behaviours and&#xD;
           job satisfaction, and cost&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Analyze the cost-effectiveness and feasibility of implementing the interventions and&#xD;
           scale-up potential in other contexts.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This mixed-methods study incorporates administrative data, survey data with standardized&#xD;
      tools, in-depth interviews, analysis of policy and organizational structures, and&#xD;
      observational data. The study is divided into multiple phases of data collection. This phase&#xD;
      focuses on surveys of ED staff members and patients. The structured surveys use standardized&#xD;
      tools and measures, and aim to capture staff and patients' experiences of ED care. Surveys&#xD;
      will be conducted at three to four timepoints.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PATIENT SURVEYS will draw on patient self-reports to measure changes over time in processes&#xD;
      of care and perceived quality of care. These indicators will be measured through structured,&#xD;
      researcher-facilitated surveys conducted with a sample of 250-300 patients at each site at up&#xD;
      to four points in time, providing pre- and post-intervention comparisons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At each data collection point, all patients who are able to provide informed consent (in the&#xD;
      languages available - see below) will be invited to participate as they present for care or&#xD;
      during the course of their visit at each emergency unit. Researchers will circulate&#xD;
      throughout the emergency department, inviting participation by all patients who are conscious&#xD;
      and able to consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment will occur over a period of 1-3 weeks in 6 hour blocks. The blocks will span all&#xD;
      24 hours, and as many days of the week as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surveys will not delay or interrupt provision of care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Section 1 of the survey can be completed at any time during the patient's Emergency visit;&#xD;
      Section 2 will be completed after the patient has been cleared for discharge from the&#xD;
      Emergency (discharged to community or admitted). The system for notifying the researchers of&#xD;
      discharge status will align with the usual procedures at each ED. If at all possible, Section&#xD;
      2 will be completed before the patient leaves the hospital, in a private space close to the&#xD;
      ED. If the patient is unable or prefers not to complete Section 2 in hospital, then a phone&#xD;
      follow up will be offered; if the patient does not have a phone and is willing and able to do&#xD;
      so, they will be invited to drop in at a specified outpatient or community clinic in the&#xD;
      following 5 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recruitment and data collection will continue until target samples of 250-300 completed&#xD;
      surveys per site per time point are achieved. Every effort will be made to recruit&#xD;
      participation of people from diverse ethnocultural groups. Given the research objectives of&#xD;
      this study, recruitment will be prioritized for people who self-identify as Indigenous as&#xD;
      well as individuals who are at risk of experiencing stigma and discrimination (e.g., those&#xD;
      with diagnoses related to mental illness, HIV, substance use).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Researchers will work in pairs during each time block conducting recruitment and interviewing&#xD;
      simultaneously. Following processes already in use at one of the partnering ED sites and&#xD;
      prior practices, researchers will collect data directly on tablets using structured survey&#xD;
      instruments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A team of trained researchers will work with ED staff members (e.g., triage staff, unit&#xD;
      clerk, charge nurse, etc.), to invite participation by those patients who meet the&#xD;
      established eligibility criteria. In urgent cases, participants will be told about the study&#xD;
      by staff after their immediate/urgent health concerns have been addressed. Researchers will&#xD;
      approach potential participants to explain the study and seek consent to participate. Once&#xD;
      consent is obtained, the researcher will enroll the participant in the study, complete&#xD;
      Section 1 of the survey, and collect minimal contact information (i.e., name and phone number&#xD;
      - see Patient Survey Guide) to be used for follow up in the event that patients elect to be&#xD;
      interviewed by phone or off-site at a later time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The brief structured survey (10-15 minutes per section) will be facilitated by a researcher&#xD;
      with patients who consent. Both sections will be completed within a maximum of 5 days of the&#xD;
      ED visit in a private area close to the ED, where participants' responses cannot be overheard&#xD;
      by others and confidentiality can be maintained, or by phone or at an agreed upon drop-in&#xD;
      location within the hospital. Patients will be provided with an honorarium for completing&#xD;
      each section of the survey. Transportation and childcare expenses will be reimbursed for&#xD;
      those who choose an in-person follow up to complete the survey. A detailed safety protocol,&#xD;
      adapted from previous studies, will be used to guide all interactions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Structured surveys conducted in all waves will be facilitated by a trained researcher,&#xD;
      following an established Patient Survey Guide and using a computer-assisted data platform&#xD;
      (UBC Survey Tool) on a tablet device. This tablet interface will allow the participant and&#xD;
      researcher to view questions and select responses together on the screen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STAFF SURVEYS All staff members at each partnering ED site will be invited to complete a&#xD;
      survey questionnaire, which will include measures aligned with the theoretical principles&#xD;
      underlying the equity-oriented framework being tested (i.e., cultural safety, trauma- and&#xD;
      violence-informed care, and harm reduction).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Staff members will be invited to complete a structured questionnaire (see Staff Survey&#xD;
      Guide), to be administered online or completed on paper. To facilitate this, copies of the&#xD;
      survey will be available within each emergency department. In addition, in-person sessions&#xD;
      will be held at each emergency department. Light refreshments will be provided and&#xD;
      researchers will be on-hand to answer any questions about the study and the survey itself.&#xD;
      Participants will be encouraged to attend these sessions on their break or at shift-end, and&#xD;
      can choose to complete the surveys independently on paper or directly on a study tablet.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A preamble to the survey will explain the study and include the consent form. Completion of&#xD;
      the survey - either online or on paper - will imply consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Staff assessments will be conducted at three to four time points, to coincide with milestones&#xD;
      in the implementation of the intervention being tested. When possible, staff will be&#xD;
      encouraged to complete the survey outside of work hours, during breaks, or at the start or&#xD;
      end of their shifts.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 28, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in patients' overall rating of care post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention: baseline &amp; 6-9 months; Post-intervention: immediately following intervention period (14-15 months post-baseline #2)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in self-reported rating of care, measured on a scale from 0 to 10, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in patients' overall rating of care at 6-11 months post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention: baseline &amp; 6-9 months; Post-intervention: 6-11 months after intervention period (21-25 months post-baseline #2)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in self-reported rating of care, measured on a scale from 0 to 10, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in staff perception of patient care post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately following intervention period (12 months post-baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in staff members' self-reported perception of the patient care provided by their work unit/team, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in staff perception of patient care at 6-12 months post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>18-25 months post-baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in staff members' self-reported perception of the patient care provided by their work unit/team, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in staff perception of patient care at 17 months post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>29 months post-baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in staff members' self-reported perception of the patient care provided by their work unit/team, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Discrimination in Medical Settings Scale post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention: baseline &amp; 6-9 months; Post-intervention: immediately following intervention period (at 14 - 15 months post-baseline #2)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patients' self-reported experiences of discrimination in the emergency department, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in Discrimination in Medical Settings Scale at 6-11 months post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Pre-intervention: baseline &amp; 6-9 months; Post-intervention: 6-11 months after intervention period (21-25 months post-baseline #2)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in patients' self-reported experiences of discrimination in the emergency department, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in staff satisfaction and engagement post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediately following intervention period (12 months post-baseline)</time_frame>
    <description>Change in staff members' self-reported satisfaction and engagement with their job and workplace, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in staff satisfaction and engagement at 6-12 months post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>18-25 months post-baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in staff members' self-reported satisfaction and engagement with their job and workplace, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in staff satisfaction and engagement at 17 months post-intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>29 months post-baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Change in staff members' self-reported satisfaction and engagement with their job and workplace, comparing pre-intervention to post-intervention</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">5439</enrollment>
  <condition>Interventions to Enhance Emergency Health Care</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients of three participating emergency departments.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Staff members of three participating emergency departments.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        PATIENT SURVEYS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 19 or over, or emancipated youth (16-19 years old)*&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient presenting for care at a participating ED site when survey recruitment is&#xD;
             being conducted * Patients between age 16 and 19 will only be included if they no&#xD;
             longer live with a parent or guardian.&#xD;
&#xD;
        STAFF SURVEYS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 19 or over&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand, read and write in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Staff member or health professional working in a participating ED site&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals not meeting the inclusion criteria listed above will be excluded from&#xD;
             participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Colleen Varcoe</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of British Columbia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Northern British Columbia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Prince George</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V2M 1S2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Surrey Memorial Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Surrey</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V3V 1Z2</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Paul's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V6Z 1Y6</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://equiphealthcare.ca/</url>
    <description>EQUIP Health Care website. Click for more info about the EQUIP Emergency study.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 18, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 6, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 12, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of British Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Colleen Varcoe</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cultural Safety</keyword>
  <keyword>Discrimination</keyword>
  <keyword>Emergency Departments</keyword>
  <keyword>Health Equity</keyword>
  <keyword>Indigenous Populations</keyword>
  <keyword>Marginalized Populations</keyword>
  <keyword>Patient Experiences of Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Trauma- and Violence-Informed Care</keyword>
  <keyword>Staff Engagement</keyword>
  <keyword>Harm Reduction</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form: Patient Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>November 2, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/78/NCT03369678/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form: Accompanying Person Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>November 2, 2017</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/78/NCT03369678/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

