<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03368079</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>836211</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03368079</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Utilization of Negative Pressure Suction to Reduce Aspiration in Oropharyngeal Dysphagia</brief_title>
  <official_title>Utilization of Negative Pressure Suction to Reduce Aspiration in Oropharyngeal Dysphagia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Davis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Davis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an investigator initiated prospective study to determine whether the use of a&#xD;
      negative pressure suction in the hypopharynx will reduce the amount of aspiration during&#xD;
      Video Fluoroscopic Swallowing Exam (VFSE) among patients with oropharyngeal dysphagia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      During a properly coordinated swallow, the oropharynx, larynx, and hypopharynx undergo a&#xD;
      series of movements that serve to prepare and expand the pharyngoesophageal segment (PES),&#xD;
      which is the inlet into the esophagus. Under normal circumstances, a food bolus is safely&#xD;
      propelled from the oropharynx, through the PES, and into the esophagus. Surgical and&#xD;
      radiation therapy in the head and neck, as well as deficiencies such as poor coordination,&#xD;
      mistiming, or obstructing lesions may prevent the food bolus from safely entering the&#xD;
      esophagus and instead diverting toward the trachea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A number of patients with severe oropharyngeal dysphagia are not able to tolerate any diet&#xD;
      without risking aspiration and subsequent pneumonia, often to a degree severe enough that&#xD;
      they cannot manage to safely swallow their secreted saliva. These patients depend on a&#xD;
      gastrostomy feeding tube in order to obtain adequate daily nutritional requirements and must&#xD;
      suction or spit out their saliva to prevent aspiration and a sensation of asphyxiation.&#xD;
      Despite these precautions, many of these patients ultimately suffer life-threatening&#xD;
      pneumonia. Investigators will be testing if the use of use of a negative pressure suction in&#xD;
      the hypopharynx will reduce the amount of aspiration during Video Fluoroscopic Swallowing&#xD;
      Exam (VFSE) among patients with severe oropharyngeal dysphagia&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 30, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Degree of aspiration</measure>
    <time_frame>During VFSE, from the beginning of administration of the first bolus size to completion of the VFSE</time_frame>
    <description>Degree of aspiration or laryngeal penetration, evaluated by the validated Rosenbek Penetration-Aspiration Scale (PAS). The PAS scale is an 8-point (1 to 8), equal-appearing interval scale:&#xD;
Material does not enter airway&#xD;
Material enters the airway, remains above the vocal folds, and is ejected from the airway.&#xD;
Material enters the airway, remains above the vocal folds, and is not ejected from the airway.&#xD;
Material enters the airway, contacts the vocal folds, and is ejected from the airway.&#xD;
Material enters the airway, contacts the vocal folds, and is not ejected from the airway.&#xD;
Material enters the ariway, passes below the vocal folds, and is ejected into the larynx or out of the airway.&#xD;
Material enters the airway, passes below the vocal folds, and is not ejected from the trachea despite effort.&#xD;
Material enters the airway, passes below the vocal folds, and no effort is made to eject.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharyngo-esophageal Segment (PES) opening size</measure>
    <time_frame>During VFSE, PES is measured when the patient administers 20 cc of liquid barium and the PES is maximally distended.</time_frame>
    <description>Pharyngo-esophageal Segment (PES) is a 2.5 to 4.5 cm manometric high-pressure zone located between the pharynx and esophagus. Normal Pharyngoesophageal segment opening size on lateral view: 0.80 cm +/- 0.40 cm</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharyngeal Constriction Ratio (PCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Measurement of the pharyngeal area during maximum contraction are taken after administration of 20 cc liquid barium. The pharyngeal area at rest is measured when 1 cc bolus is held in the oral cavity.</time_frame>
    <description>Pharyngeal Constriction Ratio: is a measure of pharyngeal clearance pressure. It is calculated by dividing the lateral pharyngeal area during maximal contraction by the area with a 1 cc bolus held in the oral cavity. The area is determined by onscreen tool provided. Normal PCR: 0.14 +/- 0.28</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oropharyngeal transit time</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from when bolus head first passes posterior nasal spine to time bolus head enters base of vallecula</time_frame>
    <description>Oropharyngeal transit time is measured when the patient administers 20 cc of liquid barium. Normal oropharyngeal transit time: 0.42 sec +/- 0.36 sec</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hypopharyngeal transit time</measure>
    <time_frame>Time from when bolus head exits the vallecula to time when bolus tale exits PES</time_frame>
    <description>Hypopharyngeal transit time: is measured when the patient administers 20 cc of liquid barium. Normal Hypopharyngeal transit time: 0.77 sec +/- 0.26 sec</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Oropharyngeal Dysphagia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Negative Pressure Suction Device</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Negative Pressure Suction Catheter</intervention_name>
    <description>The negative pressure suction device to be used in the study will be a Foley catheter. The catheter will be placed through the gastrostomy tube site, directed retrograde through the esophagus, and terminating in the PES.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Negative Pressure Suction Device</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with videofluoroscopic evidence of aspiration with Rosenbek Penetration&#xD;
             Aspiration Scale (PAS) greater than 5 for all tested food consistencies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastrostomy tube dependence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exhaustion of conventional treatment options (physical, medical, and surgical&#xD;
             therapies)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Complete PES stricture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to follow commands&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current malignant disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No gastrostomy tube present&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than two years of cancer-free survival (if applicable)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vulnerable populations: adults unable to consent, pregnant women, and prisoners&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Randev Sandhu, BS</last_name>
    <phone>916-734-2863</phone>
    <email>rssandhu@ucdavis.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UC Davis Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sacramento</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>95817</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Randev Sandhu, BS</last_name>
      <phone>916-734-2863</phone>
      <email>rssandhu@ucdavis.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 29, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 4, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 11, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dysphagia</keyword>
  <keyword>Oropharyngeal dysphagia</keyword>
  <keyword>Video Fluoroscopic Swallowing Exam (VFSE)</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

