<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01585350</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15781</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01585350</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Multipeptide Vaccine Plus Toll-Like Receptor Agonists in Melanoma Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>MEL58</acronym>
  <official_title>A Multipeptide Vaccine Plus Toll-Like Receptor Agonists in Melanoma Patients, With Evaluation of the Injection Site Microenvironment</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Craig L Slingluff, Jr</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Virginia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Oncovir, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Virginia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to learn the effects an experimental vaccine (MELITAC 12.1)&#xD;
      combined with other substances called lipopolysaccharide (LPS; endotoxin), polyICLC, and&#xD;
      Montanide ISA-51. The LPS, polyICLC, and Montanide ISA-51 are included with the vaccine to&#xD;
      test whether they have an effect on the MELITAC 12.1 vaccine. The study will also look at&#xD;
      whether the experimental vaccine and these drugs cause any changes to the immune system.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Goals:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To determine the safety of intradermal and subcutaneous injection of lipopolysaccharide&#xD;
           (LPS) as a vaccine adjuvant with a multipeptide vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To obtain preliminary data on whether administration of a multipeptide vaccine plus each&#xD;
           of 2 TLR agonists is immunogenic with or without Incomplete Freund's Adjuvant (IFA)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. To obtain preliminary data on whether addition of either of 2 toll-like receptor (TLR)&#xD;
           agonists improve the persistence of circulating CD8+ T cell responses to vaccination&#xD;
           with a multipeptide vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. To determine the local and systemic toxicities of administration of a multipeptide&#xD;
           vaccine with each of 2 TLR agonists, and with or without incomplete Freund's adjuvant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. To determine the cytokine and chemokine profile of the vaccine-site microenvironment&#xD;
           week 1 after injection of a multipeptide vaccine and each of 2 TLR agonists, with or&#xD;
           without IFA.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. To obtain preliminary data on T cell activation status and apoptosis in the vaccine site&#xD;
           microenvironment (VSME) as a function of vaccine adjuvant.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. To assess whether circulating CD8 T cells induced by vaccination express different&#xD;
           homing receptor profiles (CLA, CXCR3, α4β1 integrin, α4β7 integrin).&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. To evaluate dendritic cell activation and function in sentinel immunized nodes draining&#xD;
           the site of vaccination, for production of IDO, arginase, IL10, IL12.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. To characterize MyD88 expression in dendritic cells infiltrating vaccination sites.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. To identify regulatory processes in the vaccination site.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design: This is an open-label, randomized, pilot study of cellular and molecular events at&#xD;
      the cutaneous site of immunization with a multipeptide vaccine. This and related peptide&#xD;
      vaccines have been associated with immunologic efficacy in a majority of participants and&#xD;
      have been associated with clinical tumor regressions in some participants. The maximum number&#xD;
      of participants accrued will be 51.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Safety, with measures of adverse events, locally and systemically&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CD8+ and CD4+ peptide-reactive T cell responses among lymphocytes in the peripheral&#xD;
           blood and in sentinel immunized nodes (SIN)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Toll-like receptor signaling in the replicate immunization site&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CCR and integrin expression on vaccine induced T cells in the peripheral blood and at&#xD;
           the replicate immunization site&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Th1, Th2, and Th17 profiles of T cells in the vaccination site and SIN as measured by&#xD;
           cytokine expression (IFNγ, IL-2, TNFα, IL-4, IL-5, IL-10, IL-17, IL-23), and nuclear&#xD;
           expression of transcription factors (T-bet, GATA3, RORγt) by immunohistochemistry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Chemokines CXCL9, 10, and 11; CCL19, CCL21, CXCL12, CXCL13 in the vaccine site&#xD;
           microenvironment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Markers of activation, regulation, and apoptosis on CD4 and CD8 T cells in the vaccine&#xD;
           site and SIN: CD69, Ki67, FoxP3, and TUNEL staining.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Homing receptors expressed by antigen-reactive (tetramer-positive) T cells induced by&#xD;
           vaccination, in the circulation and SIN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  MyD88 expression in the VSME and SIN&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Regulatory processes in the immunization site and SIN&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Regulatory T cells (CD4+CD25hi FoxP3+)&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Myeloid suppressor cells&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Indole-amine dioxygenase&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  PD-1, B7-H1&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  IL-10 and IL-12 expression by dendritic cells (DC)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>October 2012</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2014</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2014</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety, with measures of adverse events, locally and systemically</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>CD8+ and CD4+ peptide-reactive T cell responses among lymphocytes in the peripheral blood and in sentinel immunized nodes (SIN)</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toll-like receptor signaling in the replicate immunization site</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CCR and integrin expression on vaccine induced T cells in the peripheral blood and at the replicate immunization site</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Th1, Th2, and Th17 profiles of T cells in the vaccination site and SIN as measured by cytokine expression (IFNγ, IL-2, TNFα, IL-4, IL-5, IL-10, IL-17, IL-23), and nuclear expression of transcription factors (T-bet, GATA3, RORγt) by immunohistochemistry.</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Chemokines CXCL9, 10, and 11; CCL19, CCL21, CXCL12, CXCL13 in the vaccine site microenvironment</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Markers of activation, regulation, and apoptosis on CD4 and CD8 T cells in the vaccine site and SIN: CD69, Ki67, FoxP3, and TUNEL staining</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Homing receptors expressed by antigen-reactive (tetramer-positive) T cells induced by vaccination, in the circulation and SIN</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MyD88 expression in the VSME and SIN</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Regulatory processes in the immunization site and SIN</measure>
    <time_frame>over 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Regulatory T cells (CD4+CD25hi FoxP3+)&#xD;
Myeloid suppressor cells&#xD;
Indole-amine dioxygenase&#xD;
PD-1, B7-H1&#xD;
IL-10 and IL-12 expression by dendritic cells (DC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">53</enrollment>
  <condition>Melanoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Vaccines will be administered subcutaneously, intradermally or transdermally in one skin location that is rotated to different sites on an extremity clinically uninvolved with melanoma.&#xD;
Vaccines will be administered on days 1, 8, 15, 36, 57, and 78.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Vaccines will be administered subcutaneously, intradermally or transdermally in one skin location that is rotated to different sites on an extremity clinically uninvolved with melanoma.&#xD;
Vaccines will be administered on days 1, 8, 15, 36, 57, and 78.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MELITAC 12.1 + Montanide ISA-51 + lipopolysaccharide (LPS)</intervention_name>
    <description>Cohort 1 will be divided into three sub-groups and will receive:&#xD;
Group 1a: MELITAC 12.1 + lipopolysaccharide (LPS)&#xD;
Group 1b: MELITAC 12.1 + lipopolysaccharide (LPS) + Montanide adjuvant with vaccination #1&#xD;
Group 1c: MELITAC 12.1 + lipopolysaccharide (LPS) adjuvant + Montanide adjuvant with all vaccinations</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>MELITAC 12.1 + Montanide ISA-51 + polyICLC</intervention_name>
    <description>Cohort 2 will be divided into three sub-groups and will receive:&#xD;
Group 2a: MELITAC 12.1 + polyICLC adjuvant&#xD;
Group 2b: MELITAC 12.1 + polyICLC adjuvant + Montanide adjuvant with vaccination #1&#xD;
Group 2c: MELITAC 12.1 + polyICLC adjuvant + Montanide adjuvant with all vaccinations</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically or cytologically proven melanoma that meets one of the following two&#xD;
             criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stage IIB-IV melanoma rendered clinically free of disease by surgery, other&#xD;
                  therapy, or spontaneous remission within 6 months prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stage III or IV melanoma with disease. Patients may be eligible if there are&#xD;
                  definite or equivocal findings of persistent or metastatic disease as long as&#xD;
                  those findings do not meet RECIST criteria for measurable disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with brain metastases may be eligible if all of the following are true:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The total number of brain metastases ever is less than or equal to 3.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The brain metastases have been completely removed by surgery or have been treated&#xD;
                  completely by stereotactic radiotherapy. Stereotactic radiotherapy, such as gamma&#xD;
                  knife, can be used up to 1 week prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  There has been no evident growth of any brain metastasis since treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No treated brain metastasis is greater than 2 cm in diameter at the time of&#xD;
                  protocol entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have at least two intact axillary and/or inguinal lymph node basins.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients must have:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ECOG performance status of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ability and willingness to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laboratory parameters as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HLA-A1, A2, A3, -A11, or -A31&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ANC &gt; 1000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelets &gt; 100,000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hgb ≥ 9 g/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST and ALT ≤ 2.5 x upper limits of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Bilirubin ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Alkaline Phosphatase ≤ 2.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Creatinine ≤ 1.5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HIV negative&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hepatitis C negative&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HGBA1C level of &lt; 7%&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have had brain metastases, unless they meet inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are currently receiving systemic cytotoxic chemotherapy, radiation, or&#xD;
             other experimental therapy, or who have received this therapy within the preceding 4&#xD;
             weeks. Gamma knife or stereotactic radiosurgery may be administered within the prior 4&#xD;
             weeks, but must not be administered less than one week prior to study enrollment.&#xD;
             Patients who are currently receiving nitrosoureas or who have received this therapy&#xD;
             within the preceding 6 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with clinically detectable melanoma deemed likely by the investigator to&#xD;
             require intervention during the first 12 weeks of the study that would require&#xD;
             premature discontinuation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known or suspected allergies to any component of the vaccine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving the following medications at study entry or within the preceding 4&#xD;
             weeks are excluded:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Agents with putative immunomodulating activity (with the exception of&#xD;
                  non-steroidal anti-inflammatory agents and topical steroids&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Allergy desensitization injections.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Systemic corticosteroids, administered parenterally or orally. Inhaled steroids&#xD;
                  (e.g. Advair®, Flovent®, Azmacort®) are not permitted. Topical corticosteroids&#xD;
                  are acceptable, including steroids with very low solubility administered nasally&#xD;
                  for local effects only (e.g. Nasonex®).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any growth factors (e.g. GM-CSF, G-CSF, erythropoietin).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Interferon therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Interleukin-2 or other interleukins.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Toll-like receptor agonists, including imiquimod or resiquimod.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior melanoma vaccinations may be an exclusion criterion in some circumstances:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who have recurred or progressed either after or during administration of&#xD;
                  a melanoma vaccine may be eligible to enroll 12 weeks following their last&#xD;
                  vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients may have been vaccinated previously with peptide vaccines (except that&#xD;
                  they may not have been vaccinated with peptides included in MELITAC 12.1 or&#xD;
                  MELITAC 12.6)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients may have been vaccinated with protein, DNA, or cell-based vaccines that&#xD;
                  include the proteins from which these peptides are derived.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other investigational drugs or investigational therapy if the patient is currently&#xD;
             taking those drugs/therapy, or if they have received the drugs/therapy within 1 month.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or the possibility of becoming pregnant during vaccine administration. Women&#xD;
             must also not be breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients in whom there is a medical contraindication or potential problem in complying&#xD;
             with the requirements of the protocol, in the opinion of the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients classified as having Class III or IV heart disease according to the New York&#xD;
             Heart Association&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Body weight &lt; 110 lbs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No active or prior autoimmune disorders requiring cytotoxic or immunosuppressive&#xD;
             therapy, or autoimmune disorders with visceral involvement. The following will not be&#xD;
             exclusionary:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The presence of laboratory evidence of autoimmune disease (e.g. positive ANA&#xD;
                  titer) without associated symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinical evidence of vitiligo&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Other forms of depigmenting illness&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mild arthritis requiring NSAID medications or no medical therapy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Craig L Slingluff, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Virginia</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Virginia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Charlottesville</city>
        <state>Virginia</state>
        <zip>22908</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 24, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 24, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 25, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 11, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 11, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">August 12, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Virginia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Craig L Slingluff, Jr</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Director, Human Immune Therapy Center</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>melanoma</keyword>
  <keyword>peptide vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>polyICLC</keyword>
  <keyword>lipopolysaccharide (LPS)</keyword>
  <keyword>immunotherapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Melanoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Freund's Adjuvant</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Poly ICLC</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

