<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01583998</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1R03MH092509-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01583998</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Electronic-Measurement Based Care for Major Depressive Disorder</brief_title>
  <acronym>e-MBC</acronym>
  <official_title>Electronic-Measurement Based Care (e-MBC) for Major Depressive Disorder (MDD)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The pilot study will evaluate whether electronic-Measurement Based Care (e-MBC) using the UT&#xD;
      Southwestern MyChart personal health record is feasible, associated with patient and health&#xD;
      care team satisfaction, and improves treatment outcomes compared to a standard treatment&#xD;
      model. The project will be conducted in the Simmons Cancer Center Clinic at the University of&#xD;
      Texas Southwestern Medical Center, Dallas as a collaborative effort between the Departments&#xD;
      of Psychiatry, Oncology, and Family and Community Medicine. The primary patient population&#xD;
      will include adults with significant depression and/or starting an antidepressant treatment&#xD;
      and/or experiencing a treatment change. The study will compare two groups, an e-MBC group and&#xD;
      an office-based standard care MBC group. Study staff will explain the study to the patients,&#xD;
      specifically explaining that study participants will receive either office-based MBC or&#xD;
      e-MBC. Eligible participants must be willing to receive either form of treatment monitoring.&#xD;
      Participating patients will be randomly assigned to receive either e-MBC or office-based MBC.&#xD;
      In the e-MBC group once a month the study nurse will send a prompt from the participating&#xD;
      patients treating physician requesting the patient to use the MyChart system to fill-out the&#xD;
      MBC scales. Beyond these monthly assessments, patients will be encouraged to utilize the&#xD;
      MyChart MBC assessments (e-MBC) at any time to communicate with their physician. Patients&#xD;
      experiencing difficulties using the e-MBC system will be given additional instruction by the&#xD;
      study nurse. Patients and physicians will be trained in the use of the eMBC system. In the&#xD;
      office-based MBC group the study nurse will schedule monthly treatment visits and request the&#xD;
      patient call as needed to report symptoms. The evaluation period will be 6 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Major Depressive Disorder (MDD) is a serious, debilitating illness that affects persons of&#xD;
      all ages, races, and socioeconomic backgrounds. Despite the availability of new and effective&#xD;
      treatments over the last 20 years, recent evidence continues to demonstrate high rates of&#xD;
      inadequate antidepressant medication treatment in practice settings. Practitioners vary&#xD;
      widely in how they assess treatment outcomes, including symptoms, function, side-effect&#xD;
      frequency and burden. In contrast to other chronic medical conditions such as diabetes&#xD;
      mellitus, back/neck problems, or hypertension, clinicians treating patients with depression&#xD;
      do not routinely evaluate measurement-based care (MBC) treatment parameters. MBC provides an&#xD;
      essential framework for physicians to approach depression treatment consistent with their&#xD;
      approach for other common disorders. MBC is an effective means to provide patient-centered&#xD;
      care for MDD, personalizing treatment decisions based on patient progress and their ability&#xD;
      to tolerate the medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A key barrier to patient adherence with MBC treatment is that the approach requires patients&#xD;
      to return to the clinic for several follow-up visits. The necessity of treatment visits&#xD;
      varies widely among patients. Thus far, physicians using MBC for the treatment of MDD do not&#xD;
      have a complete set of tools that are practical to use and allow treatment to be truly&#xD;
      personalized patient-centered care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One solution to this problem is to use an enhanced electronic personal health record, such as&#xD;
      the MyChart system. This system could be easily modified to include the central elements of&#xD;
      MBC for depression to allow for the systematic assessment of a patient's depressive symptom&#xD;
      severity, antidepressant tolerability, and adherence to treatment in a timely fashion. This&#xD;
      information would be available to allow the physician to provide patient-centered care by&#xD;
      utilizing standardized assessment to personalize treatment for depression. The proposed&#xD;
      electronic-MBC (e-MBC) addresses a critical gap in depression treatment by providing&#xD;
      regularly-scheduled drug monitoring and continuity of care, in the face of limited patient&#xD;
      and clinic resources.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information technology (IT) systems have been effectively integrated into the medical&#xD;
      treatment of patients but have yet to have substantial impact at the point-of-care. Applying&#xD;
      e-MBC methods allows physicians to utilize existing information technology systems to improve&#xD;
      depression treatment at the point-of-care. The key features of the proposed e-MBC approach&#xD;
      are that it can be seamlessly integrated into standard clinical practice, and requires no&#xD;
      additional IT knowledge or training to be effectively utilized by physicians and clinical&#xD;
      staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this pilot study the investigators will compare standard treatment (office based&#xD;
      antidepressant management) to a group receiving scheduled electronic MBC assessments via an&#xD;
      enhanced personal health record system (e-MBC). To date, no one has published feasibility&#xD;
      studies evaluating the use of personal health records for measurement-based care of&#xD;
      depression patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    UTSW Family Medicine refused to comply with agreement to implement study after department head&#xD;
    left university. Attempts to implement elsewhere failed.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 30 days for 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Depression severity assessment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency, Intensity, and Burden of Side Effect Rating (FIBSER)</measure>
    <time_frame>Every 30 days for 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Antidepressant side effects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Satisfaction Questionnaire (PSQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study treament (6 months from the first assessment)</time_frame>
    <description>Assesses satisfaction with care</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physician Evaluation of Ease of Use Survey (EEUS)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study treament (6 months from the first assessment)</time_frame>
    <description>Physicians' perception of the ease of use of the e-MBC system</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physician Evaluation of Usefulness Survey (EUS)</measure>
    <time_frame>At the end of study treament (6 months from the first assessment)</time_frame>
    <description>Physicians' perception of the usefulness of the e-MBC system</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Major Depressive Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>e-MBC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive e-MBC</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as Usual Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive standard treatment</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>e-MBC</intervention_name>
    <description>antidepressant treatment</description>
    <arm_group_label>e-MBC</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>e-MBC for MDD</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must plan to continue living in the clinic area throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be 18 to 65 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must give written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must have clinically significant depression and/or starting an antidepressant&#xD;
             treatment and/or experiencing a antidepressant treatment change&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must be willing and able to use MyChart to communicate with their physician&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a current Axis I diagnosis of Bipolar disorder or Schizophrenia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who cannot read and understand English since all research instruments are not&#xD;
             yet translated and validated in Spanish or other languages&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients whose clinical status requires inpatient treatment at the time of baseline&#xD;
             interview.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current substance abuse or dependence&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with current suicidal ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with general medical conditions that contraindicate antidepressant&#xD;
             medications&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dallas</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>75390</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2019</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 19, 2012</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 20, 2012</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">April 24, 2012</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 2, 2019</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 2, 2019</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2019</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>David W. Morris</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Major Depressive Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>MDD</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Measurement Based Care</keyword>
  <keyword>MBC</keyword>
  <keyword>electronic health records</keyword>
  <keyword>EHR</keyword>
  <keyword>electronic medical records</keyword>
  <keyword>EMR</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder, Major</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

