<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04007055</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY19030453</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04007055</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Value of Screening for HPR in Patients Undergoing Lower Extremity Arterial Endovascular Interventions</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Value of Screening for &quot;High on Treatment Platelet Reactivity&quot; in Patients Undergoing Lower Extremity Arterial Endovascular Interventions</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kyle Markel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pittsburgh</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized controlled trial designed to evaluate the role of screening for and&#xD;
      intervening on patients with high on treatment platelet reactivity undergoing lower extremity&#xD;
      arterial endovascular interventions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Peripheral arterial disease (PAD) affects millions of people worldwide. Management of PAD has&#xD;
      evolved from open surgery to an endovascular first approach leading to increased volume of&#xD;
      endovascular interventions. Endovascular femoropopliteal intervention has emerged as a&#xD;
      standard treatment for symptomatic PAD with acceptable patency rates.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Histologic observation of bare metal stents with early failure shows association with&#xD;
      platelet rich thrombus, high counts of platelets, and neutrophils associated with stent&#xD;
      struts. Additionally, high inflation pressures associated with balloon angioplasty often&#xD;
      causes local tissue damage leading to platelet activation. These findings led to studies&#xD;
      targeting platelet activation following endovascular treatment showing improved outcomes in&#xD;
      patients receiving stronger platelet inhibition.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The current standard of care is prescription of dual antiplatelet therapy (DAPT) for&#xD;
      femoropopliteal angioplasty or stenting. DAPT is active use of any two antiplatelet agents,&#xD;
      often low dose aspirin plus P2Y12 inhibitor (clopidogrel, ticagrelor, prasugrel). There is&#xD;
      improved stent patency and reduced adverse cardiovascular events in patients taking DAPT&#xD;
      versus aspirin monotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clopidogrel is the most common additional antiplatelet agent prescribed, but 4-65% of&#xD;
      patients taking clopidogrel fail to achieve clinically expected platelet inhibition. This&#xD;
      persistent platelet reactivity despite compliant antiplatelet use is commonly referred to as&#xD;
      high on-treatment platelet reactivity (HPR), and increases risk of endovascular intervention&#xD;
      failure and associated adverse clinical events in these patients. Clopidogrel is a pro-drug&#xD;
      metabolized by CYP2C19 enzyme into its active form. Failure to respond appropriately to&#xD;
      clopidogrel is largely due to genetic polymorphisms within CYP2C19 enzyme resulting in&#xD;
      variable metabolization of clopidogrel into the active metabolite.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternative antiplatelet medications can overcome HPR through different metabolic pathways,&#xD;
      but unfortunately at a significantly higher cost. Of these, ticagrelor is often used to&#xD;
      overcome HPR for patients taking clopidogrel with favorable outcomes. However, regional cost&#xD;
      for ticagrelor is $352.50 compared to $1.96 for clopidogrel. Cost and bleeding concerns among&#xD;
      providers have prevented widespread use. Overall, there is paucity of evidence looking at HPR&#xD;
      and lower extremity arterial endovascular interventions without consensus or guidelines on&#xD;
      how to address this problem. Thus, the investigators propose an unblinded, randomized&#xD;
      controlled trial in patients having femoropopliteal angioplasty or stenting comparing two&#xD;
      strategies: 1. testing and treating for HPR versus 2. guideline based therapy without testing&#xD;
      for HPR.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 9, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Screening</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of participants with primary patency</measure>
    <time_frame>one year from intervention</time_frame>
    <description>primary patency is freedom from re-intervention, freedom from complete vessel occlusion, freedom from &gt;50% restenosis with duplex ultrasound or freedom from &gt;70% restenosis with computed tomography angiography</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>proportion of participants with amputation</measure>
    <time_frame>one year from intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Freedom from new amputation on the lower extremity intervened on during study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation of HPR testing results</measure>
    <time_frame>after study completion</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation of HPR results between VerifyNow and CYP2C19 pharmacogenetics testing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Major adverse cardiovascular events</measure>
    <time_frame>one year from intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Any new stroke, myocardial infarction, death during study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">296</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Artery Disease</condition>
  <condition>Clopidogrel, Poor Metabolism of</condition>
  <condition>Peripheral Vascular Disease</condition>
  <condition>Artery Disease</condition>
  <condition>Peripheral Arterial Occlusive Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: screening/treating for HPR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to this arm will be screened and treated for HPR. Pharmacogenetics testing for CYP2C19 polymorphisms will be collected, stored, and analyzed at study completion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control: guideline based therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to this arm will receive usual care without screening for HPR. Pharmacogenetics testing for CYP2C19 polymorphisms will be collected, stored, and analyzed at study completion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Point of care screening for HPR</intervention_name>
    <description>HPR testing using VerifyNow testing system. HPR is defined platelet reactivity units are greater than 234</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: screening/treating for HPR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ticagrelor 90mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants who test positive for HPR will be prescribed ticagrelor 90mg twice daily instead of standard therapy with clopidogrel 75mg daily</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: screening/treating for HPR</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Peripheral arterial disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned angioplasty or stenting of superficial femoral artery or popliteal artery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated on an emergency basis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned intervention on prior site of open surgical intervention (autogenous or&#xD;
             autologous bypass, endarterectomy, or patch angioplasty)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned intervention at site exclusive of superficial femoral artery or popliteal&#xD;
             artery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned re-stenting at site of prior stent placement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planned re-angioplasty at site of prior angioplasty&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known inability to tolerate antiplatelet regimen before enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who plan on receiving follow up care outside the University of Pittsburgh&#xD;
             Medical Center&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of prasugrel or ticlopidine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of oral anticoagulation medication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>90 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Kyle Markel</last_name>
    <phone>412-802-3031</phone>
    <email>markelkm2@upmc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Pittsburgh Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pittsburgh</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>15213</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kyle Markel</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 1, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>July 1, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">July 5, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Pittsburgh</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kyle Markel</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident in Vascular Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Arterial Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Peripheral Vascular Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arterial Occlusive Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ticagrelor</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

