<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04002102</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB-300003575</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04002102</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Open-Label Placebos to Treat Fatigue in Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Open-Label Placebos to Treat Fatigue in Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alabama at Birmingham</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alabama at Birmingham</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Fatigue is one of the most prevalent and disabling symptoms of multiple sclerosis. Current&#xD;
      treatments, including pharmacological, physical therapy, sleep regulation and psychological&#xD;
      interventions are of marginal benefit. Pharmacological treatments have inconsistent evidence.&#xD;
      Recent studies show that non-deceptive open-label placebos (OLP) have moderate-to-large&#xD;
      effects on symptoms, including fatigue, in adults with a variety of medical conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hence, this is a pilot and feasibility study to obtain data on the feasibility and effects of&#xD;
      OLP for multiple sclerosis related fatigue and its impact to provide the basis for a&#xD;
      competitive NIH application. This pilot study will be the first study to evaluate whether&#xD;
      OLP, that garners full consent and engages patients in their wellness, may offer a safe,&#xD;
      effective treatment for multiple sclerosis related fatigue.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this pilot study is to evaluate the feasibility of recruiting, enrolling and&#xD;
      retaining participants in a study on the acceptability and effects of a non-deceptive&#xD;
      (open-label) administration of placebo pills for treating MS related fatigue. Specific Aim 1&#xD;
      will assess the feasibility endpoints including accrual (enroll 44 participants), retention&#xD;
      (80% of the sample) and placebo adherence (90%). Specific Aim 2 will evaluate the&#xD;
      between-group changes in fatigue, quality of life, cognitive functioning and self-efficacy.&#xD;
      Specific Aim 3 will evaluate participant acceptability, satisfaction and experience.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This pilot study is a randomized control trial consisting of three arms: open label placebo&#xD;
      arm, expectancy arm, and usual care arm. The clinical coordinator will review medical&#xD;
      records, enroll and consent participants based on the following inclusion criteria: diagnosis&#xD;
      of MS, 19 years or older, report of moderate to severe fatigue, PDDS score of &lt; 7, and stable&#xD;
      dose of DMTs for 90 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria consists of: major comorbid conditions and use of off label medications or&#xD;
      exercise programs in the past 30 days, and if one is confined to a wheelchair.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline and 21 day tele assessments will involve objective measures performed by a physical&#xD;
      therapist, Single Digit Modality Test (SDMT) and Five Time Sit to Stand (FTSST) and&#xD;
      subjective questionnaires sent to participant's email including Modified Fatigue Impact Scale&#xD;
      (MFIS), Functional Systems Score (FSS), Patient Reported Outcomes Measurement Information&#xD;
      System (PROMIS), Perceived Deficits Questionnaire, Epworth Sleepiness Scale, and the SF-36&#xD;
      assess of quality of life. Participants will be randomized by the clinical coordinator after&#xD;
      baseline testing. The open label placebo and expectancy arm will meet with the care provider&#xD;
      who will follow a scripted orientation that mimics a typical patient-provider interaction&#xD;
      when prescribing a medication, including the rationale for effectiveness. The provider will&#xD;
      emphasize the importance of adherence to the medication for the open label placebo arm and&#xD;
      the breathing exercises for the expectancy arm for the next 21 days. A tracking sheet will be&#xD;
      provided to both arms to document adherence. The usual care arm will meet with the care&#xD;
      provider who will follow a scripted orientation on fatigue and heat management strategies.&#xD;
      All participants will receive educational materials on fatigue and heat management. A day 11&#xD;
      check in call will be made to gauge progress and answer questions. After the 21 day tele&#xD;
      assessment is performed, the participant will complete subjective questionnaires via email&#xD;
      for 28 day and 35 day follow up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline fatigue at 21 days using the Fatigue Severity Scale (FSS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later, the participant will spend 10 minutes each assessment completing this scale.</time_frame>
    <description>This scale is used to measure fatigue and the scale has a range from 9-63 with 9 being the best possible score and 63 being the worst score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline impact of fatigue at 21 days using the Modified Fatigue Impact Scale (MFIS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later, the participant will spend 15 minutes each assessment completing this scale.</time_frame>
    <description>This scale is used to measure fatigue and the scale has a range from 0 to 84 with 0 being the best possible score and 84 being the worst score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline quality of life at 21 days using the 36-item Short Form survey (SF-36).</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later, the participant will spend 15 minutes each assessment completing this scale.</time_frame>
    <description>The scores for this survey range from 0-100 with 0 being the worst possible score and 100 being the best possible score.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline sleepiness at 21 days using the Epworth Sleepiness Scale (ESS).</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later, the participant will spend 15 minutes each assessment completing this scale.</time_frame>
    <description>This scale is used to measure sleepiness and the scale has a range from 0-24 with 0 being the best possible score and 24 being the worst.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline neurological functioning at 21 days using the Perceived Deficit Questionnaire 5-Item Version (PDQ-5).</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later, the participant will spend 15 minutes each assessment completing this scale.</time_frame>
    <description>The scores for this questionnaire range from 5-25 with 5 being the best possible score and 25 being the worst possible score.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Godin Leisure-Time Exercise Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later</time_frame>
    <description>A self-explanatory, brief four-item query of usual leisure-time exercise habits</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline general self efficacy for managing chronic conditions at 21 days using the PROMIS instrument</measure>
    <time_frame>Participants will complete this scale at baseline and 21 days later, the participant will spend 15 minutes each assessment completing this scale.</time_frame>
    <description>The scores for this tool are coded separately for each of the 10 questions and range from 1-5 for questions Global01-06, 08r, 09r, and 10r with 1 being the worst possible score and 5 being the best possible score and a range from 0-10 for question Global07r with 0 being the worst possible score and 10 being the best possible score.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">48</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <condition>Fatigue</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>OLP treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to the treatment group will receive: 1) educational materials; 2) positive expectancy; 3) 2 placebo pills twice a day for 21 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants randomized to the no treatment group will remain in standard care alone for 21 days and receive educational materials.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Expectancy Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants receive educational materials and positive expectancy orientation via Zoom or telephone</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OLP treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Receive two open-label placebo pills twice a day after randomization. Will receive for 21 days and then stop. It will include educational materials and positive expectancy.</description>
    <arm_group_label>OLP treatment</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Open-Label placebo</other_name>
    <other_name>Glucose Tablet</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Usual care</intervention_name>
    <description>Remain in standard care after randomization and educational materials.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Standard care</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Expectancy Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Educational materials and positive expectancy orientation via Zoom or telephone</description>
    <arm_group_label>Expectancy Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Education</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of MS&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged 19 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  report moderate-to-severe fatigue (i.e., ≥4 on the FSS)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient Determined Disease Steps score of ≥7.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major comorbid conditions that might influence fatigue (e.g. lupus, chronic fatigue&#xD;
             syndrome)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients treated with off label medications or exercise program in the past 30 days.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tapan S Mehta, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chia-Ying Chiu, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>205-396-9002</phone>
    <email>chia53@uab.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tanner Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35209</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Tracy Tracy, OT</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Alabama at Birmingham</name>
      <address>
        <city>Birmingham</city>
        <state>Alabama</state>
        <zip>35294</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chia-Ying Chiu, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>205-396-9002</phone>
      <email>chia53@uab.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tapan S Mehta</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>June 25, 2019</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>June 26, 2019</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">June 28, 2019</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alabama at Birmingham</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Tapan Shirish Mehta</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Placebo</keyword>
  <keyword>Open-Label</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatigue</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>To be determined. Sharing study protocol, statistical analysis plan, and informed consent.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Will be posted on CT.gov</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>To be determined</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

