<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03743870</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>125/2018/PO</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03743870</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Spinal Anesthesia in Caesarean Section</brief_title>
  <official_title>Spinal Anesthesia in Caesarean Section: Comparison Between Levobupivacaine and Hyperbaric Bupivacaine</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Azienda Ospedaliera, Universitaria Policlinico Vittorio Emanuele</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Marinella Astuto</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Azienda Ospedaliera, Universitaria Policlinico Vittorio Emanuele</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Spinal anesthesia is a safe technique, widely used and tested in the gynecological field, so&#xD;
      as to be considered the first choice technique in cesarean section, which allows to quickly&#xD;
      obtain a valid sensor and motor block. Bupivacaine is one of the most widely used drug for&#xD;
      obtaining spinal anesthesia in pregnant women undergoing caesarean section. Bupivacaine is a&#xD;
      local anesthetic available as a racemic mixture of its two enantiomers, the R (+)-&#xD;
      dextrobupivacaine and the S (-) - levobupivacaine, whose clinical use is widely validated.&#xD;
      Racemic bupivacaine is available as a simple or hyperbaric solution, the latter being the&#xD;
      most commonly used for spinal anesthesia. Levobupivacaine, which is the pure levorotatory&#xD;
      enantiomer of racemic bupivacaine, is a slightly hypobaric solution compared to liquor and&#xD;
      has shown less heart and nerve toxicity, probably due to its ability to bind proteins more&#xD;
      rapidly, and a greater selectivity towards the sensory component compared to Bupivacaine,&#xD;
      presents action and effects better predictable. Its baricity would also offer the advantage&#xD;
      of providing a less sensitive block to the position.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotension is one of the most common complications of spinal anesthesia and is particularly&#xD;
      relevant in caesarean section because, in addition to the adverse effects on the parturient,&#xD;
      it can have repercussions on the fetus through a reduction of placental perfusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some studies have showed a similar incidence of hypotension in patients treated with&#xD;
      bupivacaine compared to those treated with levobupivacaine, while others assert an&#xD;
      equivalence between the two drugs. In most studies, however, a significantly lower incidence&#xD;
      of hypotension and a greater hemodynamic stability were reported in pregnant patients&#xD;
      undergoing spinal anesthesia by caesarean section with levobupivacaine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Being both hyperbaric bupivacaine and levobupivacaine routinely used at the &quot;G. Rodolico&quot;&#xD;
      Universitary Hospital of Catania for the spinal anesthesia of pregnant women undergoing&#xD;
      caesarean section and being their use decided exclusively at discretion of the treating&#xD;
      anesthesiologist, in the light of the discrepant data in the literature about the incidence&#xD;
      of hypotension with the two drugs, the main objective of this observational study is to&#xD;
      evaluate the hemodynamic effects mediated by levobupivacaine on pregnant women subjected to&#xD;
      elective cesarean section and to compare them with those mediated by hyperbaric bupivacaine&#xD;
      in an historical court of pregnant women subjected to caesarean section in the period between&#xD;
      April 2017 and April 2018. The hemodynamic parameters will be monitored in real time with a&#xD;
      non-invasive hemodynamic monitoring system (EV1000® platform + Clearsight® system - Edwards&#xD;
      LifeSciences), routinely used in the &quot;G. Rodolico&quot; Universitary Hospital of Catania, allowing&#xD;
      to obtain greater accuracy and veracity of the results compared to previous studies conducted&#xD;
      on such anesthetics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective, monocentric, not for-profit, observational study, with historical&#xD;
      control group, whose primary objective is the monitoring of changes in the hemodynamic&#xD;
      condition, intended as continuous pressure measurements by means of a non-invasive system&#xD;
      (EV1000® platform + Clearsight® system - Edwards Lifesciences), of a group of 125 pregnant&#xD;
      women who have to undergo spinal anesthesia with Levobupivacaine for elective cesarean&#xD;
      section at the &quot;G. Rodolico&quot; Presidium of Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria&#xD;
      &quot;Policlinco-Vittorio Emanuele&quot; of Catania, and to compare them with those detected, with the&#xD;
      same non-invasive system, in an historical cohort of 125 patients who underwent spinal&#xD;
      anesthesia with Bupivacaine for an elective caesarean section in the period between April&#xD;
      2017 and April 2018.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will have an expected duration of one year from the time of its approval.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the levobupivacaine group, during the preoperative anesthesiological examination, carried&#xD;
      out approximately two weeks before the scheduled date of the surgical intervention, informed&#xD;
      consent will be acquired and the eligible patients will be enrolled. On this occasion, an ASA&#xD;
      class will be assigned and the following data will be collected:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  personal and general data:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  date of birth and age&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  current weight&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  weight before pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  height&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  information concerning:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  any previous or concomitant diseases affecting the nervous, respiratory,&#xD;
                cardiovascular system&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  any previous or concomitant disease interesting: gastrointestinal system,&#xD;
                hemolymphatic system, thyroid, pancreas, kidneys, liver, adrenal glands&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  any immunodeficiencies&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  any coagulopathies&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  spinal deformities&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  previous surgeries&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  previous allergic events following the administration of drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  seasonal allergies&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  previous pregnancies and their characteristics&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  possible hypertension during the last quarter&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  conditions that represent contraindications for spinal anesthesia. Upon arrival in&#xD;
                the operating room, the Clearsight® non-invasive hemodynamic monitoring system will&#xD;
                be placed at the fingers of the parturient and the usual intraoperative monitoring&#xD;
                (ECG, non-invasive blood pressure, oxygen saturation) will be applied. The&#xD;
                continuous recording of the following hemodynamic parameters, which will last for&#xD;
                the whole duration of the intervention, will then begin through the EV1000®&#xD;
                platform (Edwards Lifesciences): Cardiac Output (CO); Cardiac Index (CI); Stroke&#xD;
                Volume (SV); Stroke Volume Index (SVI); Stroke Volume Variation (SVV); Pulse Rate&#xD;
                Variation (PRV); Systemic Vascular Resistance (SVR); Systemic Vascular Resistance&#xD;
                Index (SVRI); Central Venous Oxygen Saturation (ScvO2); Pulse rate (PR); Systolic&#xD;
                Pressure (SYS); Diastolic Pressure (DIA); Mean Arterial Pressure (MAP); Central&#xD;
                Venous Pressure (CVP).These measurements will be made every twenty seconds.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the monitoring system has been applied, the patients will be placed in position and&#xD;
      spinal anesthesia will be performed with Levobupivacaine 12 mg 0.5% and Fentanyl 25γ. Once&#xD;
      the anesthetic is injected, patients will be subjected to dislocation of the uterus and&#xD;
      placed in left lateral tilt. Once the sensory and motor block has been obtained, the surgery&#xD;
      will begin. In the event of adverse reactions to the drug, therapeutic measures that are part&#xD;
      of the usual clinical practice will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any episodes of hypotension during the operation will be treated by administration of 5 mg&#xD;
      etilefrine in bolus and/or IV fluids; any episodes of bradycardia will be treated by&#xD;
      administration of IV atropine 0.01 mg/kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sensory block will be evaluated by objective examination: the investigators will evaluate the&#xD;
      tactile discrimination ability of a blunt tip in contact with the patient's back, thus&#xD;
      determining the level of anesthesia reached and the time in which it occurs. The measurements&#xD;
      of this parameter will be carried out every fifteen minutes, during the first half hour, and&#xD;
      then at thirty and sixty minutes until the restitutio of the physiological condition of the&#xD;
      patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The motor block will be evaluated by Bromage score, ie by observing the residual motor&#xD;
      capacity of the patient's lower limbs. The measurements of this parameter will be carried out&#xD;
      every fifteen minutes, during the first half hour, and then at thirty and sixty minutes until&#xD;
      the restitutio of the physiological condition of the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For calculating the Aldrete's score, the following parameters will be assessed: respiration&#xD;
      and consciousness through objective examination, systolic blood pressure using the classic&#xD;
      intraoperative monitoring system and pulse oximetry oxygenation. The measurements of this&#xD;
      score will be carried out every fifteen minutes during the first half hour, and then at&#xD;
      thirty and sixty minutes until the restitutio of the physiological condition of the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patient data from the historical cohort will be collected by reviewing the clinical&#xD;
      documentation related to the individual case.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once collected, the data will be subjected to statistical and comparative processing in order&#xD;
      to highlight statistically relevant differences concerning the effects mediated by the two&#xD;
      anesthetics on the pregnant patient who undergoes elective cesarean section.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data obtained will be analyzed using the SPSS software (Statistical Package for Social&#xD;
      Sciences), version 21.0 for Windows (SPSS Inc., Chicago, Illinois, USA). Differences with p≤&#xD;
      0.05 will be considered significant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The descriptive analysis will be performed using frequencies, percentages and frequency&#xD;
      tables for qualitative variables. For the normally distributed quantitative variables the&#xD;
      mean and standard deviation will be used, while for those not normally distributed the median&#xD;
      and the interquartile range (IQR) will be used. For the comparison between the two groups&#xD;
      will be used the Chi-square test with Yates correction or Fisher exact test for qualitative&#xD;
      variables and the Mann-Whitney U test for quantitative variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Multivariate analysis will be performed using logistic regression models and the ORs (odds&#xD;
      ratios) will be reported together with the corresponding 95% confidence intervals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">April 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in blood pressure measured continuously by the EV1000® platform and the Clearsight® non-invasive system (Edwards Lifesciences) in the two study cohorts</measure>
    <time_frame>From arrival in the operating room until the completion of surgical procedures</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of hypotension during spinal anesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes after completion of surgical procedures</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of bradycardia during spinal anesthesia</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes after completion of surgical procedures</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for inotropes and / or vasopressor during surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes after completion of surgical procedures</time_frame>
    <description>Doses of inotropes and / or vasopressor administered during surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for fluids administration during surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes after completion of surgical procedures</time_frame>
    <description>Volume of fluids administered during surgery for the eventual treatment of hypotension</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of the sensory block reached</measure>
    <time_frame>At 15 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in which sensory block occurs</measure>
    <time_frame>At 15 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of the sensory block reached</measure>
    <time_frame>At 30 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in which sensory block occurs</measure>
    <time_frame>At 30 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of sensory block reached</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time in which sensory block occurs</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of the motor block reached by modified Bromage scale</measure>
    <time_frame>At 15 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Bromage scale is a six-point scale used to asses the intensity of motor block by evaluation of the patient's ability to move their lower extremities: Score 1 = Complete block (unable to move feet or knees); Score 2 = Almost complete block (able to move feet only); Score 3 = Partial block (just able to move knees); Score 4 = Detectable weakness of hip flexion while supine (full flexion of knees); Score 5 = No detectable weakness of hip flexion while supine; Score 6 = Able to perform partial knee bend. The motor block is measured in both legs intermittently throughout labour, as the degree of block can change.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of the motor block reached by modified Bromage scale</measure>
    <time_frame>At 30 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Bromage scale is a six-point scale used to asses the intensity of motor block by evaluation of the patient's ability to move their lower extremities: Score 1 = Complete block (unable to move feet or knees); Score 2 = Almost complete block (able to move feet only); Score 3 = Partial block (just able to move knees); Score 4 = Detectable weakness of hip flexion while supine (full flexion of knees); Score 5 = No detectable weakness of hip flexion while supine; Score 6 = Able to perform partial knee bend. The motor block is measured in both legs intermittently throughout labour, as the degree of block can change.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of the motor block reached by modified Bromage scale</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The modified Bromage scale is a six-point scale used to asses the intensity of motor block by evaluation of the patient's ability to move their lower extremities: Score 1 = Complete block (unable to move feet or knees); Score 2 = Almost complete block (able to move feet only); Score 3 = Partial block (just able to move knees); Score 4 = Detectable weakness of hip flexion while supine (full flexion of knees); Score 5 = No detectable weakness of hip flexion while supine; Score 6 = Able to perform partial knee bend. The motor block is measured in both legs intermittently throughout labour, as the degree of block can change.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aldrete score evaluation.</measure>
    <time_frame>At 15 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The evaluation of Aldrete score, also known Post Anesthesia Recovery (PAR), focuses on the following directions: muscle activity, assessed by observing the patient's ability to move his extremities on command; respiratory efficiency, reflected by the respiratory effort; circulation, evaluated through systemic blood pressure and compared to the preanesthetic level; consciousness, reflected by full alertness and ability to answer questions; tegument color, that evaluates whether the skin aspect is normal or cyanotic or jaundiced. Each of the five items in the Aldrete score calculation is awarded from 0 to 2 points, depending on the answer chosen in the evaluation. The higher the score, the more likelihood of recovery without need of observation. Results vary between 0 and 10. Patients with scores of 9 and 10 can be safely discharged from operatory room. Scores of 10 indicate a patient in the best condition. Scores of 7 and below come with indication of continuous close observation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aldrete's score evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>At 30 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The evaluation of Aldrete score, also known Post Anesthesia Recovery (PAR), focuses on the following directions: muscle activity, assessed by observing the patient's ability to move his extremities on command; respiratory efficiency, reflected by the respiratory effort; circulation, evaluated through systemic blood pressure and compared to the preanesthetic level; consciousness, reflected by full alertness and ability to answer questions; tegument color, that evaluates whether the skin aspect is normal or cyanotic or jaundiced. Each of the five items in the Aldrete score calculation is awarded from 0 to 2 points, depending on the answer chosen in the evaluation. The higher the score, the more likelihood of recovery without need of observation. Results vary between 0 and 10. Patients with scores of 9 and 10 can be safely discharged from operatory room. Scores of 10 indicate a patient in the best condition. Scores of 7 and below come with indication of continuous close observation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Aldrete's score evaluation</measure>
    <time_frame>At 60 minutes from the beginning of anesthesia</time_frame>
    <description>The evaluation of Aldrete score, also known Post Anesthesia Recovery (PAR), focuses on the following directions: muscle activity, assessed by observing the patient's ability to move his extremities on command; respiratory efficiency, reflected by the respiratory effort; circulation, evaluated through systemic blood pressure and compared to the preanesthetic level; consciousness, reflected by full alertness and ability to answer questions; tegument color, that evaluates whether the skin aspect is normal or cyanotic or jaundiced. Each of the five items in the Aldrete score calculation is awarded from 0 to 2 points, depending on the answer chosen in the evaluation. The higher the score, the more likelihood of recovery without need of observation. Results vary between 0 and 10. Patients with scores of 9 and 10 can be safely discharged from operatory room. Scores of 10 indicate a patient in the best condition. Scores of 7 and below come with indication of continuous close observation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">250</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypotension Drug-Induced</condition>
  <condition>Cesarean Section Complications</condition>
  <condition>Spinal Anesthetics Causing Adverse Effects in Therapeutic Use</condition>
  <condition>Bradycardia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>levobupivacaine cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>125 pregnant patients that will have to undergo spinal anesthesia with Levobupivacaine for elective caesarean section.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>bupivacaine cohort</arm_group_label>
    <description>Historical control group made of 125 patients underwent spinal anesthesia with Bupivacaine for elective cesarean section during the period between April 2017 and April 2018.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Levobupivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>Levobupivacaine will be spinally administered, as required by normal clinical practice, at the dose of 12 mg 0,5% in combination with fentanyl 25γ.</description>
    <arm_group_label>levobupivacaine cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bupivacaine</intervention_name>
    <description>Bupivacaine has been spinally administered, as required by normal clinical practice, at the dose of 12 mg 0,5% in combination with fentanyl 25γ.</description>
    <arm_group_label>bupivacaine cohort</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study will involve consecutive pregnant womento to be subjected/subjected to spinal&#xD;
        anesthesia for cesarean section at the Obstetric Emergency Room of the &quot;G. Rodolico&quot;&#xD;
        Presidium of the Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria &quot;Policlinco-Vittorio Emanuele&quot; of&#xD;
        Catania that meet the inclusion and criteria of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  signature of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age between 18 and 40 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  indication for spinal anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anesthesiology (ASA) classification I or II&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  height less than 180 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  weight less than 100 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  absence of spinal deformities&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age under 18 years old or over 40 yers old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ASA III or IV&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindications to spinal anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of hemodynamically relevant cardiovascular co-morbidities&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  co-morbidities requiring invasive monitoring&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  refusal of pregnant women to sign informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  refusal of pregnant women to spinal anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  spinal deformities in pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known hypersensitivity to the anesthetics used&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  weight over 100 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  height over 180 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  preeclampsia or eclampsia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of fetal or placental abnormalities such as placenta previa or placental&#xD;
             abruption&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carmelo Minardi, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 3398643162</phone>
    <email>minardi.carmelo@virgilio.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>&quot;G. Rodolico&quot; Presidium of the Azienda Ospedaliero Universitaria &quot;Policlinico-Vittorio Emanuele&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Catania</city>
        <zip>95123</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Carmelo Minardi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+39 3398643162</phone>
      <email>minardi.carmelo@virgilio.it</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Carmelo Minardi, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Marinella Astuto, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alberto Morgana, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 31, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">November 16, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Azienda Ospedaliera, Universitaria Policlinico Vittorio Emanuele</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carmelo Minardi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>intraoperative hypotension</keyword>
  <keyword>bupivacaine</keyword>
  <keyword>levobupivacaine</keyword>
  <keyword>cesarean section</keyword>
  <keyword>spinal anaesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>intraoperative bradycardia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypotension</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bradycardia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bupivacaine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Levobupivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

