<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01054508</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TRED012010</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01049</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01054508</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Tredaptive on Serum Lipoproteins and Inflammatory Markers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Tredaptive on Serum Lipoproteins, Lipoproteins Metabolism, Oxidative Stress and HDL Antioxidant Function</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is associated with high levels of low-density lipoprotein (LDL)&#xD;
      cholesterol and low levels of high-density lipoprotein (HDL) cholesterol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CVD results from 'hardening of the arteries' when there is a build-up of cholesterol in the&#xD;
      walls of blood vessels. LDL is the main carrier of cholesterol in the body. LDL particles are&#xD;
      responsible for transporting cholesterol that is deposited in vessel walls. LDL particles can&#xD;
      also be altered in structure and turn into an irritant to the vessel walls. The body responds&#xD;
      to the irritating effect of LDL by producing substances that result in inflammation. This&#xD;
      sequence of events eventually leads to the vessels becoming permanently damaged. HDL has a&#xD;
      protective role in CVD. It is associated with the enzyme paraoxonase which protects the body&#xD;
      from the damaging effects of altered LDL particles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nicotinic acid (niacin) has the ability to lower LDL levels and raise HDL levels thus&#xD;
      reducing the incidence of CVD. Our study aims to show that niacin not only has good effects&#xD;
      on cholesterol levels but is also able to reduce inflammation. Niacin is often poorly&#xD;
      tolerated due to flushing side effect. Tredaptive is a formulation that combines niacin with&#xD;
      laropiprant, an agent that reduces flushing hence improving tolerability and compliance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who are receiving cholesterol-lowering medication and whose LDL levels have not&#xD;
      reached the recommended target are recruited to the study. The study will be conducted at the&#xD;
      Manchester Royal Infirmary. The study has two consecutive 16 week periods. In each period&#xD;
      patients will be randomised to either tredaptive or placebo. They will attend for 5&#xD;
      monitoring visits. Apart from the first visit, fasting blood samples will be taken from them&#xD;
      during all subsequent visits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The design is a placebo-controlled cross-over study. The study has 2 consecutive 16 week&#xD;
      periods. If a patient satisfies the inclusion/exclusion criteria and consents to participate&#xD;
      in the study, he/she will enter a 4-week placebo run-in period. This is followed by a 12-week&#xD;
      treatment period where the patient will be assigned tredaptive or placebo randomly. At the&#xD;
      end of the treatment period the patient will enter a second 4-week placebo period before&#xD;
      going onto the second 12-week treatment period. Patients who are randomised to placebo in the&#xD;
      first treatment period will receive tredaptive in the second treatment period and vice versa.&#xD;
      Thus all participating patients will receive active medication for one treatment period in&#xD;
      the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will continue taking statins for the duration of the study, ensuring the&#xD;
      cholesterol-lowering benefits they have from their usual medication are not compromised.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited from the Lipid Clinic at the Manchester Royal Infirmary. The study&#xD;
      will be explained fully to the patients who will have time to ask questions. Information&#xD;
      leaflets will be given to patients who will be encouraged to take at least 1 day to discuss&#xD;
      the study with their families, friends and general practitioners before consenting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study comprises 5 visits. At the first visit, informed consent will be taken from the&#xD;
      patients. The visit also includes history taking and physical examination. Subsequent visits&#xD;
      take place at the end of 4th and 16th weeks. This is repeated for the second 16 week period.&#xD;
      Apart from the first visit, patients will be required to give a blood sample of 50 ml at each&#xD;
      of the visits. They will be asked to fast overnight (from 22.00 hours) the day before the&#xD;
      visit and blood sampling will be done before midday the following day. Blood will be taken by&#xD;
      an experienced doctor or nurse and the only risks involved may be bruising at the puncture&#xD;
      site.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in HDL Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>14 months</time_frame>
    <description>As exactly listed in the protocol, the primary outcome will be changes in HDL-C level. The mean value will be assessed before and after treatment. This level will be compared to the mean value between the placebo and Tredaptive groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in paraoxonase activity</measure>
    <time_frame>14 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in PON1</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in LDL</measure>
    <time_frame>14 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in oxidised LDL and glycated LDL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in HDL inflammatory index</measure>
    <time_frame>14 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in HDL inflammatory index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">38</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypercholesterolemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1: Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (12 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Tredaptive (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (12 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Tredaptive (12 weeks) There were two interventional periods of 12 weeks during which patients received either Placebo or Tredaptive (nicotinic acid/laropiprant). Patient who received Tredaptive were given dosages of 1g/20mg for 4 weeks followed by 2g/40mg for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2: Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Tredaptive (12 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Tredaptive (12 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (12 weeks) There were two interventional periods of 12 weeks during which patients received either Placebo or Tredaptive (nicotinic acid/laropiprant). Patient who received Tredaptive were given dosages of 1g/20mg for 4 weeks followed by 2g/40mg for 8 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>nicotinic acid/laropiprant</intervention_name>
    <description>Nicotinic acid/laropiprant (1g/20mg) daily for 4 weeks, then nicotinic acid/laropiprant (2g/40mg) daily for 8 weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 1: Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (12 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Tredaptive (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm 2: Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Tredaptive (12 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (4 weeks) --&gt; Placebo (12 weeks)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Tredaptive</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -Men and women who are taking cholesterol-lowering medication (maximum tolerated statins&#xD;
        and/or ezetimibe) and who have not reached the recommended LDL target of less than 1.8&#xD;
        mmol/l (70 mg/l). Ezetimibe will be stopped 4 weeks before entering the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant and/or breast-feeding women.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant renal impairment (eGFR &lt; 59ml/min).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active liver disease and transaminases &gt; 3 times upper limit of normal range.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on fibrates.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on Omacor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are allergic to nicotinic acid.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Handrean Soran, MRCP</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Manchester University NHS Foundation Trust</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Manchester Royal Infirmary</name>
      <address>
        <city>Manchester</city>
        <zip>M13 9WL</zip>
        <country>United Kingdom</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 21, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 22, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 26, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nicotinic Acids</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Niacin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Niacinamide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

