<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01051934</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>100032</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>10-C-0032</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01051934</nct_id>
    <nct_alias>NCT01041118</nct_alias>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Phase I Trial of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 With Paclitaxel, Carboplatin, and Bevacizumab in Subjects With Unresectable Non-Small Cell Lung Adenocarcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Trial of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 With Paclitaxel, Carboplatin, and Bevacizumab in Subjects With Unresectable Non-Small Cell Lung Adenocarcinoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Advanced cases of non-small-cell lung carcinoma (NSCLC) usually are not successfully&#xD;
           treated with standard therapies. Even treatments that attempt to specifically target&#xD;
           NSCLC cells have not proved effective.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Researchers are interested in determining whether a combination of the chemotherapy&#xD;
           drugs SS1 (dsFv) PE38, paclitaxel, carboplatin, and bevacizumab may be effective in&#xD;
           shrinking the size of NSCLC tumors. Three of the drugs (paclitaxel, carboplatin, and&#xD;
           bevacizumab) are commercially available, while the other is a drug that is currently&#xD;
           being tested to determine its usefulness in cancer treatment. This study will help to&#xD;
           determine if the combination of all four drugs is more effective and as safe, safer, or&#xD;
           less safe than other drug combinations given to treat NSCLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - To determine a safe and tolerable dose for the combination of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 with&#xD;
      paclitaxel, carboplatin, and bevacizumab in patients with advanced mesothelin-expressing lung&#xD;
      adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age &gt; 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Newly diagnosed advanced non-small-cell lung carcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  No prior chemotherapy for lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Individuals at least 18 years of age who have advanced non-small-cell lung carcinoma&#xD;
           that has not responded to standard treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The study will last for two 21-day cycles of treatment for the four-drug combination,&#xD;
           with additional treatment cycles of carboplatin, paclitaxel, and bevacizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Two to three weeks prior to the study, participants will be screened with a full medical&#xD;
           history and physical exam, bone marrow biopsy (we do not do bone marrow biopsies) (if&#xD;
           one has not been performed in the last 6 months), computed tomography (CT) or ultrasound&#xD;
           scan, tumor measurements, and other tests as required by the researchers. Participants&#xD;
           will provide blood and urine samples at this time as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  During the study, participants will receive SS1 (dsFv) PE38, carboplatin, paclitaxel,&#xD;
           and bevacizumab for a maximum of two cycles. On Day 15 of the first cycle, participants&#xD;
           will provide a blood sample to be tested to see if SS1 (dsFv) PE38 is being effective.&#xD;
           If the tests show that SS1 (dsFv) PE38 is not effective, participants will not receive&#xD;
           another dose of it, but will continue to receive paclitaxel, carboplatin, and&#xD;
           bevacizumab for the second cycle.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  After the first two cycles, participants will continue to receive carboplatin,&#xD;
           paclitaxel, and bevacizumab every 3 weeks for up t...&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      -  Treatment with platinum-based doublet chemotherapy results in a median survival of 7 to&#xD;
           10 months in patients with locally advanced or metastatic non-small cell lung cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  In a randomized clinical trial of patients with non-squamous cell lung cancer, treatment&#xD;
           with carboplatin, paclitaxel and bevacizumab resulted in an objective response rate of&#xD;
           35%, overall survival of 12.3 months compared to objective response rate of 15%, overall&#xD;
           survival of 10.3 months in patients treated with carboplatin and paclitaxel alone.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Mesothelin is a cell surface glycoprotein present on normal mesothelial cells that is&#xD;
           highly expressed in many human cancers including lung adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  SS1 (dsFv) PE38 is a recombinant anti-mesothelin immunotoxin that has undergone phase I&#xD;
           testing and is currently in clinical trials in combination with pemetrexed and cisplatin&#xD;
           for treatment of malignant pleural mesothelioma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pre-clinical studies demonstrate increased anti-tumor activity of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 in&#xD;
           combination with chemotherapy and bevacizumab against mesothelin-expressing tumors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - This is a phase I study to determine a safe and tolerable phase II dose for the combination&#xD;
      of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 with paclitaxel, carboplatin and bevacizumab in patients with advanced&#xD;
      mesothelin-expressing lung adenocarcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To assess response rate, duration of response, and progression-free survival (PFS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To characterize the pharmacokinetics (PK) of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 in combination with&#xD;
           chemotherapy and bevacizumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Monitor serum mesothelin levels prior to and during chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To identify T-cell epitopes responsible for neutralizing SS1 (dsFv) PE38 activity using&#xD;
           mononuclear cells obtained by apheresis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Histologically confirmed stage IIIB (malignant pleural effusion) or IV or recurrent&#xD;
           NSCLC (non-squamous cell, with mesothelin expression greater than or equal to 10% of&#xD;
           tumor cells by IHC).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adequate organ and bone marrow function.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ECOG performance status of 0-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      - Open label phase I trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 29, 2009</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 28, 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 28, 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Determined safe and tolerable phase 2 dose for combination of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 with paclitaxel, carboplatin, and bevacizumab.</measure>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Study pharmacokinetics. Assess response rate, duration of response and progression-free survival.</measure>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">2</enrollment>
  <condition>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Adenocarcinoma</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SS1 (dsFv) PE38</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paclitaxel</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Carboplatin</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bevacizumab</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Histologically or cytologically documented non-small cell lung adenocarcinoma&#xD;
                  that is confirmed by the Laboratory of Pathology, NIH.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Mesothelin expression greater than or equal to 10% of tumor cells as determined&#xD;
                  by immunohistochemistry (IHC) on tumor tissue specimens.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Patients must have measurable disease, defined as at least one lesion that can be&#xD;
                  accurately measured in at least one dimension (longest diameter to be recorded)&#xD;
                  as &gt; 20 mm with conventional techniques or as &gt; 10 mm with spiral CT scan.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Stage IIIB (malignant pleural effusion) or stage IV non-small cell lung cancer or&#xD;
                  recurrent non-small cell lung cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Age greater than or equal to 18 years (males or non-pregnant females).&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Life expectancy of greater than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. ECOG performance status 0-1 (Karnofsky &gt; 60%).&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Serum Creatinine less than or equal to 1.5mg/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Hemoglobin greater than or equal to 10.0g/dl.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. Absolute neutrophil count greater than or equal to 1,500/m(3) and platelets&#xD;
                  greater than or equal to 100,000/m(3).&#xD;
&#xD;
              11. AST/SGOT and ALT/SGPT less than or equal to 2.5 times ULN, total bilirubin less&#xD;
                  than or equal to 1.5 times ULN (In patients with evidence of Gilberts disease,&#xD;
                  elevated bilirubin should not be related to tumor or other liver diseases and&#xD;
                  should be less than or equal 2 times upper limit of normal).&#xD;
&#xD;
              12. Urine protein to creatinine ratio &lt; 1.0.&#xD;
&#xD;
              13. The ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent&#xD;
                  document and the ability to comply with the requirements of the protocol. The&#xD;
                  effects of SS1 (dsFv) PE38 on the developing human fetus are unknown. For this&#xD;
                  reason and because immunotoxins are known to be teratogenic, women of&#xD;
                  child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception&#xD;
                  (hormonal or barrier method of birth control; abstinence) prior to study entry&#xD;
                  and for the duration of study participation and for at least 3 months thereafter.&#xD;
                  Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy at study&#xD;
                  enrollment. Should a woman become pregnant or suspect she is pregnant while&#xD;
                  participating in this study, she should inform her treating physician&#xD;
                  immediately.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion of Women and Minorities:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Both men and women and members of all races and ethnic groups are eligible for this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Squamous cell cancer or mixed tumors with any small cell element.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Tumor of any histology in close proximity to a major vessel or cavitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. History of hemoptysis (bright red blood of teaspoon or more (greater than or equal to&#xD;
             2.5 mL)) on one occasion unrelated to any diagnostic procedure within the past year.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients with CNS metastases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of uncontrolled hypertension, defined as blood pressure &gt; 140/90 mmHg (NCI&#xD;
             CTEP Active Version of the CTCAE grade greater than or equal to 2) are excluded.&#xD;
             However, these patients will be eligible if the blood pressure is &lt; 140/90 mmHg after&#xD;
             anti-hypertensive treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any of the following within 6 months prior to study enrollment: myocardial infarction,&#xD;
             unstable angina pectoris or uncontrolled angina pectoris, coronary/peripheral artery&#xD;
             bypass graft, NYHA class III or IV congestive heart failure, clinically significant&#xD;
             peripheral vascular disease (Grade II or greater). History of stroke or transient&#xD;
             ischemic attack within 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Psychiatric or neurologic illness that would limit compliance with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with serious illness or medical condition.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Severe active infection within 14 days requiring use of intravenous antibiotics before&#xD;
             beginning treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients may not be receiving any other investigational agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of an active malignancy unless curatively treated and risk of recurrence of &lt;&#xD;
             5% at five years other than in situ carcinoma of the cervix, or non-melanomatous skin&#xD;
             cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients must not be on therapeutic anticoagulation, chronic daily treatment with&#xD;
             aspirin 325mg/day or non steroidal anti-inflammatory agents, or any agent known to&#xD;
             inhibit platelet function, within 10 days prior to day 1 on study. Low dose aspirin&#xD;
             81mg/day is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of pulmonary embolism, deep venous thrombosis or other thromboembolic event&#xD;
             within 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patients with a history of severe hypersensitivity reaction to compounds of similar&#xD;
             chemical or biologic composition to carboplatin, paclitaxel, bevacizumab or other&#xD;
             agents used in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of a major surgical procedure, open biopsy, or a significant traumatic injury&#xD;
             within 35 days prior to commencing treatment, or the anticipation of the need for a&#xD;
             major surgical procedure during the course of the study prior to the predetermined&#xD;
             date of tumor excision. Fine needle aspirations or core biopsies within 7 days prior&#xD;
             to commencing treatment are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. History of abdominal fistula, gastrointestinal perforation, intra- abdominal abscess&#xD;
             or tracheo-esophageal fistula.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Non-healing wound or ulcer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Evidence of coagulopathic disorder or hemorrhagic diathesis. INR greater than 1.5.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Pregnancy (positive pregnancy test) or active breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Urine protein: creatinine ratio greater than or equal to 1.0 at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. HIV-positive patients on combination antiretroviral therapy are ineligible because of&#xD;
             the potential for pharmacokinetic interactions with chemotherapy. In addition, these&#xD;
             patients are at increased risk of lethal infections when treated with&#xD;
             marrow-suppressive therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Significant laboratory abnormality requiring further investigation that may cause&#xD;
             undue risk for the subject's safety, inhibit protocol participation, or interfere with&#xD;
             interpretation of study results, and in the judgment of the investigator would make&#xD;
             the subject inappropriate for entry into this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chang K, Pastan I. Molecular cloning of mesothelin, a differentiation antigen present on mesothelium, mesotheliomas, and ovarian cancers. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1996 Jan 9;93(1):136-40.</citation>
    <PMID>8552591</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Folkman J. Tumor angiogenesis: therapeutic implications. N Engl J Med. 1971 Nov 18;285(21):1182-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>4938153</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hassan R, Bera T, Pastan I. Mesothelin: a new target for immunotherapy. Clin Cancer Res. 2004 Jun 15;10(12 Pt 1):3937-42. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15217923</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 28, 2011</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 16, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>January 16, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">January 20, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Recombinant Immunotoxin</keyword>
  <keyword>Monoclonal Antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Pseudomonas Exotoxin</keyword>
  <keyword>Targeted Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Non-Small-Cell Lung</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma of Lung</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paclitaxel</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Bevacizumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carboplatin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

