<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05063253</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SYSA1803-CSP-006</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05063253</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of TG103 Injection in Overweight/Obese Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Phase II Study to Evaluate the Efficacy of TG103 Injection in Overweight/Obese Subjects With Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>CSPC Baike (Shandong) Biopharmaceutical Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>CSPC Baike (Shandong) Biopharmaceutical Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main purpose of this study is to evaluate the efficacy, safety, PK and PD characteristics&#xD;
      of different doses of TG103 injection in overweight/obese subjects with type 2 diabetes&#xD;
      mellitus.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study to evaluate&#xD;
      the efficacy of TG103 injection in subjects with type 2 diabetes mellitus combined with&#xD;
      overweight/obesity. The study will consist of 3 periods: an approximately 4-week screening&#xD;
      period, a 20-week treatment period, and a 3-week safety follow-up period. Eligible subjects&#xD;
      will be randomized in a 1:1:1:1 ratio into four paralleled dose groups (15 mg, 22.5 mg ,30 mg&#xD;
      and placebo) with 52 subjects in each group. Within each group, subjects will receive TG103&#xD;
      injection or placebo subcutaneously (SC) once a week (QW) over a period of 20 weeks. Each&#xD;
      group will be started at a low dose of 7.5 mg and gradually up-titrated at weekly intervals&#xD;
      until the target dose.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in glycosylated hemoglobin (HbA1c) from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day 141 (the end of the 20-week treatment)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body weight from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in body mass index (BMI) from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in waist circumference from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in waist-hip ratio from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in blood pressure(systolic and diastolic blood pressure) from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in blood lipid from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of subjects with a baseline weight loss of more than 5%</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day155 (the end of the follow-up)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Minimum steady-state plasma drug concentration during a dosage interval (Cmin, SS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day1, 29, 57, 85 and 113</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in fasting blood glucose from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day 141 (the end of the 20-week treatment)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in 2-hour postprandial blood glucose from baseline to week 20</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Day 141 (the end of the 20-week treatment)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The occurrence of TG103 anti-drug antibodies (ADA) and neutralizing antibody (Nab).</measure>
    <time_frame>Day1, 29, 57, 85, 113 and 155</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">208</enrollment>
  <condition>Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TG103, 15 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TG103 (15 mg) will be administered via subcutaneous injection once weekly.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TG103, 22.5 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TG103 (22.5 mg) will be administered via subcutaneous injection once weekly.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TG103, 30 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>TG103 (30 mg) will be administered via subcutaneous injection once weekly.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo will be administered via subcutaneous injection once weekly.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>TG103</intervention_name>
    <description>TG103 injection, SC, once weekly</description>
    <arm_group_label>TG103, 15 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TG103, 22.5 mg</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>TG103, 30 mg</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Administered SC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo, SC, once weekly</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Administered SC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects have diagnosed with type 2 diabetes according to the Guidelines for&#xD;
             prevention and treatment of type 2 diabetes in China (2020 Edition);&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Aged 18 to 75 years (inclusive), no gender limitation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Body mass index (BMI) ≥ 24.0 kg/m^2 with stable body weight (less than 5%&#xD;
             self-reported change within 3 months);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects diagnosed with type 2 diabetes ≤ 3 years, and not on medication or with a&#xD;
             history of regular medication for no more than 1 week within the 3 months prior to&#xD;
             screening (subjects with a history of medication only include those with a history of&#xD;
             single-agent oral medication and a history of short-term intensive insulin therapy (≤&#xD;
             2 weeks)); 5.7.5% ≤ HbA1c ≤ 10.0%;&#xD;
&#xD;
        6.Subjects of childbearing potential must use reliable methods of contraception from the&#xD;
        date of signing an informed consent to at least 3 months after the last dose; 7. The&#xD;
        subject fully understand the trial and possible adverse reactions, has the ability to&#xD;
        communicate properly with the investigator and comply with the research protocol;&#xD;
        8.Voluntarily participate in the trial and sign the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Fasting plasma glucose ≥ 13.9 mmol/L at screening or a history of severe hypoglycemia&#xD;
             (Serious event requiring help from others with changes in consciousness and/or body)&#xD;
             within 6 months prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Systolic blood pressure ≥ 160 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg during&#xD;
             screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have one or more positive tests in anti-human immunodeficiency virus antibody or&#xD;
             anti-treponema pallidum-specific antibody;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) ≥2.5x upper limit&#xD;
             of normal (ULN), or Total bilirubin (TBiL)≥1.5x ULN, or triglyceride &gt; 5.7 mmol/L or&#xD;
             eGFR &lt; 60 mL/(min*1.73 m^2) during the screening period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with hematological diseases (e.g., aplastic anemia, myelodysplastic syndrome)&#xD;
             or any disease causing hemolysis or erythrocyte instability (e.g., malaria), or&#xD;
             hemoglobin&lt;100 g/L;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Hypercortisolism, polycystic ovary syndrome, abnormal thyroid function (those&#xD;
             requiring medication or who have not reached a stable dose of treatment in 3 months&#xD;
             prior to screening), etc. or other diseases that may affect blood glucose metabolism;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Have a personal or family history of medullary thyroid carcinoma (MTC) or type 2&#xD;
             multiple endocrine neoplasia, or other genetic diseases that are susceptible to&#xD;
             medullary cancer, or calcitonin ≥ 50 ng/L(pg/mL);&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Acute complications of diabetes (including diabetic ketoacidosis, hyperosmolar&#xD;
             nonketotic diabetic coma, lactic acidosis) occurred once or more within 3 months or&#xD;
             twice or more within 6 months before screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Proliferative diabetic retinopathy, foot ulcers/gangrene, and manifestations of&#xD;
             peripheral neuropathy with obvious symptoms (e.g., gastroparesis, urinary retention,&#xD;
             intestinal obstruction, urinary incontinence, and painful peripheral neuropathy);&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects with degree II or III atrioventricular block in 12-lead ECG (except for&#xD;
             subjects who use the pacemaker), long QT syndrome or prolonged QTc interval (QTcF:&#xD;
             &gt;450 ms for males, &gt;470 ms for females), or signs of clinically significant localised&#xD;
             ischemic heart disease during the screening period; or those with other heart diseases&#xD;
             that are judged by the investigator to be unsuitable for entry into the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any of the following cardiovascular and cerebrovascular events within half a year&#xD;
             before screening: unstable angina pectoris requiring hospitalization, myocardial&#xD;
             infarction, coronary artery bypass grafting, percutaneous coronary intervention&#xD;
             (diagnostic angiography is allowed), moderate to severe congestive heart failure (NYHA&#xD;
             grade III or IV), atrial or ventricular arrhythmia requiring hospitalization (such as&#xD;
             atrial fibrillation and ventricular tachycardia), pacemaker or defibrillator&#xD;
             implantation, transient ischemic attack or cerebrovascular accident (e.g. stroke), or&#xD;
             those with coronary artery bypass grafting or revascularization planned during the&#xD;
             study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Have chronic or acute pancreatitis ( or have a history of recurrent acute&#xD;
             pancreatitis), or serum amylase and/or lipase ≥ 3x ULN (If lipase cannot be detected&#xD;
             in some centers, it is acceptable to judge only based on amylase),or severe&#xD;
             gastrointestinal disease, such as confirmed reflux esophagitis or gallbladder disease,&#xD;
             or any disease impacting gastric emptying (such as gastric bypass surgery, pyloric&#xD;
             stenosis, except for appendectomy) or gastrointestinal diseases that may be aggravated&#xD;
             by GLP-1 analogues; for subjects with a history of gallbladder stones (gallstone&#xD;
             removal or lithotripsy) and/or cholecystectomy, access to the study will be determined&#xD;
             by investigator after assessing the risk if there are no further sequelae;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of severe respiratory tract, blood system, central nervous system diseases&#xD;
             (e.g., epilepsy, etc.), or history of malignant tumor (except for basal cell carcinoma&#xD;
             or carcinoma in situ that has been clinically cured), mental diseases (e.g.,&#xD;
             depression, anxiety, etc.), or history of other diseases that may endanger the safety&#xD;
             of the subjects and are considered unsuitable for this study in the investigator's&#xD;
             opinion;&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects who have undergone major surgery within 3 months before screening, or have&#xD;
             ongoing severe or acute infection within 4 weeks before screening, or whose white&#xD;
             blood cell count exceeds 10% of the upper limit of normal during the screening period;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Use of drugs that can affect glucose metabolism or directly reduce gastrointestinal&#xD;
             motility within the 3 months prior to screening or expected during the course of the&#xD;
             study, including the cumulative use of systemic glucocorticoids (topical, intraocular&#xD;
             and inhaled preparations), immunosuppressants and cytotoxic drugs for more than 7&#xD;
             days; Large doses of thiazide diuretics (hydrochlorothiazide&gt;100 mg/d, chlorothiazide&gt;&#xD;
             2 g/d, indapamide&gt; 5 mg/d, chlorthalidone&gt; 100 mg/d), anticholinergics,&#xD;
             antispasmodics, etc. for more than 7 consecutive days;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Have taken prescription or over-the-counter medications for weight loss (e.g.,&#xD;
             orlistat, sibutramine, rimonabant, phenylpropanolamine, or chlorphenimiindole, etc)&#xD;
             within 3 months prior to screening; or have undergone surgery that can cause weight&#xD;
             instability;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Drugs that may cause significant weight gain have been used or are being used within 3&#xD;
             months before screening, including tricyclic antidepressants, atypical antipsychotics&#xD;
             and mood stabilizers (e.g., midazolam, amitriptyline, mirtazapine, paroxetine, phenyl&#xD;
             valproic acid and its derivatives and lithium), etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Have a serious history of drug or food allergy, or may be allergic to the&#xD;
             investigational product according to the judgment of the investigator;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Lost more than 400 mL of blood due to blood donation or other reasons within 3 months&#xD;
             before the screening period;&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Average alcohol intake more than 21 units of alcohol (male)/14 units of alcohol&#xD;
             (female) per week within the 3 months prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Regular consumption of caffeine more than 600 mg per day within the 3 months prior to&#xD;
             screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Smoke more than 20 cigarettes per day within 3 months prior to screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Have skin abnormalities or dermatitis within a radius of 2 cm of the administration&#xD;
             site;&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Participation in other drug studies within 3 months prior to screening and the last&#xD;
             received test drug less than 3 months prior to screening; or subjects out of the group&#xD;
             due to adverse events in the previous study; or attempted to participate in other drug&#xD;
             trials during the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Pregnant (blood pregnancy test positive in screening period) or lactating female;&#xD;
&#xD;
         26. Vaccinated within 28 days before screening or planned to be vaccinated during the&#xD;
             study;&#xD;
&#xD;
         27. Not suitable for this study in the investigator's opinion.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dalong Zhu</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The Affiliated Nanjing Drum Tower Hospital of Nanjing University Medical School</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Le Wang</last_name>
    <phone>+86-15511312686</phone>
    <email>wangle@mail.ecspc.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Can Zhang</last_name>
    <phone>+86-18632118280</phone>
    <email>zhangcan@mail.ecspc.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Overweight</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

