<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05068271</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WEBFIT: Memory &amp; fMRI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05068271</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Multi-Domain Exercise and Memory in Adults Relative to ApoE Genotype: A fMRI Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Multi-Domain Exercise Intervention on Memory Performance in Healthy Adults With and Without ApoE e4 Allele: A fMRI Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Taiwan Normal University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Taiwan Normal University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Most research on the effects of regular exercise on cognitive and brain functions has been&#xD;
      focused on exercise programs with a single mode of exercise. Studies focusing on the effects&#xD;
      of exercise programs with multi-domains on cognitive function and cortical functionality are&#xD;
      sparse in late-middle-aged and older adults. Therefore, the current project will utilize a&#xD;
      single-blinded, double arm, 6-month randomized controlled trial to assess the effects of a&#xD;
      multi-domain exercise program containing multiple physical fitness components, meditation,&#xD;
      and social interaction on memory performance, as well as cortical activities during the&#xD;
      memory tasks in cognitively intact adults (i.e., 45-70 years). In addition, the potential&#xD;
      moderator role of apolipoprotein epsilon-4 (ApoE e4) status and the mediator role of the&#xD;
      serum biomarkers (i.e., brain-derived neurotrophic factor, BDNF) will be explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Aging has been adversely associated with the deterioration of cognitive and brain functions.&#xD;
      Most research on the effects of regular exercise on cognitive and brain functions has been&#xD;
      focused on exercise programs with a single mode of exercise. Studies focusing on the effects&#xD;
      of exercise programs with multi-domains on cognitive function and cortical functionality are&#xD;
      sparse in late-middle-aged and older adults. In addition, while growing evidence has revealed&#xD;
      the beneficial effects of regular exercise on cognitive function, scientific evidence&#xD;
      regarding the effects of multi-domain exercise programs on cognitive function and brain&#xD;
      function in late-middle-aged and older adults who are with or without the genetic risk for&#xD;
      Alzheimer's disease (AD) is scarce. Lastly, the potential mediator role of the levels of the&#xD;
      serum biomarkers (i.e., brain-derived neurotrophic factor, BDNF) in individuals is required&#xD;
      to be explored.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the current study, a single-blinded, double arm, 6-month randomized controlled trial will&#xD;
      be utilized to assess the effects of a multi-domain exercise program containing multiple&#xD;
      physical fitness components, meditation, and social interaction on memory, as well as&#xD;
      cortical functionalities during the memory tasks in cognitively intact adults (i.e., 45-70&#xD;
      years) . Specifically, the investigators aim to examine: (1) the causal links between a&#xD;
      multi-domain exercise program composing of various physical fitness components, meditation,&#xD;
      and social interaction against an active control group on the memory performance in&#xD;
      cognitively intact adults aged between 45 and 70 years with or without a genetic risk for AD,&#xD;
      (2) the cortical functionality through functional images collected through a series of&#xD;
      functional magnetic resonance images (fMRI), and (3) the potential influence of&#xD;
      apolipoprotein epsilon-4 (ApoE e4) and BDNF on the effects of exercise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One hundred eligible participants will participate in the current study and will be randomly&#xD;
      assigned into either the 6-month multi-domain exercise group (exercise group) or the online&#xD;
      educational course group (active control group). In each group, the ages ratio (≤ 55 years&#xD;
      vs. &gt; 55 years), and ApoE genotype [i.e., High-risk candidates (ApoE e3/e4 and ApoE e4/e4)&#xD;
      vs. the Low-risk candidates (ApoE e2/e4, ApoE e2/e3, ApoE e2/e2 and ApoE e3/e3)] will be in a&#xD;
      ratio of 1:1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the exercise and the active control groups would receive either the two&#xD;
      90-min exercise sessions or online educational courses per week, respectively. All&#xD;
      participants' physical fitness, cognitive function, and cortical functionalities via fMRI&#xD;
      scanning will be assessed at the Baseline (Baseline-Assessments) and at the cessation of the&#xD;
      6-month intervention (Post-Assessments). The potential moderating role of ApoE genotypes and&#xD;
      the mediation role of BDNF will be explored. Participation in this study will take&#xD;
      approximately 7 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>fMRI</measure>
    <time_frame>60 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Two sessions of the fMRI will be conducted at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment) to measure participants' brain functionalities.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Working memory performance: N-back working memory task</measure>
    <time_frame>30 min assessment time at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Working memory performance will be assessed using the computerized n-back working memory task at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment). A total of 6 blocks with 108 trials (18 trials each block) will be utilized in the current study.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Episodic memory performance: Relational and item-specific encoding and recognition test</measure>
    <time_frame>30 min each session at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Episodic memory performance will be assessed using the relational and item-specific encoding and recognition test at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ApoE genotype</measure>
    <time_frame>5 min at the Baseline Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Based on the genetic biomarkers (rs429358 and rs7412), participants' ApoE genotype will be determined.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood neurotrophic marker: Brain-derived neurotrophic factor</measure>
    <time_frame>5 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>6 mL serum sample will be drawn from the antecubital vein at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment) to determine the concentration of the brain-derived neurotrophic factor.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical fitness measurements: Aerobic fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>20 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Participants' aerobic fitness will be estimated using the submaximal cycle ergometer test at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical fitness measurements: Muscular fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Muscular fitness will be assessed using either the push-up test/30sec or the chair stand test/30sec at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment). Higher number completed indicated better level of muscular fitness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical fitness measurements: Flexibility</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Flexibility will be assessed using the sit-and-reach test at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment). Further distance indicates better lower back and hip joint flexibility.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Physical fitness measurements: Body composition</measure>
    <time_frame>15 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>The body composition (e.g., body water, body fat, skeletal muscle mass, body mass index, and percentage of body fat) will be assessed simultaneously using a body composition analyzer (ACCUNIQ BC380 Body Composition Analysis, SELVAS Healthcare Inc., Korea) at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychosocial measures: Mindfulness</measure>
    <time_frame>5 min each at the Baseline-Assessment and at the Post-Assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of mindfulness will be assessed using the 15-items Chinese version of the Mindful Attention Awareness Scale questionnaire at the baseline (Baseline-Assessment) and at the end of the 6-month intervention (Post-Assessment). Participants respond on a 6-point Likert scale from 1 (almost always) to 6 (almost never). Higher scores are associated with higher dispositional mindfulness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Exercise Training</condition>
  <condition>Executive Function</condition>
  <condition>Aging</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multi-Domain Exercise Program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Time: 6 months, total of 180 min of exercise per week.&#xD;
Intervention: aerobic training, muscular fitness training, balance, flexibility, meditation and social interaction.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Time: 6 months, total of 180 min of online educational course per week.&#xD;
Intervention: educational materials relating to the effects of exercise on cognitive function and aging-related cognitive decline.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Multi-Domain Exercise Program</intervention_name>
    <description>The multi-domain exercise consisted of 15 min of warm-up and aerobic exercise from light to moderate intensity, 25 min of resistance exercise and flexibility exercise, 30 min of resistance exercise and coordinative exercise from the &quot;Eastern exercise&quot; perspective, 10 min of social interaction exercise, and 10 min of cool-down and meditation. Participants will be encouraged to attend the 90-min exercise program twice a week for 6 months, and to exercise at a moderate intensity for at least 20 min during each session.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Multi-Domain Exercise Program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Active Control Group</intervention_name>
    <description>The &quot;usual physical activity group,&quot; as the active control group, will not receive an exercise program and will be informed to maintain their lifestyles. In addition, participants will be invited to attend the online educational course at a frequency of 2 sessions per week for 90 min each to eliminate the experimental expectation effect. The logs of physical activity behavior will be obtained from the participants once per month during the intervention period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal or corrected-to-normal vision&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to speak and read Chinese&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Scores of Mini-Mental Status Examination &gt;= 25&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical Activity Readiness Questionnaire score &lt; 0&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to conduct the exercise with moderate intensity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meet the criteria to undergo magnetic resonance imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed or self-reported cognitive problems (e.g., mild cognitive impairment or&#xD;
             dementia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed or self-reported physical disease (e.g., untreated hypertension and chronic&#xD;
             heart disease, stroke, brain tumor, musculoskeletal disorders, other exercise&#xD;
             contradictions)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed or self-reported major psychiatric illness (e.g., major depression,&#xD;
             schizophrenia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed or self-reported neurodegenerative disease (e.g., Alzheimer's disease and&#xD;
             other dementias, Parkinson's disease (PD) and PD-related disorders, Huntington's&#xD;
             disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of alcohol or drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Traveling consecutively for three weeks or more during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness to be randomized to one of the two groups&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently participating in another study trial&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria for functional magnetic resonance images (fMRI):&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will be excluded if s/he has a contraindication to fMRI scanning, such as&#xD;
        aneurysm clip, implanted neural stimulator, cochlear implant, any implanted device, cardiac&#xD;
        pacemaker. To ensure volunteers are eligible for the current project, they will be asked to&#xD;
        fill out a questionnaire to inform whether they have conditions (e.g. paralyzed&#xD;
        hemidiaphragm) or present unnecessary risks (e.g., pregnancy) during the recruitment&#xD;
        period.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>45 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yu-Kai Chang, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Department of Physical Education and Sport Sciences, National Taiwan Normal University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yu-Kai Chang, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+886277493220</phone>
    <email>yukaichangnew@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Yu-Kai Chang</name>
      <address>
        <city>Taipei</city>
        <zip>106</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Yu-Kai Chang, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+886277493220</phone>
      <email>yukaichangnew@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Taiwan Normal University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Yu-Kai Chang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>multiple fitness</keyword>
  <keyword>meditation</keyword>
  <keyword>mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>Apolipoprotein E</keyword>
  <keyword>aging</keyword>
  <keyword>magnetic resonance images</keyword>
  <keyword>memory</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

