<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05063097</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP190870</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-A00702-39</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05063097</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Addiction in Intensive Cardiac Care Units</brief_title>
  <acronym>ADDICT-CCU</acronym>
  <official_title>Assessment of ADDICTion to Psychoactive Drug Use in Intensive Cardiac Care Units - The ADDICT-CCU Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fondation Coeur et Recherche</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Illicit drug use is a growing issue in Europe and leading cause of acute cardiac events in&#xD;
      patients admitted to intensive cardiac care units. Indeed, cardiovascular complications are&#xD;
      one of the main causes of death due to illicit drug use. However, its prevalence in patients&#xD;
      hospitalized in intensive cardiac care units is unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This large multicenter prospective study will assess the prevalence of illicit drug use in&#xD;
      consecutive patients hospitalized in intensive cardiac care units by urine drug assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patient over 18 years old admitted to intensive Cardiac Care Unit (CCU) for any reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Without hospitalization for a planned interventional procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Without hospitalization for more than 24 hours at any hospital facility before admission&#xD;
           to the CCU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Multicentre cohort study with a prospective enrolment of all consecutive patients&#xD;
           admitted to the CCU to assess the prevalence of illicit drug use in 40 centers&#xD;
           throughout France.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened with a physical exam, medical history and addiction&#xD;
           survey.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be screened for drug use by urine drug assay (NarcoCheck®, Kappa City&#xD;
           Biotech SAS, Montluçon, France) and for tobacco by standardized exhaled carbon monoxide&#xD;
           (CO) measurement with a CO-Check Pro device (Bedfont Scientific Ltd, Kent, UK).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants will be followed at 6 months of follow-up to assess the occurrence of&#xD;
           cardiovascular events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Illicit drug use is a growing issue in Europe. In France, the prevalence of the illicit use&#xD;
      of any drug is 11.4% of the population, ahead of Italy (10.6%), the United Kingdom (8.7%) and&#xD;
      Germany (7.8%).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cardiovascular complications are one of the main causes of death due to psychoactive drug use&#xD;
      with more than 100,000 deaths per year are due to psychoactive drug use in France. Although&#xD;
      the use of illicit drugs may be involved in several acute cardiac events in patients admitted&#xD;
      to intensive cardiac care units (CCU), its prevalence in patients hospitalized in CCU is&#xD;
      unknown. Interestingly, the current guidelines recommend only a declarative survey to&#xD;
      investigate psychoactive drug use but no systematic urine or plasma screening. However, the&#xD;
      rate of underreporting of these illegal substances remains high. To our knowledge, no study&#xD;
      has ever consecutively assessed the prevalence of psychoactive drug use using systematic&#xD;
      urine or plasma screening at the time of CCU admission. Because illicit drug use is a&#xD;
      potential cardiovascular risk factor, accurate drug screening may initiate addictology&#xD;
      management, modify the treatment and improve patient prognosis after a cardiovascular event.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the prospective ADDICT-CCU study is to assess the prevalence of illicit drug use&#xD;
      in consecutive patients hospitalized in intensive cardiac care units by urine drug assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      All consecutive patients over 18 years admitted to the CCU during a 3 week recruitment period&#xD;
      in 40 centers. The main exclusion criteria will be hospitalization for a planned&#xD;
      interventional procedure, dementia, or hospitalization for more than 24 hours at any hospital&#xD;
      facility before admission to the CCU. Informed consent will be obtained from all&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators will conduct a multicentre cohort study with a prospective enrolment of all&#xD;
      consecutive patients admitted to the CCU to assess the prevalence of psychoactive drug use in&#xD;
      40 centers throughout France. Anonymized data supporting the findings of this study will be&#xD;
      collected using CleanwebTM software.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary outcome will be the prevalence of at least one illicit drug among all consecutive&#xD;
      patients hospitalized in the CCU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following psychoactive drugs will be evaluated for all consecutive patients by urine drug&#xD;
      assay (NarcoCheck®, Kappa City Biotech SAS, Montluçon, France) within two hours of admission&#xD;
      to the CCU: i) cannabinoids (tetrahydrocannabinol [THC]), including cannabis and hashish; ii)&#xD;
      cocaine and metabolites, including cocaine and crack; iii) amphetamines; iv) MDMA; and v)&#xD;
      heroin and other opioids.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition to the analysis of illicit drug use, the investigators will also use the&#xD;
      NarcoCheck® urine drug assay to evaluate the associated use of the following psychoactive&#xD;
      drugs: barbiturates, benzodiazepines, tricyclic antidepressant drugs, methadone and&#xD;
      buprenorphine. Tobacco consumption will also be evaluated for each patient using a&#xD;
      questionnaire with three choices: &quot;never smoked,&quot; &quot;smoking cessation&quot; specifying the number&#xD;
      of years, or &quot;active smoking.&quot; Active smoking will also be systematically investigated in all&#xD;
      patients using a standardized exhaled carbon monoxide (CO) measurement with a CO-Check Pro&#xD;
      device (Bedfont Scientific Ltd, Kent, UK) on arrival, with a measure of &gt; 3 parts per million&#xD;
      (ppm) signifying active smoking. Every patient will be provided with relevant instructions&#xD;
      regarding the urine drug assay and exhaled CO measurement, and trained investigators will&#xD;
      conduct the tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Regarding the secondary outcomes, participants will be followed at 6 months of follow-up to&#xD;
      assess the occurrence of cardiovascular events.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 6, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of psychoactive drug use assessed by urine drug assay at the time of patient admission.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0</time_frame>
    <description>The following psychoactive drugs will be evaluated for all consecutive patients by urine drug assay (NarcoCheck®, Kappa City Biotech SAS, Montluçon, France) within two hours of admission to the CCU: i) cannabinoids (tetrahydrocannabinol [THC]), including cannabis and hashish; ii) cocaine and metabolites, including cocaine and crack; iii) amphetamines; iv) MDMA; and v) heroin and other opioids.&#xD;
In addition to the analysis of psychoactive drug use, the investigators will also use the NarcoCheck® urine drug assay to evaluate the associated use of the following psychostimulant drugs: barbiturates, benzodiazepines, tricyclic antidepressant drugs, methadone and buprenorphine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital major adverse events (MAE)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>In-hospital major adverse events (MAE) will be a combined outcome including:&#xD;
all-cause mortality,&#xD;
cardiogenic shock according to the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) guidelines, and requiring medical (catecholamines or inotropic agents) or mechanical haemodynamic support&#xD;
cardiac arrest: severe ventricular arrhytmia requiring defibrillation or anti-arrhytmic agents&#xD;
This outcome will be assessed by the clinical team in charge of the CCU during the hospitalization.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of the hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The duration of the hospitalization of each patient in CCU and in the hospital.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Combined major adverse clinical events (MACE).</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>MACE will be defined as all-cause death or unplanned hospitalization for acute cardiovascular reasons, confirmed by independent adjudication experts who will review medical documents according to the standardized definitions.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>All cause mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The adjudication of all-cause death was performed using the electronic French National Registry of Death (Institut National de la Statistique et des Etudes Economiques, INSEE registry).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The occurrence of cardiovascular events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months of follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Other secondary outcomes will be assessed by independent adjudication experts will be as follows: all-cause death, cardiovascular mortality, nonfatal myocardial infarction, unstable angina, resuscitated cardiac arrest, hospitalizations for heart failure, heart transplantation or implantation of a mechanical circulatory support device, sustained ventricular arrhythmias, coronary revascularization, stroke, venous thromboembolic events, endocarditis and the implantation of a pacemaker or implantable cardioverter-defibrillator.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1500</enrollment>
  <condition>Intensive Care Unit Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Drug Abuse</condition>
  <condition>Substance-Related Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Events</condition>
  <condition>Cardiac Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CCU patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>All consecutive patients over 18 years admitted to the CCU.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>urine test</intervention_name>
    <description>The following illicit drugs will be evaluated for all consecutive patients by urine drug assay (NarcoCheck®, Kappa City Biotech SAS, Montluçon, France) within two hours of admission to the ICCU: i) cannabinoids (tetrahydrocannabinol [THC]), including cannabis and hashish; ii) cocaine and metabolites, including cocaine and crack; iii) amphetamines; iv) MDMA; and v) heroin and other opioids. In addition to the analysis of psychoactive drug use, the investigators will also use the NarcoCheck® urine drug assay to evaluate the associated use of the following psychostimulant drugs: barbiturates, benzodiazepines, tricyclic antidepressant drugs, methadone and buprenorphine.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CCU patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fagerström questionnaire</intervention_name>
    <description>Tobacco consumption will also be evaluated for each patient using a Fagerström questionnaire.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CCU patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Exhaled carbon monoxide (CO) measurement</intervention_name>
    <description>Active smoking will also be systematically investigated in all patients using a standardized exhaled carbon monoxide (CO) measurement with a CO-Check Pro device (Bedfont Scientific Ltd, Kent, UK) on arrival, with a measure of &gt; 3 parts per million (ppm) signifying active smoking.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CCU patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All consecutive patients over 18 years admitted to the CCU. The main exclusion criteria&#xD;
        will be hospitalization for a planned interventional procedure, dementia, or&#xD;
        hospitalization for more than 24 hours at any hospital facility before admission to the&#xD;
        CCU. Informed consent will be obtained from all participants.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient over 18 years old admitted to Cardiac Intensive Care Unit (CCU) for any&#xD;
             reason.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Oral informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalization for a planned interventional procedure (percutaneous coronary&#xD;
             intervention, coronary artery bypass graft surgery, transcatheter aortic valve&#xD;
             implantation…).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dementia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hospitalization for more than 24 hours at any hospital facility before admission to&#xD;
             the CCU.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under legal protection without the consent of the legal representative.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with no social security.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Declining participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean-Guillaume DILLINGER, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Lariboisière Hospital, APHP, Paris</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patrick HENRY, MD,PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 1 49 95 82 24</phone>
    <email>patrick.henry@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Théo PEZEL, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+33 1 49 95 86 74</phone>
    <email>theo.pezel@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Lariboisière, APHP, Cardiology</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <state>Ile De France</state>
        <zip>75010</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patrick Henry</last_name>
      <phone>00-33-1-49 95 82 24</phone>
      <email>Patrick.henry@lrb.aphp.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prevalence</keyword>
  <keyword>Drug Abuse</keyword>
  <keyword>Illicit drug use</keyword>
  <keyword>Substance-Related Disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>Intensive cardiac care unit</keyword>
  <keyword>Cannabis</keyword>
  <keyword>Cocaine</keyword>
  <keyword>Cardiovascular events</keyword>
  <keyword>Psychoactive drug use</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Substance-Related Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carbon Monoxide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

