<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05068375</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Soh-Med-21-04-39</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05068375</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Unleash the Mystery of COVID-19 Related Unusual Thrombosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Unusual Pattern of Thrombotic Events in Young Adults Noncritically Ill Patients With COVID-19 May Result From An Un-diagnosed Inherited Form of Thrombophilia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sohag University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sohag University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Arterial thrombosis and unusual patterns of thrombotic events in young adults patients with&#xD;
      COVID-19 are yet rarely described in this setting and could be underestimated. There is a&#xD;
      real need for studies to describe the frequency of unusual thrombotic complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2), first identified in Wuhan,&#xD;
      China in December of 2019, has become a worldwide pandemic with widespread illness and&#xD;
      mortality. Clinical manifestations of Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) are absent or mild&#xD;
      in a substantial proportion of patients who test positive for COVID-19. Although respiratory&#xD;
      compromise is the cardinal feature of the disease, early studies have suggested that elevated&#xD;
      circulating D-dimer levels are associated with mortality suggesting a distinct coagulation&#xD;
      disorder associated with COVID-19. COVID-19 infection is commonly complicated with&#xD;
      pro-thrombotic state and endothelial dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent autopsy studies of COVID-19 patients supported this hypothesis by demonstrating the&#xD;
      extensive extracellular fibrin deposition and presence of fibrin thrombi within distended&#xD;
      capillaries and small vessels. Observational studies reported an excess of venous&#xD;
      thromboembolic events (deep vein thrombosis (DVT), pulmonary embolism (PE)) among patients&#xD;
      suffering from Covid-19. Retrospective studies have reported thrombotic rates in excess of&#xD;
      20% to 30%, but the use of prophylactic anticoagulation and duration of treatment were not&#xD;
      consistent between studies. Unrecognized PE and pulmonary in situ thrombosis were reported as&#xD;
      causes of the high mortality observed among COVID-19 patients. There is currently no clear&#xD;
      estimation of the risk of arterial and, in particular, venous thromboembolic complications&#xD;
      which depend on local diagnostic and pharmacological preventive strategies. In addition to&#xD;
      D-dimer, a prolonged prothrombin time (PT) has been associated with decreased survival and&#xD;
      increased need for critical care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, arterial thrombosis and unusual patterns of thrombotic events in young adults&#xD;
      patients with COVID-19 are yet rarely described in this setting and could be underestimated&#xD;
      (9). Thus, there is a real need for studies to describe the frequency of unusual thrombotic&#xD;
      complications. Therefore, the purpose of this study will be to explore thromboembolic risk&#xD;
      and associated predicting factors in the young adults' cohort of noncritically ill COVID-19&#xD;
      patients which will help to optimize diagnostic, therapeutic, and preventive strategies of&#xD;
      COVID-19 related thrombosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>Form April 2020 to April 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of unusual thrombotic events among non-critically ill young adults' patients with COVID-19</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombosis progression</measure>
    <time_frame>First month after diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Thrombosis progression: Symptomatic extension of a pre-existing thrombus or new symptomatic thrombus not evident on the initial imaging at a second compressive examination.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding complications of the UTEs</measure>
    <time_frame>First month after diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Bleeding (major, minor bleedings)&#xD;
I. Major bleeding is defined as frank bleeding contributed to death or associated with a decreasing in hemoglobin ≥2 g/dL, or need a packed red blood cells transfusion ≥2 units, or bleeding at a critical site.&#xD;
II. Non-major bleeding was defined as any symptom or sign of bleeding that did not fit the criteria of major bleeding but fulfilled at least one of the these criteria: leading to hospitalization, or requiring healthcare professional medical intervention, or spurring a face-to-face assessment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>First month after diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Death frequency</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Thrombosis recurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>During 6 months of follow up period</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of thrombosis recurrence after the initial thrombotic event(s)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bleeding</measure>
    <time_frame>During 6 months of follow up period</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of bleeding (major, minor bleedings)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>During 6 months of follow up period</time_frame>
    <description>Death frequency</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Thrombotic group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Non-critically COVID-19 patients with unusual thrombotic events</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Non-thrombotic group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Non-critically COVID-19 patients without thrombotic events</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Thrombophilia screening</intervention_name>
    <description>Genetic thrombophilia and acquired thrombophilia screening</description>
    <arm_group_label>Thrombotic group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        - Study group:&#xD;
&#xD;
        At Sohag University Hospitals, we conducted a longitudinal observational study with a&#xD;
        6-month follow-up duration across a fourteen-month period (April 2020 to June 2021). This&#xD;
        study enrolled young adult non-critical ill patients (age 18 to 40) with a positive&#xD;
        SARS-CoV-2 reverse-transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (rt-PCR) test and unusual sites&#xD;
        of thrombotic events. These patients will be compared to young adult non-critical patients&#xD;
        presented to our hospital with COVID-19 without thrombosis during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients will be classified into two groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Group I: COVID-19 patients with unusual thrombosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Group II: COVID-19 patients without unusual thrombosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  non-critically ill young adults' patients with COVID-19 admitted to our hospital will&#xD;
             have confirmed unusual thrombotic events and accept recruitment to this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        After that, we will focus only on previously healthy patients without pre-existing&#xD;
        prothrombotic factors and presented with COVID-19 related unusual thrombotic events&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patients below 18 years and above 40 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patients diagnosed as critically ill COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patients with pre-existing diabetes mellitus (DM), hypertension, ischemic&#xD;
             heart disease (IHD), valvular heart disease, cardiomyopathy and chronic arrhythmia,&#xD;
             dyslipidemia, metabolic syndrome, chronic kidney disease, liver disease, nephrotic&#xD;
             syndrome, previous autoimmune disease, and malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patients with chronic lung disease or immune compromise&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patient with history of thrombosis/ psychiatric disorders/ drug abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patient previously diagnosis with congenital thrombophilia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patient with drug history could induce thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patient unwilling to be followed up.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients are previously diagnosed with one or more risk factors of thrombosis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>, Faculty of Medicine, Sohag University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sohag</city>
        <zip>82524</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mahmoud I. Elbadry, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+01065964083</phone>
      <email>mahmoudibrahim@med.sohag.edu.eg</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>October 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sohag University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mahmoud Ibrahim Yousef</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor MD Phd.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

