<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05064722</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GIW 21-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05064722</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Duodenal-Ileal Diversion in Obese Patients Undergoing Primary Sleeve or Those With Inadequate Weight Loss After Sleeve</brief_title>
  <official_title>Initial Safety and Device Functionality of the Self-Forming Magnetic Anastomosis Device to Create a Duodenal-Ileal Diversion in Obese Patients Undergoing Primary Sleeve (SNAP-S) or Those With Inadequate Weight Loss After Sleeve (SNAP-PS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>GI Windows, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>GI Windows, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objectives of this study are to assess the initial safety and device functionality of the&#xD;
      SFM Anastomosis System including delivery systems when used to create a dual-path&#xD;
      duodenal-ileal (D-I) diversion either during sleeve gastrectomy (i.e., SNAP-S procedure) or&#xD;
      patients with prior sleeve gastrectomy who experience inadequate weight loss (i.e., SNAP-PS&#xD;
      procedure). Additionally, the study is designed to evaluate the potential of the&#xD;
      SNAP-S/SNAP-PS procedures to induce weight loss and to improve metabolic comorbidities in&#xD;
      obese subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a single-arm, single-center, early feasibility study to evaluate the use of the SFM&#xD;
      Anastomosis System for creation of a D-I diversion in participants undergoing primary sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomy (SNAP-S cohort) or who have experienced inadequate weight loss following sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomy (SNAP-PS cohort) defined to be failure to achieve a minimum 50% EWL at least 18&#xD;
      months post sleeve gastrectomy. Five patients will be enrolled in each cohort. Adult male and&#xD;
      female subjects between the ages of 22 and 65 years-old who are candidates for the primary or&#xD;
      revisional surgery will be considered for participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients appearing to meet basic eligibility criteria and who sign the study specific consent&#xD;
      form will be screened for enrollment into this study and will be assessed by a&#xD;
      multidisciplinary research team with pre-procedure nutritional and medical evaluation&#xD;
      (including psychological and behavioral evaluation by an internist/bariatrician).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects meeting the inclusion and exclusion criteria and enrolled into the study will&#xD;
      undergo a dual-path enteral diversion using the SFM anastomosis device in which the duodenum&#xD;
      will be connected to the ileum with the creation of a side-by-side anastomosis using the SFM&#xD;
      device and delivery systems. For subjects undergoing concurrent sleeve gastrectomy and D-I&#xD;
      Diversion (SNAP-S cohort) it is anticipated that the D-I diversion will be created first&#xD;
      followed by the sleeve gastrectomy (unless the investigator determines that the reverse order&#xD;
      is more appropriate for a particular subject).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight Loss</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Total Body Weight Loss from baseline</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent Responders</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Percent of patients losing at least 10% of their baseline weight</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>%EWL</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean Excess Weight Loss from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum lipids</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change of serum lipids from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Systolic/diastolic blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean percent change in systolic/diastolic blood pressure from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hemoglobin A1c</measure>
    <time_frame>12 Months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean change of hemoglobin A1c (in patients with Type 2 Diabetes (T2DM) from baseline</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity, Morbid</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SNAP-S</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Creation of a D-I diversion in participants undergoing primary sleeve gastrectomy (SNAP-S cohort)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SNAP-PS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Creation of a D-I diversion in participants who have experienced inadequate weight loss following sleeve gastrectomy (SNAP-PS cohort)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Self Forming Magnets (SFM)</intervention_name>
    <description>To create the duodenal-ileal diversion, the duodenal magnet will be placed transorally in the proximal duodenum and the distal magnet will be placed in the ileum. Magnets are coupled and a compression induced anastomosis is created.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SNAP-PS</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>SNAP-S</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age 22-65 years at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Obesity with Body Mass Index (BMI) ≥ 35 kg/m2 with at least one obesity related&#xD;
             comorbidity or ≥ 40 but ≤ 50 kg/m2 with or without comorbidities at time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
             a. For SNAP-PS Cohort, subject should be at least 18 months from the initial sleeve&#xD;
             gastrectomy and have failed to achieve at minimum 50% EWL&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If subject has obesity-related comorbidities such as hypertension, dyslipidemia, and&#xD;
             sleep apnea, these comorbidities must be well-controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to understand and sign informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient lives, and intends to remain, within a 300-km radius of study center for 24&#xD;
             months&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Willing to refrain from smoking during the study follow-up period&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. If subject is female, she must commit to not becoming pregnant for 24 months and agree&#xD;
             to use of contraceptives during this period and may not be nursing&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Type 1 Diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Uncontrolled T2DM Fasting glucose ≥ 200 mg/dl (11.1 mmol/L) and/or hemoglobin A1c &gt;10&#xD;
             or use of injectable insulin&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any documented conditions for which endoscopy and/or laparoscopy would be&#xD;
             contraindicated or history of previous technically difficult or failed endoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Contraindication to general anesthesia&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Clinically significant finding during procedural endoscopy such as presence of an&#xD;
             unhealed ulcers, bleeding lesions, tumors or ischemic or necrotic tissue at target&#xD;
             magnet deployment site&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Congenital or acquired anomalies of the GI tract, including atresias, stenosis, prior&#xD;
             obstruction or malrotation&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence of a duodenal diverticulum (&gt;10mm)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any previous major surgery on the stomach, duodenum, hepatobiliary tree (excluding&#xD;
             laparoscopically removed gallbladder or prior sleeve gastrectomy for SNAP-PS cohort),&#xD;
             pancreas or right colon&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of chronic gastrointestinal disease (e.g., cirrhosis, inflammatory bowel&#xD;
             disease) that in the opinion of the Investigator may preclude safe and complete study&#xD;
             participation&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Uncontrolled severe hypertension (blood pressure &gt;160/100mmHg)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Pre-existing severe comorbid cardio-respiratory disease (e.g., congestive heart&#xD;
             failure, uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia, coronary artery disease, chronic obstructive&#xD;
             lung disease requiring supplemental oxygen, pulmonary embolism, MI with prior 6&#xD;
             months)&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Liver biochemistries (ALT and AST) ≥ 3 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Uncorrectable coagulation disorder (platelets &lt; 100,000, PT &gt;2 seconds above control&#xD;
             or INR &gt;1.5) at time of procedure, Note: management of anti-platelet medications, when&#xD;
             applicable, will follow standard practices of the institution&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Uncorrectable anemia (Hemoglobin &lt; 11 g/dL in women and &lt;12.5 g/dL in men)&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Specific genetic or hormonal cause of obesity such as Prader -Willi syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. For females of child-bearing potential: Pregnancy or desire to be pregnant during the&#xD;
             study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Cottam, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bariatric Medicine Institute, Salt Lake City, UT</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Walter Medlin, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Bariatric Medicine Institute, Salt Lake City, UT</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Peter Lukin</last_name>
    <phone>9787610183</phone>
    <email>peter.lukin@giwindows.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bariatric Medicine Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salt Lake City</city>
        <state>Utah</state>
        <zip>84102</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Amit Surve, MD</last_name>
      <email>dramitksurve@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniel Cottam, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Walter Medlin, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

