<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05062954</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Sentinel North (2020-2023)</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05062954</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of a Polyphenol-rich Cranberry Extract on Cardiometabolic and Neurocognitive Health</brief_title>
  <acronym>Neurocan</acronym>
  <official_title>Effects of a Polyphenol-rich Cranberry Extract on Cardiometabolic and Neurocognitive Health in Individuals With Abdominal Obesity: a Double-blind Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Laval University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Laval University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this double-blind, parallel, randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial is&#xD;
      to evaluate the effects of consumption of polyphenol-rich cranberry extract standardized in&#xD;
      PACs (36 mg PACs/capsule) on cardiometabolic and neurocognitive health in women and men&#xD;
      presenting abdominal obesity over an 8-week intervention period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will be conducted at Quebec Heart and Lung Institute - Laval University. The study&#xD;
      will involve a total of 60 adult men and women presenting abdominal obesity. Included&#xD;
      participants will be randomly assigned to the consumption of a cranberry extract or a placebo&#xD;
      at a rate of one capsule per day for 8 weeks (56 days). The main outcomes are changes in&#xD;
      metabolic profile, neurocognitive performance as well as brain structure and function&#xD;
      following polyphenol-rich cranberry extract standardized in PACs compared with the placebo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background :&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abdominal obesity is associated with impaired cognitive function and increased risk of&#xD;
      neurodegenerative diseases. The metabolic disorders associated with obesity may lead to&#xD;
      alterations in brain function and structure, explaining the link between obesity and some&#xD;
      cognitive dysfunction. Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) studies show that obese individuals&#xD;
      are characterized by gray matter atrophy in brain regions involved in self-control. Atrophy&#xD;
      and alteration of white matter fibers have also been observed in these individuals. However,&#xD;
      the mechanisms explaining these changes are not yet elucidated. It has been suggested that&#xD;
      metabolic and inflammatory alterations associated with abdominal obesity may lead to these&#xD;
      brain alterations.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is well known that dietary intake influences the composition and diversity of the gut&#xD;
      microbiota and that its disruption plays a central role in the development of obesity,&#xD;
      chronic low-grade inflammation, insulin resistance and cardiovascular disease. Some studies&#xD;
      have reported improvements in blood pressure, lipid profile, glucose homeostasis, endothelial&#xD;
      function, arterial stiffness and inflammation following cranberry consumption, but others&#xD;
      found no significant changes. A recent meta-analysis reported that taking a polyphenol-rich&#xD;
      supplement is associated with improved cognitive function in young adults. Although the&#xD;
      mechanisms underlying the beneficial effects of polyphenols on brain function and cognition&#xD;
      remain to be elucidated, some studies suggest that these effects may be associated with their&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory and antioxidant properties and their possible effect on the cerebrovascular&#xD;
      system. To our knowledge, there are no randomized controlled studies that have evaluated the&#xD;
      effects of polyphenol-rich cranberry extract standardized in PACs on neurometabolic and&#xD;
      neurocognitive functions in participants with abdominal obesity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives and Hypothesis:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this double-blind, randomized placebo-controlled clinical trial is to&#xD;
      evaluate the effects of consumption of polyphenol-rich cranberry extract standardized in PACs&#xD;
      (36 mg PACs/capsule) on cardiometabolic and neurocognitive health in abdominally obese women&#xD;
      and men over an 8-week period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The overall hypothesis is that standardized extract of PACs from cranberry improves the&#xD;
      metabolic profiles in abdominally obese individuals and this will have a beneficial impact on&#xD;
      brain and neurocognitive functions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sixty men and women with a BMI between 30 and 40 kg/m2 and an altered blood lipid profile&#xD;
      (triglycerides) will be recruited at the IUCPQ-Université Laval via social networks and Laval&#xD;
      University's recall lists. The study will include 3 visits to the IUCPQ-Université Laval as&#xD;
      well as the consumption of a cranberry extract or a placebo at a rate of one capsule per day&#xD;
      for 8 weeks (56 days). The eligibility visit (V1) consists of completing a medical history&#xD;
      questionnaire, and anthropometric and fasting blood lipid measurements. Individuals eligible&#xD;
      to participate will then be invited to 2 identical visits at the IUCPQ-Université Laval (V2&#xD;
      and V3). At visit 2, cognitive tasks, anthropometric measurements, blood pressure, MRI&#xD;
      (Philips 3T) and a pan-body DXA will be performed in all participants. Cognitive function&#xD;
      will be measured using a battery of validated neurocognitive tasks. On the morning of each&#xD;
      MRI session, fasting blood samples will be collected. Stool samples will be collected by&#xD;
      participants prior to each visit 2 and 3 to measure microbiota composition. Following visit&#xD;
      2, participants will leave with capsules of cranberry extract containing 36 mg of PACS or a&#xD;
      placebo (double-blind randomization) and will be asked to consume one capsule per day for 56&#xD;
      consecutive days. They will return for the 3rd visit (identical to V2) 8 weeks after starting&#xD;
      the supplements. Dietary and physical activity questionnaires will also be completed online&#xD;
      before visits 2 and 3. At the beginning of the visits, any changes in the participant's&#xD;
      health condition and use of medications and natural health products will be documented. A&#xD;
      follow-up phone call will be scheduled with each participant on day 28 of the intervention to&#xD;
      ensure that the intervention is going well. Adverse events related to supplementation will be&#xD;
      documented. An end-of-study questionnaire will be completed by the participant at the last&#xD;
      visit (V3) to confirm study blinding. Participants will be asked to report the remaining&#xD;
      capsules at the last visit (V3), which will allow assessment of compliance with the&#xD;
      intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in basic plasma lipid-lipoprotein profile</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in glucose homeostasis</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in lipopolysaccharide binding protein (LBP)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Fasting blood samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in white matter health assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>T2-weighted images, axial fluid-attenuated inversion recovery</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in brain density in key regions</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Structural MRI measurements</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in functional brain connectivity</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Resting state functional MRI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in white matter integrity</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Diffusion tensor imaging</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in cerebral vasculature</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Magnetic resonance angiography time-of-flight (MRA-TOF)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Gut microbiota composition</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measures in fecal samples</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in executive function</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Stroop</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in attention span and short-term working memory</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Digit Span</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in cognitive flexibility and speed of information processing</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Trail Making Test (Parts A and B)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in biomarkers of gut endotoxemia</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Blood plasma samples will be analysed for presence of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in biomarkers of gut permability</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Blood plasma samples will be analysed for presence of zonulin</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Changes in body fat distribution</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Abdominal axial T1-weighted slices</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Abdominal Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Polyphenol-rich cranberry extract supplement standardized in PACs</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Supplementation with polyphenol-rich cranberry extract standardized in PACs (1 capsule / day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo supplement</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Supplementation with placebo (1 capsule / day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Polyphenol-rich cranberry extract supplement standardized in proanthocyanidins</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be randomly assigned to the consumption of one capsule of Polyphenol-rich cranberry extract standardized in PACs.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Polyphenol-rich cranberry extract supplement standardized in PACs</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo supplement</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be randomly assigned to the consumption of one capsule of placebo per day for 56 consecutive days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo supplement</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men and women aged between 30-65 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI between 30-40 kg/m2;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Waist circumference ≥85 cm for women, ≥90 cm for men;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable weight in the past 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Plasma triglycerides levels ≥1.5 mmol/L for men and women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a computer and Internet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any severe uncontrolled medical, surgical, neurological or psychiatric condition;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medication for hypertension, dyslipidemias, CVD, T2D or obesity;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medication that may affect the CNS;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gastro-intestinal conditions or disorders likely to impact on absorption;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of nephrolithiasis or urolithiasis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindications to MRI (cardiac pacemaker/defibrillator, cochlear implant or other&#xD;
             ear implant, implanted insulin pump or other infusion pump systems, neurostimulator or&#xD;
             other electronic/magnetic implant or device, any type of prothesis, aneurysm clips,&#xD;
             any metallic fragments, vascular access port, catheter, dental retainer,&#xD;
             claustrophobia, surgery in the last 3 months);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Anticoagulant/blood thinning medication in the last month;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding women;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Substance or alcohol abuse;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or intolerance to cranberry;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently smoking.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andréanne Michaud, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>418-656-8711</phone>
    <phone_ext>7087</phone_ext>
    <email>Andreanne.Michaud@fsaa.ulaval.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>vicky Leblanc, PhD</last_name>
    <email>vicky.leblanc@fsaa.ulaval.ca</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Quebec Heart and Lung Institute - Laval University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Québec</city>
        <zip>G1V 4G5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Andréannr Michaud, PhD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obesity, Abdominal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Proanthocyanidin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Procyanidin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

