<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05064566</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2017-1-AP1-2000</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05064566</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Caries Detection Methods</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Performance of Diagnostic Methods in Early Occlusal Caries</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Nazan Kocak Topbas</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Mersin University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mersin University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators aim will be to compare the diagnostic performance of clinical visual&#xD;
      examination (ICDAS II), intraoral/bite wing radiography (BW), near infrared light&#xD;
      transillumination (NIR-LT), and laser fluorescence (LF), in comparison to microcomputed&#xD;
      tomography (micro-CT) for the detection of non-cavitated occlusal enamel and dentin caries in&#xD;
      third molar teeth. Potential participants will be consecutively recruited.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Studies regarding comparison of diagnostic techniques for caries detection are generally&#xD;
      conducted under in vitro conditions due to ethical concerns. Considering the many recently&#xD;
      published in vitro studies which attempted to assess the diagnostic ability of different&#xD;
      caries diagnosis systems, it is not possible to know at what rate in vitro findings are&#xD;
      applicable to the clinical situation.The investigators would like to assess initial occlusal&#xD;
      caries lesions by using different diagnostic methods under in vivo conditions. In the present&#xD;
      study, the investigators will assess diagnostic accuracy of clinical visual examination&#xD;
      (ICDAS II), digital intraoral radiography, near infrared light transillumination (NIR-LT),&#xD;
      and laser fluorescence (LF), by examining third molar teeth in comparison to gold standard&#xD;
      micro-CT images. The null hypothesis of the study is that no significant difference exists&#xD;
      for the clinical performance of the evaluated methods in detecting non-cavitated occlusal&#xD;
      caries in either the enamel or the dentin. This prospective study will include 101 third&#xD;
      molars of 101 patients with non-cavitated occlusal caries requiring extraction. ICDAS II, BW,&#xD;
      NIR-LT and LF examinations will be carried out by two examiners. Gold standard will be&#xD;
      determined by micro-CT imaging after extraction. Intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC)&#xD;
      value will be calculated for examiner agreement. Accuracy rate, sensitivity, specificity,&#xD;
      predictive values and areas under receiver operating characteristic curves (Az) will be&#xD;
      calculated. Clinical application time and patient comfort/pain analysis will be compared.&#xD;
      Nonparametric variables will be assessed by Kruskal Wallis Test. Significance level will be&#xD;
      set at p&lt;0.05.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 20, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 20, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Accuracy</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The accuracy of caries detection methods will be evaluated when compared to the gold standard Micro CT.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Receptor operating characteristic (ROC) curves</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Receptor operating characteristic (ROC) curves (Az) will be calculated to show the caries distinguishing ability of each caries detection method and the observer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Intra- and inter-observer reproducibility will be assessed by intraclass correlation coefficient (ICC).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient comfort/pain analysis by using Visual Analog Scale (VAS)(comparative assessment of the tests):</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The patients will be asked to rate their feelings (based on comfort and pain) from absence of discomfort and pain to extreme discomfort and pain (between 0 and 10) for each clinical method.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical time efficacy (comparative assessment of the tests)</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical application times from the beginning of the procedure to the end of the procedure for each method will be calculated by using a stopwatch. (example: LF pen 10 sn)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">101</enrollment>
  <condition>Caries</condition>
  <condition>Diagnoses Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>caries diagnosis</arm_group_label>
    <description>diagnostic accuracy of clinical visual examination (ICDAS II), digital intraoral radiography, near infrared light transillumination (NIR-LT), and laser fluorescence (LF), by examining third molar teeth in comparison to gold standard micro-CT images.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>caries assessment</intervention_name>
    <description>clinical visual examination (ICDAS II), digital io radiography, near infrared light transillumination (NIR-LT), and laser fluorescence (LF), and micro-CT images.</description>
    <arm_group_label>caries diagnosis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study sample will be comprised of 100 third molars requiring extraction with&#xD;
        non-cavitated but suspected occlusal caries from 101 patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  According to the American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) only status 1/ healthy&#xD;
             patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completely erupted permanent dentition,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No fixed orthodontic apparatus, prosthetic restoration and filling material,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A minimum age of 18 years,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least one third erupted molar teeth (third mandibular or third maxillary molar from&#xD;
             each patient was included),&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non cavitated occlusal caries,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Teeth with no hypoplasia or hypomineralization,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Third molar teeth that require extraction for surgery, orthodontics and prosthetic&#xD;
             reasons,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If clinical indicators suggest a current caries risk or activity that required&#xD;
             additional diagnosis, the patients will be asked to participate in this additional&#xD;
             examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients younger than 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that can not be recruited according to the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nazan Koçak Topbaş, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mersin University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Nazan Koçak Topbaş, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+905458297898</phone>
    <email>nazankocak@mersin.edu.tr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mersin University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Yenisehir</city>
        <state>Mersin</state>
        <zip>33150</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nazan Kocak Topbas, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>905458297898</phone>
      <email>nazankocak@mersin.edu.tr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mersin University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Nazan Kocak Topbas</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assist. Prof. Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Caries detection;</keyword>
  <keyword>laser fluorescence</keyword>
  <keyword>micro-CT</keyword>
  <keyword>visual analog scale</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

