<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05066191</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>169_2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05066191</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Gluten Contamination in Celiac Patients Clinically Responsive and Unresponsive to the Gluten-free Diet</brief_title>
  <acronym>GIP</acronym>
  <official_title>Impact of Gluten Contamination in Celiac Patients Clinically</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary aim of the study is to detect the presence of gluten immunogenic peptides (GIP)&#xD;
      in urine samples from celiac patients on a gluten-free diet clinically responsive and&#xD;
      non-responsive to dietary treatment and from suspected celiac patients already on a&#xD;
      gluten-free diet.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Once a year, celiac patients perform a clinical (gastroenterological visit) and blood&#xD;
      chemistry (blood tests) check. At the Center for the Prevention and Diagnosis of Celiac&#xD;
      Disease, about 1400 check-ups of celiac patients are carried out per year. During this annual&#xD;
      control visit, consecutive patients afferent to the center and suffering from celiac disease&#xD;
      who have been treated for more than 6 months, clinically &quot;responsive&quot; and &quot;non-responsive&quot; to&#xD;
      the gluten free diet (GFD), will be invited to participate in the proposed study. Those who&#xD;
      participate will be given the symptom questionnaires (VAS), the food questionnaire in order&#xD;
      to evaluate the relevance of the symptoms reported and the type of diet followed by the&#xD;
      patient and the adherence test to the gluten-free diet (CDAT). Urine samples will be&#xD;
      collected to test the presence of GIP (gluten immunogenic peptides) and for patients whose&#xD;
      samples test positive, will be asked for a stool sample to detect GIP.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects with suspected celiac disease but already on a gluten-free diet will undergo a&#xD;
      challenge, or the reintroduction of gluten in incremental steps of three weeks (routinely&#xD;
      performed as per the instructions of the Italian Health Care System).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>GIP</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>GIP Immunogenic Peptide Assay in Urine</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gluten-free diet</measure>
    <time_frame>3 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of adherence to gluten-free diet and of gluten food intake</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">300</enrollment>
  <condition>Celiac Disease</condition>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      urinary and fecal samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study population will be patients with celiac disease and suspected celiac disease&#xD;
        (about 300)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 18 to 65 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gender: Males and Females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients: suffering from Celiac Disease and suspected, but already on a gluten-free&#xD;
             diet&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Celiac patients less than 6 months after diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Celiac patients reporting intentional gluten ingestion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Luca Elli, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico di Milano</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Maurizio Vecchi, MD</last_name>
    <phone>0255033418</phone>
    <email>maurizio.vecchi@policlinico.mi.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fondazione IRCCS Cà Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico di Milano</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <state>MI</state>
        <zip>20122</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Comino I, Real A, Vivas S, Síglez MÁ, Caminero A, Nistal E, Casqueiro J, Rodríguez-Herrera A, Cebolla A, Sousa C. Monitoring of gluten-free diet compliance in celiac patients by assessment of gliadin 33-mer equivalent epitopes in feces. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012 Mar;95(3):670-7. doi: 10.3945/ajcn.111.026708. Epub 2012 Jan 18.</citation>
    <PMID>22258271</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Comino I, Fernández-Bañares F, Esteve M, Ortigosa L, Castillejo G, Fambuena B, Ribes-Koninckx C, Sierra C, Rodríguez-Herrera A, Salazar JC, Caunedo Á, Marugán-Miguelsanz JM, Garrote JA, Vivas S, Lo Iacono O, Nuñez A, Vaquero L, Vegas AM, Crespo L, Fernández-Salazar L, Arranz E, Jiménez-García VA, Antonio Montes-Cano M, Espín B, Galera A, Valverde J, Girón FJ, Bolonio M, Millán A, Cerezo FM, Guajardo C, Alberto JR, Rosinach M, Segura V, León F, Marinich J, Muñoz-Suano A, Romero-Gómez M, Cebolla Á, Sousa C. Fecal Gluten Peptides Reveal Limitations of Serological Tests and Food Questionnaires for Monitoring Gluten-Free Diet in Celiac Disease Patients. Am J Gastroenterol. 2016 Oct;111(10):1456-1465. doi: 10.1038/ajg.2016.439. Epub 2016 Sep 20. Erratum in: Am J Gastroenterol. 2017 Jul;112(7):1208.</citation>
    <PMID>27644734</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Moreno ML, Cebolla Á, Muñoz-Suano A, Carrillo-Carrion C, Comino I, Pizarro Á, León F, Rodríguez-Herrera A, Sousa C. Detection of gluten immunogenic peptides in the urine of patients with coeliac disease reveals transgressions in the gluten-free diet and incomplete mucosal healing. Gut. 2017 Feb;66(2):250-257. doi: 10.1136/gutjnl-2015-310148. Epub 2015 Nov 25.</citation>
    <PMID>26608460</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Luca Elli, MD, PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Gastroenterologist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>non celiac gluten sensitivity</keyword>
  <keyword>gluten reintroduction</keyword>
  <keyword>GIP</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Celiac Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

