<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05060510</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>1000078377-3</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05060510</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The School SPIT Study - COVID-19 Testing in Secondary Schools</brief_title>
  <official_title>The School SPIT Study (Saliva to Promote Improved Testing): A Prospective Evaluation of a Home Saliva Testing Program for COVID-19 Implemented With a Stepped-wedge Cluster Randomized Design in Secondary Schools.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The Hospital for Sick Children</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The Hospital for Sick Children</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will conduct an evaluation of a program that is being implemented SickKids /&#xD;
      Toronto Public health that provides take-home saliva testing kits in schools. Operationally,&#xD;
      there is a planned randomization so that all schools have an equitable chance to receive the&#xD;
      intervention at various time periods during the planned operational roll-out, which will&#xD;
      require a staggered implementation consistent with the stepped-wedge study design. The study&#xD;
      will leverage this chance implementation to do a robust evaluation of the public health&#xD;
      intervention. Schools that are not being rolled out to week one, will begin in the &quot;control&#xD;
      phase&quot; (testing at an assessment center) and transition to the program &quot;intervention phase&quot;&#xD;
      (take home saliva kits available at schools) at a randomly assigned time (wedge) over a&#xD;
      6-week period with all schools receiving the program by the end of the study. The&#xD;
      investigators will evaluate the impact of the program on SARS-CoV-2 case identification in&#xD;
      schools.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a prospective evaluation of a program that is being implemented using a&#xD;
      stepped-wedge, cluster randomized design.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligible secondary public schools in Toronto Region will be randomized. The study will occur&#xD;
      over a 7-week period with a minimum of one-week of baseline data (control phase - testing at&#xD;
      an assessment center, primary care or acute care center) and then schools will start the&#xD;
      program in a stepwise manner (10 crossovers per week) with take-home saliva being available&#xD;
      to all 60 schools by the end of the study period. The primary objective of the study is to&#xD;
      assess whether the availability of take home saliva kits at schools for symptomatic PCR&#xD;
      testing leads to increased diagnosis of COVID-19 cases in the school.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a prospective evaluation of a program that is being implemented using a stepped-wedge, cluster randomized design.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>SARS-CoV-2 Case Identification</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly measurement over 7 week study period</time_frame>
    <description>The number of cases positive for SARS-CoV-2 in a cohort per week per school (rate per cohort per week) in the intervention period compared to the control period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uptake of take-home saliva kits for testing</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly measurement over 7 week study period</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of use of take-home saliva kits per school per week</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact on timing of test for symptomatic individuals</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 7 week study period</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether availability of take-home saliva kits at school leads to earlier testing as measured by duration of symptoms before testing of the symptomatic case</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Impact on secondary transmission</measure>
    <time_frame>Over 7 week study period</time_frame>
    <description>To assess whether the availability of take-home saliva testing leads to reduced transmission within exposed cohorts as measured by the number of secondary cases identified in exposed cohorts.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV2 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>control phase</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Schools will start in the control phase (SARS-CoV-2 diagnostic testing at an assessment center, primary care office or acute care center) and transition to the intervention phase at a randomly assigned time point over the course of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention phase</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Schools will have take home saliva kits available at the school to support SARS-CoV-2 diagnostic testing. Schools will transition to the intervention phase at a randomly assigned time (wedge) over a 6-week period with all schools receiving the program by the end of the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Take home saliva kit</intervention_name>
    <description>Saliva kits will be made available at schools for pick up to support symptomatic testing using PCR for students, staff and family members.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention phase</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Secondary schools will be included in the evaluation if they are:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Considered a secondary school by the school board&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Open for in-person learning during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  They have at least 100 students&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Offer Grades 9-12 (secondary)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Schools that are middle schools only, that are not open for in-person learning, have fewer&#xD;
        than 100 students or are not a complete secondary school (i.e. adult learning schools,&#xD;
        schools offering independent courses, prep schools with 1-2 grades, secondary schools with&#xD;
        &lt; 4 grades) will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The Hospital for Sick Children</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toronto</city>
        <state>Ontario</state>
        <zip>M5G 1X8</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The Hospital for Sick Children</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Michelle Science</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>School Testing</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>COVID-19</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

