<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05065723</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AkcayB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05065723</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigation of the Effect of Internet Addiction Level in University Students</brief_title>
  <official_title>Investigation of the Effect of Internet Addiction Level on Thumb Pressure Pain Threshold, Hand Strength and Manual Dexterity in University Students</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bandırma Onyedi Eylül University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bandırma Onyedi Eylül University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The internet, which has become a part of our daily life; serves many purposes such as quick&#xD;
      access to information, e-mail, and chat, banking and shopping, having a good time, using&#xD;
      social networking sites. Internet addiction, which was first defined by Ivan Goldberg in&#xD;
      1996, is defined as the inability to control internet use, which causes pressure, feelings of&#xD;
      anxiety, and dysfunctional behaviors in daily life activities. Social media, digital games&#xD;
      and smartphone addiction are among the addiction types whose active ingredient is the&#xD;
      internet, and internet addiction is expressed as a whole, regardless of the type of addictive&#xD;
      application or activity. Considering that internet use is common among young people, one of&#xD;
      the risk groups in terms of internet addiction is university students. As a matter of fact,&#xD;
      Günay et al. stated that approximately 8% of university students are at risk of internet&#xD;
      addiction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the literature, musculoskeletal problems and pain in the thumb and related joints,&#xD;
      reduction in pinch strength, and hand function have been reported with smartphone use. In&#xD;
      addition, a significant relationship was found between the time spent surfing the Internet&#xD;
      and pain at the base of the thumb. However, to the best of our knowledge, no study has been&#xD;
      found that examines the effect of internet addiction level on thumb pain threshold, hand&#xD;
      strength and manual dexterity in university students. The aim of our research is to determine&#xD;
      the level of internet addiction in university students and to examine the effect of internet&#xD;
      addiction level on thumb pressure pain threshold, hand strength and manual dexterity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 24, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 24, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Internet Addiction Test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>It was developed by Young and its Turkish validity and reliability study was performed by Bayraktar in 2001. The test consists of 20 items in total and is evaluated with a 6-point Likert type scale. In the test, which is scored between 0-100, people who score 49 or less are grouped as &quot;No Symptom&quot;, people who score between 50 and 79 &quot;Limited Symptom&quot; and people who get 80 points or more are grouped as &quot;Pathological Internet Users&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pressure Pain Threshold</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Pressure pain threshold, defined as the minimum force that triggers pain, is measured with an instrument called an algometer. The value obtained when the person indicates when the pressure sensation turns into a painful sensation is recorded in kg/cm²</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hand Strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>For the standard grip strength measurement, the person is asked to squeeze the dynamometer strongly and leave it completely loose while the elbow is in 90⁰ flexion and the forearm is in the neutral position, which is the standard test position of the American Hand Therapists Association, with a hand dynamometer. The average of the values obtained by measuring in 3 repetitions on the right and left hands is taken</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pinch Strength</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The average is taken by measuring the pinchmeter in 3 repetitions on the right and left hands. In measurements, pinching force is evaluated by measuring in pinch, lateral and tripod grip positions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Minnesota Manual Dexterity Test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Black and red discs are used for Minnesota Manual Dexterity Test and it consists of 2 sub-parameters as Placement Test and Turning Test. The test measures gross dexterity, coordination, and speed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Purdue Pegboard Test</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Developed by Tiffin in 1948; Its use in industrial candidates, veterans, college students, and people seeking vocational guidance has yielded important information about its validity and reliability, and practical implications. For the Purdue Peg Board Test, a platform consisting of two 0.45x0.29 m vertical columns, 25 test boards with 3 mm diameter holes in each, and 4 compartments containing pins (pegs), washers and collars is used. The test that evaluates fine dexterity unilaterally and bilaterally; It consists of a total of 4 subtest sections: Right Placement, Left Placement, Bilateral Placement and Right+Left+Bilateral Placement</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">125</enrollment>
  <condition>University Students</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Students aged between 18-25 and studying at Bandırma Onyedi Eylül University&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being between the ages of 18-25&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being a student at Bandırma Onyedi Eylül University&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any injury involving the upper extremity in the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any surgical operation involving the upper extremity in the last 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any systemic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any neurological problems&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any psychiatric medication&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Burçin Akçay</last_name>
    <phone>+90 266 606 4535</phone>
    <email>akcayburcin@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bandırma Onyedi Eylül University Faculty of Health Sciences Department of Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Balıkesir</city>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Burçin Akçay</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Şule Keçelioğlu</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Hamiyet Yüce</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gülhan Yılmaz Gökmen</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Melike Sümeyye Özen</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bandırma Onyedi Eylül University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Burçin Akçay</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Internet Addiction</keyword>
  <keyword>Pain Threshold</keyword>
  <keyword>Hand Strength</keyword>
  <keyword>Manual Dexterity</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Behavior, Addictive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Internet Addiction Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

