<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05065996</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>5063566</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05065996</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Prediction of Aortic Dilatation and Rupture</brief_title>
  <acronym>DilAo</acronym>
  <official_title>Prediction of Aortic Dilation and Rupture in Different Predisposing Pathologies A Prospective Clinical Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Kuopio University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Eastern Finland</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>JAMK University Of Applied Sciences</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Kuopio University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aortic aneurysm is a very common incidental finding in the diagnostic imaging of the chest.&#xD;
      It is especially common in middle aged men (up to 40 %). It is called as a silent killer,&#xD;
      since it can lead to aortic dissection and rupture without pre-existing symptoms. Mortality&#xD;
      of rupture can be up to 50 %. This is why it causes extensive human uncertainty and fear.&#xD;
      Currently, there are no methods to identify the high risk patients. That leads to a practice&#xD;
      where all patients are followed with repeated aortic imaging using expensive methods such as&#xD;
      magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) and computed tomography.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is data, that modern 4D flow MRI parameters well describe the intra-aortic flow&#xD;
      conditions. This prospective clinical trial explore the value of 4D flow MRI parameters in&#xD;
      the prediction of aortic dilatation and rupture. The trial consists of three subtrials in&#xD;
      whitch the 4D flow MRI parameters are tested in clinical practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      1. Purpose of the study The purpose of this study is to explore prognostic parameters for&#xD;
      aortic dilation. More specifically it is to identify prognostic imaging parameters which&#xD;
      could be used to identify patients at high risk for rapid aortic dilation and should be&#xD;
      intensively followed by imaging methods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. Subtrials&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Clinical study 1 The aim of the first phase of the study targets to identify 4D MRI flow&#xD;
           parameters which are characteristic to dilated aorta and might be used to evaluate&#xD;
           future prognosis in patients with aortic dilatation or predisposing factors.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Clinical study 2 The second phase of the study aims to use identified flow parameters in&#xD;
           clinical imaging follow up to find out which parameters predict aortic dilation in real&#xD;
           life and thus could be used to select patients for more intensive imaging in future.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Study 3 - Molecular pathology, histology and genetics of aorta The aim of this part of&#xD;
           the study is to find out differences in molecular biology, histology, elasticity and&#xD;
           genetics of the aorta in patients having predisposing factors for aortic dilation.&#xD;
           Particularly, cellular factors influencing the formation of connective tissue and&#xD;
           vascular smooth muscle layer will be studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3. Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Patient population All patients and healthy volunteers will give their written informed&#xD;
      consent for the study. The Ethical Committee of Northern Savo hospital district has given&#xD;
      approval for the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 1 The first phase of the study will include twenty patients with anatomical or&#xD;
      functional BAV or other disease predisposing to dilation of aorta scheduled for routine&#xD;
      aortic MRI in Kuopio University Hospital (KUH) Department of Radiology. 4D flow MRI will be&#xD;
      done right after the routine 2D MRI and it will extend the imaging time approximately 20&#xD;
      minutes. Twenty healthy voluntary controls will be recruited from the research group and&#xD;
      personnel of the department and they will be scheduled for the similar imaging procedure. The&#xD;
      main parameters analyzed from this one-off imaging data are peak flow velocity and&#xD;
      eccentricity of the flow, flow vorticity and wall shear stress. Also, parameters related to&#xD;
      aortic stiffness and geometry will be determined in this study. Comparison of the 4D flow MRI&#xD;
      parameters between the patients and healthy controls will be done, 4D flow parameters will&#xD;
      also be compared to conventional 2D flow parameters both in the study patients and in healthy&#xD;
      controls.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 2 For the follow-up study 100 patients will be recruited on the same manner as in the&#xD;
      case of the first study patients. The inclusion criteria will be: adult (age &gt; 18 years),&#xD;
      previously documented aortic dilation, documented anatomical or functional BAV or other&#xD;
      inherited disorder, which caus-es increased risk for aortic dilation, no contraindication for&#xD;
      MRI. Similar aortic MRI will be performed as during the clinical study 1. However, the&#xD;
      follow-up imaging will be performed after 6 months from the first MRI and yearly for 5 years.&#xD;
      Same 4D and 2D flow parameters will be analyzed as in the first study. The special interest&#xD;
      will be appointed to the degree of aortic dilation and correlation between 4D (and 2D) flow&#xD;
      parameters to the aortic dimensions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical parameters All patients visiting outpatient clinic will have clinical examination&#xD;
      (auscultation, clinical signs for heart failure, hepatomegaly, peripheral edema, arterial&#xD;
      murmurs). 12-lead electrocardiography and basic laboratory analyses (hemoglobin, hematocrit,&#xD;
      sodium, potassium, creatinine, brain natriuretic peptide) will be performed. With patient&#xD;
      written permission, an additional tube of blood will be saved for future analysis and the&#xD;
      patient will be informed about the purpose of this sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Echocardiography Transthoracal echocardiography will be done by using routine clinical&#xD;
      methods. Special interest will be appointed to aortic valve anatomy and aortic dimensions.&#xD;
      Other signs of cardiac mani-festations will also be registered. Ventricular dimensions and&#xD;
      volumetric parameters as well as ventricular systolic and diastolic function will be&#xD;
      evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aorta MRI Magnetic resonance angiography and 2D flow measurements Static imaging of the aorta&#xD;
      is done with an ECG- and respiratory-gated 3D SSFP (steady state free percession) sequence&#xD;
      [Kawel et al 2012]. Image stack is obtained in sagittal plane and processed at the&#xD;
      MPR-workstation to get images perpendicular to the axis of blood flow. The diameter of the&#xD;
      aorta is measured from outer wall to the outer wall. The widest diameter of the aorta is&#xD;
      de-termined and, as a routine, diameter of the aorta is measure at 8 pre-determined levels.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4D phase contrast MRI Blood flow in the aorta will be measured based on MRI phase contrast.&#xD;
      The measurement will be done by repeating the imaging pulse sequence without and with flow&#xD;
      weighting gradients for three dimensions with interleaved manner and the measurement. The&#xD;
      imaging parameters will be set according to 4D MRI flow measurement consensus statement&#xD;
      [Dyverfelt 2015] shortly: resolution of &lt; 2.5x2.5x2.5 mm3, temporal resolution of 30 ms (time&#xD;
      resolution in flow in different cardiac phases), retrospective ECG synchronization and&#xD;
      respiratory motion compensation, flip an-gle close to Ernst angle and the flow weighting&#xD;
      gradient amplitude so that maximum flow of 10 % higher than expected maximum flow rate in the&#xD;
      aorta. The imaging volume will be cover the aor-tic valve, aortic arc and descending aorta at&#xD;
      the level of apex of myocardium. The data will be preprocessed to minimize contribution from&#xD;
      background phase offsets, gradient imperfections and phase wraps.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Flow parameters From the 4D flow images, several quantitative parameters will be extracted.&#xD;
      The main parame-ters are the ones describing flow distribution in the aorta, i.e. peak flow&#xD;
      velocity and eccentricity, flow vorticity and shear stress on the vessel walls. Furthermore,&#xD;
      several parameters related to aortic stiffness and geometry and function of aortic valve,&#xD;
      will be recorded. During follow-up, changes and prognostic value of the quantified parameters&#xD;
      will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the purpose of validation 4D flow parameters will be compared to parameters extracted from&#xD;
      conventional 2D flow sequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical follow-up protocol Patients recruited for the follow up study (study 2) will be&#xD;
      re-screened by aortic MRI after half year from the recruitment and yearly after the first&#xD;
      follow-up visit up to five years or according to clinical follow-up schedule. If the state of&#xD;
      the aortic dilation indicates more intensive follow-up will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analyses Prognostic factors will be tested for statistical significance by&#xD;
      comparing flow parameters and as-sociated factors to the degree of aortic dilation by using&#xD;
      appropriate multivariate analysis . Statis-tical significance will be set at p&lt;0.05 and high&#xD;
      statistical significance at p &lt; 0.01. The data will be analyzed by using SPSS for Windows&#xD;
      program.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study 3&#xD;
&#xD;
      The third subtrial will enroll 20+100 patients with severe aortic dilatation scheduled for&#xD;
      aortic operation. Human aorta samples are collected during routine aorta replacement surgery&#xD;
      from the removed vascular tissue. In addition to tissue samples, a blood sample will be&#xD;
      collected for genetic and molecular analysis. Patients have given their written permission&#xD;
      for the histological and blood samples before the operation. After resection, samples are&#xD;
      immediately transferred into liquid nitrogen (frozen samples), PFA-PBS (histological samples)&#xD;
      or to cell culture medium for cell isolation (endothelial cells, vascular smooth muscle&#xD;
      cells, fibroblasts). Frozen samples are stored in -70 °C and isolated cells in liquid&#xD;
      nitrogen. Histological samples will be processed into the paraffin and stored as a paraffin&#xD;
      blocks. Samples will be stored up to 10 years, and after which they are destroyed as a&#xD;
      biohazard waste. Raw data will be stored in electrical archive like European Genome-phenome&#xD;
      Archive (EGA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Analyses Molecular biology and histology of the aorta samples are examined by RT-qPCR,&#xD;
      immunohisto-chemistry and multiphoton microscopy imaging. Expression of relevant genes e.g.&#xD;
      TGF-β, VEGF-family, COX-1 and 2, eNOS/Akt and pro-inflammatory cytokines is studied, and also&#xD;
      RNA -sequencing, identifying all expressed mRNAs simultaneously, can be used for finding&#xD;
      differences in expression of all aortic genes between different patient groups. FBN1 gene is&#xD;
      sequenced and looked for mutations or deletions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aorta vessel wall architecture and expression of relevant genes is visualized by multiphoton&#xD;
      mi-croscopy and immunohistochemistry. Isolated cells are used for Single Cell Analysis, which&#xD;
      allows studying one living cell and its molecular events at a time, and gives totally new&#xD;
      information about functions of different cells in vessel wall. Obtained data is divided in&#xD;
      disease- and age matching groups, and correlations between cardiac disease status, aortic&#xD;
      gene expression and aortic histology will be looked for. Data will also be connected and&#xD;
      compared to the pre-clinical mouse study described in Appendix 1, and human aorta MRI 4D flow&#xD;
      imaging study described in paragraph 3.4.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biomechanics of histological aorta samples Biomechanical parameters such as the stiffness and&#xD;
      failure strength will be measured from the aorta samples. The measurements and analysis will&#xD;
      be done in collaboration with The BBC group in University of Eastern Finland. The&#xD;
      biomechanical parameters in the studied patients groups will be compared and used as a&#xD;
      parameter in multivariant statistical analyses. The results will also be compared and linked&#xD;
      to findings of histological and molecular biology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Controls Samples for comparison to normal tissue will be collected from 10 organ donors&#xD;
      operated in Kuopio University Hospital. The samples will be handled as described in aortic&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mathematic modelling of aorta Imaging data of 20 patients will be send anonymously to JAMK&#xD;
      University of Applied sciences for mathematic simulation modelling of aortic flow and wall&#xD;
      stress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4. Collaboration The clinical study is conducted multiprofessionally in Kuopio University&#xD;
      Hospital together with departments of clinical cardiology, cardiothoracic surgery (Heart&#xD;
      Center) and radiology (Clinical Imaging Center). The histopathological, molecular and genetic&#xD;
      studies are performed in the Department of Molecular Sciences in A I Virtanen Institute,&#xD;
      University of Eastern Finland (UEF). Biomechanical tests will be conduited in the Department&#xD;
      of Applied Physics in UEF.The mathematic modelling of the aortic images will be performed in&#xD;
      JAMK University of Applied Sciences. The acquired 4D MRI flow results will be analyzed and&#xD;
      validated according to standards of Kuopio University Hospital.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>5 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of WSS to aortic dilatation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>4D flow MRI wall shear stress value in correlation to aortic diameter in different time points</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Association of FD to aortic dilatation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>4D flow MRI flow displacement value in correlation to aortic diameter in different time points</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Association of WSS and FD to histology</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>hematoxylin eosin, CD31, inflammatory cells of human aortic samples in correlation to WSS and FD</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Association of WSS and FD to genetics</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Gene screening from human blood samples of aortic patients</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">170</enrollment>
  <condition>Aortic Rupture</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Different 4D flow MRI parameters in aortic dilatation and controls</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with aortic dilatation (n=20) scheduled for aortic MRI and healthy controls (n=20) without aortic dilatation. One time aortic MRI with 4D flow imaging.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Value of aortic 4D flow MRI parameters to predict aortic dilatation in 5 years follow up</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients with aortic dilatation (n=100) scheduled for aortic MRI follow up in Kuopio University Hospital. Aortic 4D flow MRI will be done yearly for 5 years and flow parameters predicting aortic dilatation will be analysed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Histology, molecular biology and genetics behind aortic dilatation</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients scheduled for aortic operation (n=20+100) in Kuopio University Hospital. Aortic tissue samples and blood will be collected for analysis and compared to 4D flow MRI parameters. Control samples will be collected from healthy organ donors (n=5+5) operated in Kuopio University Hospital.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Aortic MRI + 4D flow MRI</intervention_name>
    <description>Together with routine aortic MRI specific 4D flow MRI sequence will be done.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Different 4D flow MRI parameters in aortic dilatation and controls</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Histology, molecular biology and genetics behind aortic dilatation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Value of aortic 4D flow MRI parameters to predict aortic dilatation in 5 years follow up</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        -  Patients with aortic dilatation scheduled for follow up in Kuopio University Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with aortic dilatation scheduled for aortic operation in Kuopio University&#xD;
             Hospital&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  aortic dilatation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  scheduled for imaging follow up in Kuopio University Hospital&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  written informed concent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  lack of co-operation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  contraindications to MRI&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marja Hedman, Prof</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Kuopio University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Saara Sillanmäki, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+358456334855</phone>
    <email>saara.sillanmaki@kuh.fi</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Minna Husso, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+358447113918</phone>
    <email>minna.husso@kuh.fi</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kuopio University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kuopio</city>
        <zip>70029</zip>
        <country>Finland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marja Hedman, Prof</last_name>
      <phone>+358505611768</phone>
      <email>marja.hedman@kuh.fi</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Saara Sillanmäki, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+358456334855</phone>
      <email>saara.sillanmaki@kuh.fi</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Annastiina Husso, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Antti Valtola, MD,PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tarmo Korpela, MB</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Johanna P Laakkonen, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Miika Kiema, BSc</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Petteri Kauhanen, MD,PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Petri Saari, MD,PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Minna Husso, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elias Ylä-herttuala, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Iida Viitala, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Finland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Kuopio University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marja Hedman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>aortic dilatation</keyword>
  <keyword>aortic aneurysm</keyword>
  <keyword>4D flow MRI</keyword>
  <keyword>aortic rupture</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aortic Rupture</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>only anonymous imaging data will be send to JAMK university of applied sciences for mathematical modelling of aorta</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

