<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05064631</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>295882</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-000628-36</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05064631</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bacterial Lysate In Preventing Asthma</brief_title>
  <acronym>BLIPA</acronym>
  <official_title>Oral Bacterial Lysate to Prevent Persistent Wheeze in Infants After Severe Bronchiolitis; a Randomised Placebo-controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Queen Mary University of London</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Queensland University of Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Queen Mary University of London</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Bronchiolitis is a common viral infection of the small airways of infants and some affected&#xD;
      infants will require hospital admission. Severe bronchiolitis is a marker for greatly&#xD;
      increased risk of developing both preschool wheeze and subsequent school age asthma. Since&#xD;
      epidemiological studies suggest that exposure to microbial products protects against&#xD;
      preschool wheeze, lysates of bacteria may prevent the development of wheeze after&#xD;
      bronchiolitis, with long-term beneficial consequences.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BLIPA is a phase IIb, randomised, double blind, placebo-controlled study, investigating the&#xD;
      efficacy superiority of bacterial lysate (Broncho Vaxom) capsules over placebo, in reducing&#xD;
      wheeze in infants after severe bronchiolitis. The primary end point of the study is&#xD;
      parent-reported, healthcare-professional confirmed wheeze at 19-24 months. The study aims to&#xD;
      test bacterial lysate capsules (3.5mg over 24 months) for safety, efficacy, and to advance&#xD;
      mechanistic understanding of its action.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The BLIPA study aims to investigate the following research questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. In children hospitalised with bronchiolitis, does oral Broncho Vaxom (BV) given for 10&#xD;
           days per month for a total of 24 months, prevent parent-reported, healthcare&#xD;
           professional-confirmed, wheeze between 19 and 24 months post initiation of IMP/placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Does oral BV reduces the risk of wheeze after bronchiolitis by modulating T cell and DC&#xD;
           maturation and altering the gut and airway microbiota. (mechanistic hypothesis)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The BLIPA study will combine the results of two multi-centre, randomised trials with similar&#xD;
      but separate protocols: BLIPA-UK, with recruitment in London, Southampton, Edinburgh, and&#xD;
      Aberdeen and BLIPA-Australia, with recruitment in Brisbane, Gold Coast, Melbourne, Darwin and&#xD;
      Sydney.&#xD;
&#xD;
      BLIPA-UK is funded in the UK by the NIHR. BLIPA-Australia is funded in Australia by the ICTC&#xD;
      initiative. ICTC supports Australian researchers to conduct clinical trial research in&#xD;
      collaboration with international researchers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The total study duration is 54 months. The primary clinical objective is to recruit a&#xD;
      population of eligible participants, to randomise them to oral Broncho Vaxom (3.5mg) or&#xD;
      placebo, to be taken daily for 10 days a month over 24 months, follow up for 24 months and&#xD;
      compare primary and secondary outcomes between trial arms. Parents or guardians of children,&#xD;
      clinicians involved in their care and trial staff will be blinded to the treatment arm.&#xD;
      Recruitment will be for 18 months and children's outcomes will be assessed for 24 months&#xD;
      following initiation of IMP or placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within six weeks of hospital discharge following admission for bronchiolitis, parents or&#xD;
      guardians can consent to their child partaking in the study, baseline data is collected, the&#xD;
      child is randomised, and the IMP or placebo is initiated (12 months' supply). From the point&#xD;
      of treatment initiation, children are followed up for 24 months, the same length as the&#xD;
      treatment period. There will be at least one scheduled face to face visit at 12 months to&#xD;
      dispense a further year's supply of IMP or placebo.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Children will be allocated into two arms (oral BV and placebo) in a 1:1 ratio. Randomisation will be stratified by site and parental asthma and the lists generated using random blocks of size 4 and 6.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Parents or guardians will be blind to treatment allocation, as will the entire site study team involved in the management of the study, including the CI, PIs, sub-investigators, study nurses, and site coordinators. Trial Steering Committee (TSC) members will remain blind. The progress and safety of the study will be assessed by the Data Monitoring Committee (DMC). The DMC will therefore not be blinded. The main study trial manager (PCTU) and trial monitors will be blinded. The Sponsor's JRMO (including the JRMO monitor(s)) will unblind themselves to specific patients in order to report SUSARs to the MHRA. The study pharmacist will be blinded, and the study pharmacy file will contain blinded documents, please see pharmacy manual. The treatment allocation list will be available from the PCTU or their designate (Sealed Envelope) on request should the need arise.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Presence of a wheezing episode between 19 and 24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Parent or guardian reported wheeze between 19-24 months that is also confirmed by the presence of one or more of the following in the primary care record: salbutamol inhaler, active wheeze diagnosis, asthma diagnosis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prescription for more than one salbutamol inhaler between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of prescriptions for salbutamol inhalers as recorded on the primary care record between 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Active wheeze diagnosis on primary care record between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of an active wheeze diagnosis as recorded on the primary care record between 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asthma diagnosis on primary care record between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of an asthma diagnosis as recorded on the primary care record between 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to first episode of parent-reported wheeze during the 24 months since initiation of study drug</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>The time to first episode of parent-reported wheeze during the 24 months since initiation of study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of unscheduled medical attendances for wheeze between 19-24 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of unscheduled medical attendances for wheeze between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of hospital admissions for wheeze between 19-24 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospital admissions for wheeze between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of days admitted to hospital for wheeze between 19-24 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days admitted to hospital for wheeze between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of unscheduled medical attendances for any lower respiratory symptoms between 19-24 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of unscheduled medical attendances for any lower respiratory symptoms between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of courses of systemic corticosteroids for wheeze during the 24 months since initiation of study drug</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of courses of systemic corticosteroids for wheeze during the 24 months since initiation of study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of courses of oral corticosteroids for wheeze between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of courses of oral corticosteroids for wheeze between 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of courses of antibiotics for wheeze between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of courses of antibiotics for wheeze between 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prescription for regular oral montelukast between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of a prescription for regular oral montelukast recorded in the primary care record between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent reported eczema between 19-24 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of parent reported eczema between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eczema confirmed by U.K. Working Party's Diagnostic Criteria for Atopic Dermatitis. at 19-24 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Presence of Eczema confirmed by U.K. Working Party's Diagnostic Criteria for Atopic Dermatitis. between 19-24 months.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events for the treatment group between 0-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of AEs across 0-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of serious adverse events for the treatment group between 0-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SAEs across 0-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of SUSARs for the treatment group between 0-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>0-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SUSARs across 0-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of adverse events for the treatment group between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of AEs across 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of serious adverse events for the treatment group between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SAEs across 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of SUSARs for the treatment group between 19-24 months</measure>
    <time_frame>19-24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of SUSARs across 19-24 months</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">894</enrollment>
  <condition>Respiratory Tract Infections</condition>
  <condition>Pediatric ALL</condition>
  <condition>Wheezing</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Oral Broncho-Vaxom (3.5mg) administered daily for 10 days per month for 24 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Matched placebo administered daily for 10 days per month for 24 months</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bacterial Lysate</intervention_name>
    <description>Bacterial lysate medicines are made from bacterial cells that are broken down and are intended to stimulate the immune system.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo control</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Broncho Vaxom</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parent/Guardian able to provide written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Within 6 weeks of discharge from hospital for bronchiolitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Child aged 3-12 months at the time of consent to study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A diagnosis of Bronchiolitis requiring a hospital admission (defined as more than 4&#xD;
             hours in hospital)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contactable for regular follow up by the research team&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any previous hospital attendance for bronchiolitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  More than one episode of healthcare professional-diagnosed wheeze prior to index&#xD;
             bronchiolitis episode&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Premature gestational age less than 37 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any severe chronic condition such as cystic fibrosis, sickle cell disease, severe&#xD;
             developmental delay, immunodeficiency, or anything that has a significant impact on&#xD;
             the respiratory tract (such as need for non-invasive ventilation) or increases&#xD;
             vulnerability to respiratory tract infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of clinically significant neonatal disease (e.g. neonatal pneumonia,&#xD;
             congenital lung abnormality, neonatal chronic lung disease)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Genetic conditions that affect the immune system (e.g. Down's syndrome/Trisomy 21)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current regular oral montelukast or inhaled corticosteroid therapy or inhaled&#xD;
             salbutamol therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current regular treatment with immunomodulatory drugs (e.g oral steroids)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy or previous intolerance to study medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently enrolled to another RCT. (Unless prior approval is given by PI)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sibling of a BLIPA participant (of the same household or family)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Months</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jonathan Grigg, Prof. Dr</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Queen Mary University of London</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jonathan Grigg, Prof. Dr</last_name>
    <phone>00447789397850</phone>
    <email>j.grigg@qmul.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Maria D'Amico, MRes, BSc</last_name>
    <phone>07919 659975</phone>
    <email>m.damico@qmul.ac.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Asthma in childhood</keyword>
  <keyword>Bronchiolitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Wheeze</keyword>
  <keyword>Bacterial lysate</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Tract Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Respiratory Sounds</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Broncho-Vaxom</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

