<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05065476</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021P000359</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05065476</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessing the Impact of Isha Kriya Meditation on Anxiety and Depression - a Pilot Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessing the Impact of Isha Kriya Meditation on Anxiety and Depression - a Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to assess the impact of Isha Kriya, a freely available guided meditation, on&#xD;
      mental health - specifically anxiety and depression.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In 2019, over 15% of the population experienced symptoms of anxiety. This was highest amongst&#xD;
      18-29-year-olds. Amongst these adults, 9.5% experienced mild, 3.4% experienced moderate, and&#xD;
      2.7% experienced severe symptoms of anxiety. About 1 in 6 adults is expected to suffer from&#xD;
      depression at some point in their lives. Due to the pandemic, rates of anxiety and depression&#xD;
      increased significantly. In December 2020, 42% of people surveyed by the US Census Bureau had&#xD;
      symptoms associated with anxiety or depression. This is compared to 11% of adults having&#xD;
      similar symptoms from Jan-June 2019. The rapidly diminishing mental health in the general&#xD;
      population, especially since the COVID-19 pandemic, has raised the concern for an emerging&#xD;
      new pandemic: the mental health pandemic. Mental health leaders and organizations are urging&#xD;
      the federal and state authorities to make mental health a top priority and allocate resources&#xD;
      to areas including early identification and prevention, establishing integrated health and&#xD;
      mental health care to ensure &quot;whole-person&quot; well-being, assuring evidence-based standards of&#xD;
      prevention, treatment and care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Meditation has been shown to be effective in reducing symptoms associated with anxiety and&#xD;
      depression. A recent study using a meditation called Isha Kriya showed improved perceived&#xD;
      stress amongst operating room professionals in one sitting. Isha Kriya is a simple meditation&#xD;
      practice (15minutes) that can be done by anyone over 12 years of age. It is offered free&#xD;
      globally via in-person sessions, online webinars, and online videos. A meditation which is&#xD;
      available electronically and freely could be an attractive option to include in prevention&#xD;
      and treatment strategies for anxiety and depression. Furthermore, such intervention is easily&#xD;
      scalable and accessible to everyone with access to the internet and if found effective, can&#xD;
      be a valuable resource for addressing disparities in access to mental health resources in&#xD;
      minority and underserved populations. This study aims to assess the effectiveness of this&#xD;
      meditation on reducing symptoms associated with anxiety and depression over 6 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The weekly compliance questionnaire is a tool which helps the participants to keep a track of their activities each week. This enables the study team to measure compliance and protocol adherence by the participants by collecting information on their routine activity practiced, its frequency and duration.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PROMIS - Anxiety Short Form</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>PROMIS - Anxiety Short Form1 is an 8 item validated instrument that assesses severity of anxiety. Participants are asked on a scale of 1 (Never) to 5 (Always) on the frequency of occurrence of each negative experience. Overall score is computed based on sum from individual responses.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Center for Epidemiological Studies Depression Scale (CES-D-10)</measure>
    <time_frame>Changes from baseline to 6 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>PROMIS - Anxiety Short Form is an 8 item validated instrument that assesses severity of anxiety.&#xD;
Participants are asked on a scale of 1 (Never) to 5 (Always) on the frequency of occurrence of each negative experience. Overall score is computed based on sum from individual responses.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Depression</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Participants signed up for the webinar will be learning and practicing the &quot;Isha Kriya&quot; practice (meditation for beginners) taught by the Isha Foundation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Participants will be recruited from a pool of healthy volunteers who sign up for a webinar&#xD;
        where they learn the &quot;Isha Kriya&quot; practice. Isha Foundation has developed the Isha Kriya&#xD;
        practice and conducts online Isha Kriya webinars (Meditation for Beginners). This webinar&#xD;
        is routinely conducted by Isha Foundation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Interest in Isha Kriya&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low English proficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently residing in United States&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sepideh Hariri, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sepideh Hariri, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>206-313-3614</phone>
    <email>shariri1@bidmc.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Balachundhar Subramaniam, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>617-667-2721</phone>
    <email>bsubrama@bidmc.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Balachundhar Subramaniam, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>617-667-2721</phone>
      <email>bsubrama@bidmc.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Balachundhar Subramaniam, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.apa.org/news/press/releases/2020/12/mental-health-organizations</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Terlizzi EP, Villarroel MA. Symptoms of Generalized Anxiety Disorder Among Adults: United States, 2019. NCHS Data Brief. 2020 Sep;(378):1-8.</citation>
    <PMID>33054928</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kessler RC, Berglund P, Demler O, Jin R, Merikangas KR, Walters EE. Lifetime prevalence and age-of-onset distributions of DSM-IV disorders in the National Comorbidity Survey Replication. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005 Jun;62(6):593-602. Erratum in: Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2005 Jul;62(7):768. Merikangas, Kathleen R [added].</citation>
    <PMID>15939837</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abbott A. COVID's mental-health toll: how scientists are tracking a surge in depression. Nature. 2021 Feb;590(7845):194-195. doi: 10.1038/d41586-021-00175-z.</citation>
    <PMID>33536600</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saeed SA, Cunningham K, Bloch RM. Depression and Anxiety Disorders: Benefits of Exercise, Yoga, and Meditation. Am Fam Physician. 2019 May 15;99(10):620-627. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>31083878</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Saeed SA, Antonacci DJ, Bloch RM. Exercise, yoga, and meditation for depressive and anxiety disorders. Am Fam Physician. 2010 Apr 15;81(8):981-6. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20387774</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>González-Valero G, Zurita-Ortega F, Ubago-Jiménez JL, Puertas-Molero P. Use of Meditation and Cognitive Behavioral Therapies for the Treatment of Stress, Depression and Anxiety in Students. A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019 Nov 10;16(22). pii: E4394. doi: 10.3390/ijerph16224394.</citation>
    <PMID>31717682</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rangasamy V, Thampi Susheela A, Mueller A, F H Chang T, Sadhasivam S, Subramaniam B. The effect of a one-time 15-minute guided meditation (Isha Kriya) on stress and mood disturbances among operating room professionals: a prospective interventional pilot study. F1000Res. 2019 Mar 26;8:335. doi: 10.12688/f1000research.18446.1. eCollection 2019.</citation>
    <PMID>32665843</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 4, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Balachundhar Subramaniam</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Anesthesia</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>meditation</keyword>
  <keyword>anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Isha Kriya</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Depressive Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Anxiety Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

