<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04552301</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GCO 16-0945</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04552301</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessing Inflammatory and Behavioral Pathways Linking PTSD to Increased Asthma Morbidity in WTC Workers</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of an Integrated Intervention for WTC Workers With PTSD and Asthma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Asthma and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) are the most common conditions in World&#xD;
      Trade Center (WTC) rescue and recovery workers. In this study, the study team will evaluate&#xD;
      the interplay of biological and behavioral mechanisms explaining the relationship of PTSD&#xD;
      with increase asthma morbidity and adapt and pilot test a novel intervention to improve&#xD;
      outcomes of WTC workers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Significance: Importance of the Problem: Multiple studies have shown a high prevalence of&#xD;
      asthma in WTC rescue and recovery workers, local residents, and passersby. Using data from&#xD;
      the National Health Interview Survey (NHIS), the study team found that WTC workers have twice&#xD;
      the risk of asthma compared to the general United States (US) population. Data from the WTCHP&#xD;
      shows a 28% cumulative incidence of asthma 9 years after September 11, 2001 among WTC&#xD;
      workers. These studies show that asthma is the most prevalent respiratory condition among WTC&#xD;
      rescue and recovery workers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      WTC workers with asthma include individuals with prior history of the disease and new cases&#xD;
      of irritant-induced asthma. Many workers with preexistent asthma developed worsening symptoms&#xD;
      after WTC-related exposures (WTC-exacerbated asthma). Other workers developed new asthma&#xD;
      symptoms without latency during or after WTC exposure and were diagnosed with&#xD;
      irritant-induced asthma. Multiple cases of new onset asthma among WTC workers have been&#xD;
      reported in the years following exposure to the WTC site; characterization of these cases has&#xD;
      been more difficult. Despite this potential heterogeneity, these conditions are frequently&#xD;
      grouped in clinical practice as WTC-related asthma and managed similarly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Studies found substantial burden of asthma morbidity in WTC workers and exposed community&#xD;
      members, with reports of poorly-controlled in 34% and very poorly-controlled symptoms in 35%&#xD;
      of exposed individuals. Increased risk of emergency department (ED) visits and&#xD;
      hospitalizations as well as poor quality of life in WTC workers with asthma have been&#xD;
      reported, showing a major impact on health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Scientific Premise of Project: PTSD is Associated with Increased Asthma Morbidity in WTC&#xD;
      Workers: Prevalence of psychological symptoms in WTC-exposed populations is high; with PTSD&#xD;
      reported as the most common (~30%) mental health condition. Studies have also found high&#xD;
      rates (25-35%) of PTSD comorbidity in WTC workers with asthma. Mental health conditions and&#xD;
      PTSD in particular, have been associated with increased asthma morbidity. The study team&#xD;
      found that WTC workers with PTSD had worse asthma control, increased healthcare use, and&#xD;
      poorer quality of life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      . Similarly, a study of WTC workers indicated that severity of PTSD symptoms predicted new&#xD;
      onset and worsening of asthma. Data from studies in the general population have also shown&#xD;
      that PTSD is associated with higher asthma morbidity. In summary, studies have documented a&#xD;
      high level of overlap between asthma and PTSD in WTC workers and other exposed populations&#xD;
      and have documented that PTSD is a major contributor to increased asthma morbidity. However,&#xD;
      the underlying mechanisms explaining this relationship remain unknown.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PTSD May Negatively Impact Asthma SMB: Asthma self-management encompasses several complex&#xD;
      behaviors such as adherence to controller medications, adequate inhaler technique, use of&#xD;
      action plans, allergen avoidance, and avoiding tobacco exposure that are critical for&#xD;
      adequate disease control. Adherence to controller medications in particular, is a factor that&#xD;
      heavily influences the outcomes of asthmatics. Studies conducted in the general population&#xD;
      and the preliminary data from WTC workers shown that only ~50% of patients with asthma adhere&#xD;
      to controller therapy or other SMB.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mental health conditions are associated with low adherence to chronic disease SMB. PTSD, in&#xD;
      particular, has been strongly associated with low treatment adherence in multiple chronic&#xD;
      diseases. With smoking being an important part of asthma self-management, it is of special&#xD;
      concern that higher rates of smoking have been reported among WTC workers with PTSD. Thus,&#xD;
      low adherence to SMB may mediate, in part, the association between PTSD and increased asthma&#xD;
      morbidity. However, there is limited data regarding the relationship between PTSD and asthma&#xD;
      SMB in the general population or among WTC workers, in particular.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the strong link between asthma and PTSD in WTC workers, there are no interventions&#xD;
      aimed at managing both conditions. During the observational component of the study, the&#xD;
      researchers found evidence that PTSD was linked to worse asthma morbidity and WTC workers&#xD;
      with PTSD did not have increased perception of symptoms. As part of this study, the&#xD;
      researchers will test an integrated strategy using Cognitive Processing Therapy (CPT) and&#xD;
      asthma self-management support to improve the outcomes of WTC workers with PTSD and asthma.&#xD;
      CPT is based on a social cognitive theory of PTSD that focuses on how the traumatic event is&#xD;
      construed and coped with by a person who is trying to regain a sense of mastery and control&#xD;
      in his or her life. The self-management support component will be based on material the&#xD;
      researchers developed as part of the SAMBA trial for elderly patients with asthma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 17, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Eligibility will be determined based on Asthma Control Questionnaire (ACQ) score &gt;1.5, indicating uncontrolled asthma and results of the Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-5 Disorders (SCID) and/or PCL-5 showing evidence of PTSD. Participants will be consented by trained research staff and randomized 1:1 (stratified by level of asthma control) into an intervention (combined asthma self-management and cognitive processing therapy for PTSD) or an active attention control arm (supportive psychotherapy plus asthma education) after completing their 12-month visit.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Research coordinators (RCs) are blinded to study randomization and treatment arm for each participant.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>PTSD Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The PTSD Checklist for DSM-5 (PCL-5), is a 20-item self-report measure that assesses the 20 DSM-5 symptoms of PTSD. The PCL-5 has a variety of purposes, including monitoring symptom change during and after treatment, screening individuals for PTSD, and making a provisional PTSD diagnosis. Full range from 0-80, higher score indicates more symptoms.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asthma Control Questionnaire (ACQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The ACQ assess asthma beliefs about asthma control. The ACQ is a 7-item instrument, full scale from 0-6, higher score indicates more impairment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asthma Quality of Life Questionnaire (AQLQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The AQLQ assess asthma beliefs about asthma quality of life. The AQLQ is a 32-item instrument, full scale from 1-7, higher score indicates better health outcomes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Medication Adherence Report Scale (MARS)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The MARS assess asthma beliefs about asthma medication adherence. The MARS is a 10-item instrument, full range from 0-10, higher score indicates higher likelihood of medication adherence.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Illness Perception Questionnaire (IPQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The IPQ assess asthma beliefs about illness perception. The IPQ is an 80-item instrument, total scale from 0-10, with higher score indicating higher perception of effects on illness.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beliefs about Medicines Questionnaire (BMQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>24 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The BMQ assess beliefs about medications. The BMQ has two components: beliefs about overuse (score range from 3-15) and perceived risk of medicines (score range from 5-25), total scale 8-40, higher score indicates stronger beliefs in the concepts of the scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <condition>PTSD</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Processing Therapy and Targeted Asthma Education</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Intervention group - Cognitive Processing Therapy and Targeted Asthma Education</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Psychotherapy and General Asthma Education</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Control group - Psychotherapy and General Asthma Education</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cognitive Processing Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Integrated CPT. CPT is based on a social cognitive theory of PTSD that focuses on how the traumatic event is construed and coped with by a person who is trying to regain a sense of mastery and control in his or her life. The asthma components that will be integrated into the intervention include psychoeducation about asthma, barriers to asthma self-care, asthma medication education, inhaler technique, and asthma self-management behaviors.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Processing Therapy and Targeted Asthma Education</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>CPT</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Psychotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>The Study Interventionist will conduct generalized supportive psychotherapy with the participants to provide emotional support for both PTSD and general education for asthma.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Psychotherapy and General Asthma Education</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Targeted Asthma Education</intervention_name>
    <description>The manualized 10-session program of asthma self-management</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cognitive Processing Therapy and Targeted Asthma Education</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Asthma Education</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>General Asthma Education</intervention_name>
    <description>A 10-session program of similar time</description>
    <arm_group_label>Psychotherapy and General Asthma Education</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Asthma Education</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with PTSD based on SCID or PCL-5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poorly controlled asthma based on ACQ score ≥1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Completion of observational study 12-month visit&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active Suicidal Ideation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-existence of COPD or other chronic respiratory illnesses&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Juan P Wisnivesky, MD, DrPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shynah James, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>212-824-7983</phone>
    <email>shynah.james@mountsinai.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10029</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Juan P Wisnivesky, MD, DrPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 11, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 11, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 11, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Juan P Wisnivesky</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>World Trade Center</keyword>
  <keyword>Cognitive Processing Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Asthma</keyword>
  <keyword>Intervention</keyword>
  <keyword>Pilot Randomized Control Trial</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

