<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04559152</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>9/UN5.2.3.1/PPM/KP-DRPM/2019</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04559152</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Zinc Supplementation During Pregnancy: Analysis of Maternal Serum Zinc, Cord Blood Osteocalcin and Neonatal Birth Length</brief_title>
  <official_title>Zinc Supplementation During Pregnancy for the Prevention of Stunting: Analysis of Maternal Serum Zinc, Cord Blood Osteocalcin and Neonatal Birth Length</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitas Sumatera Utara</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitas Sumatera Utara</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This experimental study was conducted with pre-test/post-test control groups and double-blind&#xD;
      randomization from March to December 2019 at Universitas Sumatera Utara Hospital and others&#xD;
      in Medan. Subjects were pregnant mothers in second or third trimester and with their newborns&#xD;
      who met the inclusion criteria. Subjects were divided into two groups and administered either&#xD;
      zinc supplementation 20 mg/day or placebo, respectively, for 12 weeks. The parameters&#xD;
      assessed were maternal serum zinc levels cord blood osteocalcin and birth length&#xD;
      measurements.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients and Study Design This was an experimental study with pre-test/post-test control&#xD;
      groups, double-blind with randomization block technique. This study was conducted from March&#xD;
      to December 2019 in the obstetrics and neonatology unit of Universitas Sumatera Utara&#xD;
      Hospital, Malahayati Islamic Hospital and Royal Maternity Hospital in Medan. Research&#xD;
      subjects were pregnant mothers with their newborns who met the inclusion criteria. The study&#xD;
      samples were divided into two groups and administered either zinc supplementation 20 mg/day&#xD;
      or placebos, respectively, for 12 weeks. The zinc tablets or placebos were given in the&#xD;
      morning after meals. All subjects were also given iron and folic acid tablets in accordance&#xD;
      with the Indonesian government program. Subjects were healthy pregnant mothers in their&#xD;
      second or third trimester, 20-35 years old, with a height of &gt;150 cm and no indication of&#xD;
      cons following this study, as determined by obstetrician and gynaecology specialists;&#xD;
      subjects were enrolled with a consecutive sampling technique. Births involving twins,&#xD;
      congenital abnormalities, prematurity (gestation age &lt;37 weeks) or stillbirth were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Informed consent was given by all subjects' legal guardians following the provision of&#xD;
      sufficient information prior to the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study was approved by the Health Research Ethical Committee, School of Medicine,&#xD;
      Universitas Sumatera Utara in accordance with the principles of the Helsinki Declaration&#xD;
      (No.179/TGL/FK USU-RSUP HAM/2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods The parameters assessed in this study were maternal serum zinc levels, cord blood&#xD;
      osteocalcin and birth length measurements. Maternal serum zinc levels were measured twice&#xD;
      with 6 ml of vein blood each time, both during initial antenatal care and after 12 weeks of&#xD;
      supplementation. Samples were subsequently centrifuged for 15 minutes at 3000 rpm. Specimens&#xD;
      were processed by the inductively coupled plasma-mass spectrometry (ICP-MS) method using&#xD;
      Agilent 7700 analyser (Santa Clara, USA, 2014). Normal serum zinc levels were defined based&#xD;
      on a cut-off value of ≥ 56 µg/dL in accordance with Second National Health and Nutrition&#xD;
      Examination Survey data from 1976-1980 (NHANES II).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cord blood osteocalcin levels were measured with 6 ml cord blood samples prior to delivery,&#xD;
      which were subsequently centrifuged for 15 minutes at 1000 rpm using Cobas e601 analyser&#xD;
      (Roche Diagnostic, Mannheim, Germany) and N-Mid Osteocalcin (Abbexa) reagent. Osteocalcin was&#xD;
      measured using the enzyme-linked immuno-sorbent assay (ELISA) method, and in accordance with&#xD;
      Prodia clinical laboratory standards.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Neonatal birth length was performed with a SECA 232 digital baby scale for length with an&#xD;
      accuracy of 0.1 cm. Maternal zinc intake was calculated in accordance with the NutriSurvey&#xD;
      2007 Indonesian version.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis Descriptive analyses, correlation tests, and linear regression tests&#xD;
      were performed using SPSS version 23.0 (SPSS Inc., Chicago, Illinois, USA). Statistical&#xD;
      significance was considered at a p-value &lt; 0.05 with a 95% confidence interval.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>An experimental study with pre-test/post-test control groups, double-blind with randomization block technique</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>The subjects were divided into two groups (zinc supplementation and a placebo (control) group). Researchers and the subjects did not know the type of zinc supplementation or placebo given. The blinding process is carried out by the research assistant to the subject in the field at the time of retrieval of the research data. The selection of samples for each group uses the blocked randomization technique.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Zinc Supplementation During Pregnancy Prevent Stunting Occurence to the Newborn: Analysis of Maternal Serum Zinc, Cord Blood Osteocalcin and Neonatal Birth Length</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks up to childbirth</time_frame>
    <description>Maternal serum zinc level (after intervention) was measured and analysed statistically for its correlation with mean cord blood osteocalcin levels and median neonatal birth lengths</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Correlation Between Maternal Zinc Supplementation with Maternal Serum Zinc Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Maternal Serum Zinc level was measured before and after intervention. Participants dietary intake also will be accounted and calculated via food recall.&#xD;
The serum zinc level before and after intervention will then be analysed statistically to check for any correlation between zinc dietary intake and serum zinc level</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">71</enrollment>
  <condition>Zinc Deficiency</condition>
  <condition>Birth Length</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Zinc Supplementation Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Zinc capsule (20mg) was taken in the morning after meals once daily for 12 weeks. All subjects in this arm were also given iron and folic acid tablets in accordance with the Indonesian government program.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Placebo (sugar tablet) was taken in the morning after meals once daily for 12 weeks. All subjects were also given iron and folic acid tablets in accordance with the Indonesian government program. Each placebo tablet was inserted into a capsule of the same shape and color with zinc capsule</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Zinc Supplementation Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Enrolled subjects received zinc capsule 20mg daily in the morning after meal for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Zinc Supplementation Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Group</intervention_name>
    <description>Enrolled subjects received placebo tablet, which was inserted into capsule of the same shape and color as zinc capsule, daily in the morning after meal for 12 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy pregnant mothers in their second or third trimester&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 20-35 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimal height 150 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pregnant mothers in high-risk conditions such as&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe malnutrition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eclampsia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  gestational diabetes&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  liver diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  kidney diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
        Neonatal with&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  twin babies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  congenital anomalies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  prematurity (gestation age &lt;37 weeks)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  stillbirth&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Pregnant mothers and their newborn babies</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lili Rohmawati, Researcher</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universitas Sumatera Utara</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitas Sumatera Utara</name>
      <address>
        <city>Medan</city>
        <state>Sumatera Utara</state>
        <zip>20155</zip>
        <country>Indonesia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Indonesia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Rohmawati L, Keumala DS, Sitepu M. Maternal Zinc Intake and Its Correlation with Maternal Serum Zinc Levels and Neonatal Birth Weight/Length. Pak. J. Nutr., 19 (5): 245-252, 2020. DOI: 10.3923/pjn.2020.245.252</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 16, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universitas Sumatera Utara</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lili Rohmawati</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Zinc Supplementation During Pregnancy for the Prevention of Stunting: Analysis of Maternal Serum Zinc, Cord Blood Osteocalcin and Neonatal Birth Length</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Zinc</keyword>
  <keyword>Maternal zinc</keyword>
  <keyword>Osteocalcin</keyword>
  <keyword>Birth length</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The results of this study</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Agustus 2020</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>lily_rahmawati234@yahoo.com</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

