<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04550221</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STUDY00009441</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R34MH118950</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04550221</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Shauriana Intervention for GBMSM in Kenya</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Trial of the Shauriana Intervention to Integrate PrEP, Sexual Health, and Mental Health Support for Gay, Bisexual, and Other Men Who Have Sex With Men in Kenya</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Washington</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Washington</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The Shauriana intervention, developed from qualitative work using a community-based&#xD;
      participatory approach, aims to integrate PrEP, sexual health, and mental health support for&#xD;
      gay, bisexual, and other men who have sex with men in Kenya. This study consists of a brief&#xD;
      pilot test phase with 10 participants, followed by a randomized, controlled trial with 60&#xD;
      participants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Gay, bisexual, and other men who have sex with men (GBMSM) are at high risk for HIV-1&#xD;
      acquisition, especially in rights-constrained settings such as Kenya, where men's access to&#xD;
      HIV prevention has been impeded by homophobia, stigma, and discrimination. Pre-exposure&#xD;
      prophylaxis (PrEP) has the potential to greatly reduce HIV acquisition risk in this key&#xD;
      population if accessible, sustainable PrEP programming with tailored, effective adherence&#xD;
      support can be provided. To this end, close collaboration between PrEP program implementers&#xD;
      and GBMSM-led community-based organizations is essential. Based on preliminary qualitative&#xD;
      work, this theory-based and culturally relevant PrEP support intervention is called Shauriana&#xD;
      (Kiswahili for &quot;we counsel each other&quot;). The Shauriana intervention merges peer navigation&#xD;
      and &quot;integrated Next Step Counseling&quot; (iNSC) to promote sexual health protection strategies,&#xD;
      including PrEP uptake and adherence, among GBMSM in Kisumu. The present proposal aims to&#xD;
      pilot the intervention among 10 participants for 3 months, and then to evaluate the Shauriana&#xD;
      intervention for acceptability, feasibility, safety, and estimated effect on PrEP uptake and&#xD;
      adherence, compared to standard of care, in a small randomized, controlled study with 60&#xD;
      participants followed for 6 months after enrollment. Results of the proposed research will&#xD;
      have high impact by ensuring GBMSM involvement in the scale-up of effective PrEP programming&#xD;
      for this key population in Kenya and providing a peer-led PrEP support model for GBMSM and&#xD;
      other vulnerable and marginalized populations in African settings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 28, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Pilot study with 10 intervention participants followed by randomized controlled trial with 60 participants assigned to the intervention or to standard care.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Laboratory testing for PrEP drug levels will be conducted in a blinded fashion</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>5-point Likert scales (1 to 5, with 5 being optimal) evaluating acceptability of the Shauriana intervention components collected by ACASI</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention feasibility</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Intervention session attendance</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intervention safety</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events reported by participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Ongoing PrEP use (yes or no) assessed by ACASI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>3-question self-reported adherence assessment scale (Wilson et al) asked by ACASI</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP refills</measure>
    <time_frame>up to Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Number of documented PrEP refills</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>PrEP drug levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Month 6</time_frame>
    <description>Urine tenofovir levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>HIV Prevention</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Shauriana intervention is aimed at promoting sexual health and preventing HIV through a comprehensive prevention toolbox including PrEP. Components of this intervention are: four weekly in-person sessions with a trained peer intervention specialist; optional additional in-person or by phone check-ins after the in-person sessions are delivered; and optional monthly group sessions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard care includes clinic-based HIV counseling and testing, screening for symptoms of sexually transmitted infections (STI), and individual counseling about HIV prevention methods. Standard of care counseling for HIV prevention in Kenya includes general information about HIV transmission and discussions of risk reduction including condom use. PrEP counseling sessions focus on PrEP knowledge, adherence tips, and strategies to address adherence barriers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Shauriana</intervention_name>
    <description>The components of this intervention are: four weekly in-person sessions with a trained peer intervention specialist; optional additional in-person or by phone check-ins after the in-person sessions are delivered; and optional monthly group sessions. The four in-person health education and coaching sessions will be delivered once per week, by trained peer facilitators who identify as GBMSM. These sessions will focus on the following topics: sexual health basics (understanding how HIV and STIs are transmitted, prevented, and diagnosed/treated), relationships (types of relationships we have, characteristics of healthy relationships, communication skills), stress and coping (understanding mental health challenges, adaptive and maladaptive coping strategies), and healthy sexuality and empowerment (understanding sexual orientation and gender identity, challenging stereotypes about GBMSM, making sexual choices).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard care</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biologically male at birth and identifies as male, according to self-report&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 to 35 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Resident in the Kisumu area for ≥12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reports anal intercourse with a man in the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently taking PrEP for HIV prevention in the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to provide complete locator information&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing to undergo all study procedures, including HIV testing and counselling&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently participating in any HIV prevention or vaccine study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Planning to remain in the study area for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        For the pilot study only, men will be required to speak English, in order to expedite the&#xD;
        study team's analysis of feedback from these participants in preparation for the randomized&#xD;
        controlled trial (RCT). Of note, approximately 50%-60% of young MSM in Kisumu speak&#xD;
        English.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to understand the study purpose and procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling to adhere to study procedures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently under the influence of alcohol or drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior diagnosis of HIV infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Biologically male at birth and identifies as male, according to self-report</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Susan M Graham, MD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Washington</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Susan M Graham, MD, MPH, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>206 221-8435</phone>
    <email>grahamsm@uw.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Fred Otieno, MBChB</last_name>
    <phone>+254721759867</phone>
    <email>fotieno@nrhskenya.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Anza Mapema Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kisumu</city>
        <country>Kenya</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Duncan Okall, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>+2540572023903</phone>
      <email>dokal@nrhskenya.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Fred Otieno, MBChB</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Kenya</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 30, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 8, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 17, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Washington</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Susan Graham</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor, School of Medicine: Global Health</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>preexposure prophylaxis</keyword>
  <keyword>sexual health</keyword>
  <keyword>mental health</keyword>
  <keyword>behavioral intervention</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Study data will be available upon request after publication of the main study manuscripts. Researchers requesting access to data/resources will be asked to submit a request in writing describing their qualifications including their certification by their local IRB, analytic plans and other uses of the data/resources, and plans to secure the confidentiality and safety of the data. They will be required to agree in writing that they will not share the data with others, will use it only for the research purpose(s) delineated, and will return or destroy the data upon completion. In order to maintain protection of our participants' privacy, no directly identifying information will be shared with outside investigators. Given the sensitive nature of the data we are collecting, including HIV diagnosis and sexual risk behavior, we will not create a public access file.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>After reporting of the trial results</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data sharing agreement with study investigators</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

