<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04552717</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-01704</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04552717</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>My Grief - an App for Parents With Prolonged Grief After Losing a Child to Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>My Grief - Development and Evaluation of an App for Parents With Prolonged Grief Disorder After Losing a Child to Cancer: a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Uppsala University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Uppsala University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Bereaved parents are at increased risk of developing mental and physical health problems and&#xD;
      bereavement is even associated with an increased risk of mortality, especially in mothers.&#xD;
      Prolonged grief disorder (PGD) are persistent and intensive grief reactions which can persist&#xD;
      for years. It is characterized by an intense and lasting yearning for the deceased, intense&#xD;
      emotional pain, such as difficulty accepting the loss and an inability to experience positive&#xD;
      mood. Parents are among the most vulnerable to develop PGD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal is to increase the accessibility to evidence-based and cost-effective interventions&#xD;
      for parents of children who have died of cancer, and thus facilitate the grieving process and&#xD;
      decrease the risk for parents to develop long-term distress.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific aims are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate the acceptability and feasibility of a mobile app, &quot;My Grief &quot;, a self-help&#xD;
           app for prolonged grief, in parents who lost a child to cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To evaluate possible beneficial effects of the mobile app on parents' mental health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      There is a lack of studies evaluating the effect of interventions for bereaved parents. Thus,&#xD;
      there is a need for accessible interventions with documented efficacy for preventing or&#xD;
      reducing negative mental health consequences after the loss of a child. Today, many&#xD;
      individuals carry smartphones and these devices can be used to access self-help interventions&#xD;
      aiming to improve both physical and mental health. Currently, there are an excess of apps&#xD;
      available for smartphone users that assert that they help people with their physical or&#xD;
      mental health. However, for most of these apps, there is a lack of empirical support, i.e.,&#xD;
      their efficacy is unknown. It is therefore important to evaluate mobile apps in scientific&#xD;
      studies with rigorous designs. In addition, before conducting rigorous studies of novel&#xD;
      psychosocial interventions, such as a mobile app, it is important to conduct more basic work&#xD;
      evaluating development and feasibility of the intervention. One such self-help app, the PTSD&#xD;
      Coach, has been evaluated in a randomized controlled trial conducted with traumatized&#xD;
      participants recruited from the community, which found that access to the PTSD Coach app was&#xD;
      associated with improvements in posttraumatic stress (PTS) symptoms, depression, and&#xD;
      psychosocial functioning. The PTSD Coach app is based on cognitive behavioural therapy (CBT)&#xD;
      principles and there is a growing body of evidence that elements of CBT are effective&#xD;
      interventions for prolonged grief. Thus, an app targeting prolonged grief using elements of&#xD;
      CBT could potentially be effective in improving the mental health in bereaved parents. To our&#xD;
      knowledge no such app has been developed and evaluated. The Grief Coach app will be based on&#xD;
      the smartphone app PTSD Coach. A Swedish version of the PTSD Coach has been developed and a&#xD;
      pilot study has been conducted as well as an ongoing RCT. Consultant programmers at Uppsala&#xD;
      University will develop the mobile app. The content of the app will be developed together&#xD;
      with experts in the field of grief, inspired by other grief apps and CBT therapy manuals, to&#xD;
      modify parts of the PTSD Coach app to grief.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main aim of this study is to examine the effectiveness of the app My Grief as compared to&#xD;
      a waiting list comparison in reducing symptoms of prolonged grief in bereaved parents. The&#xD;
      primary hypothesis is that the parents in the intervention group will report decreased levels&#xD;
      of prolonged grief symptoms after having used the app. A second aim is to examine the effect&#xD;
      of the app on related mental health problems (posttraumatic stress symptoms, depression&#xD;
      symptoms, quality of life) and cognitive behavioral variables putatively explaining the&#xD;
      effect of CBT techniques (i.e., grief avoidance, grief rumination and negative grief&#xD;
      cognitions). The secondary hypotheses are that the parents in the intervention group will&#xD;
      report improved mental health (i.e., lower symptom levels of depression and posttraumatic&#xD;
      stress, higher quality of life), and lower grief avoidance, grief rumination, negative&#xD;
      grief-related cognitions. A third aim is to evaluate the feasibility of the app, including&#xD;
      participant satisfaction, evaluation of the app's strengths and weaknesses, and adverse&#xD;
      events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential participants are identified using the Swedish Childhood Cancer Registry, the Cause&#xD;
      of Death Registry, and the Swedish Population Register at the Swedish Tax Agency. By linking&#xD;
      the Cause of Death Registry with the Swedish Childhood Cancer Registry, children diagnosed&#xD;
      with a malignancy and who died due to the malignancy 1 to 10 years previously will be&#xD;
      identified. Next, the children's parents/caregivers are identified through the Swedish&#xD;
      Population Register and will be sent a letter with an invitation to participate in the study.&#xD;
      Participants will complete a web based pre-assessment and then given access to the app for&#xD;
      three months followed by a web based post-assessment and an interview via telephone regarding&#xD;
      their experiences of using the app, with follow-ups att 6 and 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>wait-list controll and intervention group</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in Prolonged Grief Disorder-13 instrument, PG-13</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>13-item, self-rated measure of prolonged grief, total score ranges from 11 to 55, where a higher score indicates more symptoms</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in Posttraumatic stress disorder checklist for DSM-5, PCL-5</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>20-item, self-rated measure of posttraumatic stress disorder, total score range from 0-80, and a higher score indicates more symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in Patient Health Questionnaire, PHQ-9</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>9-item, self-rated measure of depression, total score ranges from 0-27, and a higher score indicates more symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in Utrecht Grief Rumination Scale, UGRS</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>15-item, self-rated measure of grief rumination, total scores range from 15 to 75, and a higher score indicates more grief rumination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in Depressive and Anxious Avoidance in Prolonged Grief questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>9-item, self-rated measure of avoidance, total score ranges from 9-72, and a higher score indicates more avoidance</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in 18 items from the Grief Cognitions Questionniare, GCQ</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>18-items, self-rated measure of grief cognitions, total score ranges from 0-90, and a higher score indicates more grief cognitions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change (from baseline) in Brunnsviken Brief Quality of Life Inventory, BBQ</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>12 items, self-rated measure of quality of life, covering six different life domains, Total score ranges from 0-96, higher scores indicates higher quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of the intervention and the application</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Feasibility will be measured by &quot;App Survey&quot;</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of the intervention and the application</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Acceptability will be measured by &quot;App Survey&quot;</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Participants demographics</measure>
    <time_frame>0 months</time_frame>
    <description>age, gender, time since loss, gender child, marital status, employment status, loss-related variables</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">154</enrollment>
  <condition>Prolonged Grief Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete a web based pre-assessment and then given access to the app &quot;My Grief&quot; for three months followed by a web based post-assessment and an interview via telephone regarding their experiences of using the app, and follow-up questionnaires.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waitlist controll</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will get access to the app after three months.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>My Grief</intervention_name>
    <description>The app will build on principles of cognitive behavioural theory and therapy (CBT) and contains four main sections: Learning, Self-assessment, Manage symptoms and Find support.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents/caregivers of children who have died of cancer, at the earliest 12 month ago&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have symptoms of prolonged grief (PGD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Understand Swedish language&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have access to a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing severe psychiatric problems (e.g. suicidal thoughts, psychosis)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Josefin Sveen, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Uppsala University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Josefin Sveen, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46186115206</phone>
    <email>josefin.sveen@neuro.uu.se</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rakel Eklund, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+46730672455</phone>
    <email>rakel.eklund@neuro.uu.se</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Centre for Disaster Psychiatry, Department of Neuroscience, Uppsala university</name>
      <address>
        <city>Uppsala</city>
        <zip>75185</zip>
        <country>Sweden</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Josefin Sveen, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+46186115206</phone>
      <email>josefin.sveen@neuro.uu.se</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Rakel Eklund, PhD</last_name>
      <email>rakel.eklund@neuro.uus.se</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Sweden</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 10, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 10, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Uppsala University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Josefin Sveen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>All collected IPD</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Analytic Code</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

