<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04551131</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HLHRUXO</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-08320</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04551131</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Use Of A Response-Adapted Ruxolitinib-Containing Regimen For The Treatment Of Hemophagocytic Lymphohistiocytosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Use Of A Response-Adapted Ruxolitinib-Containing Regimen For The Treatment Of Hemophagocytic Lymphohistiocytosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Incyte Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>North American Consortium for Histiocytosis</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multi-site Phase Ib/II, 2-arm non-randomized clinical trial to determine the&#xD;
      efficacy and tolerability of a response-adapted regimen combining ruxolitinib, dexamethasone,&#xD;
      and etoposide as Frontline therapy for patients with newly diagnosed hemophagocytic&#xD;
      lymphohistiocytosis (HLH) or as Salvage therapy for patients with relapsed/refractory HLH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the efficacy and tolerability of a response-adapted ruxolitinib-containing&#xD;
           regimen for patients with newly diagnosed HLH.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To describe the efficacy and tolerability of a response-adapted ruxolitinib-containing&#xD;
           regimen for patients with relapsed/refractory HLH.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To describe the overall response and outcome for patients with newly diagnosed or&#xD;
           relapsed/refractory HLH who are treated with this response-adapted&#xD;
           ruxolitinib-containing regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exploratory Objectives&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To estimate the pharmacokinetic (PK) parameters of ruxolitinib, assess covariates of&#xD;
           ruxolitinib pharmacokinetics, and test whether the drug's effectiveness is correlated&#xD;
           with systemic drug exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To query specific immunologic biomarkers and determine whether the levels of these&#xD;
           biomarkers correlate with disease response and outcome.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Frontline Arm: Safety Phase and Expansion Phase&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety Phase: The Frontline Arm will begin with a Safety Phase to identify a feasible and&#xD;
      safe dose of ruxolitinib to be given in combination with the &quot;gold standard&quot; HLH-directed&#xD;
      agents dexamethasone and etoposide. For this part of the trial, a minimum of 6 newly&#xD;
      diagnosed HLH patients will be included. These patients will first receive ruxolitinib 25&#xD;
      mg/m^2/dose by mouth BID (twice a day), dexamethasone 5 mg/m^2/dose PO or IV BID, and&#xD;
      etoposide 150 mg/m^2/dose IV weekly. Etoposide dosing is to be initiated within the first&#xD;
      24-48 hours. The first dose of dexamethasone and etoposide will be at least 8 hours after the&#xD;
      first dose of ruxolitinib for PK testing purposes, but patients will not be excluded if&#xD;
      dexamethasone has already been started before initiating ruxolitinib. The dose of ruxolitinib&#xD;
      may be escalated or de-escalated as needed, based on observed toxicities and surrogates of&#xD;
      disease response. Dexamethasone will be weaned every 2 weeks. In case of disease&#xD;
      reactivation, patients will receive individualized re-intensification.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Expansion Phase: When a dose of ruxolitinib deemed feasible and safe is identified, the&#xD;
      Expansion Phase of the Frontline Arm will begin. Patients with newly diagnosed HLH in the&#xD;
      Expansion Phase will receive ruxolitinib (at the maximally tolerated dose [MTD] established&#xD;
      in the Safety Phase) and dexamethasone 5 mg/m^2/dose by mouth or IV BID. The first dose of&#xD;
      dexamethasone will be given at least 8 hours after the first dose of ruxolitinib for PK&#xD;
      testing purposes, but patients will not be excluded if dexamethasone has already been started&#xD;
      before initiating of ruxolitinib. Disease response evaluations will be completed at 1, 2, 4,&#xD;
      6, and 8 weeks. Treatment will be individualized based on response.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients whose HLH responds favorably after 1 week (SD 8) of therapy (e.g., favorable&#xD;
      response (FR), Week 1) will remain on ruxolitinib and dexamethasone. As long as patients show&#xD;
      a CR or partial response (PR) at Week 2 (SD15), ruxolitinib and dexamethasone are tolerated,&#xD;
      and patients are clinically stable, they will remain on both agents for the remainder of the&#xD;
      8-week study period. Dexamethasone will be weaned every 2 weeks as tolerated. In case of&#xD;
      disease reactivation, therapy will be re-intensified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients whose HLH responds unfavorably after 1 week (SD8) of therapy (e.g., unfavorable&#xD;
      response, Week 1) will have etoposide added (150 mg/m^2/dose, IV weekly). As long as patients&#xD;
      show CR or PR at Week 2 (SD15), combination treatment with ruxolitinib, dexamethasone, and&#xD;
      etoposide is tolerated, and patients are clinically stable, they will remain on these 3&#xD;
      agents for the remainder of the 8-week study period. Dexamethasone will not be weaned until&#xD;
      patients have shown at least a PR, with the weaning schedule determined by the treating&#xD;
      physician. Dexamethasone weaning may continue beyond the 8-week study period. Patients whose&#xD;
      HLH does not respond favorably (e.g., exhibit non-response (NR), progressive disease (PD))&#xD;
      despite treatment with ruxolitinib, dexamethasone, and etoposide will be taken off treatment&#xD;
      and salvage therapy will be considered and decided by the treating physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Salvage Arm: Patients with relapsed/refractory HLH will be treated on the Salvage Arm. They&#xD;
      will not be included in the Safety Phase; instead, they will be treated using the&#xD;
      response-adapted approach. Patients may be enrolled on the Salvage Arm as the Safety Phase is&#xD;
      ongoing. Patients will receive ruxolitinib 25 mg/m^2/dose by mouth BID and dexamethasone 5&#xD;
      mg/m^2/dose by mouth or IV BID. The first dose of dexamethasone will be given at least 8&#xD;
      hours after the first dose of ruxolitinib for PK testing purposes, but patients will not be&#xD;
      excluded if dexamethasone has already been started before starting ruxolitinib. Disease&#xD;
      response evaluations will be completed at 1, 2, 4, 6, and 8 weeks. Treatment will be&#xD;
      individualized based on response as described for the Expansion Phase of the Frontline Arm.&#xD;
      When the MTD of ruxolitinib has been determined on the Safety Phase of the Frontline Arm, it&#xD;
      will be the dose used for any additional patients enrolled on the Salvage Arm. Any patients&#xD;
      already on the Salvage Arm who show no adverse effects or toxicity at an assigned dose of 25&#xD;
      mg/m^2 BID will be continued on this dose for the 8 week study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HLH Reactivation: For patients who initially respond favorably but then worsen (e.g.,&#xD;
      &quot;reactivate&quot;) during the later phases of induction when dexamethasone is weaned,&#xD;
      dexamethasone will be increased back to 5 mg/m^2/dose PO/IV BID (10 mg/m^2/day). If the&#xD;
      patient is on a reduced dose of ruxolitinib due to prior toxicity(ies), the ruxolitinib dose&#xD;
      may be increased to patient's starting dose, provided the prior toxicity(ies) has resolved&#xD;
      for at least 1 week. Patients whose HLH responds favorably will continue to receive&#xD;
      ruxolitinib and dexamethasone or ruxolitinib, dexamethasone and etoposide. Patients receiving&#xD;
      ruxolitinib, dexamethasone and etoposide whose HLH responds unfavorably will be taken off&#xD;
      treatment and be considered for an alternative salvage therapy. For patients receiving&#xD;
      ruxolitinib and dexamethasone whose HLH responds unfavorably, etoposide may be added. If the&#xD;
      response is favorable, the patient will continue on all 3 medications. If the response is&#xD;
      unfavorable after adding etoposide, the patient will be taken off treatment and will be&#xD;
      considered for an alternative salvage therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients with CNS disease will receive intrathecal (IT) MTX and hydrocortisone (HC), per&#xD;
      age-based dosing, once per week for up to 4 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be followed for one year after starting protocol therapy or 1 year after HSCT&#xD;
      (for those undergoing HSCT).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete Response (CR)</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Will be reported as number and percentage of patients meeting complete response criteria at the end of 8 weeks of therapy</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events (AEs) associated with the ruxolitinib-containing regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Cumulative incidence will be estimated by the Kalbfleisch-Prentice method for severe toxicities that lead to morbidity and mortality.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events (AEs) associated with the ruxolitinib-containing regimen</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year after diagnosis</time_frame>
    <description>Cumulative incidence will be estimated by the Kalbfleisch-Prentice method for severe toxicities that lead to morbidity and mortality.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response (Complete Response (CR) plus Partial Response [PR])</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Will be reported as number and percentage/proportion of patients meeting response (complete plus partial response) criteria at the end of 8 weeks of therapy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival to eight weeks</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion (probability) of patients surviving to the end of 8 weeks will be estimated by sample proportions along with the 95% exact binomial CIs in the Frontline and Salvage Arms, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival to allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (HSCT) in patients for whom an allogeneic HSCT is planned</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion (probability) of surviving to HSCT will be estimated by sample proportions along with 95% exact binomial CIs in the Frontline and Salvage Arms, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival to one year after initiation of the treatment protocol</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after initiation of treatment</time_frame>
    <description>One-year Overall Survival (OS) rate will be estimated in all patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival one year after HSCT</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year post HSCT</time_frame>
    <description>One-year post-HSCT Overall Survival (OS) rate will be estimated in patients who receive transplantation, in the Frontline and Salvage Arms, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to Response (CR or PR)</measure>
    <time_frame>At weeks 2, 4, 6, and 8</time_frame>
    <description>The mean time to CR/PR will be estimated by the sample mean along with 95% CIs, in the Frontline and Salvage Arms, respectively. The median time will be estimated by the sample median along with the 95% finite- sample CI.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">62</enrollment>
  <condition>Hemophagocytic Lymphohistiocytosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Frontline Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Safety Phase:&#xD;
Patients with newly diagnosed HLH will receive ruxolitinib PO or NGT, dexamethasone, PO or IV and etoposide IV.&#xD;
Expansion Phase:&#xD;
Patients with newly diagnosed HLH treatment will begin with ruxolitinib PO or NGT at the MTD dose. Dexamethasone will be administered PO or IV. Etoposide IV will be added based on disease response.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Salvage Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with relapsed/refractory HLH will receive ruxolitinib PO or NGT and dexamethasone PO or IV. Etoposide IV will be added based on disease response.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ruxolitinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Given orally (PO) or per nasogastric tube (NGT) twice a day for 8 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Frontline Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Salvage Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Jakafi®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>Given intravenously (IV) or orally (PO) twice a day for 8 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Frontline Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Salvage Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Decadron®</other_name>
    <other_name>Hexadrol®</other_name>
    <other_name>Dexone®</other_name>
    <other_name>Dexameth®</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Etoposide</intervention_name>
    <description>Given intravenously (IV) once a week for 8 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Frontline Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Salvage Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Etoposide Phosphate</other_name>
    <other_name>VePesid®</other_name>
    <other_name>Etopophos®</other_name>
    <other_name>VP-16</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Frontline Arm:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient is ≥6 weeks and ≤22 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient weighs ≥3 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient is able to take medication PO and/or patient or parent is willing to have NG&#xD;
             tube placed if patient is unable to take medications PO.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient has active HLH if ≥5 of 8 HLH-2004 diagnostic criteria listed below OR patient&#xD;
             has known fHLH (e.g., patient has pathogenic/likely pathogenic germline variant(s) in&#xD;
             genes such as PRF1, UNC13D, STX11, STXBP2, LYST, RAB27A, XIAP, SH2D1A, NLCR4) and&#xD;
             meets ≥4 of the HLH-2004 diagnostic criteria listed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Splenomegaly&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cytopenias affecting ≥2 of 3 cell lineages in the peripheral blood (hemoglobin &lt;9&#xD;
                  g/dL, platelets &lt;100 × 10^9/L, neutrophils &lt;1000 × 10^6/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hypertriglyceridemia (fasting triglycerides ≥265 mg/dL) or hypofibrinogenemia&#xD;
                  (fibrinogen ≤150 g/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of hemophagocytosis in BM or other tissues&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Low or absent NK-cell activity OR decreased CD107a mobilization&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ferritin ≥500 ng/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Soluble IL-2 receptor (CD25) ≥2400 U/mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient has not received prior HLH therapy, except steroids (any dose is allowed, but&#xD;
             patient must not have been treated for more than 2 consecutive weeks) OR anakinra (any&#xD;
             dose or length of therapy is allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient, parent, or legal authorized representative (LAR) must provide informed&#xD;
             consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria: Salvage Arm:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient is ≥6 weeks and ≤22 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient weighs ≥3 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient or parent is willing to have the NG tube placed if patient is unable to take&#xD;
             medications PO.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient has past history of HLH, defined as meeting ≥5 of 8 HLH- 2004 diagnostic&#xD;
             criteria for those with no known HLH-associated mutations, OR ≥4 of 8 HLH-2004&#xD;
             diagnostic criteria for those with known familial disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient must have active HLH at the time of eligibility assessment, defined as 3 or&#xD;
             more of the following Relapsed/Refractory HLH Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Fever&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Splenomegaly (recurrent or worsening)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophils &lt;1000 × 10^6/L × 2 assessments over at least 3 days OR platelets &lt;100&#xD;
                  × 10^9/L × 2 assessments over at least 3 days, OR need for platelet transfusions&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Hypofibrinogenemia (fibrinogen &lt;150 g/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Soluble IL-2 receptor level ≥ 2400 U/L&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Worsening CNS symptoms OR new abnormal brain magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)&#xD;
                  findings deemed consistent with CNS HLH by the primary treating physician OR CSF&#xD;
                  cell count &gt;5 (with or without hemophagocytosis) OR CSF protein higher than the&#xD;
                  institutional upper limit of normal OR CSF neopterin higher than the&#xD;
                  institutional upper limit of normal&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of hemophagocytosis in the BM or other tissues&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Increasing ferritin × 2 assessments over at least 3 days (both levels must be&#xD;
                  &gt;2000 ng/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient must be deemed by the primary treating physician to have not responded to&#xD;
             prior therapy by either not having or maintaining a response&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient must have received prior HLH-directed therapy:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 2 weeks of steroids (equivalent to at least 5 mg/m^2/day dexamethasone&#xD;
                  or 1 mg/kg/day methylprednisolone) AND at least 2 doses of etoposide (with at&#xD;
                  least 7 days between the last etoposide dose and starting ruxolitinib); OR&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 1 dose of ATG (with at least 7 days between the last ATG dose and&#xD;
                  starting ruxolitinib)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient or parent/LAR must provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Frontline and Salvage Arms:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient is &lt;6 weeks or &gt;22 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient weighs &lt;3 kg.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient has isolated CNS disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Life expectancy is &lt;2 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patient is likely to require &lt;4 weeks of therapy (i.e., HSCT is imminent).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with creatinine clearance (CrCl) &lt;15 mL/min who are NOT receiving dialysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient has evidence of severe organ dysfunction, defined as: Severe liver dysfunction&#xD;
             (ALT &gt;1000 U/L), OR Cardiorespiratory failure requiring any ionotropic support OR&#xD;
             extracorporeal life support, OR high frequency oscillatory ventilation, other forms of&#xD;
             respiratory support or ventilation are allowed if the patient is not on vasopressors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient with pre-existing rheumatologic disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient with known active malignancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient with previous HSCT, except when HSCT was for treatment of HLH.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient is pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patients who expect to conceive or father children within the projected duration of&#xD;
             the study and/or who are unwilling to use highly effective methods of contraception&#xD;
             throughout the duration of the study, starting with the screening visit through the&#xD;
             end of the treatment visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient has suspected or known fungal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient is unable to tolerate administration of drugs PO or NG.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patient is taking rifampin or St. John's Wort.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Patient is taking another investigational agent or is enrolled on another treatment&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Patient, parent, or LAR are unable or unwilling to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Exclusion Criteria for the Frontline Arm:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient has or is receiving treatment with a JAK inhibitor (including ruxolitinib),&#xD;
             ATG, alemtuzumab, etoposide, tocilizumab, emapalumab or any other HLH-directed therapy&#xD;
             other than steroids or anakinra (as defined in the Frontline Arm Inclusion Criteria,&#xD;
             #5).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Additional Exclusion Criteria for the Salvage Arm:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient has or is receiving treatment with a JAK inhibitor (including ruxolitinib),&#xD;
             tocilizumab, alemtuzumab, OR emapalumab within the last 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient has received therapy on the Frontline Arm of this trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Weeks</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>22 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Melissa Hines, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kim E. Nichols, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Melissa Hines, MD</last_name>
    <phone>866-278-5833</phone>
    <email>referralinfo@stjude.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Kim E. Nichols, MD</last_name>
    <phone>866-278-5833</phone>
    <email>referralinfo@stjude.org</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Orange County</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Lilibeth Torno, MD</last_name>
      <phone>714-509-4348</phone>
      <email>ltorno@choc.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Lilibeth Torno, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California San Francisco</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Francisco</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94158</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Michelle Hermiston, MD</last_name>
      <phone>415-476-2413</phone>
      <email>michelle.hermiston@ucsf.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Michelle Hermiston, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Memphis</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>38105</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Melissa Hines, MD</last_name>
      <phone>866-278-5833</phone>
      <email>referralinfo@stjude.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Melissa Hines, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Kim E. Nichols, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.stjude.org</url>
    <description>St. Jude Children's Research Hospital</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.stjude.org/protocols</url>
    <description>ClinicalTrials Open at St. Jude</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 2, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hemophagocytic lymphohistiocytosis</keyword>
  <keyword>Newly Diagnosed</keyword>
  <keyword>Frontline therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Refractory</keyword>
  <keyword>Relapsed</keyword>
  <keyword>Response-adapted</keyword>
  <keyword>Salvage therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lymphohistiocytosis, Hemophagocytic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Etoposide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Etoposide phosphate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant de-identified datasets containing the variables analyzed in the published article will be made available (related to the study primary or secondary objectives contained in the publication). Supporting documents such as the protocol, statistical analyses plan, and informed consent are available through the CTG website for the specific study. Data used to generate the published article will be made available at the time of article publication. Investigators who seek access to individual level de-identified data will contact the computing team in the Department of Biostatistics (ClinTrialDataRequest@stjude.org) who will respond to the data request.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be made available at the time of article publication.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data will be provided to researchers following a formal request with the following information: full name of requestor, affiliation, data set requested, and timing of when data is needed. As an informational point, the lead statistician and study principal investigator will be informed that primary results datasets have been requested.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

