<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04551703</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>221</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04551703</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adrenaline Solution Irrigation and Bleeding During Sinus Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Intranasal Irrigation With Adrenaline Solution on Intraoperative Visualization and Bleeding During Functional Endoscopic Sinus Surgery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Jordan University of Science and Technology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Jordan University of Science and Technology</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Intranasal irrigation with normal saline is routinely used in sinus surgery to clean the tip&#xD;
      of the nasal endoscope and clear the surgical field from blood. The purpose of this study is&#xD;
      to evaluate the difference in the surgical visualization, surgeon satisfaction and total&#xD;
      blood loss when intraoperative irrigation was performed with a solution of normal saline with&#xD;
      adrenaline as compared to irrigation with normal saline alone in FESS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Functional Endoscopic Sinus Surgery (FESS) is a common, effective and minimally invasive&#xD;
      surgical procedure indicated mainly to treat medically resistant chronic rhinosinusitis with&#xD;
      or without nasal polyposis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The surgery is often performed under general anesthesia and proceeds in anatomically based&#xD;
      surgical landmarks steps to facilitate drainage and ventilation of the paranasal sinuses. As&#xD;
      any other endoscopic and laparoscopic procedures the operation requires dry surgical field to&#xD;
      ensure accurate identification and visualization of structures and smooth surgical dissection&#xD;
      progression. Intranasal bleeding during FESS will increase time of surgery and perioperative&#xD;
      complications. Also it could affect healing process, increase adhesion formation and&#xD;
      lengthening recovery period .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Different methods and maneuvers have been described in the literature to reduce&#xD;
      intra-operative bleeding during sinus surgery. These include: elevation of the patient's&#xD;
      head, the use of bipolar cautery and powered instruments; premedication with beta blockers; a&#xD;
      controlled hypotensive anesthesia technique; total intravenous anesthesia, topical hemostatic&#xD;
      biomaterials and local application of vasoconstrictors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adrenaline is one of the most commonly used topical vasoconstrective agent. Because systemic&#xD;
      absorption of infiltrated adrenaline can give rise to a sudden increase in blood levels of&#xD;
      catecholamine compared to topical instillation and thus various life-threatening&#xD;
      complications, such as : cardiac arrhythmia, cardiac arrest, cardiomyopathy, pulmonary edema,&#xD;
      and central retinal artery occlusion; many surgeons prefer to use instillation of adrenaline&#xD;
      over infiltration in FESS&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 1, 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 11, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 11, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients will randomize into two groups based on computer generating numbers. Group 1 will have the usual method of irrigation with normal saline during surgery whereas group 2 have irrigation with 1:100 000 adrenaline in normal saline. The solution will be prepared by the senior resident through adding one ampule of 0.1 percent adrenaline in one liter bag of normal saline, which made the adrenaline concentration in the solution 1:100 000. The investigators who collected the data will be blinded to the content of both preparations. Irrigation with either solution will be used during the procedure through a 20 mL syringe attached to an olive tip long curved suction.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Boezaart intraoperative surgical field scale</measure>
    <time_frame>2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The Boezaart intra-operative surgical field scale will be used to grade the level of bleeding during surgery. This 0 to 5-point scale will be used to outline the amount of suction required to rid the area of blood disrupting vision. A score of 0 is given for an area with no bleeding, 1 for slight bleeding with no suction required, 2 for slight bleeding requiring suction, 3 for moderate bleeding which improves for several seconds once suction has occurred, 4 for moderate bleeding which restarts directly after suctioning and 5 for severe bleeding which occurs faster then can be removed</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Volume of total blood loss</measure>
    <time_frame>The volume of blood loss will be measured every 30 minutes from the start of surgery for the duration of 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Total blood loss will be calculated and measured over the duration of surgery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Rhinosinusitis (Diagnosis)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adrenaline saline irrigation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Adrenaline saline irrigation will be prepared by adding one ampule of 0.1 percent adrenaline in one liter bag of normal saline, which made the adrenaline concentration in the solution 1:100 000</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Normal saline irrigation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Normal saline bag will be used for irrigation during the procedure</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Adrenaline saline irrigation</intervention_name>
    <description>The surgical field is flushed with 20 cc of Adrenaline saline irrigation. This is in contrast to the standard of care, normal saline irrigation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Adrenaline saline irrigation</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Epinephrine saline irrigation</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with American Society of Anesthesiologist (ASA) classification &lt;2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with chronic with or without nasal polyposis refractory to medical treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a history of of bleeding diathesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with severe ischemic heart disease , pulmonary and renal disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with tumours or vascular anomalies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with cystic fibrosis, allergic fungal sinusitis and granulomatous disorders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are unable to speak, read and write English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mohannad A Al-Qudah, MD,FACS</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Jordan University of Science &amp; Technology &amp; King Abdullah University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Higgins TS, Hwang PH, Kingdom TT, Orlandi RR, Stammberger H, Han JK. Systematic review of topical vasoconstrictors in endoscopic sinus surgery. Laryngoscope. 2011 Feb;121(2):422-32. doi: 10.1002/lary.21286. Epub 2011 Jan 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21271600</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Saif AM, Farboud A, Delfosse E, Pope L, Adke M. Assessing the safety and efficacy of drugs used in preparing the nose for diagnostic and therapeutic procedures: a systematic review. Clin Otolaryngol. 2016 Oct;41(5):546-63. doi: 10.1111/coa.12563. Epub 2016 Feb 11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26452438</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yim MT, Ahmed OG, Takashima M. Evaluating real-time effects of topical 1:1000 epinephrine in endoscopic sinus and skull-base surgery on hemodynamic parameters through intraoperative arterial line monitoring. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2017 Nov;7(11):1065-1069. doi: 10.1002/alr.22012. Epub 2017 Sep 18.</citation>
    <PMID>28922579</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Khosla AJ, Pernas FG, Maeso PA. Meta-analysis and literature review of techniques to achieve hemostasis in endoscopic sinus surgery. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2013 Jun;3(6):482-7. doi: 10.1002/alr.21126. Epub 2012 Dec 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23255493</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gan EC, Alsaleh S, Manji J, Habib AR, Amanian A, Javer AR. Hemostatic effect of hot saline irrigation during functional endoscopic sinus surgery: a randomized controlled trial. Int Forum Allergy Rhinol. 2014 Nov;4(11):877-84. doi: 10.1002/alr.21376. Epub 2014 Aug 18.</citation>
    <PMID>25137523</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 23, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Sinusitis</keyword>
  <keyword>Nasal Polyp</keyword>
  <keyword>Endoscopic Sinus Surgery</keyword>
  <keyword>Adrenaline</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Sinusitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Chronic Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Epinephrine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Racepinephrine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Epinephryl borate</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

