<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04553549</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro2020000869</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04553549</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safety and Feasibility of the Infinity Catheter for Radial Access</brief_title>
  <official_title>Safety and Feasibility of the Infinity Guide Catheter for Neuro Interventional Procedures Using Transradial Access</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main objective of this single arm study is to evaluate the safety and feasibility of the&#xD;
      AXS Infinity LS (Stryker, Freemont, CA, USA) and AXS Infinity LS Plus (Stryker, Freemont, CA,&#xD;
      USA) catheters during the transradial approach through a secondary use of the data collected&#xD;
      during neurointerventional procedures. This includes evaluating the conversion rates to a&#xD;
      transfemoral approach. A secondary aim of the study is to assess the radial artery occlusion&#xD;
      rates post procedure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients who are undergoing endovascular intervention will be enrolled into the study.&#xD;
      Consent will be obtained for the procedure and for the use of their prospectively collected&#xD;
      clinical data. As the metrics analyzed in this study are already normally collected, this&#xD;
      study can be considered as a secondary use of the data. The procedure will be done using&#xD;
      standard criteria as per operator preference. All interventional cases at the study&#xD;
      institution undergo a &quot;radial first&quot; approach, meaning that the access site of choice is the&#xD;
      radial artery. The investigators will measure the radial artery size to ensure that the&#xD;
      artery is greater than 2.4 mm in order to use the Infinity catheter (8Fr). If the artery does&#xD;
      not meet the size criteria, only a 6Fr sheath will be used, and the data recorded during the&#xD;
      procedure will not be utilized for analysis in this study. The preoperative and postoperative&#xD;
      care will be the same for all the patients. No tests will be done outside of standard of&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility of TRA Intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>The size of the radial artery will be measured and the transradial approach will be used. Notation will be also be recorded if conversion to TFA is used.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assess radial artery occlusion rates post procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Reverse Barbue Test and ultrasound</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Demographics</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month</time_frame>
    <description>Patient demographics will be analyzed such as past medical history, HTN, HLD, Afib</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Tumor</condition>
  <condition>Stroke, Acute</condition>
  <condition>Brain Aneurysm</condition>
  <condition>Intracranial Arteriovenous Malformations</condition>
  <condition>Carotid Stenosis</condition>
  <condition>Cavernous Sinus Thrombosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Transradial approach</arm_group_label>
    <description>The procedure will be done using standard criteria as per operator preference. All interventional cases at our institution undergo a &quot;radial first&quot; approach, meaning that the access site of choice is the radial artery. The investigators will measure the radial artery size to ensure that the artery is greater than 2.4 mm in order to use the Infinity catheter (8Fr).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Transradial approach</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients who are undergoing endovascular intervention will be enrolled into the study. As the metrics analyzed in this study are already normally collected, this study can be considered as a secondary use of the data. The procedure will be done using standard criteria as per operator preference. All interventional cases at the study institution undergo a &quot;radial first&quot; approach, meaning that the access site of choice is the radial artery. The investigators will measure the radial artery size to ensure that the artery is greater than 2.4 mm in order to use the Infinity catheter (8Fr).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Transradial approach</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients who are undergoing endovascular intervention will be enrolled into the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age group 18 years and above.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing neuro-embolization using large bore catheters&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with Radial artery diameter less than 2.4 mm measured with Ultrasound&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age&lt;18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have previous surgeries at either approach site which precludes the use&#xD;
             of one of the approach sites&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who has poor collateral circulation, Raynaud's phenomenon, radial loop,&#xD;
             brachial or subclavian stenosis, aberrant origin of the subclavian artery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Priyank Khandelwal, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rutgers University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Priyank Khandelwal, MD</last_name>
    <phone>973-972-4692</phone>
    <email>pk544@njms.rutgers.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Newark</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07101</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Priyank Khandelwal, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jolly SS, Amlani S, Hamon M, Yusuf S, Mehta SR. Radial versus femoral access for coronary angiography or intervention and the impact on major bleeding and ischemic events: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized trials. Am Heart J. 2009 Jan;157(1):132-40. doi: 10.1016/j.ahj.2008.08.023. Epub 2008 Nov 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19081409</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bertrand OF, Rao SV, Pancholy S, Jolly SS, Rodés-Cabau J, Larose E, Costerousse O, Hamon M, Mann T. Transradial approach for coronary angiography and interventions: results of the first international transradial practice survey. JACC Cardiovasc Interv. 2010 Oct;3(10):1022-31. doi: 10.1016/j.jcin.2010.07.013.</citation>
    <PMID>20965460</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hamon M, Pristipino C, Di Mario C, Nolan J, Ludwig J, Tubaro M, Sabate M, Mauri-Ferré J, Huber K, Niemelä K, Haude M, Wijns W, Dudek D, Fajadet J, Kiemeneij F; European Association of Percutaneous Cardiovascular Interventions; Working Group on Acute Cardiac Care of the European Society of Cardiology; Working Group on Thrombosis on the European Society of Cardiology. Consensus document on the radial approach in percutaneous cardiovascular interventions: position paper by the European Association of Percutaneous Cardiovascular Interventions and Working Groups on Acute Cardiac Care** and Thrombosis of the European Society of Cardiology. EuroIntervention. 2013 Mar;8(11):1242-51. doi: 10.4244/EIJV8I11A192.</citation>
    <PMID>23354100</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kolkailah AA, Alreshq RS, Muhammed AM, Zahran ME, Anas El-Wegoud M, Nabhan AF. Transradial versus transfemoral approach for diagnostic coronary angiography and percutaneous coronary intervention in people with coronary artery disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2018 Apr 18;4:CD012318. doi: 10.1002/14651858.CD012318.pub2. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29665617</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Snelling BM, Sur S, Shah SS, Khandelwal P, Caplan J, Haniff R, Starke RM, Yavagal DR, Peterson EC. Transradial cerebral angiography: techniques and outcomes. J Neurointerv Surg. 2018 Sep;10(9):874-881. doi: 10.1136/neurintsurg-2017-013584. Epub 2018 Jan 8.</citation>
    <PMID>29311120</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 31, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 18, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 20, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Priyank Khandelwal, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>neuro-embolization</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carotid Stenosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intracranial Aneurysm</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sinus Thrombosis, Intracranial</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Intracranial Arteriovenous Malformations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cavernous Sinus Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Thrombosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Arteriovenous Malformations</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Aggregate data will be presented</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

