<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04550442</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-0128</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>NCI-2020-06538</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-0128</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04550442</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Venetoclax and Azacitidine for the Treatment of Relapsed or Refractory High-Risk Myelodysplastic Syndrome or Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I/II Study of Venetoclax in Combination With Azacitidine in Relapsed/Refractory High-Risk Myelodysplastic Syndrome (MDS) or Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia (CMML)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cancer Institute (NCI)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Genentech, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase I/II trial investigates the side effects and best dose of venetoclax when given&#xD;
      together with azacitidine and to see how well it works in treating patients with high-risk&#xD;
      myelodysplastic syndrome or chronic myelomonocytic leukemia that has come back (relapsed) or&#xD;
      has not responded to treatment (refractory). Venetoclax may stop the growth of cancer cells&#xD;
      by blocking some of the enzymes needed for cell growth. Chemotherapy drugs, such as&#xD;
      azacitidine, work in different ways to stop the growth of cancer cells, either by killing the&#xD;
      cells, by stopping them from dividing, or by stopping them from spreading. Giving venetoclax&#xD;
      and azacitidine together may help to control myelodysplastic syndrome or chronic&#xD;
      myelomonocytic leukemia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      PRIMARY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To determine the safety and tolerability (phase 1) and overall response rate (ORR) (phase&#xD;
      2) of venetoclax in combination with azacitidine in patients with high risk myelodysplastic&#xD;
      syndrome (MDS) or chronic myelomonocytic leukemia (CMML) with bone marrow excess blasts &gt; 5%&#xD;
      that are relapsed/refractory to prior hypomethylating agent (HMA) therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. Rate of complete remission (CR). II. Rate of marrow/morphologic complete remission (mCR).&#xD;
      III. Rate of hematologic improvement (HI; erythroid/platelet/neutrophil responses).&#xD;
&#xD;
      IV. Rate of red blood cell (RBC) transfusion independence. V. Rate of platelet (PLT)&#xD;
      transfusion independence. VI. Rate of cytogenetic response. VII. Rate of bone marrow blast&#xD;
      response. VIII. Time to transformation to acute myeloid leukemia (AML). IX. Duration of&#xD;
      response (DOR). X. Overall survival (OS). XI. Progression-free survival (PFS). XII. Time to&#xD;
      next MDS treatment (TTNT). XIII. Event-free survival (EFS).&#xD;
&#xD;
      EXPLORATORY OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I. To investigate the effects of therapy on MDS and to identify biological markers of&#xD;
      response to venetoclax and/or its combination with azacitidine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTLINE: This is a phase I, dose-escalation study of venetoclax followed by a phase II study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients receive venetoclax orally (PO) daily on days 1-14 and azacitidine intravenously (IV)&#xD;
      over 15 minutes or subcutaneously (SC) on days 1-5. Cycles repeat every 4-8 weeks in the&#xD;
      absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After completion of study treatment, patients are followed up within 30 days and then every&#xD;
      3-6 months for up to 5 years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 4, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 11, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 11, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum tolerated dose (MTD) (Phase I)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 28 days</time_frame>
    <description>The MTD is the highest dose level in which &lt; 2 patients of 6 develop first cycle dose-limiting toxicity (DLT).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall response rate (ORR) (Phase II)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>ORR is defined as the proportion of patients who had complete remission (CR), partial remission (PR) or marrow CR (mCR) lasting at least 4 weeks, or hematologic improvement (HI) lasting at least 8 weeks. Will estimate the overall response rate for the combination treatment, along with the 95% credible interval.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of CR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The association between CR and patient's clinical characteristics will be examined by Wilcoxon's rank sum test or Fisher's exact test, as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of mCR</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The association between mCR and patient's clinical characteristics will be examined by Wilcoxon's rank sum test or Fisher's exact test, as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of hematologic improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of platelet transfusion independence</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of red blood cell transfusion independence</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of cytogenetic response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The correlation between cytogenetic response and patient's clinical characteristics will be examined by Wilcoxon's rank sum test or Fisher's exact test, as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of bone marrow blast response</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>The correlation between bone marrow blast response and patient's clinical characteristics will be examined by Wilcoxon's rank sum test or Fisher's exact test, as appropriate.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>The number of days from the date of initial response (PR or better) to the date of first documented disease progression/relapse or death, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparisons by important subgroups will be made using the log-rank tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Event-free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>The number of days from the date of treatment initiation to the date of documented treatment failure, relapses from CR, or death from any cause, whichever occurs first, assessed up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparisons by important subgroups will be made using the log-rank tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>The time from treatment start till death or last follow-up, assessed up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparisons by important subgroups will be made using the log-rank tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>The time from treatment to progression or last follow-up, assessed up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparisons by important subgroups will be made using the log-rank tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to transformation to acute myeloid leukemia (AML)</measure>
    <time_frame>The time from treatment till transformation of AML or last follow-up, assessed up to 5 years post-treatment</time_frame>
    <description>Will be estimated using the method of Kaplan and Meier. Comparisons by important subgroups will be made using the log-rank tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">58</enrollment>
  <condition>Recurrent Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Myelodysplastic Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Chronic Myelomonocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Refractory Myelodysplastic Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>Therapy-Related Myelodysplastic Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (venetoclax, azacitidine)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients receive venetoclax PO daily on days 1-14 and azacitidine IV over 15 minutes or SC on days 1-5. Cycles repeat every 4-8 weeks in the absence of disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Azacitidine</intervention_name>
    <description>Given IV or SC</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (venetoclax, azacitidine)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>5 AZC</other_name>
    <other_name>5-AC</other_name>
    <other_name>5-Azacytidine</other_name>
    <other_name>5-AZC</other_name>
    <other_name>Azacytidine</other_name>
    <other_name>Azacytidine, 5-</other_name>
    <other_name>Ladakamycin</other_name>
    <other_name>Mylosar</other_name>
    <other_name>U-18496</other_name>
    <other_name>Vidaza</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Venetoclax</intervention_name>
    <description>Given PO</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment (venetoclax, azacitidine)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>ABT-0199</other_name>
    <other_name>ABT-199</other_name>
    <other_name>ABT199</other_name>
    <other_name>GDC-0199</other_name>
    <other_name>RG7601</other_name>
    <other_name>Venclexta</other_name>
    <other_name>Venclyxto</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with post HMA-failure high-risk MDS (intermediate [Int]-2 or high risk by the&#xD;
             International Prognostic Scoring System for Myelodysplastic Syndrome [IPSS] with&#xD;
             overall score &gt;= 1.5) with excess blasts &gt; 5% with failure defined as prior receipt of&#xD;
             4 cycles of HMA therapy with failure to attain a response, or progression of disease&#xD;
             or relapse at any time after prior response to HMA therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with relapsed/refractory chronic myelomonocytic leukemia (CMML) and&#xD;
             therapy-related MDS are also eligible&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hydroxyurea is allowed to lower the white cell count =&lt; 10,000/ul prior to initiation&#xD;
             of venetoclax&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total bilirubin =&lt; 2.0 x upper limit of normal (ULN) unless increase is due to&#xD;
             Gilbert's disease or leukemic involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT)/aspartate aminotransferase (AST) =&lt; 3.0 x ULN unless&#xD;
             considered due to leukemic involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate renal function as calculated using the modified Cockcroft-Gault equation of&#xD;
             &gt;= 30 ml/min, OR creatinine &lt; 2 x ULN, unless related to the disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Females must be surgically or biologically sterile or postmenopausal (amenorrheic for&#xD;
             at least 12 months) or if of childbearing potential, must have a negative serum or&#xD;
             urine pregnancy test within 72 hours before the start of the treatment. Women of&#xD;
             childbearing potential must agree to use an adequate method of contraception during&#xD;
             the study and until 3 months after the last treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Males must be surgically or biologically sterile or agree to use an adequate method of&#xD;
             contraception during the study until 3 months after the last treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG)/performance status (PS) =&lt; 2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients having received any prior BCL2 inhibitor therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with MDS with IPSS risk categories Low or Int-1 (overall IPSS score &lt; 1.5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection (due to potential&#xD;
             drug-drug interactions between antiretroviral medications and venetoclax). HIV testing&#xD;
             will be performed at screening, only if required per local guidelines or institutional&#xD;
             standards&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient known to be positive for hepatitis B or C infection (hepatitis C virus&#xD;
             antibody [HCV Ab] indicative of a previous or current infection; and/or positive&#xD;
             hepatitis B virus surface antigen [HBs Ag] or detected sensitivity on hepatitis B&#xD;
             virus-deoxyribonucleic acid [HBV-DNA] polymerase chain reaction [PCR] test for&#xD;
             hepatitis B virus core antibody [HBc Ab] and/or hepatitis B virus surface antibody&#xD;
             [HBs Ab] positivity) with the exception of those with an undetectable viral load&#xD;
             within 3 months of screening. (Hepatitis B or C testing is not required). Subjects&#xD;
             with serologic evidence of prior vaccination to HBV [i.e., HBs Ag-, and anti-HBs+] may&#xD;
             participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received strong and/or moderate CYP3A inducers within 7 days prior to the&#xD;
             initiation of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has consumed grapefruit, grapefruit products, Seville oranges (including&#xD;
             marmalade containing Seville oranges) or Starfruit within 3 days prior to the&#xD;
             initiation of study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a cardiovascular disability status of New York Heart Association class &gt;&#xD;
             2. Class 2 is defined as cardiac disease in which patients are comfortable at rest but&#xD;
             ordinary physical activity results in fatigue, palpitations, dyspnea, or anginal pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has chronic respiratory disease that requires continuous oxygen, or&#xD;
             significant history of renal, neurologic, psychiatric, endocrinologic, metabolic,&#xD;
             immunologic, hepatic, cardiovascular disease, any other medical condition or known&#xD;
             hypersensitivity to any of the study medications including excipients of azacitidine&#xD;
             that in the opinion of the investigator would adversely affect his/her participating&#xD;
             in this study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a malabsorption syndrome or other condition that precludes enteral route&#xD;
             of administration&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient exhibits evidence of other clinically significant uncontrolled systemic&#xD;
             infection requiring therapy (viral, bacterial or fungal)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has received a live attenuated vaccine within 4 weeks prior to the first dose&#xD;
             of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a history of other malignancies within 2 years prior to study entry, with&#xD;
             the exception of:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequately treated in situ carcinoma of the cervix uteri or carcinoma in situ of&#xD;
                  breast&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Basal cell carcinoma of the skin or localized squamous cell carcinoma of the skin&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Previous malignancy confined and surgically resected (or treated with other&#xD;
                  modalities) with curative intent; requires discussion with TA Doctor of Medicine&#xD;
                  (MD)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient has a white blood cell count &gt; 10 x 10^9/L. (Hydroxyurea or leukapheresis are&#xD;
             permitted to meet this criterion)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subject has positive results for pregnancy test&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with (grade &gt; 1) unresolved from prior treatment (including chemotherapy,&#xD;
             targeted therapy, immunotherapy, experimental agents, radiation, or surgery)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Guillermo Garcia-Manero</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Guillermo Garcia-Manero</last_name>
    <phone>713-745-3428</phone>
    <email>ggarciam@mdanderson.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>M D Anderson Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Guillermo Garcia-Manero</last_name>
      <phone>713-745-3428</phone>
      <email>ggarciam@mdanderson.org</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Guillermo Garcia-Manero</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>Related Info</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 13, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 19, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Preleukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Acute</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Chronic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myelomonocytic, Juvenile</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Myelodysplastic Syndromes</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Azacitidine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venetoclax</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

