<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04555889</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Med. Fac. of Univ. Indonesia</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04555889</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Impact of Lung Recruitment Maneuver in 24-32 Weekers, and the Incidence of Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Impact of Lung Recruitment Maneuver in 24-32 Weeks Preterm Babies With Assist-control Volume Guarantee Mode to Their Hemodynamic Status and the Incidence of Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dr. R. Adhi Teguh Perma Iskandar, Sp.A(K)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Indonesian Medical Education and Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dr Cipto Mangunkusumo General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      hypothesis :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The incident of dysplasia bronchopulmonary and/or death in 24-32 weekers babies on&#xD;
           assist-control volume guarantee ventilation are lower in lung recruitment maneuver (LRM)&#xD;
           group compare to control.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The serum levels of surfactant protein-D in 24-32 weekers babies on assist-control&#xD;
           volume guarantee ventilation are lower in lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group compare&#xD;
           to control.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. The serum concentration of CD-31+ and CD-42b- in 24-32 weekers babies on assist-control&#xD;
           volume guarantee ventilation are lower in lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group compare&#xD;
           to control.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The right and left cardiac output in 24-32 weekers babies on assist-control volume&#xD;
           guarantee mode are more higher in lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group, than group that&#xD;
           did not get LRM&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. The incident Patent Ductus Arteriosus in 24-32 weekers babies on assist-control volume&#xD;
           guarantee ventilation are lower in lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group compare to&#xD;
           control.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. The difference tc-pCO2 - PaCO2 , tcO2 index , and strong ion difference (SID) in 24-32&#xD;
           weekers babies on assist-control volume guarantee ventilation are lower in lung&#xD;
           recruitment maneuver (LRM) group compare to control.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      description of the protocol :&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. All Babies that meet inclusion criteria would immediately given surfactan. Babies will&#xD;
           do echocardiography, blood gas analize, blood sample, transcutaneous monitor. After that&#xD;
           babies will be randomized, the intervention group will get standart protocol + lung&#xD;
           recruitment maneuver (LRM) and another group get standart protocol only.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. The lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) will be done by increasing of PEEP 0,2 cm H2O every&#xD;
           3 minutes, until reach the opening pressure. After that PEEP decrease gradually until&#xD;
           get the closing pressure. Than the investigators will back to the opening pressure for 3&#xD;
           minutes, and the final PEEP will be put back 0,2 above closing pressure.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. After 3rd days (72 hours) babies, the investigators will exime serum levels of surfactan&#xD;
           protein-D, CD-31+ and CD-42b- , blood gas , tc-pCO2 - PaCO2 , tcO2 index.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. After that babies will observe within 28 days to detect Bronchopulmonary dysplasia&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The impact of lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weekers with assist-control volume guarantee mode to their hemodynamic status and the incidence of Bronchopulmonary dysplasia</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>All babies wether they experience the intervention ofr not they can not tell to other peoples.&#xD;
Only The lab analyzer will be blind to the subject of study, other measurement can not be blind.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weeks preterm babies with the incidence of Bronchopulmonary dysplasia</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will have lower incidence of Bronchopulmonary dysplasia compare to control.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weekers, with their alveolar intergrity (serum levels of surfactan protein-D)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will have lower serum levels of surfactan protein -D compare to control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weekers, with their lung endothel intergrity (serum levels of CD-31+)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will have lower serum concentrarion of CD-31+ compare to control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weeks preterm babies with their lung endothel intergrity (serum levels of CD-42b-)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will have lower serum concentrarion of CD-42b- compare to control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weeks preterm babies with their micro circulation (oxygen index)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will have higher oxygen index compare to control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weeks preterm babies with their their micro circulation (tc-pCO2 - PaCO2 index)</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recrutment manuver will have transcutaneous-arterial partial carbon dioxide gap lower than control ( less than 6 mmHg ). babies with better microcirculation status will show less than 6 mmHg transcutaneous-arterial partial carbon dioxide gap.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weeks preterm babies with their incidence patent ductus arteriosus (PDA) significant</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will make lower incident of Patent Ductus Arteriosus compare to control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowing the relationship between lung recruitment maneuver in 24-32 weeks preterm babies with their macro circulation</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Preterm babies ( 24-32 weeks) with Lung Recruitment maneuver will make right and left cardiac output higher compare to control.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">110</enrollment>
  <condition>Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) will be done by increasing of PEEP 0,2 cm H2O every 3 minutes, until reach the opening pressure. After that PEEP decrease gradually until get the closing pressure. Than the investigators will back to the opening pressure for 3 minutes, and the final PEEP will be put backo 0,2 above closing pressure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>without lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Another group get standart protocol only.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) with DrageerVN500</intervention_name>
    <description>interventions involving device that may help to gradually lung development</description>
    <arm_group_label>lung recruitment maneuver (LRM) group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  24-32 weeks preterm babies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Babies on assist-control volume guarantee ventilation with FiO2 &gt; 30% to reach oxygen&#xD;
             saturations within 90-95%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age less than 48 hours.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Born in Cipto Mangunkusumo Hospital and Bunda Menteng Hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents/guardians agreed to participate in this study with sign informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight birth &lt;750 grams.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  APGAR score at 10 minutes are &lt;5.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Born with congenital heart disease except patent ductus arteriosus or presistence&#xD;
             foramen ovale.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Born with congenital disorder that need surgery intervention (for example :&#xD;
&#xD;
        diaphragmatic hernia, atresia ani, esophageal atresia, duodenal atresia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Born with congenital disorder that worsening of the respiratory distress (for example&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  hydrops fetalis, phrenic nerve paralysis, abnormality of chest wall, abnormality&#xD;
                  of air way (for example : Choanal atresia, Laryngeal stenosis, cleft palate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Born inborn error metabolism disease.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>48 Hours</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dr. R. Adhi T Perma Iskandar, Sp.A (K)</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>RSCMPerinatology</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Dr. R. Adhi T Perma Iskandar, Sp.A (K)</last_name>
    <phone>+62 85779153162</phone>
    <email>adhitpi@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>DR.Dr. Risma K Kaban, Sp.A (K)</last_name>
    <phone>+62 816902051</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.paediatricaindonesiana.org/index.php/paediatrica-indonesiana/article/view/2203</url>
    <description>Heated, humidified high-flow nasal cannula vs. nasal CPAP in infants with moderate respiratory distress</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://doi.org/10.1080/14767058.2017.1392506</url>
    <description>Serum surfactant protein D as a marker for bronchopulmonary dysplasia</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://doi.org/10.1161/01.ATV.0000243941.72375.15</url>
    <description>Increased Ratio of CD31+/CD42- Microparticles to Endothelial Progenitors as a Novel Marker of Atherosclerosis in Hypercholesterolemia</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubs.asahq.org/anesthesiology/article/110/6/1341/10637/Experimental-Ventilator-induced-Lung</url>
    <description>Experimental Ventilator-induced Lung Injury: Exacerbation by Positive End-Expiratory Pressure</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pedneo.2015.07.002</url>
    <description>Transitional Hemodynamics in Preterm Neonates: Clinical Relevance</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.neocosur.org/neocosur_contenido/bajando.php?archivo=Preds%20DBP%20NEOCOSUR%202019.pdf</url>
    <description>Bronchopulmonary dysplasia: risk prediction models for very-lowbirth-weight infants</description>
  </link>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Blencowe H, Cousens S, Oestergaard MZ, Chou D, Moller AB, Narwal R, Adler A, Vera Garcia C, Rohde S, Say L, Lawn JE. National, regional, and worldwide estimates of preterm birth rates in the year 2010 with time trends since 1990 for selected countries: a systematic analysis and implications. Lancet. 2012 Jun 9;379(9832):2162-72. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(12)60820-4.</citation>
    <PMID>22682464</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Liu L, Oza S, Hogan D, Chu Y, Perin J, Zhu J, Lawn JE, Cousens S, Mathers C, Black RE. Global, regional, and national causes of under-5 mortality in 2000-15: an updated systematic analysis with implications for the Sustainable Development Goals. Lancet. 2016 Dec 17;388(10063):3027-3035. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)31593-8. Epub 2016 Nov 11. Erratum in: Lancet. 2017 May 13;389(10082):1884.</citation>
    <PMID>27839855</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kumar A, Bhat BV. Epidemiology of respiratory distress of newborns. Indian J Pediatr. 1996 Jan-Feb;63(1):93-8.</citation>
    <PMID>10829971</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>van Kaam AH, de Jaegere A, Haitsma JJ, Van Aalderen WM, Kok JH, Lachmann B. Positive pressure ventilation with the open lung concept optimizes gas exchange and reduces ventilator-induced lung injury in newborn piglets. Pediatr Res. 2003 Feb;53(2):245-53.</citation>
    <PMID>12538782</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Peng W, Zhu H, Shi H, Liu E. Volume-targeted ventilation is more suitable than pressure-limited ventilation for preterm infants: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2014 Mar;99(2):F158-65. doi: 10.1136/archdischild-2013-304613. Epub 2013 Nov 25. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24277660</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>DiBlasi RM. Neonatal noninvasive ventilation techniques: do we really need to intubate? Respir Care. 2011 Sep;56(9):1273-94; discussion 1295-7. doi: 10.4187/respcare.01376. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21944681</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Haczku A. Protective role of the lung collectins surfactant protein A and surfactant protein D in airway inflammation. J Allergy Clin Immunol. 2008 Nov;122(5):861-79; quiz 880-1. doi: 10.1016/j.jaci.2008.10.014.</citation>
    <PMID>19000577</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Eisner MD, Parsons P, Matthay MA, Ware L, Greene K; Acute Respiratory Distress Syndrome Network. Plasma surfactant protein levels and clinical outcomes in patients with acute lung injury. Thorax. 2003 Nov;58(11):983-8.</citation>
    <PMID>14586055</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Reid VL, Webster NR. Role of microparticles in sepsis. Br J Anaesth. 2012 Oct;109(4):503-13. doi: 10.1093/bja/aes321. Epub 2012 Sep 4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22952169</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Woodfin A, Voisin MB, Nourshargh S. PECAM-1: a multi-functional molecule in inflammation and vascular biology. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol. 2007 Dec;27(12):2514-23. Epub 2007 Sep 13. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17872453</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cabrera-Benítez NE, Valladares F, García-Hernández S, Ramos-Nuez Á, Martín-Barrasa JL, Martínez-Saavedra MT, Rodríguez-Gallego C, Muros M, Flores C, Liu M, Slutsky AS, Villar J. Altered Profile of Circulating Endothelial-Derived Microparticles in Ventilator-Induced Lung Injury. Crit Care Med. 2015 Dec;43(12):e551-9. doi: 10.1097/CCM.0000000000001280. Erratum in: Crit Care Med. 2016 Mar;44(3):e180.</citation>
    <PMID>26308427</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Kluckow M, Evans N. Superior vena cava flow in newborn infants: a novel marker of systemic blood flow. Arch Dis Child Fetal Neonatal Ed. 2000 May;82(3):F182-7.</citation>
    <PMID>10794783</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Bancalari E, Claure N. Definitions and diagnostic criteria for bronchopulmonary dysplasia. Semin Perinatol. 2006 Aug;30(4):164-70. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16860155</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Madurga A, Mizíková I, Ruiz-Camp J, Morty RE. Recent advances in late lung development and the pathogenesis of bronchopulmonary dysplasia. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2013 Dec;305(12):L893-905. doi: 10.1152/ajplung.00267.2013. Epub 2013 Nov 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24213917</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Castoldi F, Daniele I, Fontana P, Cavigioli F, Lupo E, Lista G. Lung recruitment maneuver during volume guarantee ventilation of preterm infants with acute respiratory distress syndrome. Am J Perinatol. 2011 Aug;28(7):521-8. doi: 10.1055/s-0031-1272970. Epub 2011 Mar 4.</citation>
    <PMID>21380992</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 12, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 21, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dr Cipto Mangunkusumo General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. R. Adhi Teguh Perma Iskandar, Sp.A(K)</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator of Perinatology Division</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>lung recruitment maneuver</keyword>
  <keyword>preterm babies</keyword>
  <keyword>Bronchopulmonary dysplasia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hyperplasia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

