<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04555382</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-791</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04555382</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Combining CAF, L-FABP and NGAL as a Potentially Diagnostic Model for Acute Kidney Injury.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Association Between CAF, L-FABP and NGAL and the Occurence of Acute Kidney Injury : a Potential Diagnostic Model of Three Biomarkers.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Second Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Acute kidney injury was a common clinical complication, and many diseases were associated&#xD;
      with a high risk of occurrence of AKI. We explored the clinical utility of serum CAF, L-FABP&#xD;
      and NGAL by constructing a diagnostic model for identification of ICU patients at risk for&#xD;
      AKI and distinguish different etiologies of AKI.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This observational cohort study included one hundred patients who had been in ICU from the&#xD;
      Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine between August 2020 and&#xD;
      August 2022. Blood and urine samples were collected every 12 hours until 7 days. The time of&#xD;
      staying with ICU less than 2 days were removed. CAF, L-FABP and NGAL was measured based on&#xD;
      the platform of Chemiluminescent Immunoassay, and assessed the diagnostic value of the&#xD;
      occurrence of AKI. By constructing an effective diagnostic model to provide effective&#xD;
      clinical decision-marking for early intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The observational cohort study included one hundred patients who were from the intensive care&#xD;
      unit of the Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine between&#xD;
      August 2020 and August 2022. AKI was defined according to the Kidney Disease Improving Global&#xD;
      Outcomes (KDIGO) guidelines as renal function was suddenly decreased within 48 hours and&#xD;
      serum creatinine increased at least 0.3mg/dL, or serum creatinine increased more than 1.5&#xD;
      times higher than baseline within 7 days, or urine volume less than 0.5mL/Kg per hour for 6&#xD;
      hours. The staging criteria of AKI as follows: stage I means serum creatinine higher than&#xD;
      baseline between 1.5times and 1.9 times, or serum creatinine increased at least 26.5μmol/L,&#xD;
      or serum creatinine increased more than 1.5 times higher than baseline within 7 days, or&#xD;
      urine volume less than 0.5mL/Kg per hour for 6 hours; stage II means serum creatinine higher&#xD;
      than baseline between 2.0 times and 2.9 times, or urine volume less than 0.5mL/Kg per hour&#xD;
      for 12hours; stage III means serum creatinine higher than baseline 3.0 times, or serum&#xD;
      creatinine higher than baseline 353.6μmol/L, or started renal replacement therapy. Patients&#xD;
      who stayed in the ICU for less than 24 hours and whose serum creatinine had increased above&#xD;
      normal reference range on the first day of ICU were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collecting the blood and urine samples of the patients regularly every twelve hours,&#xD;
      centrifuging samples in 3000rpm for 5 minutes, freezing at -80℃, all patients' clinical&#xD;
      information should be recorded by name, age ,sex, BMI index, hypertension, diabetes, cardiac&#xD;
      disease, and so on. All patients have written informed contents and this study was approved&#xD;
      by the Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine.NGAL, CAF and&#xD;
      L-FABP was measured by chemiluminescent immunoassay with Robust i1000.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 15, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 15, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>the concentration of CAF, L-FABP and NGAL</measure>
    <time_frame>seven days after admission</time_frame>
    <description>the concentration of CAF, L-FABP and NGAL of blood and urine samples of every patients are measured by Chemiluminescent Immunoassay</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Acute Kidney Injury</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>AKI group</arm_group_label>
    <description>this group are included patients who have not occured acute kidney injury at first, however acute kidney injury are occured soon afterwards during the observation period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>non-AKI group</arm_group_label>
    <description>this group are included patients who have not occured acute kidney injury during the observation period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood and Urine</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood and urine samples are collected every twelve hours when the patients are included in the study during observation period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>AKI group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>non-AKI group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood and urine samples were collected from the patients every twelve hours, and time was&#xD;
      limited with a maximum of seven days for every patients. After centrifuging with 3000rpm for&#xD;
      5minutes, 1.5mL of supernate was taken into EP tube and stored in the refrigerator at -80℃&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The objects of study are the patients from the intensive care unit of the Second Affiliated&#xD;
        Hospital of Zhejiang University School of Medicine between August 2020 and August 2022.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. the serum creatinine was increased above reference range at first when patients were&#xD;
             included intensive care unit;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. renal dialysis and plasma exchange were never occured when patients were included in&#xD;
             the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. patients who were included in the study stayed at two days in ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. patients who stayed in ICU for less than 24 hours;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. the serum creatinine was increased above reference range before ICU admission;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. kidney-related diseases were existed before ICU admission.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tao Zhihua</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>2nd Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, China</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sun Tao</last_name>
    <phone>15858168218</phone>
    <email>stzr@zju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tao Zhihua</last_name>
    <phone>18258196858</phone>
    <email>zrtzh@zju.edu.cn</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>2nd Affiliated Hospital, School of Medicine, Zhejiang University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hangzhou</city>
        <state>Zhejiang</state>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wang Weilin</last_name>
      <phone>+86 0571 87783759</phone>
      <email>keyanlunli_zheer@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 15, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 15, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 18, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>L-FABP, Acute Kidney Injury, diagnosis, biomarker</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Acute Kidney Injury</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

