<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04550936</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>C3791008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04550936</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Patterns of Real-World Isavuconazole Use - a Study of Patients With Mucormycosis or Invasive Aspergillosis</brief_title>
  <acronym>PRISMA</acronym>
  <official_title>Patterns of Real-World Isavuconazole Use, Effectiveness, Safety, and Healthcare Resource Utilization-a Retrospective Chart Review Study of Patients With Mucormycosis or Invasive Aspergillosis (PRISMA)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pfizer</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pfizer</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a non-interventional medical chart review study aiming to examine the effectiveness,&#xD;
      safety, and treatment patterns of isavuconazole in 5 European countries (France, Germany,&#xD;
      Italy, Spain, and United Kingdom). Eligible patients are adults who have been treated with&#xD;
      isavuconazole in routine practice at participating sites since 15 October, 2015 or since the&#xD;
      date of launch in the country if it is after 15 October, 2015 until 30 June, 2019. As this is&#xD;
      an observational study, patients will be treated based on the standard of care at the&#xD;
      discretion of their physician. No drugs will be supplied for this study and patients will&#xD;
      receive treatment through standard local practice.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This observational study will include approximately 600 patients diagnosed with invasive&#xD;
      aspergillosis or mucormycosis who received treatment with at least one dose of isavuconazole&#xD;
      in the hospital setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be recruited in approximately 20 sites across 5 countries in Europe. Patients&#xD;
      will be followed from isavuconazole initiation (index event) until six-months post-index&#xD;
      treatment discontinuation, death, loss to follow-up, or 31 December, 2019, whichever occurs&#xD;
      first.&#xD;
&#xD;
      De-identified data on patient demographics, disease characteristics, treatment effectiveness,&#xD;
      safety outcomes, isavuconazole treatment patterns, and HCRU will be collected from patient&#xD;
      medical records and entered into an electronic data capture (EDC) system by site staff.&#xD;
      Follow-up data will include details of treatment over time and clinical, radiological,&#xD;
      mycological, and healthcare resource utilization outcomes. As this study is retrospective,&#xD;
      information pertaining to patient care will already be documented in patient medical records&#xD;
      at the time of chart abstraction.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 26, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 26, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients and their respective clinical outcomes of treatment with isavuconazole</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 months post-index</time_frame>
    <description>overall response, including clinical response, mycological response, radiological response, and mortality</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients and their respective safety outcomes of treatment with isavuconazole</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 months post-index</time_frame>
    <description>treatment related AEs and SAEs</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients for each indication and usage pattern of isavuconazole</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 months post-index</time_frame>
    <description>formulation, dosage (loading and maintenance), duration, treatment changes (including dosage adjustments, switching, and discontinuation), and concomitant medication</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients and their respective healthcare resource utilization after treatment with isavuconazole</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 6 months post-index</time_frame>
    <description>length of stay [LOS], emergency room [ER] visits, intensive care unit [ICU] visits and LOS, inpatient hospitalizations, and planned and unplanned outpatient visits</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">600</enrollment>
  <condition>Invasive Aspergillosis</condition>
  <condition>Mucormycosis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Isavuconazole</intervention_name>
    <description>antifungal agent</description>
    <other_name>Cresemba</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients who received isavuconazole for the treatment of invasive aspergillosis or&#xD;
        mucormycosis in the hospital setting in five European countries (France, Germany, Italy,&#xD;
        Spain, and the United Kingdom).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hospitalized patient must be aged ≥ 18 years at the time of isavuconazole initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient must have a record of a diagnosis of invasive aspergillosis or mucormycosis in&#xD;
             their medical record at the time isavuconazole was initiated (regardless of whether&#xD;
             this diagnosis is suspected or confirmed )&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient must have received at least one dose of isavuconazole during the eligibility&#xD;
             period (October 15, 2015, to June 30, 2019)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients who did not receive at least one dose of isavuconazole for treatment of&#xD;
        invasive aspergillosis or mucormycosis within the eligibility period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Pfizer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Pfizer CT.gov Call Center</last_name>
    <phone>1-800-718-1021</phone>
    <email>ClinicalTrials.gov_Inquiries@pfizer.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Fundació Clínic Per A La Recerca Biomèdica</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <zip>08036</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pmiform.com/clinical-trial-info-request?StudyID=C3791008</url>
    <description>To obtain contact information for a study center near you, click here.</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 9, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 16, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Aspergillosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mucormycosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Zygomycosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Isavuconazole</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Pfizer will provide access to individual de-identified participant data and related study documents (e.g. protocol, Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP), Clinical Study Report (CSR)) upon request from qualified researchers, and subject to certain criteria, conditions, and exceptions. Further details on Pfizer's data sharing criteria and process for requesting access can be found at: https://www.pfizer.com/science/clinical_trials/trial_data_and_results/data_requests.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

