<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04554602</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP191069</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2019-A02828-49</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04554602</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fusion Ultrasound for Diagnosis and Monitoring of Endometriosis Lesions</brief_title>
  <acronym>ENDOFUSION</acronym>
  <official_title>Fusion Ultrasound for Diagnosis and Monitoring of Endometriosis Lesions ENDOFUSION</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is evaluate the fusion ultrasound performance compared to MRI and&#xD;
      coelioscopy diagnosis when a surgical intervention is performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The research is about diagnosis performance between fusion ultrasound and the gold standard&#xD;
      (MRI coelioscopy ). Fusion ultrasound is a no-invasive scientific technical which allow with&#xD;
      security to evaluate the progress of endometriosis lesions. During 39 months, 200 patients&#xD;
      will be follow. In one arm, there is the control group with women without endometriosis. In&#xD;
      the second arm, there is the patient with endometriosis. We will compare monitoring&#xD;
      differences between gold standard and fusion ultrasound ( Cost assessment,exams duration,&#xD;
      reproductibility, the link between symptoms and evolution of the lesion size).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 23, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensitivity, specificity, positive predictive value (VPP) and negative predictive value (VPN) of fusion ultrasound compared to transvaginal ultrasound and MRI for the diagnosis of endometriosis lesions</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the diagnostic performance of fusion ultrasound compared to transvaginal gynaecological ultrasound and MRI for the diagnosis of endometriosis lesions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To evaluate the contribution of fusion ultrasound in the follow-up of patients suffering from endometriosis, in particular with an ultrasound follow-up in comparison with an initial reference MRI in the case of medical or surgical management.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Correlation between the evolution of clinical and quality of life symptoms (EHP30 form and Short Form 36) and the evolution of lesion size between initial MRI and follow-up ultrasounds at 6 months and one year</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of the cost of imaging for 3 years between an annual fusion ultrasound surveillance in replacement of a annual MRI surveillance</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of imaging costs will be carried out over 3 years between a conventional procedure with annual MRI and the procedure being evaluated</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the duration of a standard ultrasound scan to an ultrasound scan with fusion</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the average examination time by a Student T-test between standard and fusion ultrasound.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the reproducibility of the conclusions of the fusion ultrasound between 2 operators.</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years and 3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the reproducibility by an intra-class correlation test for the conclusions of fusion ultrasound between two operators.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">200</enrollment>
  <condition>Endometriosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with endometriosis or suspicion of endometriosis</arm_group_label>
    <description>Information and collection of the non-objection before inclusion&#xD;
Interrogation, clinical examination, EHP30 and SF36 form at inclusion&#xD;
MRI, pelvic ultrasound (coupled with fusion ultrasound)&#xD;
Laparoscopy if indicated after MRI, ultrasound and fusion ultrasound&#xD;
Monitoring by form and fusion ultrasound at 6 months and then once a year for 3 years</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with other gynaecological pathology</arm_group_label>
    <description>Information and collection of the non-opposition before inclusion&#xD;
Interrogation, clinical examination, EHP30 and SF36 form at inclusion&#xD;
MRI, pelvic ultrasound (coupled with fusion ultrasound)&#xD;
laparoscopy if indicated after MRI, ultrasound and fusion ultrasound</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fusion ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>Fusion ultrasound is a technique that allows a volume acquired in MRI to be coupled to an ultrasound scan with real-time image synchronisation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with endometriosis or suspicion of endometriosis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with other gynaecological pathology</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Any major patient with an indication for pelvic MRI and pelvic ultrasound outside a proven&#xD;
        cancer indication (suspicion of endometriosis or other pathology for the control&#xD;
        population).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients from 18 to 50 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient informed and who gave her non-opposition to participate in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with an indication for pelvic MRI and pelvic ultrasound either for the&#xD;
             exploration of endometriosis or pelvic pain, or for another gynaecological pathology&#xD;
             (ovarian cyst, poly-myomatous uterus, uterine malformation) outside of a proven cancer&#xD;
             indication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient affiliated to a social security or entitled to a social security allowance&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient with a proven cancerous pathology at the time of the prescription of the&#xD;
             complementary examinations.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Virgin patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients under protective measures&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to MRI (claustrophobia, intracorporeal metallic foreign body)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>50 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hervé FERNANDEZ, PR</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>APHP</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Perrine CAPMAS, DR</last_name>
    <phone>0033145217590</phone>
    <email>perrine.capmas@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 14, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 14, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 18, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 14, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 14, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 18, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Endometriosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

