<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04842370</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PHI-101-001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04842370</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics, and Pharmacodynamics of PHI 101 for the Treatment of AML</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Prospective, Phase Ia/Ib, Multicenter Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of the FLT3 Inhibitor, PHI 101, Alone in Subjects With Relapsed or Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Seoul National University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Pharos iBio Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Seoul National University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to find out the maximum tolerable dose and safety of PHI-101,&#xD;
      novel FLT3 inhibitor in the treatment of relapsed or refractory AML for patients who have&#xD;
      received standard therapy or cannot tolerate standard therapy, and/or for whom no standard&#xD;
      therapy exists.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There will be two parts to the study, which we will call Phase Ia and Phase Ib. Phase Ia is&#xD;
      called the dose escalation. Approximately 20 to 24 patients are planned to be enrolled into&#xD;
      Phase Ia. Phase 1a is conducted to determine the best dose and schedule of dosing of PHI-101&#xD;
      to be used in Phase 1b. There will be 5 different dose levels of PHI-101 given to patients in&#xD;
      Phase Ia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase Ib is called the dose expansion. Approximately 14-34 patients (approximately 14-17&#xD;
      patients in each of the 2 cohorts planned) of each cohort are planned in Phase Ib based on&#xD;
      study design. Phase Ib is also being conducted to assess anti-leukemia response, changes in&#xD;
      transfusion requirements, and safety of PHI-101 at the dose level identified during Phase Ia.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 8, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 21, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 21, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety assessed through adverse events to determine maximum tolerated dose</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening to the last Safety Follow up Visit(Safety Follow-up visit occurs 30 days after from EOT)</time_frame>
    <description>Safety will be measured by AEs, vital signs, ECG, clinical laboratory tests, physical examination, ECOG performance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Tolerability assessed by dose compliance</measure>
    <time_frame>From screening to the last Safety Follow up Visit(Safety Follow-up visit occurs 30 days after from EOT)</time_frame>
    <description>Tolerability will be measured by reviewing data of dose interruptions, reductions, and doses administered</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">42</enrollment>
  <condition>Relapsed or Refractory Acute Myeloid Leukemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Dose escalation and expansion of PHI-101</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PHI-101</intervention_name>
    <description>PHI-101, oral, once-daily administration, consisting of 28-days per 1 cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Dose escalation and expansion of PHI-101</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to understand and sign an informed consent form (ICF) and to comply&#xD;
             with all aspects of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female or male subjects aged ≥18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The ECOG performance status ≤2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phase Ia (dose escalation part only): Subjects with relapsed and/or refractory AML&#xD;
             which is diagnosed with World Health Organization (WHO) classification9 who have&#xD;
             received standard therapy or are intolerant of standard therapy, and/or for whom no&#xD;
             standard therapy exists.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Phase Ib (dose expansion): Subjects with relapsed and/or refractory AML which is&#xD;
             diagnosed with WHO classification and who have a FLT3 abnormality (i.e., FLT3-ITD&#xD;
             and/or TKD mutation) as determined by accredited laboratory.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female subjects must be surgically sterile, or have a monogamous partner who is&#xD;
             surgically sterile, or be of postmenopausal status (at least 2 years or serum follicle&#xD;
             stimulating hormone &gt;40 mIU/mL and estradiol &lt;20 pg/mL or according to the&#xD;
             postmenopausal range definition for the laboratory involved), or commit to use an&#xD;
             effective form of birth control (Appendix 5) for the duration of the study and for 90&#xD;
             days following the last PHI-101 administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active males must commit to use an effective form of birth control (Appendix&#xD;
             5) while taking the drug and for 30 days after stopping PHI-101. A condom is required&#xD;
             to be used by vasectomized men in order to prevent delivery of the drug via seminal&#xD;
             fluid.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject having laboratory values defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Creatinine clearance (calculated using Cockcroft-Gault formula, or measured) &gt;40 mL/min.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Total bilirubin &lt;1.5 × upper limit of normal (ULN), except for subjects with Gilbert's&#xD;
        syndrome who are excluded if total bilirubin &gt;3.0 × ULN or direct bilirubin ≥1.5 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt;2.5 × ULN, except for subjects that have leukemic&#xD;
        involvement of the liver, who are excluded if ALT &lt;5 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &lt;2.5 × ULN, except for subjects that have leukemic&#xD;
        involvement of the liver, who are excluded if AST &lt;5 × ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of overt leptomeningeal or active central nervous system involvement with&#xD;
             AML.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has a diagnosis of acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL), French American British&#xD;
             classification M3 or WHO classification of APL with t(15;17)(q22;q12), or BCR ABL&#xD;
             positive leukemia (chronic myelogenous leukemia in blast crisis).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has favorable risk cytogenetics as categorized by the National Comprehensive&#xD;
             Cancer Network Guidelines Version 2, 2014 for AML.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has had hematopoietic stem cell transplant and meets any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Is within 2 months of transplant from Cycle 1 Day 1. Has clinically significant&#xD;
        Graft-versus-host disease requiring treatment. Has ≥ Grade 2 persistent nonhematological&#xD;
        toxicity related to the transplant. Donor lymphocytes infusion is not permitted ≤30 days&#xD;
        prior to study registration or during the first cycle of treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has disseminated intravascular coagulation abnormality.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired cardiac function or clinically significant cardiac disease, including any of&#xD;
             the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Clinically significant and/or uncontrolled heart disease such as congestive heart failure&#xD;
        requiring treatment (New York Heart Association Grade ≥2), left ventricular ejection&#xD;
        fraction &lt;50% as determined by multiple gated acquisition (MUGA) or echocardiogram,&#xD;
        uncontrolled hypertension, or clinically significant arrhythmia.&#xD;
&#xD;
        QT interval as corrected by the Fridericia method (QTcF) &gt;450 ms ECG or congenital long QT&#xD;
        syndrome at the Screening Visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Subject with hypokalemia and hypomagnesemia at Screening (defined as values below lower&#xD;
        limit of normal).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Acute myocardial infarction or unstable angina pectoris &lt;3 months prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with interstitial pneumonia or history of drug-induced interstitial&#xD;
             pneumonia/pneumonitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A positive human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) antibody test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active hepatitis B virus (HBV) infection (chronic or acute), defined as having a&#xD;
             positive hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) test, or active hepatitis C virus (HCV)&#xD;
             infection, defined as having a positive HCV antibody test followed by a positive HCV&#xD;
             RNA test.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Subjects with a past or resolved HBV infection, defined as having a negative HBsAg&#xD;
        test and a positive hepatitis B core antibody test followed by a quantitative HBV DNA &lt; 9&#xD;
        log (80) IU/mL are eligible for the study. Subjects who are inactive carriers of HBV/HCV&#xD;
        are eligible for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic liver disease or chronic hepatitis (Child Pugh Class B or C hepatic&#xD;
             impairment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any gastrointestinal disorders interfering with study drug absorption or subjects who&#xD;
             are unable to swallow tablets or capsules.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Malignant disease, other than that being treated in this study. Exceptions to this&#xD;
             exclusion include the following: malignancies that were treated curatively and have&#xD;
             not recurred within 2 years prior to study treatment; completely resected basal cell&#xD;
             and squamous cell skin cancers; any malignancy considered to be indolent and that has&#xD;
             never required therapy; and completely resected carcinoma in situ of any type.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects receiving systemic chronic steroid therapy or any immunosuppressive therapy&#xD;
             (≥10 mg/day prednisone or equivalent). Topical, inhaled, nasal, and ophthalmic&#xD;
             steroids are allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of any live vaccines against infectious diseases within 28 days of initiation of&#xD;
             study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of medications, herbal products, or foods known to be moderate or potent&#xD;
             inhibitors of P glycoprotein (P gp) within the last 7 days prior to Day 1 or known to&#xD;
             be moderate or potent inducers of P gp within the last 14 days prior to Day 1 (see&#xD;
             Section 6.5).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects with a history of stroke or having active neurological symptoms, with the&#xD;
             exception of chronic conditions which in the opinion of the neurologist, Investigator,&#xD;
             and the Sponsor, would not impact on ongoing neurologic assessments while on study&#xD;
             treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active uncontrolled infection requiring systemic or antiviral antibiotic therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 2 weeks of the first dose of study treatment (mediastinoscopy,&#xD;
             insertion of a central venous access device, and insertion of a feeding tube are not&#xD;
             considered major surgery).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy within 3 weeks of the first dose of study drug, except for palliative&#xD;
             radiotherapy to a limited-field, such as for the treatment of bone pain or a focally&#xD;
             painful tumor mass.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of CTCAE ≥ Grade 2 toxicity (except alopecia, peripheral neuropathy, and&#xD;
             ototoxicity, which are excluded if ≥ CTCAE Grade 3) due to prior cancer therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior treatment with cytotoxic agents (except hydroxyurea given for controlling&#xD;
             hyperleukocytosis) within 2 weeks prior to study drug administration, or other&#xD;
             experimental agents or noncytotoxic agents within 5 half-lives prior to study drug&#xD;
             administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Note: Subjects in Phase Ia of this study can still take PHI-101 before entering Phase Ib of&#xD;
        this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical condition that would, in the Investigator's judgment, prevent the&#xD;
             subject's participation in the clinical study due to safety concerns, compliance with&#xD;
             clinical study procedures, or interpretation of study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating women, where pregnancy is defined as the state of a female after&#xD;
             conception and until the termination of gestation, confirmed by a positive human&#xD;
             chorionic gonadotropin laboratory test.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sung-Soo Yoon, MD. PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Seoul National University Hospital, Seoul National University College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sung-Soo Yoon, MD. PhD</last_name>
    <phone>82-2-2072-3079</phone>
    <email>ssysmc@snu.ac.kr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Seoul National University Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Seoul</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sung-Soo Yoon, MD. PhD</last_name>
      <phone>82-2-2072-3079</phone>
      <email>ssysmc@snu.ac.kr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Myeloid, Acute</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

