<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04841057</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2032062</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04841057</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Biometabolic Outcomes After Weight Loss Surgery: An Individualized Approach</brief_title>
  <official_title>Biometabolic Outcomes After Weight Loss Surgery: An Individualized Approach</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Missouri-Columbia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Missouri-Columbia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Variable outcomes after weight loss surgery are likely attributable to complex, poorly&#xD;
      understood mechanisms. Due to the significant impact that morbid obesity has on a patient's&#xD;
      health, successful management of obesity and its related comorbid medical conditions is&#xD;
      important and thus necessitates continued improved therapies for treating obesity. Although&#xD;
      the mechanisms of weight loss after surgical intervention are poorly understood, improved&#xD;
      understanding of molecular and metabolic changes that occur after weight loss surgery may&#xD;
      offer the ability to provide targeted precision therapy for patients with morbid obesity&#xD;
      undergoing surgical therapy. In this proposal, the investigators will combine a clinical&#xD;
      trial whereby modifications to the gold-standard for weight loss surgery, the gastric bypass,&#xD;
      are evaluated while simultaneously measuring molecular and metabolic changes that occur in&#xD;
      response to these weight loss procedures. Through creating variable lengths of bypass&#xD;
      intestine after gastric bypass, the investigators will be able to determine the effect of&#xD;
      malabsorption on clinical outcomes and mechanisms involved in weight loss after gastric&#xD;
      bypass. The investigators will also use two control groups. One will be a surgical weight&#xD;
      loss control group and consist of patients undergoing a laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy, a&#xD;
      non-intestinal bypass procedure. The other group will consist of patients having non-surgical&#xD;
      weight loss therapy. To asses metabolic changes that occur in response to surgical weight&#xD;
      therapy and specifically intestinal bypass and malabsorption, the investigators will examine&#xD;
      changes in the gut microbiome and plasma gut enteroendocrine hormones. To evaluate molecular&#xD;
      pathways that are impacted as a result of gastric bypass and malabsorption, the investigators&#xD;
      will measure circulating microRNAs (miRNAs) in the blood. Measurement of miRNAs will provide&#xD;
      data on an easily measurable molecular marker for each treatment group. This is a first step&#xD;
      in translational exploration of mechanisms of weight loss after surgery by evaluating both&#xD;
      clinical and molecular/metabolic outcomes and begin an explorative process towards creating&#xD;
      an individualized approach to improving outcomes after weight loss surgery.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Outcomes after weight loss surgery are quite variable with some patients regaining a&#xD;
      significant amount of weight in the postoperative period. Increasing evidence suggests&#xD;
      gastric bypass leads to weight loss and improvement in associated metabolic illness through&#xD;
      mechanisms other than just restriction and malabsorption and may include circulating bile&#xD;
      acids, gut hormones, genetic/epigenetic variability, changes in gut microbiota as well as&#xD;
      other mechanisms. Whether modifications to bypassed intestine length may improve outcomes&#xD;
      after gastric bypass has not been adequately studied with inconsistent results in the&#xD;
      literature. Whether increasing the amount of bypassed intestine may positively amplify the&#xD;
      multi-factorial mechanisms involved in successful weight loss has not been studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary goal of the research is to determine if increasing the amount of bypassed&#xD;
      intestine during gastric bypass surgery improves outcomes and effects molecular and metabolic&#xD;
      changes that may impact outcomes after gastric bypass. The proposed research will evaluate&#xD;
      not only biologic mechanisms of weight loss and correlation between these mechanisms and&#xD;
      successful weight loss but also investigate the role intestinal bypass has on molecular and&#xD;
      metabolic mechanisms involved in effective weight loss therapy. Regardless if weight loss&#xD;
      outcomes are similar in patients with different lengths of bypassed intestine, the role of&#xD;
      the gut in gastric bypass will be investigated through evaluation of gut microbiota,&#xD;
      circulating miRNAs and gut hormones, three mechanisms thought to play a role in the&#xD;
      effectiveness of the gastric bypass for weight loss surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: Determine if increasing length of bypassed intestine leads to improved clinical&#xD;
      outcomes after gastric bypass. A randomized-controlled trial design will be used with&#xD;
      patients randomized to variable lengths of bypassed intestine when undergoing gastric bypass.&#xD;
      A randomized trial will help avoid procedure selection bias. Surgical and non-surgical&#xD;
      control groups will consist of patients having sleeve gastrectomy (non-intestinal bypass&#xD;
      surgical control) and those undergoing best non-surgical, medical therapy. Primary outcomes&#xD;
      measured will include weight loss and relief of medical comorbidities of obesity specifically&#xD;
      diabetes and dyslipidemia. Secondary outcomes include complications related to malabsorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Measure gut hormone changes after increased intestinal bypass during gastric bypass.&#xD;
      The investigators will measure gut hormones after variable amounts of intestinal bypass to&#xD;
      determine the role of intestinal bypass in improvement of gut hormone production that affects&#xD;
      metabolism, hunger and possibly weight loss. Blood collected from patient's in Aim 1 will be&#xD;
      used to measure gut hormone levels which will then be correlated to clinical outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: miRNA profiling in patients having gastric bypass with variable intestinal bypass&#xD;
      lengths. The investigators will perform miRNA arrays on plasma from patients from Aim 1 to&#xD;
      determine possible pathways impacted by weight loss and in particular increased intestinal&#xD;
      bypass lengths in patients undergoing gastric bypass. The variable expression of miRNA will&#xD;
      also be correlated to weight loss outcomes and metabolic disease improvement in the surgical&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 4: Measure variation in gut microbiome due to increased intestinal bypass during gastric&#xD;
      bypass. The investigators will examine the impact of weight loss and variable intestinal&#xD;
      bypass lengths during gastric bypass on the gut microbiome. This will be determined through&#xD;
      collection of stool samples preoperatively as well as postoperatively in patients having&#xD;
      weight loss surgery. Samples will be collected from patients in Aim 1 above. Sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomy patients will be used to determine the impact of surgical weight loss on gut&#xD;
      microbiome and variation in intestinal bypass lengths will provide insight into the role of&#xD;
      bypassed intestine in the effects of gastric bypass on changes in gut microbiota after weight&#xD;
      loss surgery. Through correlation with clinical outcomes the investigators will be able to&#xD;
      determine any association with weight loss and relief of metabolic disease when the gut&#xD;
      microbiota are modified after weight loss surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Approach&#xD;
&#xD;
      Protocol Aim 1: Determine if increasing length of bypassed intestine leads to improved&#xD;
      clinical outcomes after gastric bypass.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary outcomes will include weight loss and relief of medical comorbidities of obesity, in&#xD;
      particular diabetes and dyslipidemia. Secondary outcomes include determining complications&#xD;
      that occur such as protein calorie malnutrition, vitamin and micronutrient deficiencies and&#xD;
      chronic diarrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1a. Randomization of patients and surgical technique. A total of five groups will be used.&#xD;
      The surgical control group will consist of patients having a laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy&#xD;
      as described below under procedure descriptions. The non-surgical control group will include&#xD;
      patients undergoing best medical therapy through our medical weight loss program. The other&#xD;
      three groups will be randomized through a sealed-envelope method. The assigned group will be&#xD;
      in a sealed envelope and the patient will be blinded to the treatment group that they are&#xD;
      assigned to. Patients will be randomized to variable lengths of intestinal bypass during&#xD;
      performance of a laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass. See description of procedure below.&#xD;
      These groups will function to examine the impact of increasing lengths of bypassed small&#xD;
      intestine through modifications of the BPL length. The following three groups will be&#xD;
      utilized:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Alimentary limb length 100 cm and biliopancreatic limb length (true bypassed intestinal&#xD;
           length) of 50 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Alimentary limb length 100 cm and biliopancreatic limb length (true bypassed intestinal&#xD;
           length) of 100 cm&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Alimentary limb length 100 cm and biliopancreatic limb length (true bypassed intestinal&#xD;
           length) of 150 cm Sample size for randomization to the three gastric bypass groups will&#xD;
           be approximately 75 patients in each group. 75 sleeve gastrectomy patients will also be&#xD;
           included. Sample size was determined based on previously published literature. The total&#xD;
           number of these patients will be used only for the clinical portion of the study. Sample&#xD;
           size for this pilot study for each of the gut hormone assays, gut microbiome analyses&#xD;
           and miRNA arrays will be 15 subjects in each group. This will include 15 patients&#xD;
           selected from each of the groups of randomized gastric bypass patients, the sleeve&#xD;
           gastrectomy group, and the medical control group for a total of 75 patients. Each&#xD;
           patient will have stool and blood collected at pre-treatment (surgical or non-surgical&#xD;
           therapy), 6 months post therapy and 12 months post therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surgical Procedure A gastric bypass will be performed using our standard technique. In brief,&#xD;
      all procedures will be performed laparoscopically as is standard practice. Specifically at&#xD;
      our institution, the gastric pouch will be constructed with a linear stapler approximately 5&#xD;
      cm long and 3 cm wide. The gastrojejunostomy anastomosis will be constructed either with a 25&#xD;
      mm circular stapler or a linear stapler. The linear stapler common gastroenterotomy will be&#xD;
      closed in a running 2 layer manner to narrow to approximately 13-15 mm. The jejunojejunostomy&#xD;
      will be created with a liner stapler after creation of BPL length of 50 cm, 100 cm or 150 cm&#xD;
      and an alimentary limb length of 100 cm which will be connected to the gastric pouch via the&#xD;
      gastrojejunostomy. The remaining small bowel, which will represent the common small bowel&#xD;
      channel will also be measured. Measurements will be achieved using premeasured markings on a&#xD;
      laparoscopic grasper used to handle the small intestine.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients undergoing a sleeve gastrectomy will serve as the control group in order to&#xD;
      determine the effect that intestinal bypass has on the measured outcomes. The sleeve&#xD;
      gastrectomy is performed laparoscopically to resect and remove approximately 80% by volume of&#xD;
      the outer portion of the stomach. At our institution, specifically the sleeve gastrectomy is&#xD;
      performed using multiple firings of a laparoscopic stapler using a bougie as an intraluminal&#xD;
      template for sizing purposes. The bougie is either 36 or 40 French per our usual practice.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2a. Sample collection preoperatively and postoperatively for metabolic and molecular studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample Collection&#xD;
&#xD;
      Samples will be collected and processed by the OneHealth Biorepository or other on site&#xD;
      research laboratory. The following samples will be collected in each patient:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Blood: will be collected at a preoperative time point then at 6 months and 12 months&#xD;
           postoperatively. The blood will be drawn by MU Health Care laboratories or associated&#xD;
           research personnel and transported by courier per standard protocol to the OneHealth&#xD;
           Biorepository or other research lab. It will be fractionated into its components and&#xD;
           plasma collected and stored at -80℃ as previously described.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Stool: Stool samples will be collected by patients at home using provided kits and&#xD;
           mailed to the OneHealth Biorepository or other affiliated research lab and stored, as&#xD;
           previously described. Samples will be aliquoted and stored at -20℃.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3a. Prospective collection of clinical data. Weight related data will be collected to&#xD;
      determine effectiveness of weight loss operations. Weight data collected will include high&#xD;
      weight when entering the weight loss surgery program, immediate preoperative weight collected&#xD;
      on day of operation and postoperative weights at 1 week, 1 month, 3 months, 6 months and 12&#xD;
      month follow-up appointments. Additional outcomes collected will include presence of diabetes&#xD;
      mellitus with glycated hemoglobin (HgbA1C) levels measured preoperatively and at 6 and 12&#xD;
      months postoperatively Remission of diabetes will be considered if the patient is off all&#xD;
      anti-diabetic medications with a normal HgbA1C. Presence of preoperative dyslipidemia will&#xD;
      also be documented to include abnormalities of LDL cholesterol, HDL cholesterol and&#xD;
      triglyceride levels. Remission of dyslipidemia will be considered if preoperative abnormal&#xD;
      levels of LDL and HDL cholesterol and triglycerides return to normal in the absence of&#xD;
      lipid-lowering agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Measure gut hormone changes after increased intestinal bypass during gastric bypass&#xD;
      Millipore Human Metabolic Hormone Magnetic Bead Panel - Metabolism Multiplex Assay will be&#xD;
      used to investigate a panel of gut hormones including GLP-1, GIP, leptin, PYY, and ghrelin.&#xD;
      Plasma from 15 patients from each group (as described above) for a total of 75 total patients&#xD;
      will be examined. Hormone levels in the plasma will be measured. Data will be analyzed both&#xD;
      for intergroup differences as well as correlation with clinical outcomes will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: miRNA profiling in patients having gastric bypass with variable intestinal bypass&#xD;
      lengths 15 patients from each group (as described above) for a total of 75 total patients&#xD;
      will be examined. Plasma will be used to perform Affymetrix miRNA arrays to measure&#xD;
      expression of all currently known miRNA. Corresponding pathways that miRNA affect will be&#xD;
      identified using publicly available databases. Differences in miRNA expression between&#xD;
      treatment groups will be compared. Differential levels of expression of miRNA will also be&#xD;
      compared to clinical outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 4: Measure variation in gut microbiome due to increased intestinal bypass during gastric&#xD;
      bypass.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Stool samples will be collected as described above. They will be stored in the OneHealth&#xD;
      Biorepository or other laboratory until processing. 15 patients from each group (as described&#xD;
      above) for a total of 75 total patients will be examined. Composition of microbiota in each&#xD;
      group will be determined as previously described. Comparison between treatment groups will be&#xD;
      performed. Correlation to clinical outcome variables will be determined&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2031</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2031</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients undergoing gastric bypass</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>Blinded to participant at time of surgery. Randomization during operation</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight loss after Variable Biliopancreatic Limb Length Bypass</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of weight loss after modifications to the length of BP limb length</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Complications after Variable Biliopancreatic Limb Length Bypass</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of weight loss after modifications to the length of BP limb length</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MicroRNA expression after Variable Biliopancreatic Limb Length Bypass</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>measurement of circulating microRNA expression in treatment groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gut microbiome changes after Variable Biliopancreatic Limb Length Bypass</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>measurement of circulating microRNA expression in treatment groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Gut enteroendocrine changes after Variable Biliopancreatic Limb Length Bypass</measure>
    <time_frame>7 years</time_frame>
    <description>measurement of circulating microRNA expression in treatment groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">750</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity, Morbid</condition>
  <condition>Metabolic Syndrome</condition>
  <condition>NASH - Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard BP limb length</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>50 cm BP limb length</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Medium BP limb length</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>100 cm BP limb length</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Long BP limb length</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>150 cm BP limb length</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>50 cm BP limb length</intervention_name>
    <description>50 cm biliopancreatic limb length</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard BP limb length</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>100 cm BP limb length</intervention_name>
    <description>100 cm biliopancreatic limb length</description>
    <arm_group_label>Medium BP limb length</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>150 cm BP limb length</intervention_name>
    <description>150 cm BP limb length</description>
    <arm_group_label>Long BP limb length</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age greater than 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index of 40-60 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Meet insurance criteria, as set forth by the patient's insurance policy, to qualify&#xD;
             for coverage for weight loss surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Planned laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willingness to have blood collected before and after surgical procedure at defined&#xD;
             points and collect and mail stool sample before operation and at defined&#xD;
             post-operative time points.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age less than 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient fails to fulfill insurance mandated criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Unwilling to be randomized to variable length to gastric bypass or unwilling to have&#xD;
             blood collected or personally collect and mail in stool sample&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unwilling to follow-up at required postoperative visits&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrew Wheeler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Missouri-Columbia, Department of Surgery</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Andrew A Wheeler, MD</last_name>
    <phone>314-708-9708</phone>
    <email>wheeleraa@health.missouri.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Sarah Brown, MBA</last_name>
    <phone>573-882-5609</phone>
    <email>brownsarah@health.missouri.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Missouri-Columbia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andrew Wheeler</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>gastric bypass</keyword>
  <keyword>intestinal bypass</keyword>
  <keyword>gut microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>microRNA</keyword>
  <keyword>enteroendocrine hormones</keyword>
  <keyword>weight recidivism</keyword>
  <keyword>biliopancreatic limb</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Metabolic Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obesity, Morbid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Weight Loss</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Only deidentified samples and clinical data with all HIPAA identifiers will be shared with any other researchers</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will only be made available on a case by case data and provided in a deidentified manner</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data must be deidentified and data must be requested from the PI listed</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

