<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04845906</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MDS-21STLOCK001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04845906</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A 7 Day Adhesive Device Wear Study to Evaluate BD StatLock™ Devices</brief_title>
  <official_title>A 7 Day Adhesive Device Wear Study to Evaluate BD StatLock™ Devices</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Becton, Dickinson and Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Becton, Dickinson and Company</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is a prospective healthy human volunteer wear study to evaluate the safety and&#xD;
      performance of the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device and the StatLock™ stabilization&#xD;
      device Accessory (Foam Strip) and to meet the design input requirements.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a healthy human wear study of a minimum of 100 study participants who will wear the&#xD;
      StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device and the StatLock™ stabilization device accessory&#xD;
      (Foam Strip). Participants will report to the research center, on Day 0 to have their skin&#xD;
      assessed by the investigator, clinician, and/or designee. On Day 0 the participants will have&#xD;
      the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Devices and the foam strip applied. There will be 4&#xD;
      separate StatLock™ devices being tested, which will be randomly applied to the participants&#xD;
      on their inner (ventral) forearms. Each participant will have 2 separate devices applied, one&#xD;
      to each arm. Those participants who have the StatLock ™ Arterial Plus, StatLock™ Dialysis II,&#xD;
      or the StatLock IV Select , will also have the Foam Strip applied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The participant will also wear a dressing over top of a StatLock™ compatible catheter, which&#xD;
      will be connected to an extension set. For this study, the catheter will not be inserted into&#xD;
      the study participant but instead will be shortened or modified and placed on the skin and&#xD;
      secured with the StatLock™ Stabilization Device. The catheter tip will be marked with&#xD;
      indelible ink, to assess for any catheter movement. The use of the catheters, extension set,&#xD;
      and the dressing represents how the device would be used in a clinical setting.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once the devices are applied the participant will have the skin assessed (using a modified&#xD;
      Draize Scale) by the investigator, clinician, and/or designee on Day 0. The participant will&#xD;
      wear the devices at home for 1 week and will return on Day 7 for a skin assessment,&#xD;
      evaluation of pad and foam strip lift, and catheter movement, evaluation of pain, and removal&#xD;
      of the devices by the investigator, clinician, and/or designee. On Day 8, there may be a&#xD;
      phone call and/or video call with the participant to review the skin condition of the site&#xD;
      where the device was removed from.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 23, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 23, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent lift of the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device Pad at Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Device pad lift will be assessed using a Visual Analog Scale, ranging from 0 - Fully adhered to 100 - Device absent. When the percent lift at day 7 is &gt;50%, it is considered a failure.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of Device Movement of the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device at Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The percent of device movement of the catheter will be assessed using a Visual Analog Scale from 0 (no movement) to 100 (completely displaced).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Ease of Removal of the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Ease of removal will be assessed using a 100 mm Visual Analog Scale where 0 is very easy to remove and 100 is very difficult to remove.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent of participants with erythema score ≥ 2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Erythema score will be assessed using a modified Draize scale with scores ranging from 0 to 3, as follows: 0 - no visible reaction; 0.5 - Doubtful or negligible erythema reaction; 1.0 - mild or just perceptible macular erythema reaction in a speckled/follicular, patchy or confluent pattern (slight pinking); 2.0 - Moderate erythema reaction in a confluent pattern (definite redness); 3 - Strong or brisk erythema reaction that may spread beyond the test site).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent lift of the Foam Strip (StatLock™ Stabilization Device Accessory) at Day 7</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The percent lift of the foam strip will be assessed using a Visual Analog Scale ranging from 0 (fully adhered) to 100 (device accessory absent).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Ease of Removal of the StatLock™ Stabilization Device Foam Strip</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>The ease of removal will be assessed using a 100 mm Visual Analog Scale where 0 is very easy to remove and 100 is very difficult to remove.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of pain upon removal of the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 7</time_frame>
    <description>Pain upon removal of the device will be assessed using a 100 mm Visual Analog Scale where 0 is no pain and 100 is unbearable pain.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization device-related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 0 to Day 8</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of device-related adverse events.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Peripheral Intravenous Catheter Stabilization</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <description>There will be 4 separate StatLock™ devices being tested, which will be randomly applied to the participants on their inner (ventral) forearms. Each participant will have 2 separate devices applied, one to each arm. Those participants who have the StatLock ™ Arterial Plus, StatLock™ Dialysis II, or the StatLock IV Select, will also have the foam strip applied.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device and the StatLock™ stabilization device accessory (Foam Strip)</intervention_name>
    <description>Each participant will have 2 separate devices applied, one to each arm, with or without a Foam Strip.The participant will also wear a dressing over top of a StatLock™ compatible catheter, which will be connected to an extension set. For this study, the catheter will not be inserted into the study participant but instead will be shortened or modified and placed on the skin and secured with the StatLock™ Stabilization Device. The use of the catheters, extension set, and the dressing represents how the device would be used in a clinical setting.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy volunteers</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>StatLock™ Pro- SLP001</other_name>
    <other_name>StatLock™ IV Select- IV0521CE</other_name>
    <other_name>StatLock™ Arterial Plus- ART0222CE</other_name>
    <other_name>StatLock™ Dialysis II- VDS2</other_name>
    <other_name>Foam Strip- SL0100 (StatLock™ Stabilization Device Accessory)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Potential participants will be recruited from healthy volunteer participant pools&#xD;
        identified and/or held by the study site(s).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any healthy human, 14 years of age or older, regardless of gender (Note: Consent of&#xD;
             guardian or parent may be required for patients who are under 18 years of age).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they provide written and informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expected to be available for observation from consent, to the application on Day 0,&#xD;
             and then removal of the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device on Day 7, and for a&#xD;
             follow up phone and/or video call on Day 8 for a skin assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant agrees to maintain a diary from device application, Day 0, through device&#xD;
             removal, Day 7.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agree to keep the StatLock™ Catheter Stabilization Device, ancillary products, and&#xD;
             site dry throughout the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Agrees to not use moisturizers, lotions, or any product labeled moisturizing for the&#xD;
             duration of the study, at or around the site where the devices will be applied (inner&#xD;
             (ventral) forearm).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If their skin was burned or scarred at the insertion site, or has any other skin&#xD;
             condition which may affect the adherence and/or interpretation of the study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  If they have a known allergy to the study products (known tape or adhesive allergy).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has a medical condition which may prevent him or her from completing the study or&#xD;
             place the study participant at undue risk.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>14 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Michael Casser, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>TKL Research, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gary Grove, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dermico, LLC</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>TKL Research, Inc</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fair Lawn</city>
        <state>New Jersey</state>
        <zip>07410</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dermico, LLC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Broomall</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19008</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

