<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04848844</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>WF163-20</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04848844</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The PAtients pResenTing With COngenital HeaRt DIseAse Register (ARTORIA-R)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ARTORIA-R</acronym>
  <official_title>The PAtients pResenTing With COngenital HeaRt DIseAse Register (ARTORIA-R): A Global Register to Investigate Factors Associated With Morbidity and Mortality in Adult Patients With Congenital Heart Disease (ACHD) on the Waiting List for Heart or Heart/Lung Transplantation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Deutsches Zentrum für Herz-Kreislauf-Forschung (DZHK)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Advances in surgical and medical care have led to improved outcomes in patients with&#xD;
      congenital heart disease (CHD). As a consequence, the majority of patients nowadays survives&#xD;
      to adulthood (adults with CHD, that is, adult CHD [ACHD]) with good quality of life. Despite&#xD;
      the surgical success, the morbidity and mortality of ACHD is higher than in the general&#xD;
      population and is linked to the development of heart failure (HF) in adulthood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HF occurs in approximately 25% of patients with ACHD, even in those patients in whom the&#xD;
      congenital mal-formation has been corrected successfully in childhood. The time course and&#xD;
      presentation are heterogeneous owing to variable congenital malformation and limitation of&#xD;
      treatment options. ACHD with an anatomic right ventricle as the systemic ventricle (e.g.,&#xD;
      atrial switch operation in patients with transposition of the great arteries [TGAs]) and&#xD;
      those with a functional single ventricle (e.g., Fontan circulation) appear to be at higher&#xD;
      risk of developing HF. Young age at initial corrective surgery-often in the ﬁrst 2 years of&#xD;
      life-and lack of speciﬁc medical therapies can contribute to a high and early demand for&#xD;
      heart transplantation in patients with ACHD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The ARTORIA-R is an international, observational research project collecting retrospective&#xD;
      data from 17 countries in the period 1989 to 2020 and will thereafter include data&#xD;
      prospectively (Figure 1). These data include patient profiles at time of evaluation for&#xD;
      listing, listing, waiting list dynamics, post-transplant data and basic donor data. Future&#xD;
      data will be updated annually in July each year and each institution willing to contribute&#xD;
      anonymised data to the register is invited to participate. Furthermore, the institutions and&#xD;
      organ allocation agencies have to obtain a positive vote of the ethic committee responsible&#xD;
      for the data transmission of anonymized patient data.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion criteria are: a. The patient has to be listed as an adult transplant candidate&#xD;
      in the country the data is obtained with an age ≥18 years b. The patient has to have a&#xD;
      congenital heart defect or an inherited cardiomyopathy (specific; hypertrophic&#xD;
      cardiomyopathy, arrhythmogenic right ventricular cardiomyopathy or non-compaction&#xD;
      cardiomyopathy) which is often included into the category ACHD c. Data is obtained from the&#xD;
      first evaluation for listing or listing for heart-only or heart-combined organ&#xD;
      transplantation d. Transfer of anonymised data e. The institution/organization agrees to the&#xD;
      memorandum how data is managed, and scientific cooperation is planned between all&#xD;
      institutions. The registry has the aim to achieve meticulous information regarding the&#xD;
      underlying congenital heart defect and the previous treatment of the patient. With these&#xD;
      information the patients can be divided into different cohorts with a systemic left&#xD;
      ventricle, a systemic right ventricle or a single ventricle (which can be either an anatomic&#xD;
      left or right ventricle). Further data is acquired regarding the medical treatment, the&#xD;
      haemodynamic evaluation of the patient, laboratory testing to assess additional organ&#xD;
      function of the kidney or liver, treatment in the intermediate care or intensive care unit.&#xD;
      As it is of special relevance in ACHD patient treatment of arrhythmia, antiarrhythmic&#xD;
      medication and use of ICD or cardiac resynchronization therapy are evaluated. Were available&#xD;
      the data regarding imaging at listing with ejection fraction for the systemic ventricle with&#xD;
      echocardiography or cardiac magnetic resonance imaging are obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The exclusion criteria is: a. The patient is listed for a second heart transplantation&#xD;
      (retransplantation) During the ongoing study additional institutions and organizations will&#xD;
      be asked to include their data as well. Although the initial data is retrospective additional&#xD;
      data into the register will be entered prospectively.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 2, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 30, 2030</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>20 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Delisting due to clinical worsening or death on the waiting list</measure>
    <time_frame>The primary outcome will be assessed at entering data into the study</time_frame>
    <description>If the patients has a clinical worsening of their status due to advanced heart failure he or she is removed from the waiting list. Patients can as well die while on the waiting list as a consquence of heart failure</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Delisting due to clinical improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>The secondary outcome will be assessed at entering data into the study</time_frame>
    <description>Patients can improve from the status at listing and can be removed from the waiting list due to clinical improvement of their clinical status</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>All-cause mortality following transplantation</measure>
    <time_frame>The patient status will be included into the study database at entry</time_frame>
    <description>When a patient was succesfully transplanted and receives follow-up visits at transplant center, the patient might have died due to various causes which is reflected by this outcome measure</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2000</enrollment>
  <condition>Congenital Heart Disease</condition>
  <condition>Heart Failure</condition>
  <condition>Transplant; Complication, Failure</condition>
  <condition>Arrythmia</condition>
  <condition>Ventricular Dysfunction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient transplanted due to ACHD and heart failure</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients successfully transplanted due to congenital heart failure.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ACHD listed due to heart failure for heart or heart and combined organ transplantation</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients on the actual waiting list for heart or heart and combined organ transplantation. They can have either outcome transplantation or the primary outcome death on the waiting list or delisting due to clinical worsening. The secondary outcome is as well delisting due to clinical improvement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ACHD evaluated for heart transplantation</arm_group_label>
    <description>All patients evaluated for heart or heart and combined organ transplantation at the hospital level</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The PAtients pResenTing with COngenital HeaRt DIseAse Register (ARTORIA-R) will collect&#xD;
        data from patients with ACHD evaluated or listed for heart or heart-combined organ&#xD;
        transplantation from 17 countries in Europe and the Asia/Pacific region. We plan&#xD;
        retrospective collection of data from 1989 - 2020 and will include patients prospectively.&#xD;
        The primary outcome is the combined endpoint of delisting due to clinical worsening or&#xD;
        death on the waiting list. The secondary outcome is delisting due to clinical improvement&#xD;
        while on the waiting list.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The patient has to be listed as an adult transplant candidate in the country the data&#xD;
             is obtained with an age ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. The patient has to have a congenital heart defect or an inherited cardiomyopathy&#xD;
             (specific; hypertrophic cardiomyopathy, arrhythmogenic right ventricular&#xD;
             cardiomyopathy or non-compaction cardiomyopathy) which is often included into the&#xD;
             category ACHD&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Data is obtained from the first evaluation for listing or listing for heart-only or&#xD;
             heart-combined organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Transfer of anonymised data&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The institution/organization agrees to the memorandum how data is managed, and&#xD;
             scientific cooperation is planned between all institutions&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        a. The patient is listed for a second heart transplantation (retransplantation)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Christoph Sinning, MF</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Heart &amp; Vascular Center Hamburg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Heart and Vascular Center Hamburg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20246</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Heart Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Defects, Congenital</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ventricular Dysfunction</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Data is shared with investigators participating in the register and provide patient data to the register</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>The data base is shared with the researchers institution on demand. The researcher will receive a password protected copy of the study data base. The data base only includes anonymized data.</ipd_time_frame>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

