<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04847011</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ExpoBiome</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04847011</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Deciphering the Impact of Exposures From the Gut Microbiome-derived Molecular Complex in Human Health and Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>ExpoBiome</acronym>
  <official_title>Deciphering the Impact of Exposures From the Gut Microbiome-derived Molecular Complex in Human Health and Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Andreas Michalsen</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Luxembourg Centre for Systems Biomedicine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Paracelsus-Elena-Klinik Kassel</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ExpoBiome project will analyze the impact of fasting on patients with Parkinsons's&#xD;
      Disease (PD) or rheumatoid arthritis (RA) on a clinical level as well as the effect of&#xD;
      fasting on their immune system and gut microbiota. ExpoBiome will combine metagenomics and&#xD;
      other &quot;omics&quot; [meta-transcriptomics, meta-proteomics and (meta-)metabolomics], bioinformatic&#xD;
      analyses and biostatistics under a systems biology framework to gain new mechanistic insights&#xD;
      into microbiome-immune system interactions in the context of chronic diseases with&#xD;
      inflammatory signatures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Besides a one time crossectional study of healthy participants, patients with RA and PD a&#xD;
      longitudinal fasting study with two arms (RA and PD) is planned.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The human gut microbiome is a complex ecosystem, which contributes essential functions to&#xD;
      human physiology. Changes to the microbiome are associated with several chronic diseases&#xD;
      characterised by inflammation, including neurodegenerative and autoimmune diseases.&#xD;
      Microbiome-derived effector molecules comprising nucleic acids, (poly)peptides and&#xD;
      metabolites are present at high levels in the gut but have so far eluded systematic study.&#xD;
      This gap in knowledge is limiting mechanistic understanding of the microbiome's functional&#xD;
      impact on chronic diseases such as Parkinson's Disease (PD) and rheumatoid arthritis (RA).&#xD;
      Here, for the first time a combination of advanced high-resolution methodologies will be&#xD;
      integrated to comprehensively identify the constituents of this molecular complex and their&#xD;
      impact on the human immune system. First, a quantitative, integrated multi-omic analysis on&#xD;
      microbiome samples collected from healthy individuals and patients with newly diagnosed PD or&#xD;
      RA will be performes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Using contextualised prior knowledge (ExpoBiome Map) and machine learning methods, we will&#xD;
      identify microbial molecules associated with condition-specific immunophenotypes. Second, the&#xD;
      biomarker signature during a model clinical intervention (therapeutic fasting) will be&#xD;
      validated and tracked to predict treatment outcomes. Third, microbes and molecules will be&#xD;
      screened in personalised HuMiX gut-on-chip models to identify novel anti-inflammatory&#xD;
      compounds. By providing mechanistic insights into the molecular basis of human-microbiome&#xD;
      interactions, the project will generate essential new knowledge about causal relationships&#xD;
      between the gut microbiome and the immune system in health and disease. By facilitating the&#xD;
      elucidation of currently unknown microbiome-derived molecules, it will identify new genes,&#xD;
      proteins,metabolites and host pathways for the development of future diagnostic and&#xD;
      therapeutic applications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 21, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Gut microbiota Characterization</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Molecular typing of the gut microbiota using sequencing and high-throughput analysis from stool samples (metagenomics, metatranscriptomics, metaproteomics, metabolomics)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resting blood pressure</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Heart rate</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Abdominal circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Waist to Hip Ratio</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index (kg/m2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Disease Activity Score 28 (DAS-28-CRP)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in the DAS-28-CRP, range from 2.0 to 10.0 while higher values meaning a higher disease activity and below of 2.6 meaning remission</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Assessement Questionnaire (HAQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in the HAQ, range from 0 to 3 while higher values meaning a higher grade of disability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Simplified Disease Activity Index Score (SDAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in the SDAI, range from 0 to 86 with assumed range from 0.1 to 10mg/dL for CRP. Higher values mean a higher disease activity and below of 34 meaning remission.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hannover Functional Ability Questionnaire (Funktionsfragebogen Hannover, FFbH-R)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in the FFbH-R, range from 0 to 100 % while higher values meaning a higher grade of functional capacity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>MDS-UPDRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Movement Disorders Society-sponsored revision of the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale part I, II, IV (MDS-UPDRS part I, II, IV). Total score range: 0-260 (including the MDS-UPDRS part III), including 4 subcategories. Subcategories are summed to compute the total score. A lower score means a better outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parkinson's Disease Sleep Scale-2 (PDSS-2)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Parkinson's Disease Sleep Scale 2 (PDSS-2) is designed to assess nocturnal disability in Parkinson's disease. The PDSS-2 is a 15 question analog scale that ranks answers from 0 - 4, with 4 being worse. (Question 1 is an exception, where 4 is better and 0 is worse). In addition to an overall assessment of sleep disability three aspects of sleep problems can be obtained; disturbed sleep (total of questions 1-3, 8 and 14), PD-specific nocturnal motor symptoms (total of questions 4-6, 12 and 13), and PD-specific nocturnal symptoms (Total of questions 7, 9-11 and 15).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire-39 (PDQ-39)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The 39 question Parkinson's Disease Questionnaire (PDQ-39) is a patient-reported rating scale for quality of life in Parkinson's disease. Respondents affirm if they have experienced problems due to their disease using a five point scale from never (0 points) to always (4 points, or worse) in doing common activities. The PDQ-39 is comprised of 8 domains: mobility, emotion, activities of daily living, cognition, stigma, social support, communication, bodily discomfort. Total possible range of scores = 0 - 156, with higher scores representing worse severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non-motor symptoms questionnaire (NMSQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The non-motor symptoms (NMS) questionnaire can be given to people affected by Parkinson's in order to aid health and social care professionals to assess their non-motor symptoms.The non-motor symptoms questionnaire is a 30-point, patient-based questionnaire used to determine the non-motor symptoms experienced by the patient during the past month. The points should be totalled to give a score out of 30. A score of under 10 is mild, 10-20 moderate and over 20, severe.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Non Motor Symptoms Scale (NMSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Non-Motor Symptoms Scale (NMSS) measures the frequency and severity of a range of non-motor symptoms in Parkinson's Disease, through 30 questions grouped into 9 domains: cardiovascular, sleep/fatigue, mood/cognition, perceptual problems/hallucinations, attention/memory, gastro-intestinal tract, urinary, sexual function, and miscellaneous (pain, taste/smell, weight change, excessive sweating). Severity is rated on a scale from 0 (none) to 3 (severe). Frequency is rated on a scale from 1 (rarely) to 4 (very frequent). Item scores are calculated as the product of severity and frequency; the total score is obtained by summing the item scores. The NMSS total score ranges from 0 to 360 with a lower score indicating fewer symptoms. A negative change from baseline indicates improvement in symptoms (reduced score).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stress questionnaire (Cohen Perceived Stress Scale, CPSS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in the CPSS, range from 0 to 4 in each item. Scores are obtained by reversing responses (e.g., 0 = 4, 1 = 3, 2 = 2, 3 = 1 &amp; 4 = 0) to the positively stated items and then summing across all scale items, higher values meaning a higher grade of perceived stress.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of Life questionnaire (WHO-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in the WHO-5, range from 0 to 100 %, higher values meaning a higher grade of well-being</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessing full scale, range 0-42, lower score meaning a better outcome</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mood questionnaire (Profile of Mood States, POMS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Change from Baseline in Emotional Distress will be measured using the German Version of the Profile of Mood States (ASTS) short version (19 items, 7-point Likert scale; 0=not at all, 6=extremely). Lower scores indicate more stable mood profiles.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sociodemographic Measurements</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Age, gender, education level, household income, employment status, marital status, language spoken, complete family history, current and previous illness and co-morbidities, and current medications</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavioral Factors</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Physical inactivity, coffee, health promoting activities via Likert Scales, range from 0 to 5 while higher values meaning a higher grade of agreement</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dietary Behaviour</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Modified FFQ recording dietary behaviour such as mealtimes, frequency of food intake, food preferences, fasting experiences</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavioral Factors: alcohol consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Number of alcoholic beverages on average per week in the last month</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Behavioral Factors: smoking</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Smoking status in packyears</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Expectation questions</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>For fasting on a 5-point likert scale from 1 (nothing at all) to 5 (very strong)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differential blood count</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hepatic transaminases (GPT, GOT) and Gamma glutamyl transpeptidase (y-GT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>GPT in units per liter (U/L) GOT (U/L) y-GT (U/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Bilirubine (total, direct, indirect in mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total protein in grams per liter (g/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Albumine in grams per liter (g/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Creatinine in µmol per liter (µmol/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) in milliliter per minute (mL/min)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Alcalic Phosphatase in units per liter (U/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Urea in milligrams per deciliter (mg/dL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Blood lipids and fasting glucose</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>triglycerides (mmol/L)&#xD;
total cholesterol (mmol/L)&#xD;
LDL (mmol/L)&#xD;
HDL (mmol/L)&#xD;
fasting glucose (mmol/L)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1C (mmol/mol Hb, %)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>TSH (mU/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>IGF-1 (ng/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Insulin (mU/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>High sensitive CrP (mg/L)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate change in hs-CrP levels in participants with RA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rheumatoid factor (RF, IgM) (U/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate RF status in participants with RA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anti-cyclic citrullinated peptide (ACPA) (U/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluate change in ACPA levels in participants with RA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Zonulin (ng/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatty acid binding protein 2 (FABP2) (pg/mL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma Calprotectin (µg/g)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fecal Calprotectin (µg/g)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Phenotyping of immune cells</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determination of cytometric parameters that indicate changes in cell activation or quantitative changes in the absolute and/or relative size of subpopulations (e.g. classical/intermediate/non-classical monocytes, naïve and memory T-cells, B-cell differentiation to plasmablasts/-cells) Gene expression analysis of immune cells with Affymetrix whole genome microarrays and RNAseq to search for transcriptional patterns and markers that help to identify relevant immune cell (sub-)populations, which are not yet included in the cytometric phenotyping screen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Urine metabolomics (10 ml midstream urine)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Oral microbiota analysis in saliva</measure>
    <time_frame>Change over baseline to 12 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>5</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">180</enrollment>
  <condition>Rheumatoid Arthritis</condition>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RA - longitudinal arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PD - longitudinal arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>RA - crosssectional arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>PD - crossectional arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy controls - crosssectional arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fasting</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients undergo a 5-10 day fasting period with a dietary energy supply 350-400kcal per day with fruit and vegetable juices or, if not feasible, an established fasting-mimicking diet of 600-800 kcal according to Longo et al.</description>
    <arm_group_label>PD - longitudinal arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>RA - longitudinal arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  One of the following diagnoses: rheumatoid arthritis (first diagnosis &gt;6 weeks ago and&#xD;
             &lt;8 years), parkinson's disease OR healthy volunteer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Control (&quot;healthy&quot;) individuals must be without any evidence of active, known or&#xD;
             treated RA, without any evidence of active, known or treated central nervous system&#xD;
             disease, and without a known family history of idiopathic PD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arthritis in at least one joint&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Control individuals should match the RA or PD individuals as closely as possible,&#xD;
             especially their age, sex, and education&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Present written declaration of consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consent to specimen collection and specimen use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand the patient information and willingness to sign the consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  gout or proven bacterial arthritis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Psychiatric illness that limits understanding of the examination protocol (unable to&#xD;
             consent)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &lt; 18.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pre-existing/current eating disorders (bulimia nervosa, anorexia nervosa) within the&#xD;
             past 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe internal diseases (e.g. renal insufficiency with creatinine &gt; 2mg/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Existing vegan diet or fasting within the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Chronic inflammatory bowel disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of antibiotics within the past 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of anemia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>79 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andreas Michalsen, Prof. Dr. med.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Charite - Universitätsmedizin Berlin</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Etienne Hanslian, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+49 30 80505682</phone>
    <email>etienne.hanslian@charite.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Paracelsus-Elena-Klinik Kassel</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kassel</city>
        <state>Hessen</state>
        <zip>34128</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Schade, Dr.</last_name>
      <phone>+4956160090</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Brit Mollenhauer, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Charité Hochschulambulanz für Naturheilkunde am Immanuel Krankenhaus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Berlin</city>
        <zip>14109</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Nadine Sylvester, Study Nurse</last_name>
      <phone>+49 30 80505682</phone>
      <email>nadine.sylvester@immanuelalbertinen.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Andreas Michalsen, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Charite University, Berlin, Germany</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Andreas Michalsen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof. Dr. med.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>It is not yet known if there will be a plan to make IPD available.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

