<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04842864</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2021-12857</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04842864</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Time Course for Fasting-induced Autophagy in Humans</brief_title>
  <official_title>Time Course for Fasting-induced Autophagy in Humans</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Montefiore Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Glenn Foundation for Medical Research</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Montefiore Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Autophagy, which involves the degradation of aged or damaged cellular components, has been&#xD;
      shown to extend healthspan and lifespan in multiple organisms, including flies, worms, and&#xD;
      mice. Research has also demonstrated that autophagy declines with age in these simpler&#xD;
      experimental models. However, human studies are lacking. Our study seeks to determine whether&#xD;
      fasting, a robust stimulus of autophagy, upregulates autophagy in humans, and whether&#xD;
      autophagy is reduced in healthy older people compared to healthy younger individuals.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Autophagy is a cellular quality control pathway that degrades aged or damaged organelles and&#xD;
      protein aggregates within lysosomes. By doing so, autophagy provides an alternate source of&#xD;
      energy for cells to cope with adverse conditions. The level of autophagy determines the&#xD;
      degree to which aged cells are able to eliminate damaged organelles and/or toxic aggregates&#xD;
      and mount a protective response against stress. At the physiological level, nutrient&#xD;
      deprivation or fasting is one of the most robust stimuli for autophagy across diverse&#xD;
      experimental systems.1 Our lab has shown important roles for autophagy in lipid/glucose&#xD;
      homeostasis and regulation of energy balance. We have found that autophagy degrades cellular&#xD;
      lipid stores via a process we described as lipophagy. We have also shown contributions of&#xD;
      autophagy to the regulation of feeding as well as its developmental roles in maintenance of&#xD;
      muscle and fat mass. In addition to these physiological functions, a number of studies have&#xD;
      revealed that mice lacking autophagy in the central nervous system show rapid onset of&#xD;
      neurodegeneration and an early death.2,3 These studies support a central role of autophagy in&#xD;
      the maintenance of healthspan.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is well-established that autophagy activity declines with age, which has led to the&#xD;
      hypothesis that autophagy failure contributes to the metabolic syndrome of aging. In fact,&#xD;
      young mice with tissue-specific knockout of the autophagy gene Atg7 display features of&#xD;
      aging, including loss of muscle mass (mimicking sarcopenia of aging), fatty liver, decreased&#xD;
      adipose lipolysis, de-differentiation of brown fat, and pancreatic β-cell dysfunction.4-6&#xD;
      Conversely, restoration of autophagy via pharmacological or genetic approaches prevents&#xD;
      age-associated decline in cell function and improves stress response-thus directly extending&#xD;
      healthspan. As a consequence, there is great interest in developing new experimental&#xD;
      approaches to prevent age-associated chronic diseases. In fact, caloric restriction (CR) has&#xD;
      been shown to stimulate autophagy and extend lifespan and healthspan in multiple experimental&#xD;
      models. While these CR studies were carried out in simpler organisms, such as flies, worms,&#xD;
      and mice,7-9 similar studies in humans are largely lacking. Since autophagy is activated by&#xD;
      starvation, the prevailing hypothesis is that caloric restriction (CR) or more physiological&#xD;
      approaches such as intermittent fasting will stimulate autophagy in humans, which in turn&#xD;
      will prevent or retard the onset of age-associated chronic diseases. There is limited&#xD;
      knowledge if indeed extended periods of fasting will activate autophagy in humans. In&#xD;
      addition, we do not know what duration of fasting may be required to stimulate autophagy in&#xD;
      humans. Finally, we do not know if, nor by how much, fasting-induced autophagy is reduced in&#xD;
      aging humans. Due to the aforementioned gaps in our knowledge regarding autophagy in humans,&#xD;
      in this study we will test the ability of extended periods of restriction to food to&#xD;
      stimulate autophagy in healthy, young individuals. Further, we will compare the extent to&#xD;
      which autophagy is reduced in healthy older subjects, when compared to those observed in&#xD;
      young controls. In our study, we will be using samples of adipose tissue, a metabolically&#xD;
      active endocrine organ, and peripheral blood cells, which have both been evaluated in prior&#xD;
      autophagy studies and can be obtained in a less invasive manner.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Autophagy flux</measure>
    <time_frame>23 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The turnover rate of the autophagosome marker LC3-II will be assessed. LC3-II flux will be performed in freshly isolated fat tissues and in PBMCs at various timepoints. Freshly collected fat tissue explants and PBMCs will be incubated in dishes with high-glucose culture medium (DMEM) in the presence or absence of lysosomal inhibitors (Lys Inh), leupeptin (200uM) and ammonium chloride (20uM) at 37°C, 5% CO2 for 4 hours. Fat explants and scraped PMBC pellets will then be homogenized in a buffer containing protease and phosphatase inhibitors and subjected to immunoblotting for LC3. Autophagy flux will be determined by subtracting the densitometric value of LC3-II in Lys Inh-untreated samples from the Lys Inh-treated samples.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of ketone bodies</measure>
    <time_frame>23 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Levels of ketones in the plasma will be assessed with blood draws at various timepoints.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Fasting</condition>
  <condition>Autophagy</condition>
  <condition>Aging Well</condition>
  <condition>Ketosis, Metabolic</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Young</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>10 healthy men and women 18-35 yo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Older adults</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>10 healthy men and women 65-85 yo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fasting</intervention_name>
    <description>23 hours fasting</description>
    <arm_group_label>Older adults</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Young</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy men and women 18-35 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Healthy men and women 65-85 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serious acute/chronic illness (e.g., active cancer, inflammatory states, RA, SLE, or a&#xD;
             CVD event within past 6 months)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diabetes or pre-diabetes with an A1c &gt;6.0%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BMI &gt;30 kg/m2 or &lt;20 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  eGFR &lt;45 ml/min&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ALT &gt;3x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hct &lt;35 or Hb &lt;10&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exclusionary meds: calcium channel blockers, anticonvulsants or other drugs shown to&#xD;
             affect autophagy (see table below)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Food allergy or known food intolerance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active Smoking (&gt;1 cigarette or cigar per week)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of recreational drugs (opioids, cocaine, marijuana, etc.) in past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of alcohol on the day prior to and the day of study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Shift workers or other dysregulated sleep pattern (habitual use of sleep medications,&#xD;
             jet lag, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Strenuous exercise within 3 days prior to study visit 2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition the investigator believes would impair the ability to interpret targeted&#xD;
             outcomes&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jill Crandall, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Nir Barzilai, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Montefiore Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rajat Singh, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Albert Einstein College of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jill Crandall, MD</last_name>
    <phone>718-430-3765</phone>
    <email>Jill.crandall@einsteinmed.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 6, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

