<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04845243</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EmoRecTraining_EVA</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04845243</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of a Short Computer-based Emotion Recognition Training in Different Patient Groups</brief_title>
  <official_title>Compared Effectiveness of a Short Computer-based Emotion Recognition Training in Conduct Disorder and Autistic Spectrum Disorder Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Prof. Christina Stadler</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University Psychiatric Clinics Basel</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Emotion recognition and regulation are necessary skills for social interaction. Disrupted&#xD;
      development of these processes severely interferes with socio-emotional development. These&#xD;
      difficulties are commonly reported in patients with Autistic Spectrum Disorder (ASD) or&#xD;
      Conduct Disorder (CD), with the subsequent social/interpersonal difficulties. The available&#xD;
      evidence suggest that impaired emotion regulation processes might underlie the aggressive&#xD;
      behaviours frequently observed in both disorders. However, no study has yet investigated the&#xD;
      presence of disorder-specific characteristics on emotion processing between these two&#xD;
      disorders. Different impaired emotion recognition difficulties may underlie the reported&#xD;
      emotion dysregulation. A practical implication of this is that given that both disorders have&#xD;
      shown difficulties during emotion recognition processes, a short, computer-based intervention&#xD;
      to improve emotion recognition might benefit both cases, even though their aetiologies might&#xD;
      differ.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      For ASD patients, studies training facial emotion recognition have focused on increasing the&#xD;
      active attention to the eye region, re-directing attention to facial features to facilitate&#xD;
      facial emotion recognition. Evidence shows positive results using computer-based emotion&#xD;
      recognition training programs with young children and adolescents with ASD. It has also been&#xD;
      recently suggested that emotion recognition training may be a suitable intervention for&#xD;
      patients with CD. This would be supported by some preliminary evidence in patients with&#xD;
      severe behavioural problems, young offenders and patients with CD + CU Traits. The overall&#xD;
      goal of this project is to investigate the compared impact of an emotion recognition training&#xD;
      in patients with ASD or CD. This goal can be subdivided into three separate subgoals: a)&#xD;
      identify whether the training program is effective; b) identify whether the training program&#xD;
      has differentiated or comparable effects between both patients groups and c) investigate&#xD;
      individual characteristics that may help identify those individuals who would benefit most&#xD;
      from the intervention. This information is crucial to inform the design of more efficient&#xD;
      treatments to differentially address the specific deficits associated to the disorders.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 15, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Participants will receive six sessions (duration approx. 1h/session) of the software-based training program &quot;Emotionen Verstehen und Ausdr端cken&quot; (EVA; Moebert &amp; Lucke, 2019). Sessions will be administered 2-3 times/week depending on the participants' time availability. In order to objectively identify the potential benefit of the training for each participant, they will perform two separate tasks before and after the emotion recognition training, the Geneva Emotion Recognition test (GERT; Schlegel, Grandjean,&amp; Scherer, 2014) and a social decision-making task. A comparison of their performance pre- and post-training is taken as an indicator of improvement in emotion recognition skills.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in performance accuracy in Geneva Emotion Recognition Test (GERT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in performance before and after the emotion recognition training, after 1 month (pre/post measure)</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of accuracy to stimuli showing facial emotions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in performance response times in Geneva Emotion Recognition Test (GERT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in performance before and after the emotion recognition training, after 1 month (pre/post measure)</time_frame>
    <description>Response times to stimuli showing facial emotions</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in performance reaction times in Social decision-making task</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in Performance before and after the emotion recognition training, after 1 month (pre/post measure)</time_frame>
    <description>Reaction times for each of the facial emotions shown</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in choices in Social decision-making task</measure>
    <time_frame>Change in choices before and after the emotion recognition training, after 1 month (pre/post measure)</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of choices that maximise their self-gain for each of the facial emotions shown</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Autism Spectrum Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Conduct Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Emotion recognition training</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>All participants have to complete the online emotion recognition training E.V.A. as well as the pre- and post training tasks: GERT and social decision making task.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Emotionen Verstehen und Ausdr端cken (E.V.A.)</intervention_name>
    <description>The online training is focused on the strengthening of socioemotional competences and consists of different training tasks (up to 3 million) presented to the participant as mini games. These training tasks are specifically designed according to empirical findings to match the socio-emotional recognition needs of people with ASD. During these games, an adapted Elo-Algorithm allows to automatically evaluate the participants' performance and adapts the difficulty levels throughout the users' progress in the training.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Emotion recognition training</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis: ASD or CD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  German speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IQ &gt; 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age: 10-18&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Comorbid Anxiety or Depressive disorder diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IQ &lt; 70&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Insufficient German language skills&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe developmental disorders&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christina Stadler, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>+41 61 325 51 11</phone>
    <email>Christina.stadler@upk.ch</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ana Cubillo, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+41 61 325 80 33</phone>
    <email>Ana.cubillo@upk.ch</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ahmed SP, Bittencourt-Hewitt A, Sebastian CL. Neurocognitive bases of emotion regulation development in adolescence. Dev Cogn Neurosci. 2015 Oct;15:11-25. doi: 10.1016/j.dcn.2015.07.006. Epub 2015 Jul 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26340451</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Blakemore SJ. The social brain in adolescence. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2008 Apr;9(4):267-77. doi: 10.1038/nrn2353. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18354399</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Somerville LH, Casey BJ. Developmental neurobiology of cognitive control and motivational systems. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2010 Apr;20(2):236-41. doi: 10.1016/j.conb.2010.01.006. Epub 2010 Feb 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20167473</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tanaka JW, Sung A. The &quot;Eye Avoidance&quot; Hypothesis of Autism Face Processing. J Autism Dev Disord. 2016 May;46(5):1538-52. doi: 10.1007/s10803-013-1976-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24150885</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wieckowski AT, White SW. Attention Modification to Attenuate Facial Emotion Recognition Deficits in Children with Autism: A Pilot Study. J Autism Dev Disord. 2020 Jan;50(1):30-41. doi: 10.1007/s10803-019-04223-6.</citation>
    <PMID>31520245</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ramdoss S, Machalicek W, Rispoli M, Mulloy A, Lang R, O'Reilly M. Computer-based interventions to improve social and emotional skills in individuals with autism spectrum disorders: a systematic review. Dev Neurorehabil. 2012;15(2):119-35. doi: 10.3109/17518423.2011.651655. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22494084</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kouo JL, Egel AL. The Effectiveness of Interventions in Teaching Emotion Recognition to Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder. Rev J Autism Dev Disord. 2016 Sep;3(3):254-65.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Silver M, Oakes P. Evaluation of a new computer intervention to teach people with autism or Asperger syndrome to recognize and predict emotions in others. Autism. 2001 Sep;5(3):299-316.</citation>
    <PMID>11708589</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zoerner D, Schutze J, Kirst S, Dziobek I, Lucke U. Zirkus Empathico: Mobile Training of Socio-Emotional Competences for Children with Autism. In: 2016 IEEE 16th International Conference on Advanced Learning Technologies (ICALT) [Internet]. Austin, TX, USA: IEEE; 2016 [cited 2021 Feb 10]. p. 448-52. Available from: http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7757020/</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hunnikin LM, van Goozen SHM. How can we use knowledge about the neurobiology of emotion recognition in practice? Journal of Criminal Justice. 2019 Nov;65:101537.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cooper S, Hobson CW, van Goozen SH. Facial emotion recognition in children with externalising behaviours: A systematic review. Clin Child Psychol Psychiatry. 2020 Oct;25(4):1068-1085. doi: 10.1177/1359104520945390. Epub 2020 Jul 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32713184</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wells AE, Hunnikin LM, Ash DP, van Goozen SHM. Improving emotion recognition is associated with subsequent mental health and well-being in children with severe behavioural problems. Eur Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2020 Sep 30. doi: 10.1007/s00787-020-01652-y. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32997168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dadds MR, Cauchi AJ, Wimalaweera S, Hawes DJ, Brennan J. Outcomes, moderators, and mediators of empathic-emotion recognition training for complex conduct problems in childhood. Psychiatry Res. 2012 Oct 30;199(3):201-7. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2012.04.033. Epub 2012 Jun 15.</citation>
    <PMID>22703720</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hubble K, Bowen KL, Moore SC, van Goozen SH. Improving Negative Emotion Recognition in Young Offenders Reduces Subsequent Crime. PLoS One. 2015 Jun 29;10(6):e0132035. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0132035. eCollection 2015.</citation>
    <PMID>26121148</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moebert, T. &amp; Lucke, U., (2019). E.V.A. - Emotionen Verstehen und Ausdr端cken. In: Pinkwart, N. &amp; Konert, J. (Hrsg.), DELFI 2019. Bonn: Gesellschaft f端r Informatik e.V.. (S. 289-290). DOI: 10.18420/delfi2019_324</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schlegel K, Grandjean D, Scherer KR. Introducing the Geneva emotion recognition test: an example of Rasch-based test development. Psychol Assess. 2014 Jun;26(2):666-72. doi: 10.1037/a0035246. Epub 2013 Dec 2.</citation>
    <PMID>24295238</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University Psychiatric Clinics Basel</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prof. Christina Stadler</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head Psychologist, Clinical Professor, Clinic for Children and Adolescents</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Autism Spectrum Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Emotion recognition training</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Conduct Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

