<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04845295</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2316/19-2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04845295</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Resistance Training Effects on Muscle Morphological, Mechanical and Contractile Properties</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effects of Resistance Training on Skeletal Muscle Morphological, Mechanical and Contractile Properties</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Belgrade</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Belgrade</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the research project is to investigate the influence of resistance-training&#xD;
      prescription (repetition duration, time under tension and training volume) and sex have on&#xD;
      morpho-functional adaptations of upper and lower-body skeletal muscles. Twenty-four male and&#xD;
      female university students were randomly assigned to one of two experimental groups, based on&#xD;
      the repetition duration : &quot;fast&quot; group (with 1 second for eccentric and concentric phase) and&#xD;
      &quot;slow&quot; group with prolonged duration of eccentric contraction (4 seconds for eccentric and 1&#xD;
      second concentric phase). At baseline and final measurement, cross-section area,&#xD;
      one-repetition maximum and tensiomyography parameters (contraction time - Tc and radial&#xD;
      displacement - Dm) of elbow flexors (biceps brachii) and knee extensors (4 quadriceps&#xD;
      muscles) were evaluated.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Isotonic resistance training has been widely applied in sport and exercise. Design of&#xD;
      resistance training programs depends on numerous training variables, such as intensity,&#xD;
      volume, time under tension (TUT), repetition duration (tempo), etc. It has been shown that&#xD;
      manipulation of repetition duration affects TUT and training volume, which in turn could&#xD;
      results in distinct morphological and contractile adaptative response of skeletal muscle. The&#xD;
      aim of the research was three-fold: i) to compare two different tempos of resistance&#xD;
      exercise, which differ in the duration of eccentric phase on hypertrophy, strength and&#xD;
      contractile properties of the elbow flexors and knee extensors muscles, ii) to compare&#xD;
      sex-specific adaptations in hypertrophy, strength and contractile properties of the elbow&#xD;
      flexors and knee extensors muscles produced by training intervention, iii) to investigate&#xD;
      potential cause-and-effect association between changes in size, strength and contractile&#xD;
      properties of the tested muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The subjects were assigned to two experimental groups, based on the duration of the eccentric&#xD;
      muscle contraction in resistance training. All participants were fully informed about&#xD;
      experimental procedures and potential risks and they signed written informed consent prior to&#xD;
      participation in the study. The training intervention was performed twice per week for a&#xD;
      7-week period. Before training intervention, a 2-week familiarization period was conducted.&#xD;
      Elbow flexor and knee extensors muscle dimensions and strength were assessed 2 days before&#xD;
      and after training intervention, while contractile properties were evaluated 5 days before&#xD;
      and after experiment. The number of repetitions, training volume (number of repetitions x&#xD;
      number of series), and TUT were recorded after first session of training intervention for&#xD;
      both groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Muscle strength was assessed by one-repetition maximum test (1RM) for two exercises: elbow&#xD;
      flexion on Scott's bench and parallel barbell squat. Each participant had 5 attempts to lift&#xD;
      the maximum weight with pauses between trials of 3 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Muscles cross-section area (CSA) were evaluated by ultrasonic device (Siemens Antares,&#xD;
      Erlangen, Germany), using the 2D ellipse diagnostic method with variable high frequency&#xD;
      transducer (from 7 MHz to 13 MHz), for 5 muscles: elbow flexor (biceps brachii) and 4 knee&#xD;
      extensors (rectus femoris , vastus intermedius, vastus medialis, vastus lateralis). The&#xD;
      measurements were performed while the subjects seated with their elbows and knees extended&#xD;
      and relaxed. The biceps brachii CSA was measured at two-thirds of the distance from the&#xD;
      acromion to the antecubital crease. CSA of rectus femoris was measured at the height of&#xD;
      proximal section of its distal third, above musculoskeletal joint. CSA of vastus intermedius&#xD;
      and vastus medialis were measured at the height of distal part right above the patella. The&#xD;
      visible part of vastus lateralis was measured at the distal third directly above the patella,&#xD;
      under rectus femoris level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The contractile properties of biceps brachii, rectus femoris and vastus lateralis muscles&#xD;
      were evaluated by tensiomyography according to the manufacturer's instructions (TMG-Science&#xD;
      for Body Evaluation, Ljubljana, Slovenia). The values of contraction time (Tc) and radial&#xD;
      deformation (Dm) were taken for analysis. The biceps brachii testing was performed while&#xD;
      subjects were in a sitting position with the dominant arm bent at 90°. During the assessment&#xD;
      of the knee extensors subjects were lying on the back, where dominant leg was placed on the&#xD;
      support, forming a knee angle of 120°. Subjects were asked to perform a voluntary&#xD;
      contraction, in order to mark the point of placement of the TMG sensor by the palpation&#xD;
      method. Two self-adhesive electrodes (Pals Platinum, model 895220 with multi-stick gel,&#xD;
      AxelGaard Manufacturing Co. Ltd) were placed proximal and distal at 3 cm from the marked&#xD;
      point, emitting an electrical impulse. A sensor (GK40, Panoptik d.o.o., Ljubljana, Slovenia)&#xD;
      was placed between the electrodes to detect muscle changes initiated by electrical&#xD;
      stimulation. The initial impulse was 25 milliamperes (mA) and it increased proportionally by&#xD;
      10 mA, until the maximum (muscle no longer responds to electrical stimulus).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Both experimental groups performed two exercises to target elbow flexor and knee extensor&#xD;
      muscles: biceps curl on a Scott bench and parallel barbell squat, respectively. All sessions&#xD;
      were performed at the same time (13-15 h), with a minimum 48 h rest between sessions on the&#xD;
      same days during the week. For both groups, the intensity of load (1RM%) and number of sets&#xD;
      were as follows: in the first three weeks the subjects exercises with ̴ 60% of 1RM in 3 sets,&#xD;
      while during the next four weeks the load was set at ̴ 70% of 1RM in 4 sets. The difference&#xD;
      in training protocols was in the duration of the eccentric phase, where one group performed&#xD;
      training with a tempo of 1 seconds for eccentric and concentric phase, while for other group&#xD;
      tempo was 4 seconds for eccentric and 1 seconds for concentric phase. All repetitions were&#xD;
      performed until muscular failure. The pause between sets was 2 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Prior to analysis data were checked for normality and that the relevant assumptions for each&#xD;
      test were met. Differences in the training volume and the TUT between the groups were&#xD;
      determined by an independent t-test. One-way ANCOVA (using baseline values as covariates) was&#xD;
      used to examine differences in changes of CSA, 1RM and TMG parameters between the groups. If&#xD;
      ANCOVA showed statistical significance, the bonferroni post-hoc test was used for further&#xD;
      estimation of differences between groups. Additionally, using sex as between-group factor and&#xD;
      baseline values as covariates, ANCOVA was used to determine possible differences between&#xD;
      males and females in changes of morphological, mechanical and contractile variables. Relative&#xD;
      changes for each variable was derived from Pre to Post change in percentage, and for each&#xD;
      participant. Pearson's correlation coefficient was used to examine the association between&#xD;
      relative pre-to-post changes of CSA, 1RM and TMG for tested muscles. Data were reported as&#xD;
      mean ± standard deviation. The level of significance was set at p &lt; 0.05. The program used&#xD;
      for statistical analysis was Statistical Package for Social Sciences (IBM SPSS Statistics),&#xD;
      version 20.0.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 7, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 7, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>muscle hypertrophy</measure>
    <time_frame>7 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>cross-section area assessment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>muscle strength changes</measure>
    <time_frame>7 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>one-repetition maximum assessment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>contractile properties changes</measure>
    <time_frame>7 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>TMG assessment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">24</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypertrophy</condition>
  <condition>Contraction</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Fast Tempo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Performed training intervention with a tempo of 1 second for eccentric and 1 second for concentric phase</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Slow Tempo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Performed training intervention with a tempo of 4 seconds for eccentric and 1 second for concentric phase</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>resistance training</intervention_name>
    <description>Both experimental groups performed two exercises to target elbow flexor and knee extensor muscles: biceps curl on a Scott bench and parallel barbell squat, respectively. All sessions were performed at the same time (13-15 h), with a minimum 48 h rest between sessions on the same days during the week. For both groups, the intensity of load (1RM%) and number of sets were as follows: in the first three weeks the subjects exercises with ̴ 60% of 1RM in 3 sets, while during the next four weeks the load was set at ̴ 70% of 1RM in 4 sets. All repetitions were performed until muscular failure. The pause between sets was 2 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Fast Tempo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Slow Tempo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  without resistance training participation in past 8 months&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of upper or lower body musculoskeletal injuries&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vladimir Ilic</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Faculty of Sport and Physical Education, University of Belgrade</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of Sport and Physical Education</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belgrade</city>
        <zip>11000</zip>
        <country>Serbia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Serbia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hackett DA, Davies TB, Orr R, Kuang K, Halaki M. Effect of movement velocity during resistance training on muscle-specific hypertrophy: A systematic review. Eur J Sport Sci. 2018 May;18(4):473-482. doi: 10.1080/17461391.2018.1434563. Epub 2018 Feb 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29431597</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schoenfeld BJ. The mechanisms of muscle hypertrophy and their application to resistance training. J Strength Cond Res. 2010 Oct;24(10):2857-72. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e3181e840f3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>20847704</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Davies TB, Kuang K, Orr R, Halaki M, Hackett D. Effect of Movement Velocity During Resistance Training on Dynamic Muscular Strength: A Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis. Sports Med. 2017 Aug;47(8):1603-1617. doi: 10.1007/s40279-017-0676-4. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28105573</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pisot R, Narici MV, Simunic B, De Boer M, Seynnes O, Jurdana M, Biolo G, Mekjavić IB. Whole muscle contractile parameters and thickness loss during 35-day bed rest. Eur J Appl Physiol. 2008 Sep;104(2):409-14. doi: 10.1007/s00421-008-0698-6. Epub 2008 Feb 23.</citation>
    <PMID>18297302</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pryor RR, Sforzo GA, King DL. Optimizing power output by varying repetition tempo. J Strength Cond Res. 2011 Nov;25(11):3029-34. doi: 10.1519/JSC.0b013e31820f50cb.</citation>
    <PMID>21881531</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 14, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Belgrade</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vladimir Ilic</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypertrophy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

