<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04843904</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-415</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04843904</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Safe Accelerated Venetoclax Escalation in CLL</brief_title>
  <acronym>SAVE</acronym>
  <official_title>SAVE (Safe Accelerated Venetoclax Escalation): A Phase Ib Study of Venetoclax Monotherapy With Accelerated Dose Ramp-up in Patients With CLL</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This research study is trying to determine which patients with newly diagnosed or&#xD;
      relapsed/refractory chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) or small lymphocytic lymphoma (SLL),&#xD;
      as grouped by their risk for tumor lysis syndrome (TLS), are able to safely tolerate an&#xD;
      accelerated, daily venetoclax dose ramp-up rather than the standard approved schedule (5-week&#xD;
      dose ramp-up).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The name of the study drug involved in this study is:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Venetoclax&#xD;
&#xD;
      The following drugs may also be included in some participants treatment regimen:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Obinutuzumab&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Rituximab&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is an open label phase Ib study of an accelerated venetoclax ramp-up in patients with&#xD;
      CLL/SLL in either the front-line or relapsed/refractory setting. This clinical trial is&#xD;
      testing a new dosing schedule of a drug that is normally dosed in a different fashion. As&#xD;
      such, venetoclax is considered an investigational drug when given in this new schedule.&#xD;
      &quot;Investigational&quot; means that the drug is being studied. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration&#xD;
      (FDA) has approved venetoclax as a treatment option for CLL or SLL but the approval is based&#xD;
      on a different schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Venetoclax is an oral drug inhibitor of BCL-2, a protein that regulates the death of cells in&#xD;
      the body. It has been FDA approved with or without rituximab for the treatment of adult&#xD;
      patients with CLL/SLL who have received at least one prior therapy, with obinutuzumab for&#xD;
      frontline therapy of CLL/SLL, as well in combination with azacitabine, decitabine, or&#xD;
      low-dose cytarabine for the treatment of adults with newly diagnosed acute myeloid leukemia&#xD;
      (AML).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Venetoclax is typically started at a low dose and increased on a weekly basis, over 5 weeks,&#xD;
      to the desired dose for patients with CLL/SLL.This study is trying to determine if patients&#xD;
      can safely increase the venetoclax dose in the hospital on a daily basis, over 5 days rather&#xD;
      than weekly, and which patients, grouped by their risk for TLS, with newly diagnosed or&#xD;
      relapsed/refractory CLL/SLL, are able to safely tolerate this accelerated, daily venetoclax&#xD;
      dose ramp-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The research study procedures include screening for eligibility and study treatment including&#xD;
      evaluations and follow up visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be actively followed for approximately 3 months. Following completion&#xD;
      of the active study period, participants will be encouraged to return for a response&#xD;
      evaluation. Following this, patients will enter a long-term follow up period where they will&#xD;
      be observed for a maximum of 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is expected that about 40 people will take part in this research study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 14, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Highest risk TLS group that can safely tolerate the daily ramp up</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Rates of laboratory and clinical TLS</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Objective response rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated using the 2018 iwCLL criteria for CLL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Complete response (CR) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated using the 2018 iwCLL criteria for CLL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of first documented progression or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time to progression or death</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From date of enrollment until the date of first documented progression or date of death from any cause, whichever came first, assessed up to 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Death due to any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of undetectable minimal residual disease (uMRD)</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>Determined by flow cytometry and ClonoSeq</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Venetoclax</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be separated into two cohorts: Cohort A: Patients at low risk for TLS. Cohort B: Patients with both median and high risk for TLS.&#xD;
Five (5) participants from cohort A will be initially enrolled, if these first 5 participants tolerate the accelerated ramp-up, cohorts A and B will enroll simultaneously.&#xD;
All participants will be hospitalized and receive venetoclax daily with accelerated dose increases over 5 days to reach full dose. After reaching full dose, participants will be discharged and continue daily venetoclax at home.&#xD;
Per doctor assessment, some participants may also receive rituximab or obinutuzumab as part of the treatment regimen with venetoclax.&#xD;
Rituximab: Given every 28 days starting on the second study cycle and continuing for up to 6 cycles as per standard of care.&#xD;
Obinutuzumab: Days 1, 2, 8, and 15 of cycle 1 and once every 28 days there after for up to 6 cycles as per standard of care.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Venetoclax</intervention_name>
    <description>Tablet, taken by mouth</description>
    <arm_group_label>Venetoclax</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Venclexta</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Obinutuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given as an infusion into the vein (intravenous, IV).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Venetoclax</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Gazyva</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rituximab</intervention_name>
    <description>Given as an infusion into the vein (intravenous, IV).</description>
    <arm_group_label>Venetoclax</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rituxan</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have a confirmed diagnosis of chronic lymphocytic leukemia or small lymphocytic&#xD;
             lymphoma per IW-CLL 201814 requiring therapy based on at least one of the following&#xD;
             criteria as listed below:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Evidence of progressive marrow failure as manifested by the development of, or&#xD;
                  worsening of, anemia (hemoglobin &lt;11.0 g/L) and/or thrombocytopenia (platelets&#xD;
                  &lt;100 x 109/L)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Massive (≥6 cm below the left costal margin), progressive, or symptomatic&#xD;
                  splenomegaly&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Massive nodes (at least 10 cm longest diameter), progressive, or symptomatic&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  lymphadenopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Progressive lymphocytosis with an increase of more than 50% over a 2-month period&#xD;
                  or LDT of &lt;6 months. Lymphocyte doubling time may be obtained by linear&#xD;
                  regression extrapolation of absolute lymphocyte counts obtained at intervals of 2&#xD;
                  weeks over an observation period of 2 to 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Autoimmune anemia and/or thrombocytopenia that is poorly responsive to&#xD;
                  corticosteroids or other standard therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Documented constitutional symptoms, defined as 1 or more of the following disease&#xD;
                  related symptoms or signs: unintentional weight loss &gt;10% within 6 months prior&#xD;
                  to screening, significant fatigue (inability to work or perform usual&#xD;
                  activities), fevers &gt;100.5° F or 38.0° C for 2 or more weeks prior to screening&#xD;
                  without evidence of infection, night sweats for more than 1 month prior to&#xD;
                  screening without evidence of infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both previously untreated and relapsed or refractory patients will be eligible,&#xD;
             including those who will be receiving venetoclax as monotherapy or in combination with&#xD;
             anti-CD20 monoclonal antibody therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age greater or equal to 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ECOG performance status ≤2 (Karnofsky ≥60%, see Appendix A)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must meet the following hematologic criteria at screening, unless they have&#xD;
             significant bone marrow involvement of CLL confirmed on biopsy:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absolute neutrophil count ≥1000 cells/mm3. Growth factor is allowed in order to&#xD;
                  achieve this&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Platelet count ≥25,000 cells/mm3 (25 x 109/L) independent of transfusion within 7&#xD;
                  days of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate hepatic function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum aspartate transaminase (AST) and alanine transaminase (ALT) ≤ 3.0 x upper&#xD;
                  limit of normal (ULN), bilirubin ≤1.5 x ULN (unless bilirubin rise is due to&#xD;
                  Gilbert's syndrome or of non-hepatic origin)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adequate renal function as defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serum creatinine ≤1.5 times the ULN or creatinine clearance ≥ 50 mL/min using a&#xD;
                  24-hour urine collection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women of child-bearing potential and men must agree to use adequate contraception&#xD;
             (hormonal, barrier method or abstinence) prior to study entry and for the duration of&#xD;
             study participation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and the willingness to sign a written informed consent document&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Treatment with venetoclax within the past 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Transformation of CLL to aggressive NHL (Richter's transformation or pro-lymphocytic&#xD;
             leukemia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving cancer therapy (i.e., chemotherapy, radiation therapy,&#xD;
             immunotherapy, biologic therapy, surgery within 2 weeks of Cycle 1/Day 1 with the&#xD;
             following exceptions:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  CD20 antibody therapy (i.e. rituximab or obinutuzumab) if it is being used as&#xD;
                  part of the venetoclax regimen (see inclusion criteria 3.1.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  For patients on targeted therapies, a washout of least five half lives is&#xD;
                  required&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients who experience clinical deterioration may start therapy after a shorter&#xD;
                  washout period with prior approval by the PI&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Corticosteroid therapy (prednisone or equivalent &lt;=20 mg daily) is allowed&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed central nervous system involvement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allogeneic hematologic stem cell transplant within 6 months of starting study&#xD;
             treatment or active graft vs. host disease (GVHD) requiring treatment or prophylaxis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active malignancy requiring therapy that would interact with venetoclax as per the&#xD;
             discretion of the treating investigator&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any active systemic infection requiring IV antibiotics or other uncontrolled, active&#xD;
             infections&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known history of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis C virus (HCV), or&#xD;
             hepatitis B virus (HBV)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery within 4 weeks of first dose of study drug&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently active, clinically significant cardiovascular disease, such as uncontrolled&#xD;
             arrhythmia or Class 3 or 4 congestive heart failure as defined by the New York Heart&#xD;
             Association Functional Classification; or a history of myocardial infarction, unstable&#xD;
             angina, or acute coronary syndrome within 6 months of initial dosing on study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of Coumadin for anticoagulation (other anticoagulants permitted)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lactating or pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Concurrent administration of medications or foods that are strong inhibitors or&#xD;
             inducers of CYP3A . The concomitant use of drugs or foods that are strong or moderate&#xD;
             inhibitors or inducers of CYP3A are not allowed beginning 1 week prior to the first&#xD;
             dose of venetoclax.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ongoing use of prophylactic antibiotics are eligible as long as there is&#xD;
             no evidence of active infection and the antibiotic is not included on the list of&#xD;
             prohibited medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to swallow capsules or malabsorption syndrome, active disease significantly&#xD;
             affecting gastrointestinal function, or resection of the stomach or small bowel,&#xD;
             symptomatic inflammatory bowel disease or ulcerative colitis, or partial or complete&#xD;
             bowel obstruction resulting in malabsorption or chronic diarrhea&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active abuse of alcohol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jennifer Crombie, Crombie</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jennifer Crombie, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(617) 632-4106</phone>
    <email>jennifer_crombie@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02215</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jennifer Crombie, MD</last_name>
      <phone>617-632-4106</phone>
      <email>jennifer_crombie@dfci.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jennifer Crombie, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Dana-Farber Cancer Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jennifer Crombie</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chronic Lymphocytic Leukemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Small Lymphocytic Lymphoma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphoid</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Leukemia, Lymphocytic, Chronic, B-Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rituximab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Obinutuzumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Venetoclax</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The Dana-Farber / Harvard Cancer Center encourages and supports the responsible and ethical sharing of data from clinical trials. De-identified participant data from the final research dataset used in the published manuscript may only be shared under the terms of a Data Use Agreement. Requests may be directed to: [contact information for Sponsor Investigator or designee]. The protocol and statistical analysis plan will be made available on Clinicaltrials.gov only as required by federal regulation or as a condition of awards and agreements supporting the research.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data can be shared no earlier than 1 year following the date of publication</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Contact the Belfer Office for Dana-Farber Innovations (BODFI) at innovation@dfci.harvard.edu</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

