<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04844970</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>LHMC 20193054</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04844970</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Anamorelin Study for Advanced Pancreatic Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-blind, and Placebo Controlled Multicenter Phase II Trial Evaluating Anamorelin in the Prevention of Cancer Induced-Weight Loss and Anorexia in Patients Receiving First-line Treatment of Advanced Pancreatic Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Lahey Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Helsinn Healthcare SA</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Quartesian LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Lahey Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Multicenter, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled study to evaluate the efficacy and&#xD;
      safety of anamorelin HCl. Approximately 100 subjects with advanced PDAC and cachexia will be&#xD;
      randomized 1:1 to anamorelin HCl 100 mg or placebo, taken orally once daily (QD) for a total&#xD;
      of 25 weeks. Subjects will be instructed to take the study drug at least 1 hour before their&#xD;
      first meal of the day&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Anorexia and cachexia are common clinical sequelae of uncontrolled, metastatic cancer. These&#xD;
      effects can impair physical function, reduce quality of life, impair tolerability of&#xD;
      anticancer therapy, and reduce survival. Anorexia and cachexia are especially challenging&#xD;
      problems in patients diagnosed with metastatic pancreatic cancer. With an annual incidence&#xD;
      approaching 50,000 patients in the U.S. alone, pancreatic cancer has an annual mortality of&#xD;
      approximately 40,000 patients with most individuals succumbing to their disease within two&#xD;
      years. Between 70-80% of patients with metastatic pancreatic cancer experience cancer&#xD;
      cachexia, which has been associated with reduced survival, increased risk of disease&#xD;
      progression, and impaired chemotherapy tolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anamorelin HCl is an orally-active selective ghrelin receptor agonist which has shown&#xD;
      anabolic and appetite-stimulating effects. Several randomized, double-blind, clinical trials&#xD;
      in cancer patients have shown that anamorelin HCL is safe, efficacious and increases lean&#xD;
      body mass, bodyweight, and appetite. Investigators propose to test anamorelin HCL&#xD;
      administered with chemotherapy in the first-line treatment of locally advanced unresectable&#xD;
      and metastatic pancreatic cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is a randomized, placebo controlled multicenter, Phase II trial to evaluate the&#xD;
      efficacy and safety of anamorelin HCl. Approximately 100 patients with be enrolled in a 1:1&#xD;
      randomization to anamorelin HCL 100mg per day given concurrently with first-line chemotherapy&#xD;
      compared to chemotherapy alone. Patients randomized to anamorelin HCL will take it daily for&#xD;
      24 weeks starting one day prior to chemotherapy. All patients will undergo an assessment by a&#xD;
      certified nutritionist at or prior to their first cycle of chemotherapy. Both body weight and&#xD;
      appetite will be measured at enrollment as well as at the initiation of chemotherapy.&#xD;
      Patients will be stratified by degree of weight loss in the six months prior to enrollment,&#xD;
      choice of first-line chemotherapy, and by baseline score of 5-item Anorexia Symptom Scale.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>One group receives Anamorelin, and the other group receives placebo.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>double-blind. Neither the investigator nor the participant would know the assigned drug/placebo</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight change</measure>
    <time_frame>25 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>demonstrate superiority of anamorelin HCl dosed at 100mg per day vs. placebo on body weight gain and improvement in anorexia symptoms in patients undergoing first-line chemotherapy for incurable pancreatic cancer.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anorexia Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Absolute change in the FAACT 5 item Anorexia Symptom Score from baseline at week</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>25 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiologic Response to Chemotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Chemotherapy response will be evaluated by RECIST criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Weight gain</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 25 (end of the study)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatigue Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Change in FACIT-F questionnaire, fatigue subscale</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v5.0</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 25 (end of study)</time_frame>
    <description>expected toxicities for Chemotherapies (FOLFIRINOX and Gemcitabine/Nab-Paclitaxel) will be assessed by CTCAE v5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AEs</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 25 (end of study)</time_frame>
    <description>AEs that are related to the drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Unplanned visits</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 25 (end of the study)</time_frame>
    <description>number of unplanned visits for symptom management as defined by unscheduled clinic visits, emergency department visits, or hospitalizations</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Chemotherapy Dose change</measure>
    <time_frame>from baseline to week 13</time_frame>
    <description>Percent change in dose intensity of chemotherapy as defined by percent reduction in anticipated chemotherapy dose as determined y the treating physician</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Metastatic Pancreatic Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anamorelin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients randomized to anamorelin HCL will take it daily for 24 weeks starting 3-5 days prior to chemotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients randomized to placebo will take it daily for 24 weeks starting 3-5 days prior to chemotherapy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anamorelin Hydrochloride</intervention_name>
    <description>Anamorelin HCl is an orally-active selective ghrelin receptor agonist which has shown anabolic and appetite-stimulating effects.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anamorelin</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Anamorelin placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Signed written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Female or male ≥18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Documented histologic or cytologic diagnosis of American Joint Committee on Cancer&#xD;
             (AJCC) unresectable or metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Body mass index &lt; 20 kg/m2 with involuntary weight loss or &gt;5% within 6 months prior&#xD;
             to screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Ongoing problems with appetite/eating associated with the underlying cancer, as&#xD;
             determined by having score of ≤ 17 points on the 5-item Anorexia Symptom Scale and ≤&#xD;
             37 points on the 12-item FAACT A/CS&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects eligible to receive first line palliative chemotherapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ECOG performance status 0 or 1 at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Acceptable hepatic function as defined by total bilirubin &lt; 1.6 mg/dl unless&#xD;
             associated with Gilbert syndrome, then total bilirubin &lt; 2 x ULN. AST (SGOT) and ALT&#xD;
             (SGPT) ≤ 2.5 x ULN or if hepatic metastases are present ≤ 5 x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Appropriate treatment with pancreatic enzyme replacement prior to trial initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Female subjects shall be:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. of non-childbearing potential or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. of childbearing potential using reliable contraceptive measures and having a&#xD;
                  negative urine pregnancy test within 24 hours prior to first dose of&#xD;
                  investigational product.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. The patient must be willing and able to comply with the protocol tests and procedures&#xD;
             All inclusion criteria will be checked at screening visit (Visit 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patient with other forms of pancreatic cancer (e.g. neuroendocrine tumors)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patient undergoing major surgery within 4 weeks of randomization or plans to undergo&#xD;
             major surgery during study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Women who are pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patient with alternative cause of cachexia as determined by the investigator&#xD;
             including: a) severe COPD requiring O2, b) severe heart failure (NYHA Class III- IV),&#xD;
             c) second malignancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Reversible causes of reduced food intake as determined by the investigator including&#xD;
             but not limited to: severe mucositis (&gt;=NCI CTCAE grade 3), mechanical obstruction,&#xD;
             severe nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea (&gt;=NCI CTCAE grade 3)&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patient unable to swallow pills&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patient with history of bariatric surgery, gastrectomy, or malabsorption disorder&#xD;
             (gastritis, esophagitis)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patient with recent use of CYP3A4 inhibitors&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patient with current daily use of therapies that may increase the QRS interval&#xD;
             durations&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patient currently taking medications/compounds intended to increase appetite or&#xD;
             decrease weight loss (e.g. testosterone, megestrol acetate, cannabis products,&#xD;
             methylphenidate, corticosteroids, olanzapine, mirtazapine (allowed if &gt;4 weeks of use&#xD;
             as therapy for depression)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patient with current use of tube feeding or parenteral feeding&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patient with pleural effusion requiring thoracentesis, pericardial effusion requiring&#xD;
             drainage, edema or evidence of ascites&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patient with uncontrolled or significant cardiovascular disease, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. History of myocardial infarction within the past 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. A-V block of second or third degree (may be eligible if currently have a&#xD;
                  pacemaker)&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Unstable angina&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Congestive heart failure within the past 3 months, if defined as NYHA class&#xD;
                  III-IV&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Any history of clinically significant ventricular arrhythmias (such as&#xD;
                  ventricular tachycardia, ventricular fibrillation, Wolff-Parkinson-White (WPW)&#xD;
                  syndrome, or torsade de pointes)&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Uncontrolled hypertension (blood pressure &gt;150 mm Hg systolic and &gt;95 mm Hg&#xD;
                  diastolic)&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Heart rate &lt; 50 beats per minute on pre-entry electrocardiogram and patient is&#xD;
                  symptomatic&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Patient with uncontrolled diabetes mellitus or unmonitored diabetes mellitus&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Patient with uncontrolled pain.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Any condition, including the presence of laboratory abnormalities, which in the&#xD;
             Investigator's opinion, places the subject at unacceptable risk if he/she were to&#xD;
             participate in the study or confounds the ability to interpret data from the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Enrollment in a previous study with anamorelin HCl&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Enrollment in another clinical trial during the time of this trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lahey Hospital &amp; Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Burlington</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>01805</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Phase II</keyword>
  <keyword>Randomized</keyword>
  <keyword>double-blind</keyword>
  <keyword>placebo-controlled</keyword>
  <keyword>Anamorelin HCI</keyword>
  <keyword>Cachexia</keyword>
  <keyword>Anorexia</keyword>
  <keyword>Weight loss</keyword>
  <keyword>FAACT A/CS</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pancreatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

