<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04849845</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MKC-TI-191</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04849845</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Afrezza® Dosing Optimization Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>DOS</acronym>
  <official_title>DOS [Dosing Optimization Study]: Open-label, Single-arm, Proof-of-Concept Dosing Study of Afrezza® in Adult Subjects 18 Years and Older With Type 1 or Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mannkind Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mannkind Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      MKC-TI-191 is a Phase 4, single-arm, multicenter, proof-of-concept clinical trial evaluating&#xD;
      the efficacy and safety of Afrezza, administered according to the current Afrezza prescribing&#xD;
      information (PI) compared to a titrated dose, in combination with a basal insulin in adult&#xD;
      subjects (≥18 years of age) with type 1 diabetes mellitus (T1DM) or type 2 diabetes mellitus&#xD;
      (T2DM). Eligible subjects will be on a stable regimen consisting of a basal bolus insulin&#xD;
      therapy prior to screening. The study is composed of up to 4 clinic visits (screening, 2&#xD;
      treatment visits, and a follow-up visit). Two individual doses of Afrezza will be&#xD;
      administered during a meal challenge at Visits 2 and 3. The duration of each subject's&#xD;
      participation in the trial is expected to be approximately 2 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Screening (Visit 1): Informed consent and California Experimental Subjects Bill of Rights&#xD;
      will be signed and eligibility confirmed. Eligible subjects will be enrolled at Visit 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will come into the clinic in a fasting state for a meal challenge and individual&#xD;
      dose of Afrezza during Visits 2 and 3. At the beginning of each visit, before their dose of&#xD;
      Afrezza, subjects will have FEV1 measurements taken in the clinic. Each meal challenge will&#xD;
      consist of 1 to 2 bottles of nutritional shake to be fully consumed within 15 minutes. The&#xD;
      nutritional shake will contain approximately 240 calories, 41 g carbohydrate, 10 g protein,&#xD;
      and 4 g fat per bottle. Each Afrezza dose will be administered at the start of the meal&#xD;
      challenge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 2: The first dose of Afrezza will be based on the dose of subcutaneous (SC)&#xD;
      rapid-acting analogue (RAA) insulin that the subject would normally take, converted according&#xD;
      to the guidelines provided in the current Afrezza prescribing information. If subject's&#xD;
      normal RAA dose is &lt;4 units or 5 units, subject will be asked to consume enough nutritional&#xD;
      shake, per their normal I:C ratio, to cover an RAA dose of 4 units or ≥6 units such that&#xD;
      their Afrezza dose at Visit 3 is higher than the dose taken at Visit 2. After completing the&#xD;
      standardized meal challenge, the Investigator will decide, based on the subject's glucose&#xD;
      excursion at Visit 2, if the subject should proceed to Visit 3 where a second dose of Afrezza&#xD;
      will be administered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Visit 3: The second dose of Afrezza will be based on the dose of SC RAA that the subject&#xD;
      would normally take, converted by multiplying their RAA dose by 2 and rounding down to the&#xD;
      nearest Afrezza cartridge size.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up Visit (Visit 4): Subjects will return for safety assessments, including a final&#xD;
      FEV1 measurement, 24 to 72 hours after their last dose of Afrezza.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">May 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in SMBG</measure>
    <time_frame>120 minutes post-dose</time_frame>
    <description>Change in self-monitored blood glucose (SMBG) from immediately before administering the dose of Afrezza (t=0; baseline) to 15, 30, 45, 60, 90 and 120 minutes after Afrezza dosing.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level 1 hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of Level 1 (&lt;70 mg/dL) hypoglycemic events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level 1 hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Event rate of Level 1 (&lt;70 mg/dL) hypoglycemic events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level 2 hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of Level 2 (&lt;54 mg/dL) hypoglycemic events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Level 2 hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Event rate of Level 2 (&lt;54 mg/dL) hypoglycemic events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>FEV1</measure>
    <time_frame>120 minutes post-dose</time_frame>
    <description>Change in percent predicted forced expiratory volume in 1 second (FEV1) before Afrezza dosing to 120 minutes after Afrezza dosing</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and severity of adverse events (AEs): treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs), serious AEs (SAEs), and AEs of special interest (AESIs)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</condition>
  <condition>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Afrezza</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The test product is defined as Afrezza [insulin human] inhalation powder administered using the Afrezza inhaler. In addition, subjects will take their personal basal insulin while enrolled in the study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Afrezza Dose 1</intervention_name>
    <description>The first dose of Afrezza will be based on the dose of subcutaneous rapid-acting analogue (RAA) insulin that the subject would normally take for the standardized meal, converted according to the guidelines provided in the current Afrezza U.S. prescribing information.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Afrezza</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Combination Product</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Afrezza Dose 2</intervention_name>
    <description>The second dose of Afrezza will be based on the dose of subcutaneous rapid-acting analogue that the subject would normally take for the standardized meal, converted by multiplying their RAA dose by 2 and rounding down to the nearest Afrezza cartridge size.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Afrezza</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Subjects will be asked to provide a recent negative COVID-19 test (if available), confirm&#xD;
        they have no symptoms of COVID-19, or provide evidence of COVID-19 vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subjects ≥18 years of age at the time of signing the informed consent form&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinical diagnosis of T1DM or T2DM (per the Investigator) and on a stable basal-bolus&#xD;
             insulin regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, or any other clinically&#xD;
             important pulmonary disease (e.g., cystic fibrosis, bronchopulmonary dysplasia), use&#xD;
             of any medications to treat such conditions within the last year, or significant&#xD;
             congenital or acquired cardiopulmonary disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. History of serious complications of diabetes (e.g., active proliferative retinopathy&#xD;
             or symptomatic autonomic neuropathy)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. On dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Respiratory tract infection within 14 days before screening (subject may return 14&#xD;
             days after resolution of symptoms for rescreening)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Treatment with any investigational drug in the past 30 days or an investigational&#xD;
             device in the past 2 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Any disease other than diabetes or initiation of any new medication that, in the&#xD;
             judgment of the Investigator, could have a direct impact on glycemic control during&#xD;
             the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Use of antiadrenergic drugs (e.g., beta blockers and clonidine)&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any concurrent illness (other than diabetes mellitus) not controlled by a stable&#xD;
             therapeutic regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of a significant eating disorder (e.g., anorexia or bulimia nervosa)&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Current drug or alcohol abuse or a history of drug or alcohol abuse that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator or the Sponsor, would make the subject an unsuitable&#xD;
             candidate for participation in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History of smoking (includes cigarettes, cigars, pipes, vaping devices, and marijuana)&#xD;
             in the 6 months before screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Female subject who is pregnant, breastfeeding, intends to become pregnant, or is of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential and not using adequate contraceptive methods as required by&#xD;
             local regulation or practice (may include sexual abstinence)&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. An event of severe hypoglycemia, as judged by the Investigator, within the 90 days&#xD;
             before screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. An episode of diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA) requiring hospitalization within the 90 days&#xD;
             before screening&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Exposure to Afrezza in the 30 days before screening&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kevin Kaiserman, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Mannkind Corporation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AMCR Institute</name>
      <address>
        <city>Escondido</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92025</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Diablo Clinical Research</name>
      <address>
        <city>Walnut Creek</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94598</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Afrezza</keyword>
  <keyword>Dosing</keyword>
  <keyword>Technosphere</keyword>
  <keyword>Inhaled</keyword>
  <keyword>Insulin</keyword>
  <keyword>Diabetes</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Insulin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Insulin, Globin Zinc</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

