<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04842890</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NYPC ERC# 2020-027</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04842890</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase II Study of Pencil Beam Scanning Proton Stereotactic Body Radiation Therapy for Prostate Cancer</brief_title>
  <official_title>Phase II Study of Pencil Beam Scanning Proton Stereotactic Body Radiation Therapy for Prostate Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The New York Proton Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The New York Proton Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a single arm phase II study of image-guided pencil beam scanning proton SBRT (40Gy&#xD;
      RBE in 5 fractions delivered every other day) for patients with low- and intermediate-risk&#xD;
      prostate cancer. The primary aim is to assess GU/GI toxicity of proton SBRT and compare this&#xD;
      to historic outcomes associated with photon-based prostate SBRT. The primary endpoint is&#xD;
      2-year grade 3+ GU/GI toxicity free rate by CTCAE v5.0, which is expected to be ≥95%.&#xD;
      Toxicity will be evaluated by the treating radiation oncologist at least once during SBRT,&#xD;
      then following SBRT at 1, 3, 6, 12, 18, and 24 months. The treatment will be considered safe&#xD;
      if grade 3 or higher GU/GI toxicity free rate at 2 years is &gt;85% (95% rate expected with a&#xD;
      10% non-inferiority margin). The accrual goal is 61 patients over 3 years. To ensure that&#xD;
      unexpected significant toxicity is identified, all grade 3 or higher toxicities will be&#xD;
      reported to the study PI and the trial will stop accruing if at any point 4 or more patients&#xD;
      experience a grade 3 or higher toxicity after completing SBRT. This is felt to be&#xD;
      conservative given the vast experience with photon SBRT at this dose with an expected G3+&#xD;
      toxicity of ~5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives are to examine patient-reported urinary, gastrointestinal, sexual, and&#xD;
      financial outcomes using IPSS, EPIC-26, and COST questionnaires at the same follow-up&#xD;
      timepoints as above. Baseline measures of these domains will be obtained prior to treatment&#xD;
      as well. Clinical outcomes will also be evaluated with PSA measured at each follow-up, as&#xD;
      well as prostate MRI and biopsies at 2 years. Patients will be followed for at least 2 years&#xD;
      to determine rates of PSA relapse, salvage treatment, development of metastases, death from&#xD;
      prostate cancer, and overall survival. A dosimetric comparison will be performed where each&#xD;
      patient will be planned for proton and photon SBRT to determine possible advantages of proton&#xD;
      SBRT.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 8, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1. Grade 3+ GU/GI toxicity-free rate determined by CTCAE v5.0 grading.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The NCI Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events v5.0 is a descriptive terminology which can be utilized for Adverse Event (AE) reporting. A grading (severity) scale is provided for each AE term.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>1. Patient reported urinary symptoms determined by IPSS.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS) was developed to assess the severity of lower urinary tract symptoms associated to Benign Prostatic Hyperplasia and has also been applied to other conditions that cause LUTS. The IPSS consists of a total of seven questions that deal with voiding symptoms (incomplete empty, intermittency, weak stream and straining to void) and storage symptoms (frequency, urgency and nocturia) and an additional question to measure quality of life. The score ranges from 0 to 35, with lower scores denoting a better health state.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>2. Patient reported urinary, bowel, and hormonal quality of life determined by EPIC-26.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>EPIC-26 is the &quot;Expanded Prostate Cancer Index Composite&quot; patient reported outcomes questionnaire. A clinical tool to assess urinary, bowel, sexual and vitality health. The score from each of the 5 domains runs from 0 (none) to 12 (severe) impact on quality of life. Each domain score when added together gives an overall score of zero (unaffected) to 60 (severely affected)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>3. Patient reported financial toxicity determined by COST</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Comprehensive Score for Financial Toxicity Functional Assessment of Chronic Illness Therapy (COST-FACIT) was developed as part of a series of questionnaires aimed at measuring different symptom indexes of health-related quality of life in patients with advance disease such as cancer. The survey contains 12 questions and each of them is rated from 0 (not at all) to 4 (very much). This survey focuses on financial distress caused by illness in patients with cancer. It takes about 5 minutes to complete.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>4. 2-year and 5-year biochemical progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years and 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Biochemical failure is defined as a sustained rise in PSA of 2 ng/mL or more above the nadir (the lowest PSA level after radiotherapy).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>5. 2-year local control determined by MRI and biopsies</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>6. 2-year and 5-year metastasis free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years and 5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>7. 2-year and 5-year prostate cancer specific survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years and 5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>8. 2-year and 5-year overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years and 5 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>9. Dosimetric advantages determined by target coverage, conformality, and normal tissue sparing</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">61</enrollment>
  <condition>Prostate Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic body radiation therapy (SBRT) with Pencil Beam Scanning (PBS) proton therapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pencil Beam Scanning Proton SBRT</intervention_name>
    <description>The intervention being investigated is ultra-hypofractionated, image-guided, pencil beam scanning proton SBRT directed at the prostate gland and seminal vesicles to 40 Gy equivalent in 5 fractions, delivered every other day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Stereotactic body radiation therapy (SBRT) with Pencil Beam Scanning (PBS) proton therapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Biopsy-proven NCCN low- or intermediate-risk prostate cancer, which includes patients&#xD;
             with:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gleason score ≤7 disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PSA ≤20 ng/ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical T1-T2c disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Patients who only have radiographic evidence of possible or probable T3&#xD;
                  disease (i.e., extracapsular extension or seminal vesical invasion) will not be&#xD;
                  excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  KPS ≥ 80%&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prostate size as determined on MRI to be &lt; 100 cc. Prostate size can be determined on&#xD;
             CT scan if MRI is not available.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  IPSS ≤ 20&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be a candidate for and agree to placement of intraprostatic fiducial&#xD;
             markers and a hydrogel rectal spacer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient must be available for at least 2 years of follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior prostate surgery (including cryosurgery)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Note: Patients who underwent TURP or greenlight PVP are eligible if it was &gt; 12&#xD;
                  weeks prior to the anticipated start date of SBRT&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior history of chronic prostatitis or urethral stricture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently active cancer(s) other than non-melanoma skin cancers. Patients are not&#xD;
             considered to have currently active cancers if they have completed therapy and are&#xD;
             considered by their physicians to be at &lt;5% risk of relapse within 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of &lt; 2 years&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Male</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Daniel Gorovets, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The New York Proton Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Shaakir Hasan, DO</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The New York Proton Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Shannon Webert, RN</last_name>
    <phone>646-968-9005</phone>
    <phone_ext>383</phone_ext>
    <email>research@nyproton.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The New York Proton Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>New York</city>
        <state>New York</state>
        <zip>10035</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Isabelle Choi, MD</last_name>
      <phone>646-968-9031</phone>
      <phone_ext>303</phone_ext>
      <email>ichoi@nyproton.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prostatic Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

