<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04847739</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STOMP-II</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04847739</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Seeded Cells on Matrix Plug Treating Crohn's Perianal Fistulas</brief_title>
  <official_title>Seeded Cells on Matrix Plug Treating Crohn's Perianal Fistulas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Avobis Bio, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Alimentiv Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Avobis Bio, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A Phase II study to assess the safety and efficacy of AVB-114 in treatment of complex Crohn's&#xD;
      perianal fistulas in subjects with quiescent rectal disease and whose fistula has failed to&#xD;
      respond to biologic or conventional therapy. Combined remission of treated perianal fistula&#xD;
      in the investigational treatment arm will be compared to a standard of care control arm.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study has 2 parts:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 1: All required study visits for subjects who initially receive study treatment and&#xD;
      those who receive standard of care therapy (control arm).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Part 2: Subjects who are enrolled in the control arm may receive treatment with AVB-114&#xD;
      following week 36. Those subjects then will be followed as specified in the clinical&#xD;
      protocol.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">August 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportions of subjects with combined remission of treated perianal fistula between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>36 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportions of subjects with fistula clinical remission between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 to Week 104</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the means of durability of clinical remission between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 to Week 104</time_frame>
    <description>Length of time fistula meets clinical remission definition.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in means of time to clinical remission between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 to Week 104</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportions of subjects with fistula relapse between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 to Week 104</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in means of time to fistula relapse between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 to Week 104</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in proportions of radiologic response of treated fistula between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 12 to Week 52</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in means of disease activity index scores using the Perianal Disease Activity Index (PDAI) between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 36</time_frame>
    <description>Perianal Disease Activity Index (PDAI). Possible scores range from 0-20, with a higher score indicating more severe perianal disease activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in means of disease activity index scores using the short Crohn's Disease Activity Index (sCDAI) between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 36</time_frame>
    <description>Short Crohn's Disease Activity Index (sCDAI). Possible scores range from 44 to &gt;450, with a higher score representing more severe disease activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in means of patient quality of life assessment scores using the Euroqol 5 Diumention 5, level measure of health status (Eq-5Q-5L) between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 36</time_frame>
    <description>Euroqol 5 Dimension 5, level measure of health status (EQ-5D-5L). The scale ranges in scores from 0 to 100, with a higher score indicating a more severe health status.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in means of patient quality of life assessment scores using the Inflammatory Bowel Disease Questionnaire (IBDQ) between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 36</time_frame>
    <description>Inflammatory Bowel Disease Questionnaire (IBDQ). Possible scores range from 32-224, with a higher score indicating a better health-related quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient assessment of impact to daily functionality related to treated fistula between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Week 12 to Week 36</time_frame>
    <description>Days of missed work or activity and reason why will be captured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the evaluations of patient care trajectory related to treated fistula between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12 to Week 36</time_frame>
    <description>Number and type of healthcare resources utilized will be captured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in number of adverse events between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Week 104</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in number of serious adverse events between the AVB-114 and standard of care groups.</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 to Week 104</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Perianal Fistula</condition>
  <condition>Crohn's Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care Treatment + AVB-114</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects receive the standard of care treatment (seton placement) prior to Day 0, when it is removed and the AVB-114 study treatment is inserted.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects receive the standard of care treatment (seton placement) prior to Day 0, when it is removed and then replaced.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Seton Placement</intervention_name>
    <description>This treatment consists of inserting a seton (a soft flexible tube or nonabsorbable string) into the subject's perianal fistula. The seton will be removed by a study doctor at study visits as applicable.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care Treatment</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care Treatment + AVB-114</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AVB-114</intervention_name>
    <description>AVB-114 consists of stem cells taken from a subject's fat tissue seeded into a bioabsorbable plug. AVB-114 will be inserted into the subject's fistula by a study doctor on Day 0.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care Treatment + AVB-114</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Provision of signed and dated ICF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ability and willingness to comply with study protocol and study requirements for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Male or female, 18-70 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subjects with CD diagnosed at least 6 months prior to screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects with a single fistula tract with one internal opening and one external&#xD;
             opening, including a previously performed conversion of a branching fistula tract to a&#xD;
             single fistula tract where the branching occurred outside the sphincter complex.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects whose perianal fistula(s) were previously treated with either biologic or&#xD;
             conventional therapy whose fistula has demonstrated a failed response or who have&#xD;
             documented medication intolerance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Women of childbearing potential (WCBP) must have negative serum pregnancy test at&#xD;
             screening (sensitive to 25 IU human chorionic gonadotropin). WCBP participating in&#xD;
             this study must agree to use an adequate method of contraception during the entire&#xD;
             duration of the study. Males who have sexual partners that are women of childbearing&#xD;
             potential must be willing to use a barrier method for contraception for the duration&#xD;
             of study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinically significant medical conditions within the six months before screening that&#xD;
             would, in the opinion of the investigator, compromise the safety of the subject with&#xD;
             study participation and/or the ability of the subject to follow study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Evidence of hepatitis B, C, or HIV or subjects with congenital or acquired&#xD;
             immunodeficiencies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participation in an investigational drug study (within 30 days of last administration&#xD;
             from screening visit) or investigational medical device study (within 1 year of&#xD;
             implant from screening visit) where investigational treatment (drug or device) is&#xD;
             placed in rectum, vagina, or near fistula location, or that may potentially interact&#xD;
             with study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History (within previous 5 years of screening visit) of invasive cancer including&#xD;
             melanoma (with the exception of localized skin cancers).&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects pregnant, trying to become pregnant, or are breast feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with contraindications to Magnetic Resonance (MR) evaluations and/or to MR&#xD;
             contrast.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of clinically significant fat-directed autoimmunity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Concomitant recto-vaginal fistula&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Concomitant ileal anal pouch perineal fistulas.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Active, unresolved infection requiring parenteral antibiotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Any major surgery of the gastrointestinal tract (including one or more segments of the&#xD;
             colon or terminal ileum) within 3 months prior to screening visit. Presence of stoma&#xD;
             is not exclusionary.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects who had a definitive surgical procedure for the target fistula or a perianal&#xD;
             procedure that resulted in a large soft tissue defect within 6 months prior to&#xD;
             screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. A compromised abdominal region due to a previous cool sculpting procedure, abdominal&#xD;
             radiation, chemotherapy, recent tattoos, local infection, or other reasons that may&#xD;
             compromise the adipose tissue for study use.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Subjects previously treated with Cx601/Alofisel or other allogeneic or autologous&#xD;
             stem-cell therapy within the past 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Contraindications to the anesthetic procedure (local and general) or to the adipose&#xD;
             tissue collection procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Subjects with one or more of the following fistula types or anatomic presentations:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Horseshoe fistulas&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Fistulas that do not have an opening inside the anal canal or low rectum&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Blind ending sinus tracts (no external opening)&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Branching fistulas that involve or are near the sphincter complex and cannot be&#xD;
                  converted to single tracts without risk to injury to the sphincter complex&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. &gt;1 internal opening&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Moderate or severe proctitis&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Severe rectal mucosal fibrosis surrounding the internal opening preventing the&#xD;
                  securing of the fistula plug cap.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Any anatomical limitation to successfully securing the fistula plug cap&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Evidence by colonoscopy of moderately or greater active luminal CD.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Subject with ongoing systemic or rectal steroids for CD in the last 2 weeks prior to&#xD;
             screening and baseline study visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. History of, or concurrent high-grade dysplasia, adenocarcinoma, and carcinoma in situ&#xD;
             on colonoscopy within 5 years of screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Subjects with renal insufficiency (creatinine value &gt; 1.8 mg/dL, eGFR &lt; 44, or patient&#xD;
             undergoing dialysis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Subjects with a hemoglobin less than 8 gm/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Subjects with serum aspartate transaminase (AST) or alanine transaminase (ALT) &gt; 2&#xD;
             times the upper limit of normal (ULN).&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Subjects with undrained peri-anal sepsis.&#xD;
&#xD;
         24. Subjects with known coagulopathy (abnormal INR) or thrombocytopenia as indicated by a&#xD;
             platelet count &lt; 75,000.&#xD;
&#xD;
         25. Subjects with history of substance abuse (drug or alcohol) that would interfere with&#xD;
             the ability to comply with the study protocol and study requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Joan Morris</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Alimentiv Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Louie Cabigao</last_name>
    <phone>(226) 270-7868</phone>
    <email>STOMP2PM@alimentiv.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 14, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Matrix plug</keyword>
  <keyword>Mesenchymal stem cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Fistula plug</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rectal Fistula</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fistula</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

