<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04849741</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ION373-CS1</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2020-000976-40</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04849741</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of ION373 in Patients With Alexander Disease (AxD)</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1-3, Double-Blind, Randomized, Placebo-Controlled Study to Evaluate the Efficacy, Safety, Pharmacokinetics and Pharmacodynamics of Intrathecally Administered ION373 in Patients With Alexander Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ionis Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ionis Pharmaceuticals, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to evaluate the safety and efficacy of ION373 in improving or&#xD;
      stabilizing gross motor function across the full range of affected domains in patients with&#xD;
      AxD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1-3, multi-center, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multiple-ascending dose&#xD;
      (MAD) study in up to 58 patients with AxD. Participants will be randomized in a 2:1 ratio to&#xD;
      receive ION373 or matching placebo for a 60-week double-blind treatment period; then all&#xD;
      participants will receive ION373 for a 60-week open-label treatment period. Multiple dose&#xD;
      cohorts will be evaluated in the study. Cohorts will be enrolled sequentially. The initial&#xD;
      participants in each dose cohort must be at least 8 years of age at the time of Screening.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2025</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent change from Baseline in the 10-Meter Walk Test (10MWT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Most Bothersome Symptom (MBS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Gross Motor Function Measure-88, Dimensions C, D and E (GMFM-88, Dimensions C-E) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The GMFM-88 is a standardized observational instrument to measure change in gross motor function over time in children with developmental disabilities consisting of 88 items scored on a 4-point ordinal scale grouped in 5 dimensions. Dimensions C (crawling and kneeling), D (standing) and E (walking, running &amp; jumping) will be assessed. The goal total score is the average of the dimension scores expressed as a percentage of the maximum score for that dimension.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in 9-Hole Peg Test (9HPT) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The 9HPT is a simple test of manual dexterity that records the time required for the participant to accurately place and remove nine pegs into a pegboard.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Vineland Adaptive Behavior Scales, Third Edition (Vineland-3) Motor Skills Domain Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The Vineland-3 is a standardized measure used to quantify adaptive behaviors necessary for socialization, communication and daily functioning. Items are scored on a 0-2 scale rating the consistency of independent completion of the assessed skill.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Pediatrics Quality of Life Inventory Gastrointestinal Symptoms Scale (PedsQL GI) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The PedsQL GI Symptoms Scales captures gastrointestinal symptoms on 10 scales and 58 items: Stomach Pain and Hurt Scale (6 items), Stomach Discomfort When Eating Scale (5 items), Food and Drink Limits Scale (6 items), Trouble Swallowing Scale (3 items), Heartburn and Reflux Scale (4 items), Nausea and Vomiting Scale (4 items), Gas and Bloating Scale (7 items), Constipation Scale (14 items), Blood in Poop Scale (2 items) and Diarrhea Scale (7 items). Higher scores indicate few symptoms and better GI-specific health-related quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Vineland Adaptive Behavior Composite, Third Edition (Vineland-3 ABC) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The Vineland-3 is a standardized measure used to quantify adaptive behaviors necessary for socialization, communication and daily functioning. The Core Adaptive Behavior Scores encompass 3 domains of behavior: communication, daily living and socialization. Items are scored on a 0-2 scale rating the consistency of independent completion of the assessed skill.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Composite Autonomic Symptom Score 31 (COMPASS-31) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>COMPASS-31 is a 31-question participant-reported assessment that measures autonomic symptoms across 6 weighted domains on a 100-point scale: orthostatic intolerance (40 points), vasomotor (5 points), secretomotor (15 points), gastrointestinal (25 points), bladder (10 points), and pupillomotor (15 points). A higher score indicates worse autonomic dysfunction.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Pediatrics Quality of Life Inventory (PedsQL) Generic Core Scales Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The generic core scale is a global health-related quality of life assessment reflecting physical (8 items), emotional (5 items), social (5 items) and school/work functioning (5 items).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Cerebrospinal Fluid (CSF) Glial Fibrillary Acid Protein (GFAP) Levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Patient Global Impression of Severity (PGIS) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The PGIS questionnaire captures the participant's rating of the severity of his/her global health status associated with AxD on a 5-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Patient Global Impression of Change (PGIC) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The PGIC questionnaire captures the participant's rating of improvement or decline in his/her global health status on a 5-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Clinical Global Impression of Severity (CGIS) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The CGIS questionnaire captures the clinician's rating of the severity of the participant's global health status associated with AxD on a 5-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Clinical Global Impression of Change (CGIC) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The CGIC questionnaire captures the participant's rating of improvement or decline in his/her global health status on a 5-point ordinal scale.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Alexander Disease Patient Domain Impression of Severity (AxD-PDIS) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The AxD-PDIS questionnaire captures the participant's rating of the severity of specific disease symptoms including gross and fine motor problems, GI problems, language or speech problems and other cognitive problems.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Alexander Disease Patient Domain Impression of Change (AxD-PDIC) Score</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
    <description>The AxD-PDIC questionnaire captures the participant's rating of improvement or decline in specific disease symptoms including gross and fine motor problems, GI problems, language or speech problems and other cognitive problems.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Body Weight Percentile (for participants &lt; 18 years old at screening) or body weight (for participants ≥ 18 years old at screening)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline and Week 61</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">58</enrollment>
  <condition>Alexander Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ION373</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>ION373 will be administered by intrathecal bolus (ITB) injection once every 12 weeks through Week 109.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Matching placebo will be administered by ITB injection once every 12 weeks through Week 109.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>ION373</intervention_name>
    <description>ION373 will be administered by ITB injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>ION373</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>ION373-matching placebo will be administered by ITB injection.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Key Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinical phenotype and brain imaging consistent with a diagnosis of Alexander disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Documented genetic mutation in the GFAP gene&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Aged ≥ 2 to 65 years old at the time of informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able and willing to meet all study requirements, including travel to Study Center,&#xD;
             procedures, measurements and visits&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients &lt; 18 years old at Screening must have a trial partner (parent, caregiver or&#xD;
             other)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Key Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Clinically significant abnormalities in medical history or physical examination&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any clinically significant laboratory abnormalities that would render a patient&#xD;
             unsuitable for inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any contraindication or unwillingness to undergo MRI&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Treatment with another investigational drug, biological agent, or device within 1&#xD;
             month of Screening, or 5 half-lives of investigational agent, whichever is longer;&#xD;
             concurrent participation in any other clinical study (including observational and&#xD;
             non-interventional studies)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Previous treatment with an oligonucleotide (including small interfering ribonucleic&#xD;
             acid [siRNA]) within 4 months of Screening if single dose received, or within 12&#xD;
             months of Screening if multiple doses received&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. History of gene therapy or cell transplantation or any other experimental brain&#xD;
             surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Obstructive hydrocephalus&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Presence of a functional ventriculoperitoneal shunt for the drainage of CSF or an&#xD;
             implanted CNS catheter&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known brain or spinal disease that would interfere with the LP process, CSF&#xD;
             circulation or safety assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Hospitalization for any major medical or surgical procedure involving general&#xD;
             anesthesia within 12 weeks prior to Screening or planned during the study&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Have any other conditions, which, in the opinion of the Investigator would make the&#xD;
             patient unsuitable for inclusion, or could interfere with the patient participating in&#xD;
             or completing the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ionis Pharmaceuticals</last_name>
    <phone>(844) 514-7157</phone>
    <email>ionisNCT04849741study@clinicaltrialmedia.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Lucile Packard Children's Hospital Stanford</name>
      <address>
        <city>Palo Alto</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>94304</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erika Shols</last_name>
      <phone>650-497-0873</phone>
      <email>eshols@stanford.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IONIS Investigative Site (Will be initially recruiting children only)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30329</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IONIS Investigative Site (Will be initially recruiting children only)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Chicago</city>
        <state>Illinois</state>
        <zip>60611</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mass General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Haley Andonian</last_name>
      <phone>617-724-1379</phone>
      <email>handonian@partners.org</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Hospital of Philadelphia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Philadelphia</city>
        <state>Pennsylvania</state>
        <zip>19104</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Geraldine Liu</last_name>
      <phone>267-425-2063</phone>
      <email>liug@chop.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IONIS Investigative Site (Will be initially recruiting children only)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Houston</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IONIS Investigative Site (Will be initially recruiting children only)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Vancouver</city>
        <state>British Columbia</state>
        <zip>V6H3N1</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>McGill University Health Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Montreal</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>H3A 0G4</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <phone>514-412-4400 ext 23380</phone>
      <email>bernardlab.neuropediatrics@mcgill.ca</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Amsterdam Universitair Medische Centra - Academisch Medisch Centrum</name>
      <address>
        <city>Amsterdam</city>
        <state>Noord-Holland</state>
        <zip>1105 AZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marjo van der Knaap</last_name>
      <phone>+31205667508</phone>
      <email>ms.vanderknaap@amsterdamumc.nl</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 19, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>AxD</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Alexander Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

