<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04844021</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>R01MH123491</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>R01MH123491</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04844021</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Adolescent Suicide Prevention in Routine Clinical Encounters</brief_title>
  <acronym>ASPIRE</acronym>
  <official_title>A Comparative Effectiveness Trial of Strategies to Implement Firearm Safety Promotion as a Universal Suicide Prevention Strategy in Pediatric Primary Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The objective of this study is to compare two approaches to implement an evidence-based&#xD;
      firearm safety promotion program, SAFE Firearm, in pediatric primary care as a universal&#xD;
      suicide prevention strategy. The first implementation approach is a prompt in the electronic&#xD;
      health record (EHR; Nudge) reminding clinicians to discuss firearm safety and to offer a free&#xD;
      cable firearm lock during the pediatric well visit. The second implementation approach&#xD;
      (Nudge+) includes both the EHR Nudge described above plus one year of support to the clinics&#xD;
      in deploying the program (i.e., practice facilitation). The study also aims to identify how&#xD;
      these strategies work and whether the SAFE Firearm program results in reduced unauthorized&#xD;
      access to firearms by young people. The investigators hypothesize that more parents will&#xD;
      report that their clinician delivered SAFE Firearm to them in Nudge+ clinics vs. Nudge&#xD;
      clinics.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will conduct a hybrid type III effectiveness-implementation trial using a&#xD;
      longitudinal cluster randomized design to test the most effective way to implement SAFE&#xD;
      Firearm among 32 clinics, 151 clinicians, and 38,989 youth nested in two Mental Health&#xD;
      Research Network (MHRN) health systems in Michigan and Colorado. Clinics will be randomized&#xD;
      to receive either the EHR implementation strategy (Nudge) or the EHR implementation strategy&#xD;
      plus 1 year of facilitation to target implementation barriers (Nudge+). The investigators&#xD;
      will collect implementation outcomes for 6 months before exposure to condition (i.e.,&#xD;
      pre-implementation or pre-exposure) and for 1 year following (i.e., sustainment) to allow for&#xD;
      comparisons between (a) the active and pre-exposure periods and (b) the active and&#xD;
      sustainment periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 1: Examine the effects of Nudge vs. Nudge+ on implementation outcomes. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that in both active conditions, parent-reported clinician fidelity (primary&#xD;
      outcome) will be superior to the pre-exposure period and that Nudge+ will be superior to&#xD;
      Nudge in the active period. The investigators will assess implementation strategy cost. The&#xD;
      investigators will also examine parent-reported clinician fidelity during a follow-up period&#xD;
      to evaluate sustainment, and the investigators hypothesize that Nudge and Nudge+ will be&#xD;
      equivalent after the interventions are removed but that both will remain superior to the&#xD;
      pre-exposure period with respect to fidelity. The investigators also hypothesize that Nudge+&#xD;
      will result in greater patient reach (i.e., EHR-documented program delivery), cable lock&#xD;
      distribution, and acceptability compared with Nudge (secondary outcomes) in both the active&#xD;
      and sustainment periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 2: Use mixed methods to identify implementation strategy mechanisms. The investigators&#xD;
      hypothesize that Nudge+ will have a stronger effect because it will improve clinic adaptive&#xD;
      reserve (i.e., the ability to make and sustain change). The investigators will also&#xD;
      investigate the role of intrinsic and extrinsic motivation. The investigators hypothesize&#xD;
      that clinician attitudes towards suicide prevention, implementation climate, and leadership&#xD;
      will moderate implementation strategy effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Aim 3: Examine the effects of the adapted intervention on clinical outcomes. The&#xD;
      investigators hypothesize that in both active conditions, parent-reported firearm storage&#xD;
      will be superior to the pre-exposure period. Nudge+ will result in greater safe storage&#xD;
      compared with Nudge. The investigators will explore rates of youth suicide attempts, deaths,&#xD;
      and unintentional firearm injury and mortality by implementation condition and across time.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The investigators will randomize clinics to the active implementation conditions (Nudge [k = 16] or Nudge+ [k = 16]). Clinicians in clinics assigned to both conditions will deliver the safe firearm storage program to patients during well-child visits.&#xD;
Clinicians from all participating clinics, regardless of study arm, will be invited to participate in surveys and interviews.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Health Services Research</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fidelity</measure>
    <time_frame>surveys collected from parents within one week of well-child visit. Surveys will be collected during the duration of the pre-implementation, active implementation, and sustainment phases (30 months total)</time_frame>
    <description>Whether the clinician followed the two SAFE Firearm steps (counseling and offering cable lock), measured via parent-report</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reach</measure>
    <time_frame>EHR data on reach will be extracted for the time period: the beginning of the pre-implementation period through the sustainment period (30 months total)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of parent-youth dyads who receive the safe firearm program divided by number of eligible parent-youth dyads (extracted from EHR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parent-reported acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>Parent surveys will be collected from parents within one week of well-child visit from pre-implementation through sustainment (30 months total)</time_frame>
    <description>Parent-report of acceptability of the SAFE Firearm program. Parents will be asked to answer questions pertaining to the acceptability of program components from the Acceptability of Intervention Measure (AIM; Weiner et al., 2017), which measures acceptability. Each of the four items in the measure are rated on a 1-5 scale (i.e., total score range is 4-20), with higher scores indicating higher acceptability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinician-reported acceptability</measure>
    <time_frame>Clinician surveys will be collected at two time points during the study period: during pre-implementation (surveys will be administered for approximately 1 month) and during active implementation (surveys will be administered for approximately 1 month)</time_frame>
    <description>Clinician-report of acceptability of the SAFE Firearm program. Acceptability of the implementation strategies - EHR nudge and facilitation - will be collected from clinicians as well. Clinicians will be asked whether they found various components of the program and implementation strategies acceptable, and will answer &quot;yes&quot; or &quot;no&quot; to each question about acceptability. Clinicians also will be asked to answer questions pertaining to the program components and implementation strategies from the Acceptability of Intervention Measure (AIM; Weiner et al., 2017), which measures acceptability. Each of the four items in the measure are rated on a 1-5 scale (i.e., total score range is 4-20), with higher scores indicating higher acceptability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cost</measure>
    <time_frame>Cost data will be collected from pre-implementation through sustainment (30 months total)</time_frame>
    <description>Cost of the implementation strategies (EHR nudge, facilitation) and the SAFE Firearm program delivery. Data on the cost of implementing the program (e.g., costs for printing program materials and distributing firearm locks) and the implementation strategies (e.g., facilitator full-time equivalent [FTE] time) will be collected to estimate the overall cost of the program and implementation strategy delivery.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Distribution of cable locks</measure>
    <time_frame>Cable lock distribution data will be collected from active implementation through sustainment (24 months total)</time_frame>
    <description>Number of cable locks distributed from each clinic will be collected</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">23484</enrollment>
  <condition>Suicide</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nudge</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Clinics randomized to the Nudge condition will receive the EHR prompt only. The investigators will add default language to the standard Well Child Visit workflow to serve as a reminder and allow for tracking of SAFE Firearm implementation. The clinician will be asked to denote whether the program was delivered (e.g., whether conversation around firearm storage was conducted, whether cable firearm lock was offered) to the patient during the visit. This EHR prompt will remain turned &quot;on&quot; from active implementation through the sustainment period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nudge+</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>This arm consists of Nudge as described above, as well as facilitation. Facilitation (i.e., external support delivered by health system employees not employed within the clinic site) will be offered for 12 months to each clinic, in keeping with other implementation trials. The investigators will use a train-the-trainer model to train facilitators at both health systems to ensure they achieve facilitator core competencies with an eye toward implementation of SAFE Firearm. The role of the facilitator is to engage with study clinics, to assist each clinic in setting change and performance goals around the implementation of SAFE Firearm, and to troubleshoot implementation barriers.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nudge</intervention_name>
    <description>EHR-based &quot;nudge&quot;</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nudge</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nudge+</intervention_name>
    <description>EHR-based &quot;nudge&quot; plus facilitation</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nudge+</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Parents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents and/or legal guardians at participating pediatric clinics who have a child age&#xD;
             5-17 who attends a well visit. At least one parent must attend the well visit to be&#xD;
             eligible. The parent must be at least 18 years old to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Parents&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Due to translation costs and challenges of recruiting non-US resident participants,&#xD;
             respectively, non-English speaking parents and non-US resident parents will not be&#xD;
             eligible to participate at Henry Ford Health System.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria: Clinicians and leaders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pediatric physicians and non-physician clinicians employed within the participating&#xD;
             pediatric clinics, as well as health system leaders employed within the two health&#xD;
             systems, are eligible to participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria: Clinicians and leaders&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  n/a&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rinad S Beidas, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>215-746-1759</phone>
    <email>rinad.beidas@pennmedicine.upenn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 14, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>implementation</keyword>
  <keyword>fidelity</keyword>
  <keyword>facilitation</keyword>
  <keyword>firearm</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Suicide</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

