<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04842643</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAK-664-3002</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1265-9447</secondary_id>
    <secondary_id>jRCT2041210006</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04842643</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Extension Study of TAK-664 for Japanese People With Primary Immunodeficiency Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3, Open-label, Non-controlled, Multi-dose, Extension Study to Evaluate the Long-term Safety and Tolerability of IGSC, 20% in Japanese Subjects With Primary Immunodeficiency Disease (PID)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is an extension study for participants with primary immunodeficiency disorders who&#xD;
      were previously treated with IGSC, 20% in the TAK-664-3001 study. They must have completed&#xD;
      that study or be about to complete it before joining this study. Participants will continue&#xD;
      treatment with IGCS, 20% in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main aim of this study is to check for side effects from long-term treatment with IGSC,&#xD;
      20% . This medicine is not yet licensed in Japan, so participants will be treated with IGSC,&#xD;
      20% until it becomes commercially available.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants with Treatment Emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment emergent adverse events are defined as AEs with onset after date/time of first dose of study drug in Study-TAK-664-3001, or medical conditions present prior to the start of study drug Study-TAK-664-3001 but increased in severity or relationship after date/time of first dose of study drug in Study-TAK-664-3001. An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation subject administered a drug; it does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. An AE can therefore be any unfavorable and unintended sign (eg, a clinically significant abnormal laboratory value), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a drug whether or not it is considered related to the drug. Number of participants with TEAEs will be assessed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Trough Levels of Immune Globulin G (IgG) Antibodies Following Weekly Administration of IGSC, 20%</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Every 12 weeks after first dose up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Serum trough levels of IgG antibodies measured during treatment after Epoch 2 of the previous study will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Trough Levels of IgG Subclasses Following Weekly Administration of IGSC, 20%</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Every 12 weeks after first dose up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Serum trough levels of IgG subclasses measured during treatment after Epoch 2 of the previous study will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Trough Levels of IgG Antibodies Following Biweekly Administration of IGSC, 20%</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Every 12 weeks after first dose up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Serum trough levels of IgG antibodies measured during treatment after Epoch 3 of the previous study will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Trough Levels of IgG Subclasses Following Biweekly Administration of IGSC, 20%</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Every 12 weeks after first dose up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Serum trough levels of IgG subclasses measured during treatment after Epoch 3 of the previous study will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Annual Rate of Validated Acute Serious Bacterial Infections (ASBI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>The ASBI rate will be calculated as the mean number of ASBI per participants per year. Annual rate of validated ASBI per participant will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Annual Rate of All Infections</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Annual rate is the number of participants reporting any infection per year.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Days Participants not Able to Attend School or Work to Perform Normal Daily Activities due to Illness/Infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days not able to attend school or work to perform normal daily activities due to illness/infection will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Days Participants on Antibiotics</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days participants on antibiotics will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Hospitalizations due to Illness or Infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospitalizations due to illness or infection will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of Hospital Stay due to Illness or Infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of days due to illness or infection will be assessed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Acute Physician Visits due to Illness/Infection</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Up to 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Number of acute (urgent or unscheduled) physician visits due to illness/infection will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment Preference</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, End of study (2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Treatment preference questionnaire is a self-administered questionnaire developed to assess participants' preference towards the administration of new IGSC therapy. There are 4-items on the questionnaire, which investigate a participant's preference on the clinic/hospital/home setting of receiving the immunoglobulin therapy, the participant's rating on the frequency and method of administration, and the participant's preference to continue receiving the IGSC treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Primary Immunodeficiency Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Epoch 2 in previous study: Immune Globulin Subcutaneous 20% Solution (IGSC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive between 50 and 200 mg/kg of Immunoglobulin Globulin subcutaneous (IGSC) infusion, 20 percent (%) once a week until the study drug becomes commercially available (approximately 2 years). All participants of this arm will have assigned Epoch 2 of previous study (TAK-664-3001). The dose of IGSC will be established in previous study.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Epoch 3 in previous study: Immune Globulin Subcutaneous 20% Solution (IGSC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive between 100 and 400 mg/kg of Immunoglobulin Globulin subcutaneous (IGSC) infusion, 20 percent (%) once every 2 weeks until the study drug becomes commercially available (approximately 2 years). All participants of this arm will have assigned Epoch 3 of previous study (TAK-664-3001).The dose of IGSC will be established in previous study (TAK-664-3001).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>IGSC 20% infusion</intervention_name>
    <description>IGSC 20% infusion, The dose of IGSC will be established in previous study (TAK-664-3001)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Epoch 2 in previous study: Immune Globulin Subcutaneous 20% Solution (IGSC)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Epoch 3 in previous study: Immune Globulin Subcutaneous 20% Solution (IGSC)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Immune Globulin Infusion (Human)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant has completed or is about to complete Takeda Clinical Study TAK-664-3001.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Written informed consent is obtained from either the Participant or the Participant's&#xD;
             legally authorized representative prior to any study-related procedures and study&#xD;
             product administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Participant is willing and able to comply with the requirements of the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participant has developed a new serious medical condition during participation in&#xD;
             Study TAK-664-3001 such that the Participant's safety or medical care would be&#xD;
             impacted by participation in the extension study TAK-664-3002.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Participant is scheduled to participate in another non-Takeda clinical study involving&#xD;
             an Investigational Product or investigational device in the course of this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. If a female of childbearing potential, Participant is pregnant or has a negative&#xD;
             pregnancy test but does not agree to employ adequate birth control measures for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Contact</last_name>
    <phone>+1-877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medinfoUS@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nagoya University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nagoya</city>
        <state>Aichi</state>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Completed</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kurume University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kurume</city>
        <state>Fukuoka</state>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kanazawa University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kanazawa</city>
        <state>Ishikawa</state>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National defense medical college Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tokorozawa</city>
        <state>Saitama</state>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Kyushu University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Fukuoka</city>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Completed</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Gifu University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Gifu</city>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Active, not recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hiroshima University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hiroshima</city>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Tokyo Medical Dental University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tokyo</city>
        <country>Japan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Japan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.takeda.com/study-detail/60769026688ad8001f42fb97</url>
    <description>To obtain more information on the study, click here/on this link</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Primary Immunodeficiency Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Immunologic Deficiency Syndromes</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Immunoglobulins</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual participant data from this particular study will not be shared as there is a reasonable likelihood that individual patients could be re-identified (due to the limited number of study participants/study sites).</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

