<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02772640</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AMI9</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02772640</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of Treatment of Hypercholesterolemia With Rosuvastatin and Ezetimibe</brief_title>
  <acronym>ROSEZE</acronym>
  <official_title>The Impact of the Time of Drug Administration on the Effectiveness of Combined Treatment of Hypercholesterolemia With ROSuvastatin and EZEtimibe (ROSEZE) - A Single-center, Crossover, Open-label Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Collegium Medicum w Bydgoszczy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Collegium Medicum w Bydgoszczy</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to demonstrate, whether the time of day of administration of the&#xD;
      study drug (containing rosuvastatin and ezetimibe) has an impact on the effectiveness of&#xD;
      lipid-lowering therapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The current guidelines recommend statins as drugs of first choice in the treatment of&#xD;
      hypercholesterolemia. If the target LDL cholesterol is not achieved, combination of a statin&#xD;
      with a cholesterol absorption inhibitor -ezetimibe may be considered.&#xD;
&#xD;
      According to meta-analyzes of studies assessing statins, each 1.0 mmol / L (~ 40 mg / dL)&#xD;
      reduction in LDL-C corresponds to a 10% reduction in all-cause mortality and a 20% reduction&#xD;
      in the number of deaths from coronary artery disease. Each 1 mmol / L (40 mg / dL) reduction&#xD;
      in LDL-C also translates into a 23% and 17% reduction of the risk of major coronary events&#xD;
      and stroke, respectively. Similar results concerning the efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      lipid-lowering therapy using statins were obtained in meta-analyzes of studies on primary&#xD;
      prevention. Statins are a heterogenous group of drugs with respect to their LDL-C reduction&#xD;
      power. So far, the most potent statin is rosuvastatin. Despite intensive statin therapy&#xD;
      provided, a large group of patients still does not reach therapeutic goals. Statin dose&#xD;
      titration seems to be less effective compared with the combined therapy with statin and&#xD;
      ezetimibe. The combination of statin with ezetimibe reduces the LDL-C by additional 15-20%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Tablets comprising both of these drugs (statin and ezetimibe) simplify the drug&#xD;
      administration and increase the probability of drug compliance. This may increase the&#xD;
      probability for achieving therapeutic goals in hypercholesterolemia treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Taking into account the metabolism of cholesterol and possible drug-drug interactions it is&#xD;
      recommended to administer simvastatin in the evening. Rosuvastatin may be administer at any&#xD;
      time of the day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is designed as an open-label, single-center, cross-over study evaluating the&#xD;
      effectiveness of combined therapy with rosuvastatin and ezetimibe for hypercholesterolemia&#xD;
      depending on timing of the day of administration of the study treatment. After enrollment the&#xD;
      participants will be allocated into two arms, each receiving rosuvastatin and ezetimibe. The&#xD;
      study drug (rosuvastatin with ezetimibe) will be given: 1) in the morning (8:00) for 6 weeks&#xD;
      and then in the evening for the next 6 weeks; 2) in the evening (20:00) for the first 6 weeks&#xD;
      and then in the morning for the following 6 weeks. The change in total cholesterol and&#xD;
      LDL-cholesterol at 6 and 12 weeks of the tested therapy will be measured as the primary&#xD;
      outcome of the study. Moreover, other parameters including: HDL-cholesterol, triglycerides,&#xD;
      apolipoprotein B (ApoB), ApoAI, nonHDL-cholesterol, sd-LDL-cholesterol, lipoprotein (a),&#xD;
      glucose, HBA1c, high sensitivity C reactive protein (hsCRP), ALT, aspartate aminotransferase&#xD;
      (AST), creatine kinase (CK ) will be assessed as secondary outcomes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">May 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in total cholesterol and LDL-Cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in total cholesterol and LDL-Cholesterol at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in HDL-Cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in HDL-Cholesterol at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in triglycerides</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in triglycerides at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in apolipoproteins ApoB, APO AI</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in apolipoproteins ApoB, APO AI at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in non - HDL-Cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in non - HDL-Cholesterol at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in sd-LDL-Cholesterol</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in sd-LDL-Cholesterol at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in lipoprotein (a)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in lipoprotein (a) at 6 and 12 weeks of study drug treatment (combination of ezetimibe and rosuvastatin), depending on the time of day of study drug administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of change of glucose concentration</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of glucose at baseline and at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of HbA1c at baseline and at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of hsCRP</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment hsCRP at baseline and at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of ALT</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment ALT at baseline and at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of AST</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment AST at baseline and at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of CK</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment CK at baseline and at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of plasma fluorescence using stationary and time-resolved spectrofluorimetry</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 6 and 12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of plasma fluorescence using stationary and time-resolved spectrofluorimetry at baseline, at 6 and 12 weeks of treatment with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">83</enrollment>
  <condition>Hypercholesterolemia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I: R+E morning-&gt;evening</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rosuvastatin and Ezetimibe morning or evening administration: Rosuvastatin (R) plus Ezetimibe (E) administration in the morning (8:00) for 6 weeks. After 6 weeks - intervention - change of the timing of study drug administration to the evening hours (20:00).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ARM II: R+E evening-&gt;morning</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Rosuvastatin and Ezetimibe evening or morning administration: Rosuvastatin (R) plus Ezetimibe (E) administration in the evening (20:00) for 6 weeks. After 6 weeks - intervention - change of the timing of study drug administration to the morning hours (8:00).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Rosuvastatin and Ezetimibe morning or evening administration</intervention_name>
    <description>Timing of the drug administration:&#xD;
morning -&gt; evening evening -&gt; morning</description>
    <arm_group_label>ARM II: R+E evening-&gt;morning</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Arm I: R+E morning-&gt;evening</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Rosuvastatin, Ezetimibe</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hypercholesterolemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Ineffectiveness of statin monotherapy in the treatment of hypercholesterolemia after&#xD;
             at least 6 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Active liver disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Unexplained persistent increase in serum transaminase levels, including more than 3&#xD;
             times the upper limit of normal activity of one of them&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Severe renal impairment (creatinine clearance &lt;30 ml / min)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Myopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Concomitant treatment with cyclosporine, gemfibrozil&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Lactation&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Women of childbearing age not using effective methods of contraception&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Symptoms of muscle damage after using statins or fibrates in the past.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. The activity of creatine kinase&gt; 5 times the upper limit of normal&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jacek Kubica, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Collegium Medicum w Bydgoszczy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Cardiology Department, Dr. A. Jurasz University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bydgoszcz</city>
        <state>Kujawsko-Pomorskie</state>
        <zip>85-094</zip>
        <country>Poland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Poland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://journals.viamedica.pl/cardiology_journal/article/view/CJ.a2020.0166/52446</url>
    <description>Study results</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 28, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 12, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 13, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Collegium Medicum w Bydgoszczy</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jacek Kubica</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor Jacek Kubica MD, PhD.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Hypercholesterolemia</keyword>
  <keyword>Rosuvastatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Statin</keyword>
  <keyword>Ezetimibe</keyword>
  <keyword>Compliance</keyword>
  <keyword>Cholesterol</keyword>
  <keyword>Secondary prevention</keyword>
  <keyword>Coronary artery disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Cholesterol absorption inhibitor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hypercholesterolemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rosuvastatin Calcium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ezetimibe</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

