<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT02775994</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0032-16-RMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT02775994</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Ilaris (Canakinumab) in Patient With Periodic Fever, Aphthous Stomatitis, Pharyngitis and Cervical Adenitis (PFAPA)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Ilaris (Canakinumab) in Patient With Periodic Fever, Aphthous Stomatitis, Pharyngitis and Cervical Adenitis (PFAPA)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rabin Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Rabin Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Periodic Fever, Aphthous stomatitis, Pharyngitis and cervical Adenitis (PFAPA) is one of the&#xD;
      most common, least explored periodic fever syndrome in childhood. This study aims to&#xD;
      investigate whether a single dose of an interleukin beta (IL-1) antagonist, Canakinumab will&#xD;
      be able to abort PFAPA flares in patients who experience a flare in an average of 2 weeks or&#xD;
      less. This will be a single arm open label pilot study. 10 patients will be recruited from 1&#xD;
      center (Pediatric rheumatology unit -Schneider children's medical center of Israel).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients in ages 2-10 years old who are diagnosed with PFAPA according to clinical criteria&#xD;
      at least 3 months prior to enrollment and who are under regular care for this disease (single&#xD;
      dose of glucocorticoids during flare) and who suffer from more than 4 PFAPA flares for the&#xD;
      last 2 months, will be screened for this study. In the second documented flare, patients will&#xD;
      be enrolled to receive a single dose of subcutaneous (SC) Canakinumab 4 mg/kg. The primary&#xD;
      outcome is defined as - 50% reduction in PFAPA flares for the next 2 consecutive months as&#xD;
      reported by the patient (use of diary) and documented by the patient primary care physician&#xD;
      and/ or the researcher in a monthly follow up visits. Secondary outcome measure are define as&#xD;
      time to flare (days) and Parent/patient quality of life assessment measured by 100mm visual&#xD;
      analog scale (VAS).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Study Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary objective: Patients will experience at least 50% reduction in PFAPA flares for the&#xD;
      next 2 consecutive months after receiving single dose of canakinumab (4 mg/kg).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Time to flare&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Parent/patient quality of life assessment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study rationale:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Periodic Fever, Aphthous stomatitis, Pharyngitis and cervical Adenitis (PFAPA) is one of the&#xD;
      most common, least explored periodic fever syndrome in childhood. It was discovered only in&#xD;
      1987 by Marshall et al. who noticed periodic attacks of fever along with pharyngitis and&#xD;
      cervical adenitis mimicking streptococcal acute tonsillitis. Many of these patients were&#xD;
      erroneously treated with antibiotic despite negative throat cultures. The exact prevalence of&#xD;
      this syndrome is not known but PFAPA seems to be far more frequent than other&#xD;
      auto-inflammatory diseases . Since PFAPA has an unknown etiology and lacks a specific&#xD;
      laboratory marker, the diagnosis is made by using clinical criteria which include more than&#xD;
      three documented episodes of fever, lasting no more than five days and occurring at regular&#xD;
      intervals at a range of three to six weeks, pharyngitis plus tender cervical lymphadenopathy&#xD;
      or aphthous ulcers, normal growth parameters and good health between episodes . Single dose&#xD;
      of glucocorticoids usually leads to prompt resolution of the disease. Their usefulness as&#xD;
      therapy, however, is limited by the fact that glucocorticoid treatment results in shortening&#xD;
      the interval between attacks in about 30 percent of case up to even weekly attacks.&#xD;
      Prophylaxis therapy with cimetidine or colchicine has limited value and most children do not&#xD;
      respond. Some physicians will try to use them, mainly in patients who suffer from frequent&#xD;
      attacks despite glucocorticoids therapy as the last resort before tonsillectomy, however,&#xD;
      many children eventually will undergo tonsillectomy which, in many cases, does not prevent&#xD;
      the attacks and may cause morbidity and even mortality. The pathogenesis of PFAPA is still&#xD;
      not fully understood. However, the rapid response to corticosteroid treatment suggests an&#xD;
      immune dysregulation. Recent studies suggest, as in other autoinflammatory syndromes, an&#xD;
      essential role of the innate immune system by activation of the inflammasome during fever&#xD;
      attacks which leads to production of Interleukin 1 along with other proinflammatory cytokines&#xD;
      and chemokines and indeed, treatment with anakinra has been reported to cause remission in an&#xD;
      adult patient with resistant PFAPA and is in clinical use in several medical centers in the&#xD;
      US.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Timelines and Study duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Start date: within 2 months after Helsinki committee approval- estimated first patient first&#xD;
      visit (FPFV) -1 month Estimated Last Patient Last treatment (LPLT) last patient first&#xD;
      treatment (LPFT)/last patient (LP) enrollment - 6 months End date: 6 months after last&#xD;
      patient enrollment Once enrolled, patients will receive a single dose of Canakinumab and then&#xD;
      will be followed for a period of a total 24 weeks after receiving Canakinumab - weekly during&#xD;
      the first month and then monthly for the next 5 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Report date: within 4 month after Last Patient Last Visit. Publication date: within 10&#xD;
      month after Last Patient Last Visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a single arm open label pilot study. This study will be approved by our&#xD;
      institutional and national Helsinki committees. Patients in ages 2-10 years old who are&#xD;
      diagnosed with PFAPA according to clinical criteria at least 3 months prior to enrollment and&#xD;
      who are under regular care for this disease (single dose of glucocorticoids during flare) and&#xD;
      who suffer from more than 4 PFAPA flares for the last 2 months, will be screened for this&#xD;
      study. Patients with another chronic disease, neutropenia, elevated liver enzymes or in which&#xD;
      the diagnosis of PFAPA is in doubt, will be excluded. In addition patients that receive&#xD;
      treatment with cimetidine/famotidine, montelukast or colchicine will undergo a washout period&#xD;
      of 2 weeks (see appendix).&#xD;
&#xD;
      . Screening period: After signing the informed consent and filling demographic and clinical&#xD;
      questionnaires, the patient will enter a screening period of one month. At the screening&#xD;
      visit, participants will undergo purified protein derivative (PPD) test to rule out&#xD;
      tuberculosis and laboratory workup which includes: Complete blood count (CBC), full chemistry&#xD;
      panel, erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR), C reactive protein (CRP) and urinalysis. During&#xD;
      this period, the first PFAPA flare will be treated with a single dose of oral glucocorticoids&#xD;
      (which is given as part of their regular care) and the response will be documented by the PI&#xD;
      or co-PI in a formal study visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrolment: In the second documented flare, patients will be enrolled to receive a single dose&#xD;
      of SC Canakinumab 4 mg/kg. Treatment with glucocorticoids during the second flare will not be&#xD;
      allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients who have less than 2 flares during the screening period will have the option to be&#xD;
      enrolled in the next consecutive month as long as they have 2 documented PFAPA flares at that&#xD;
      month. Patients, who fail to flare in that phase as well, will be censored (screening&#xD;
      failure).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Once a patient experiences a flare after the administration of canakinumab, He will be&#xD;
      treated according to the clinician/ researcher decision (e.g. - a dose of corticosteroids).&#xD;
      All flares will be documented during the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Number of centers &amp; patients: 10 patients will be recruited from 1 center (Pediatric&#xD;
      rheumatology unit -Schneider children's medical center of Israel). Potential patients from&#xD;
      other pediatric rheumatology clinics around the country will be referred to our clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size justification: This is a pilot study and it is not powered for statistical&#xD;
      significance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Key inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients in ages 2-10 years old who are diagnosed with PFAPA at least 3 months prior to&#xD;
           enrollment according to clinical criteria will be screened for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Suffer from more than 4 PFAPA flares 2 months prior to the screening period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Have signed informed consent for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Have at least 2 documented PFAPA flare during the screening period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Key exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Patients who are diagnosed with chronic disease including another auto inflammatory&#xD;
           disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Patients who suffer from neutropenia or elevated liver enzymes.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Patients who receive treatment with cimetidine/famotidine, montelukast or colchicine 2&#xD;
           weeks or less prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pharmacovigilance requirements:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Definition of an AE: Any untoward medical occurrence in a subject administered a&#xD;
      pharmaceutical product that does not necessarily have a causal relationship with the&#xD;
      treatment. An AE can therefore be any unfavorable and unintended sign (including an abnormal&#xD;
      laboratory finding), symptom, or disease temporally associated with the use of a medicinal&#xD;
      (investigational) product, whether or not considered related to the investigational medicinal&#xD;
      product.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Investigational Medicinal Product (IMP) includes the drug under evaluation and the comparator&#xD;
      drug(s) if specified as part of the research objective, given at any time during the study.&#xD;
      Medical conditions/diseases present before starting the drug of interest are only considered&#xD;
      adverse events if they worsen after starting the drug of interest.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The occurrence of adverse events will be sought by non-directive questioning of the patient&#xD;
      at each visit during the study. Adverse events also may be detected when they are volunteered&#xD;
      by the patient during or between visits or through physical examination, laboratory test, or&#xD;
      other assessments. All adverse events will be recorded in the study database including the&#xD;
      following information:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. severity grade (mild, moderate, severe)&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. its relationship to the drug(s) of interest (suspected/not suspected)&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. its duration (start and end dates or if continuing at final exam)&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. whether it constitutes a serious adverse event (SAE)&#xD;
&#xD;
      A SAE is any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  results in death,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  is life-threatening,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  is a congenital anomaly/birth defect,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  is otherwise a significant medical event. This includes any SAEs likely to arise from&#xD;
           the trial indication or progression of underlying/concomitant illness (e.g. progression&#xD;
           of cancer in oncology trials), unless specified in the protocol as study specific&#xD;
           exemptions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any SAE, irrespective of causality, occurring after the subject has provided informed consent&#xD;
      and until four weeks after the subject has stopped study participation must be reported&#xD;
      unless otherwise stated in the protocol. SAEs occurring after four weeks from ending study&#xD;
      participation should only be reported if considered by the Investigator attributable to the&#xD;
      exposure to the investigational drug(s) during the trial period. This includes the period in&#xD;
      which the study protocol interferes with the standard medical treatment given to a subject,&#xD;
      even if study treatment has not yet started (e.g. withdrawal of previous treatment during&#xD;
      washout period, change in treatment to a fixed dose of concomitant medication).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Timelines: All serious adverse events (SAEs) from interventional clinical trials must be&#xD;
      reported by the sites to Sponsor within 24 hours of occurrence of the SAE. The timelines for&#xD;
      investigator initiated trials reporting to Novartis will be done as per Third Party&#xD;
      Study/Investigator Initiated Trial Agreement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up reports:&#xD;
&#xD;
      SAEs will be followed until resolution or until it is judged to be permanent, and an&#xD;
      assessment will be made at each visit (or more frequently, if necessary) of any changes in&#xD;
      severity, the suspected relationship to the drug of interest, the interventions required to&#xD;
      treat it, and the outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Sponsor shall support Novartis in the following-up of all SAEs so that complete&#xD;
      information is available to maintain patient safety and also as part of any commitments by&#xD;
      Novartis to any Health authority OR specific Health authority follow-up requests for the&#xD;
      product under investigation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pregnancies: N/A&#xD;
&#xD;
      Evaluation criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary endpoint:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Efficacy measure - 50% reduction in PFAPA flares for the next 2 consecutive months as&#xD;
      reported by the patient (use of diary) and documented by the patient primary care physician&#xD;
      and/ or the researcher in a monthly follow up visits. This will be compared to the average&#xD;
      number of flares (per 2 months) during the last 3 consecutive months before therapy (i.e&#xD;
      number of flares in last 3 months before therapy divided by 3 and multiplied by 2).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Secondary endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Time to flare (period between administration of a single dose of canakinumab until the&#xD;
           first documented PFAPA flare. Will be compared to the average time between 2 consecutive&#xD;
           flares before therapy (e.g.: first documented flare- will be day 1. In the following 90&#xD;
           days 5 more flares ( 3 before screening and 2 after)= 90/5= 18d mean time to flare).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Parent/patient quality of life assessment measured by 100mm visual analog scale (VAS)&#xD;
           difference at screening vs. 2 months after administration of a single dose of&#xD;
           canakinumab.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 2016</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in average number of flares - documented by the use of diary</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline (canakinumab administration) and 2 months after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy measure - 50% reduction in PFAPA flares for the next 2 consecutive months as reported by the patient (use of diary) and documented by the patient primary care physician and/ or the researcher in a monthly follow up visits. This will be compared to the average number of flares (per 2 months) during the last 3 consecutive months before therapy (i.e number of flares in last 3 months before therapy divided by 3 and multiplied by 2).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to flare - documented by the use of diary</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline (canakinumab administration) and up to 24 weeks after baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Time to flare - period between administration of a single dose of canakinumab until the first documented PFAPA flare as reported by the patient (use of diary) and documented by the patient primary care physician and/ or the researcher in a monthly follow up visits. Will be compared to the average time between 2 consecutive flares before therapy (e.g: first documented flare- will be day 1. In the following 90 days 5 more flares (3 before screening and 2 after) = 90/5= 18d mean time to flare).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life - documented by the use of questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>at the time of screening visit and 2 months after baseline (canakinumab administration)</time_frame>
    <description>Parent/patient quality of life assessment measured by 100mm visual analog scale (VAS) difference at screening vs. 2 months after administration of a single dose of canakinumab.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Periodic Fever</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose of Canakinumab 4mg/kg</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Canakinumab</intervention_name>
    <description>interleukin beta (IL-1) antagonist</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment Arm</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Ilaris</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Key inclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients in ages 2-10 years old who are diagnosed with PFAPA at least 3 months prior&#xD;
             to enrollment according to clinical criteria will be screened for this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Suffer from more than 4 PFAPA flares 2 months prior to the screening period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Have signed informed consent for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Have at least 2 documented PFAPA flare during the screening period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Key exclusion criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who are diagnosed with chronic disease including another auto inflammatory&#xD;
             disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who suffer from neutropenia or elevated liver enzymes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients who receive treatment with cimetidine/famotidine, montelukast or colchicine 2&#xD;
             weeks or less prior to enrollment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>2 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>10 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Liora Harel, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>SCMCI</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Liora Harel, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972544334856</phone>
    <email>liorahar@clalit.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gil Amarilyo, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+972504057153</phone>
    <email>gamarilyo@clalit.org.il</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>SCMCI</name>
      <address>
        <city>Petah tikva</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 27, 2016</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 15, 2016</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 18, 2016</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 4, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pharyngitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatitis, Aphthous</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Familial Mediterranean Fever</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyloidosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fever</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

