<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03144999</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HMR-1001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03144999</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Advanced Dry Age Related Macular Degeneration With AAVCAGsCD59</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Open-Label, Multi-Center, Dose-Escalating, Safety and Tolerability Study of a Single Intravitreal Injection of AAVCAGsCD59 in Patients With Advanced Non-Exudative (Dry) Age-Related Macular Degeneration With Geographic Atrophy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Janssen Research &amp; Development, LLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Age related macular degeneration (AMD) is the leading cause of vision loss in individuals&#xD;
      over age 60. AMD is classified as wet and dry. Wet AMD constitutes 10 to 15% of all cases of&#xD;
      AMD and occurs when an abnormal blood vessel grows in or under the retina leading to central&#xD;
      vision loss. Wet AMD is successfully treated with injections in the eye on a monthly basis&#xD;
      that stop the blood vessel from growing and leaking. The most common form of AMD is the dry&#xD;
      variant or dry AMD that affects 85 to 90% of all patients with AMD. In dry AMD, there is loss&#xD;
      of retinal pigment, formation of deposits called drusen, and loss of the vessels in a layer&#xD;
      of the retina called the choriocapillaris. In the most severe forms of dry AMD there is loss&#xD;
      of retinal tissue called geographic atrophy. Over time retinal tissue degenerates in the area&#xD;
      responsible for central vision leading to vision loss leading to legal blindness. Currently&#xD;
      no treatment for dry AMD exists so that there is a significant unmet need in patients with&#xD;
      this ocular disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, evidence has implicated an overactive inflammatory cascade called the complement&#xD;
      system as playing a pivotal role in the development of dry AMD. The complement cascade&#xD;
      consists of 3 arms that converge to form a pore-like complex on the surface of cells called&#xD;
      the membrane attack complex (MAC). Accumulation of MAC on cell surfaces leads to cell damage&#xD;
      and death causing the clinical findings seen in AMD. Normal cells within the human body&#xD;
      produce a protein on their cell surfaces called CD59 that blocks the MAC from forming. In&#xD;
      AMD, the complement cascade is upregulated and leads to more MAC formation than the body can&#xD;
      protect itself against leading to cell destruction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AAVCAGsCD59, an ocular gene therapy product that is injected in to the eye in the physician's&#xD;
      office, causes normal retinal cells to increase the expression of a soluble form of CD59&#xD;
      (sCD59). This soluble recombinant version of the naturally occurring CD59 is designed and&#xD;
      intended to protect retinal cells that are responsible for central vision by inhibiting the&#xD;
      formation of the membrane attack complex (MAC), the terminal step of complement-mediated cell&#xD;
      lysis. In gene therapy the cells of the retina are potentially permanently altered to make&#xD;
      sCD59 for the life of the patient. With gene therapy only one injection is needed for the&#xD;
      drug to be effective for the patient's entire life. This study will evaluate the safety after&#xD;
      a single injection of AAVCAGsCD59 administered in an office setting for patients whose&#xD;
      enrolled eye has advanced dry AMD with geographic atrophy. The initial study is 26 weeks&#xD;
      followed by an additional 18-month safety evaluation.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 29, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 9, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 6, 2017</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a dose escalation study consisting of a low, mid, and high dose to evaluate the maximum tolerated dose (MTD). An additional 8 patients are enrolled at the MTD.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants experiencing ocular and systemic adverse events as graded by CTCAE v4.0</measure>
    <time_frame>26 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Measure intraocular inflammation, ocular changes and systemic side effects following a single intraocular injection of AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the change in area of GA in eyes with dry AMD</measure>
    <time_frame>26 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the rate of growth of GA in eyes with dry AMD</measure>
    <time_frame>26 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of conversion of dry AMD to wet AMD</measure>
    <time_frame>26 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in drusen volume measured by spectral domain OCT</measure>
    <time_frame>26 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevention of loss of 15 or more letters on an ETDRS visual acuity chart</measure>
    <time_frame>26 Weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Efficacy of AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">17</enrollment>
  <condition>Dry Age-related Macular Degeneration</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Mid Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>AAVCAGsCD59</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>AAVCAGsCD59</intervention_name>
    <description>AAVCAGsCD59 is administered as a single intravitreal injection in an office setting</description>
    <arm_group_label>High Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Low Dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Mid Dose</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>HMR59</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Men or women 50 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Advanced dry AMD with GA in the study eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BCVA Snellen equivalent of 20/80 or worse in the study eye using ETDRS charts at a&#xD;
             starting distance of 4m after the first 3 patients are enrolled and demonstrate&#xD;
             favorable safety data&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Total GA lesion size 5mm2 (2 DA) to 20mm2 (8 DA) in the study eye; if multifocal, then&#xD;
             at least one focus of GA needs to measure 1.27 mm2 (0.5 DA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fellow eye BCVA of 20/800 or better and must be the eye with the better visual acuity&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing to undergo paracentesis of the anterior chamber&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GA secondary to non AMD etiologies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior or active choroidal neovascularization (CNV) in the study eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of conditions in the study eye during screening which might alter visual&#xD;
             acuity or interfere with study testing&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active uncontrolled glaucoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intraocular surgery in the study eye within 3 months of enrollment or are known or&#xD;
             likely candidate for intraocular surgery (including cataract surgery) in the study eye&#xD;
             within 1 year of treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acute or chronic infection in the study eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of inflammation in the study eye or ongoing inflammation in either eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of uveitis in the study eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ongoing ocular inflammation in either eye&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any contraindication to intravitreal injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently using or have used treatment for exudative AMD in the study eye only: laser&#xD;
             photocoagulation, photodynamic therapy (PDT), ranibizumab (Lucentis速), pegaptanib&#xD;
             sodium (Macugen速), bevacizumab (Avastin速) or aflibercept (Eylea速)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently using any periocular (study eye), intravitreal (study eye) or systemic (oral&#xD;
             or intravenous) corticosteroids within 3 months prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any of the following underlying systemic diseases:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Unstable or severe cardiovascular disease, e.g., congestive heart failure (New&#xD;
                  York Heart Association Functional class III or IV), myocardial infarction within&#xD;
                  6 months, ventricular tachyarrhythmias requiring ongoing treatment, unstable&#xD;
                  angina, or critical limb ischemia;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Poorly controlled diabetes;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Clinically significant impaired renal or hepatic function, for example:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cerebrovascular disease within 12 months prior to Screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Dementia or neurodegenerative disease (e.g., Alzheimer's disease, Parkinson's&#xD;
                  disease);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Have a malignancy at Screening or a history of malignancy that precludes&#xD;
                  completion of this 2-year study, including presence of tumor or disease whose&#xD;
                  treatment may directly affect the ability to evaluate the safety and efficacy of&#xD;
                  AAVCAGsCD59, or currently undergoing treatment for a specific cancer;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Immunocompromised conditions and/or need for immunosuppressive therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any significant poorly controlled illness that would preclude study compliance and&#xD;
             follow-up&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current or prior use of any medication known to be toxic to the retina or optic nerve&#xD;
             including, but not limited, to chloroquine/hydrochloroquine, deferoxamine,&#xD;
             phenothiazines and ethambutol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous treatment with any ocular or systemic gene transfer product&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received any investigational product within 120 days prior to screening&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>50 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeff Heier, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ophthalmic Consultants of Boston</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ophthalmic Consultants of Boston</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 2, 2017</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 4, 2017</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 9, 2017</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Dry AMD</keyword>
  <keyword>Dry Age-related Macular Degeneration</keyword>
  <keyword>Gene Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Complement</keyword>
  <keyword>Intravitreal Injection</keyword>
  <keyword>Geographic Atrophy</keyword>
  <keyword>Drusen</keyword>
  <keyword>Membrane Attack Complex</keyword>
  <keyword>CD59</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Macular Degeneration</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Geographic Atrophy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

