<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01189513</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2009-0576</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01189513</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SCH-900105 in Recurrent Glioblastoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase I Evaluation of SCH 900105 With Correlative Tissue Studies in the Treatment of Adult Patients With Recurrent Glioblastoma</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Schering-Plough</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>M.D. Anderson Cancer Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The goal of this clinical research study is to find the highest tolerable dose of SCH 900105&#xD;
      that can be given to patients with glioblastoma before surgery. The safety of this drug will&#xD;
      also be studied.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The Study Drug:&#xD;
&#xD;
      SCH 900105 is designed to block the activity of one of the tumor-causing proteins responsible&#xD;
      for the development and uncontrolled growth of tumor cells and the formation of new blood&#xD;
      vessels. This may result in shrinking or stopping tumor growth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will need to take SCH 900105 for 14 days before surgery. If the doctor decides there is a&#xD;
      risk from the delay of surgery, you will not be able to take part in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are found to be eligible to take part in this study, you will be assigned to a dose&#xD;
      level of SCH 900105 based on when you joined this study. Up to 3 dose levels (Dose Levels 0,&#xD;
      1, and 2) of SCH 900105 will be tested before surgery. Three (3) participants will be&#xD;
      enrolled at each dose level. The first group of participants will receive the lowest dose&#xD;
      level (Dose Level 0). Each new group will receive a higher dose than the group before it, if&#xD;
      no intolerable side effects were seen. This will continue until the highest tolerable dose of&#xD;
      SCH 900105 is found.&#xD;
&#xD;
      No matter what dose level you are assigned before surgery, all participants will receive Dose&#xD;
      Level 1 of SCH 900105 after surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The amount of study drug you receive may change if you experience side effects. If at any&#xD;
      time you experience any intolerable side effects, tell the study doctor right away.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Drug Administration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cycle 1 will be 30 days and each following cycle will be 28 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are assigned to Dose Levels 0 or 2, you will receive SCH 900105 by vein over about 1&#xD;
      hour on Days 1, 8, and 15 of Cycle 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If you are assigned to Dose Level 1, you will receive SCH 900105 by vein over about 1 hour on&#xD;
      Days 1 and 15 of Cycle 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As a part of standard of care, you will have a surgery to remove the regrown tumor on Day 16&#xD;
      of Cycle 1. You will sign a separate consent for this surgery, which will describe the&#xD;
      procedure and its risks in detail.&#xD;
&#xD;
      You will not receive SCH 900105 for about 2 weeks after surgery. After 2 weeks, you will&#xD;
      receive SCH 900105 by vein on Days 1 and 15 of each cycle (Cycles 2 and beyond).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      At every visit, you will be asked about any drugs you may be taking and if you have&#xD;
      experienced any side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of Cycle 1, blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine&#xD;
      tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Day 17 of Cycle 1, you will have an MRI scan to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Day 1 of Cycles 2 and beyond:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Your complete medical history will be recorded. You will have a physical exam, including&#xD;
           measurement of your weight and vital signs.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  You will have a neurological exam.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Your performance status will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Day 15 of Cycles 2 and beyond, blood (about 2 teaspoons) will be drawn for routine tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On Day 1 of every other cycle starting Cycle 3 (Cycles 3, 5, 7, and so on), you will have an&#xD;
      MRI scan to check the status of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pharmacokinetic (PK) and Biomarker Tests:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Extra blood will be drawn for PK testing and biomarker testing. PK testing measures the&#xD;
      amount of study drug in the body at different time points. These tests are for research only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood (about 1 teaspoon each time) will be drawn during the following times for PK testing:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  On Day 1 of Cycle 1, blood will be drawn 4 times.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  On Day 15 of Cycle 1, blood will be drawn 3 times.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  On Days 16, 17, and 19 of Cycle 1, blood will be drawn 1 time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  On Day 1 of Cycles 2 and beyond, blood will be drawn 1 time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At 45 and 60 days after the last dose of SCH 900105, blood will be drawn 1 time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If you are assigned to Dose Levels 0 or 2, blood will also be drawn 2 times on Day 8 of&#xD;
           Cycle 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood (about 2 teaspoons each time) will be drawn during the following times for biomarker&#xD;
      testing:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  On Days 1 and 15 of Cycle 1, blood will be drawn 1 time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  On Day 1 of Cycles 2 and beyond, blood will be drawn 1 time.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If you are assigned to Dose Levels 0 or 2, blood will also be drawn 1 time on Day 8 of&#xD;
           Cycle 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Leftover tumor tissue (removed during your surgery on Day 16 of Cycle 1) will be collected&#xD;
      and used for PK tests and biomarker tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Length of Study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      You may continue receiving SCH 900105 for as long as you are benefitting. You will be taken&#xD;
      off study if the disease gets worse or you experience intolerable side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an investigational study. SCH 900105 is not FDA approved or commercially available.&#xD;
      At this time, SCH 900105 is only being used in research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Up to 21 patients will be enrolled in this study. All will be enrolled at M. D. Anderson.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Sponsor decision.&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>August 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Maximum Tolerated Dose (MTD)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days for Cycle 1, and every 28 days for following cycles</time_frame>
    <description>MTD of SCH 900105 defined as the dose level prior to that resulting in dose limiting toxicity (DLT i.e., the dose level at which no more than 1 out of 6 subjects experiences). DLT).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Glioblastoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>SCH 900105</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>10 mg/kg intravenous Days 1, 8 and 15 of 30 day cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SCH 900105</intervention_name>
    <description>10 mg/kg by vein every week on days 1, 8 and 15 of a 30 day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>SCH 900105</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have a diagnosis of supratentorial glioblastoma or gliosarcoma by&#xD;
             pathology review after initial tumor resection and who have radiographic evidence of&#xD;
             recurrent tumor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Eligibility will be restricted to patients in whom the clinical decision has been made&#xD;
             to perform surgery at recurrence for symptom relief or for cytoreduction. Due to the&#xD;
             requirement that SCH 900105 treatment will be given for 15 days prior to surgery, only&#xD;
             patients who are determined to be not at risk from this delay in the best clinical&#xD;
             judgment of the neurosurgeon, the treating neuro-oncologist and the study chair will&#xD;
             be eligible for entry into the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. (2. continued) Patients who are in poor clinical condition as defined by Karnofsky&#xD;
             performance status (KPS) or have progressive symptoms necessitating urgent surgery&#xD;
             will be excluded from this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must have enhancing disease on the MRI scan sufficient to provide tissue&#xD;
             samples for pathological diagnosis &amp; correlative studies AND if the surgical plan&#xD;
             includes resection of this part of the tumor. Patients with radiologically evident&#xD;
             areas of tumor necrosis will be eligible for entry into this study if there is&#xD;
             sufficient non-necrotic tumor to permit tissue correlative studies. The study chair&#xD;
             will make a determination with the help of the treating physician, neuro-radiologist&#xD;
             and neurosurgeon whether a particular patient fulfils the radiological requirements&#xD;
             for study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must have failed prior radiation therapy and must have an interval of greater&#xD;
             than or equal to 12 weeks (84 Days) from the completion of radiation therapy to study&#xD;
             entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients may have had treatment for no more than 3 prior relapses. Relapse is defined&#xD;
             as progression following initial therapy (i.e. radiation +/- chemo if that was used as&#xD;
             initial therapy). The intent therefore is that patients had no more than 4 prior&#xD;
             therapies (initial and treatment for 3 relapses). For patients who had prior therapy&#xD;
             for a low-grade glioma, a prior surgical diagnosis of a high-grade glioma will be&#xD;
             considered the first relapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients must have recovered from the toxic effects of prior therapy at the time of&#xD;
             initiation of the study drug: 4 weeks from any investigational agents, two weeks from&#xD;
             vincristine, 6 weeks from nitrosoureas, 3 weeks from procarbazine administration, 3&#xD;
             weeks for temozolomide, 4 weeks for carboplatin, and 1 week for non-cytotoxic agents,&#xD;
             e.g., interferon, tamoxifen, cis-retinoic acid, etc. (radiosensitizer does not count).&#xD;
             Prior anti-angiogenic therapy is not allowed. For patients who have undergone&#xD;
             radiation therapy (XRT), at least 12 weeks should have elapsed since completion of&#xD;
             XRT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients must be equal to or greater than 18 years of age.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. All patients must sign an informed consent indicating that they are aware of the&#xD;
             investigational nature of this study. Patients must have signed an authorization for&#xD;
             the release of their protected health information.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients must have adequate bone marrow function (absolute granulocyte count &gt;/= 1,500&#xD;
             and platelet count &gt;/= 100,000), normal coagulation profile (PT/PTT), adequate liver&#xD;
             function (SGPT, SGOT, and alkaline phosphatase &lt;/= 2.5 times normal and bilirubin &lt;&#xD;
             1.5 mg/dL), adequate renal function (BUN or creatinine &lt;/= 1.5 times institutional&#xD;
             normal) and institutional normal serum amylase within 14 days prior to starting&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Patients must have a Karnofsky performance status (KPS) of &gt;/= 60.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. All patients (men and women) of childbearing potential must agree to use adequate&#xD;
             birth control (barrier methods) during and for 1 month after participation in this&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative Beta Human Chorionic&#xD;
             Gonadotropin(B-HCG) pregnancy test documented within 14 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. This study was designed to include women and minorities, but was not designed to&#xD;
             measure differences of intervention effects. Males and females will be recruited with&#xD;
             no preference to gender.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Archived paraffin embedded tissue (15 unstained slides) must be available for&#xD;
             confirmation of tumor diagnosis and correlative studies prior to receiving the first&#xD;
             dose of SCH 900105.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have been previously treated with c-Met inhibitors are ineligible for&#xD;
             this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients must not have any significant medical illnesses that in the investigator's&#xD;
             opinion cannot be adequately controlled with appropriate therapy or would compromise&#xD;
             the patient's ability to tolerate this therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients with a history of any other cancer (except non-melanoma skin cancer or&#xD;
             carcinoma in-situ of the cervix), unless in complete remission and off of all therapy&#xD;
             for that disease for a minimum of 3 years are ineligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must not have active infection or with a fever &gt;/= 38.5°C within 3 days prior&#xD;
             to the first dose of SCH 900105.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Patients must not be pregnant/breast feeding during and for 1 month after&#xD;
             participation in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients must not have any disease that will obscure toxicity or dangerously alter&#xD;
             drug metabolism.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients on full-dose anticoagulants (e.g., warfarin, low molecular weight heparin)&#xD;
             for the treatment of deep vein thrombosis(DVT), pulmonary emboli (PE), atrial&#xD;
             fibrillation, myocardial infarction, or any other thromboembolic event are not&#xD;
             eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. No exclusion to this study will be based on race. Minorities will actively be&#xD;
             recruited to participate. The malignant glioma patient population treated at MDACC&#xD;
             over the past year is as follows: American Indian or Alaskan Native - 0; Asian or&#xD;
             Pacific Islander - &lt;2%; Black, not of Hispanic Origin - 3%; Hispanic - 6%; White, not&#xD;
             of Hispanic Origin - 88%; Other or Unknown - 2%; Total - 100%&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The safety profile of SCH 900105 was not established in the pediatric population,&#xD;
             Patients under age 18 will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>John DeGroot, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <removed_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </removed_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.mdanderson.org</url>
    <description>UT MD Anderson Cancer Center website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2012</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 26, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2012</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2012</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">February 20, 2012</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Recurrent Glioblastoma</keyword>
  <keyword>Gliosarcoma</keyword>
  <keyword>SCH 900105</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioblastoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

