<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01188096</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Poly ICLC</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>004385</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01188096</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Trial of Poly-ICLC in the Management of Recurrent Pediatric Low Grade Gliomas</brief_title>
  <acronym>Poly-ICLC</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase II Trial of Poly-ICLC in the Management of Recurrent Pediatric Low Grade Gliomas</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Donald Durden</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Atrium Health</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is for patients up to 21 years of age who have a tumor called a low grade glioma&#xD;
      of the central nervous system (brain and spinal cord). The tumor has grown despite attempts&#xD;
      to control it with chemotherapy or radiation. Low grade gliomas are a group of tumors that&#xD;
      tend to grow slowly and could be cured if every bit of the tumor were surgically removed.&#xD;
      These tumors are called Grade I or II astrocytomas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These tumors often grow in parts of the brain that prevent total removal without devastating&#xD;
      neurologic complications or death. Although some low grade gliomas never grow, most will and&#xD;
      are treated with either chemotherapy or radiation. There is good data showing that the growth&#xD;
      of most low grade gliomas can be controlled with chemotherapy or radiation. However, some low&#xD;
      grade gliomas in children and young adults grow despite these treatments. Poly-ICLC is a new&#xD;
      drug that has been used safely in children and adults with different types of brain tumors.&#xD;
      Earlier studies showed that this drug worked better for children and young adults with low&#xD;
      grade gliomas than for children with more aggressive brain tumors. The main purpose of this&#xD;
      study is to use Poly-ICLC treatment in a larger number of patients to see how well it works&#xD;
      and how many side effects occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As Poly-ICLC is not FDA approved, this study is authorized to use it under IND# 43984, held&#xD;
      by Oncovir.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will get injections of Poly-ICLC into muscle two times weekly. The first treatments&#xD;
      will be given in the clinic so allergic or other severe reactions, if any, can be monitored.&#xD;
      If subjects tolerate the injections and don't have a severe reaction, then the rest of the&#xD;
      injections will be given at home. Subjects/caregivers will be trained to give injections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Treatment will last for about 2 years. Subjects may stay on treatment for longer than 2 years&#xD;
      if their tumor shrinks in response to the injections, if study doctors think it is safe, if&#xD;
      subjects want to remain on treatment, and if Poly-ICLC is available.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks: Poly-ICLC has been used safely in children and adults at the dose used in this study,&#xD;
      and at higher doses. Frequently seen side effects include irritation of the skin at the&#xD;
      injection site and mild flu-like symptoms. These are usually relieved or avoided by use of&#xD;
      over-the-counter medicines like acetaminophen (Tylenol).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Funding Source: FDA OOPD&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background/Rationale The incidence of primary pediatric brain tumors in the United States is&#xD;
      about 1500 per year. Brain tumors are the most common solid tumor diagnosed in childhood and&#xD;
      thus account for significant childhood mortality in the United States. Low-grade astrocytomas&#xD;
      and gliomas are the most common type of brain tumor of childhood (36% of childhood brain&#xD;
      tumors). These tumors encompass a heterogeneous assortment of histological subtypes&#xD;
      including: fibrillary, protoplasmic, gemistocytic, and mixed variants. Pilocytic&#xD;
      astrocytomas, pleomorphic xanthoastrocytomas and subependymal giant cell astrocytomas are&#xD;
      also included. Furthermore, in young children there are some unique rare entities that behave&#xD;
      like low-grade tumors, including infantile desmoplastic gangliogliomas, and desmoplastic&#xD;
      astrocytomas. Although children with low-grade astrocytomas often survive many years after&#xD;
      conventional treatment with surgery and sometimes radiotherapy, some children will not fare&#xD;
      as well. These tumors constitute a heterogeneous group because of differing locations within&#xD;
      the brain and varying biological behavior of different subtypes. For those where total&#xD;
      excision is possible, such as cerebellar astrocytomas, prognosis is excellent with over 90%&#xD;
      ten-year survival rates with surgical excision alone. In contrast, survival rates in children&#xD;
      with cerebral or diencephalic tumors are 40-70% at five years with irradiation, but decline&#xD;
      to 11-50% at 10 years (Mundigers, 1990). Some tumors however may be unresectable/partially&#xD;
      resectable, and radiation can have undesirable side effects in young children. While the most&#xD;
      significant intellectual deficits occur in young children less than 5 years treated with&#xD;
      cranial irradiation, the deficits recognized even in young adults warrant extending the age&#xD;
      to 10 years for avoiding radiation. Chemotherapy regimens are used for high-risk patients&#xD;
      (progressive tumor, residual tumor) as a means to avoid or delay radiation in young patients,&#xD;
      but side effects of chemotherapy are frequently reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Newer forms of effective treatment that will have lesser side effects are much needed in&#xD;
      childhood brain tumors especially low-grade gliomas. We propose to study the efficacy and&#xD;
      toxicity of poly-ICLC, a biological response modifier in children with low-grade gliomas.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROTEOMICS&#xD;
&#xD;
      Current diagnostic and therapeutic monitoring of brain tumor patients are significantly&#xD;
      hindered due to limited understanding of brain tumor biology and response to therapy. The&#xD;
      majority of CNS tumors cannot be identified or followed by expression of serum or CSF&#xD;
      markers. However, if available, such markers would be highly desirable and could be used to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Detect minimal residual disease&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Predict response to specific targeted therapies&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Predict or anticipate tumor progression&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Distinguish tumor recurrence from post surgical changes or post-radiation changes on&#xD;
           neuro-imaging&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Augment current histopathologic classification systems&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Improve current clinical and pathological treatment stratification schemata&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Assess efficacy of and tumor response to specific biologic targeted therapies that may&#xD;
           not impact tumor size as a primary tumor endpoint (e.g., small molecule inhibitors or&#xD;
           anti-angiogenic strategies) While such markers would be useful to prognosticate, monitor&#xD;
           and treat all CNS tumors, its use in glial tumors including recurrent low grade&#xD;
           astrocytomas is critical since these tumors are often biopsied at presentation, but not&#xD;
           at recurrence. Often these tumors are not amenable complete resection or biopsy due to&#xD;
           the eloquence of brain tissue they infiltrate (e.g., optic pathway, brainstem or&#xD;
           hypothalamic gliomas), or the blood vessels that they encase.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CNS biologic material in CSF Glial tumors tend to disseminate locally along white matter&#xD;
      tracts rather than through sub-arachnoid seeding. Dissemination of low grade gliomas along&#xD;
      the sub-arachnoid space has been reported in children with low grade gliomas. Even focal&#xD;
      tumors are frequently adjacent to CSF pathways (e.g., intrapeduncular fossa, third and fourth&#xD;
      ventricles) resulting in direct contact between tumor tissue and spinal fluid. Yet&#xD;
      examination of CSF cytology for these tumors is not standard. Given limitations of&#xD;
      identifying tumor cells in the CSF, methodologies that could improve our understanding of CNS&#xD;
      tumors of all types are needed. This would provide a significant improvement in currently&#xD;
      available knowledge about the biology of these tumors, and could elucidate potential&#xD;
      therapeutic avenues.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proteomics, a relatively new area of research whereby total protein complement of a tissue&#xD;
      compartment is analyzed, has successfully been used to identify novel biomarkers in solid&#xD;
      tumors (Zheng, 2003);( Khwaja, 2007). Because proteins are effectors of all cellular&#xD;
      functions, their measurement should represent the most direct means of cellular&#xD;
      characterization and hence tumor biology. Because cells and their environment exist in an&#xD;
      integrated state, it has been possible to interrogate the proteins of extra-cellular&#xD;
      compartments to assess the presence and impact of tumor cells. This has been done primarily&#xD;
      using serum or plasma to establish a method of screening for the presence of low stage&#xD;
      tumors. An analogous extra-cellular compartment for use in brain tumors would be&#xD;
      cerebrospinal fluid (CSF). It circulates throughout the CNS and exchanges proteins with the&#xD;
      extra-cellular fluid of the brain and spinal cord.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CSF is continuously created and reabsorbed, providing a real time steady state proteome.&#xD;
      Unlike serum, which contains a highly complex protein mixture ranging from very low abundance&#xD;
      proteins in the 10-30 pg/mL range to very abundant proteins in the 35-55 mg/mL range, CSF&#xD;
      contains a less complex protein mixture (Omenn, 2005).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the CSF is more likely to contain higher relative concentrations of tumor-specific&#xD;
      proteins (higher signal to noise ratio) than serum. Taken together this makes CSF and&#xD;
      attractive alternative to serum for detection of brain tumor related biomarkers. Unlike&#xD;
      leukemia and many solid tumors outside the CNS, where serial biopsies are readily performed,&#xD;
      tumors of the CNS are not easily accessible other than at the time of initial or repeat&#xD;
      resection or biopsy. While studies on these samples provide important findings regarding&#xD;
      tumor biology, serial analyses during treatment are not reasonable. By contrast, the CSF of&#xD;
      tumor patients can be more readily sampled in most pediatric patients. With the development&#xD;
      of proteomic technology, investigation of tumor related signals at the time of diagnosis&#xD;
      through treatment, and then in remission and/or at the time of recurrence or progression is&#xD;
      possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While CSF for seeding tumors is readily available and routinely obtained for cytology, the&#xD;
      systematic evaluation of the proteins within these samples could be of considerable&#xD;
      scientific importance. In addition to identifying potential makers of disease or response to&#xD;
      therapy, the glycosylation and phosphorylation status of many proteins can also be evaluated.&#xD;
      Studies in tumor tissue show that such information reveals activity of different enzymes that&#xD;
      correlate with treatment response (Mellinghoff, 2005); (Helgi, 2005) or progression of&#xD;
      leptomeningeal metastases (Brandsma, 2006).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proteomics CSF proteomics has been applied to many neurological disorders including&#xD;
      Alzheimer's disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, multiple sclerosis, acute brain injury&#xD;
      and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease (Rohlff, 2001).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Reports of its use in neuro-oncology are limited, but demonstrate the potential of this&#xD;
      technology to effectively identify tumor biomarkers. One study used two dimensional&#xD;
      polyacrylamide (2-D) gel electrophoresis to measure the relative quantities of two&#xD;
      pre-selected markers, N-Myc and l-CaD, in the CSF of brain tumor patients (Zheng, 2003).&#xD;
      Another used ELISA of CSF to identify Osteopontin as predictive of AT/RT and correlated with&#xD;
      response to therapy (Kao, 2005). CSF proteomics using 2-D gel electrophoresis in combination&#xD;
      with mass spectroscopy and cleavable isotope Coded Affinity Tag (cICAT) was used to evaluate&#xD;
      60 samples of CSF and tumor cyst fluid taken from adults with brain tumors and non-neoplastic&#xD;
      controls. These techniques were used to find a panel of proteins differentially expressed in&#xD;
      lower vs. higher-grade gliomas. Findings were confirmed using Western Blot analysis probing&#xD;
      for eight selected proteins based on implied role in gliomagenesis and availability of&#xD;
      antibodies. This report, which has been accepted for publication pending revisions,&#xD;
      identified 21 potential CSF biomarkers for astrocytoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As mentioned above, there is evidence that gliomas disseminate through the subarachnoid&#xD;
      space. Currently there are several consortia actively studying protein expression in the&#xD;
      spinal fluid of children with malignant glial and embryonal tumors (Pediatric Brain Tumor&#xD;
      Consortium, Pediatric Oncology Experimental Therapeutics Consortium). Proteins interrogated&#xD;
      in these protocols include those involved with angiogenesis and neovascularity (EGF, VEGF and&#xD;
      bFGF), those involved in tumor growth and migration (Secreted protein with acidic and&#xD;
      cysteine rich domains (SPARC), attractin). There is no consortium actively collecting spinal&#xD;
      fluid sample in children with lower grade tumors. A secondary goal of this study is to&#xD;
      examine these proteins in the CSF of children with low grade gliomas who have tumor&#xD;
      progression. Comparison of CSF protein expression of in high grade and low grade tumors is&#xD;
      likely to help identify biological markers specific for tumor progression, or for tumor&#xD;
      pathology.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>August 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">July 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>tumor assessments are to be performed per Modified McDonald's criteria</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>at 2 years</time_frame>
    <description>tumor assessments are to be performed per 3D measurements</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression free survival</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">23</enrollment>
  <condition>Brain Tumors</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Poly ICLC</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Children will receive poly-ICLC 20 mcg/kg twice weekly IM (using Monday/Wednesday schedule if possible). The first 2 doses will be administered in the clinic under supervision.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Poly ICLC</intervention_name>
    <description>Children will receive poly-ICLC 20 mcg/kg twice weekly IM (using Monday/Wednesday schedule if possible). The first 2 doses will be administered in the clinic under supervision.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Poly ICLC</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age:Patients must be between 0 - 21 years of age when registered on this protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis:Patients must have pathologically confirmed low grade glioma with histologic&#xD;
             subtypes interpreted as WHO grade I and II including:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  juvenile pilocytic astrocytoma (JPA)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pleomorphic JPA&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  diffuse astrocytoma (fibrillary, gemistocytic, giant cell, or pleomorphic&#xD;
             xanthoastrocytoma)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  low grade oligoastrocytoma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  low grade oligodendroglioma&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  low grade glioma NOS Tumors of all regions of the CNS, with appropriate histology are&#xD;
             eligible for study. However patients with tumors intrinsic to the optic nerve and&#xD;
             involvement of the optic nerve cannot be biopsied/resected are eligible without&#xD;
             histological confirmation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients with neurofibromatosis type 1(NF1) are also eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must have demonstrated either tumor progression or recurrence by radiographic&#xD;
        criteria and/or clinical criteria as defined below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients with progressive non-resectable disease regardless of location in the brain&#xD;
             or spine are eligible for this study. Patients with evidence of leptomeningeal&#xD;
             dissemination are eligible for this study. Patients do not require biopsy/histologic&#xD;
             confirmation at the time of progression or relapse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Radiographic progression is defined as &gt;40% increase in the product of the three&#xD;
             perpendicular diameters of initial tumor relative to the initial baseline measurement&#xD;
             - length (L)x width (W) x transverse (T) (current scan) &gt; 1.4 x L x W x T (initial&#xD;
             scan), or the development of any new sites of disease independent of the response of&#xD;
             the initial tumor. See section 7.1.2 for methodology for tumor measurement.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Post radiation changes are often seen on post-treatment imaging studies, so that&#xD;
             classification of a patient as having progressive disease may require several serial&#xD;
             MRI's if the child has received radiation within the preceding 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Tumor volume includes the entire tumor volume seen on gadolinium enhanced T1 MR&#xD;
             imaging plus non-enhancing abnormality seen on T2 or FLAIR.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. All tumor cysts will be included in the tumor volume&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Clinical progression without radiographic progression includes children with optic&#xD;
             pathway gliomas who demonstrate sustained decrease in visual fields and/or acuity in&#xD;
             three serial vision examinations. Each of the vision examinations must be performed &gt;2&#xD;
             weeks apart.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Children with previously negative cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) cytology who show evidence&#xD;
             of tumor cells in fluid obtained by lumbar puncture can be designated as having&#xD;
             progressive disease in the absence of radiographic evidence of progression.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Measurable disease: Patients must have measurable disease documented by radiographic&#xD;
        criteria prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Performance Level and Life Expectancy:Patients must have a performance status of &gt; 50%&#xD;
        (Appendix I). Use Karnofsky for patients &gt; 16 years of age and Lansky for patients ≤ 16&#xD;
        years of age. Patients must have a life expectancy of ≥ 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prior Therapy:Patients must have fully recovered from the acute toxic effects of all prior&#xD;
        chemotherapy, immunotherapy, or radiotherapy prior to entering this study and meet time&#xD;
        restrictions from end of prior therapy as stated below:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Myelosuppressive chemotherapy patients must have received the last dose of&#xD;
             myelosuppressive therapy at least 3 weeks prior to study registration or at least 6&#xD;
             weeks if nitrosourea.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Investigational / Biological agent: Patient must have received the last dose of other&#xD;
             investigational or biological agent &gt;7 days prior to study registration&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. XRT: Patients must be ≥ 8 weeks since the completion of radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Study specific limitations on prior therapy: There is no limit on the number of prior&#xD;
             treatment regimens or received doses of radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Growth factor(s): Must not have received any hematopoetic growth factors within 7 days&#xD;
             of study entry or 21 days for neulasta.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Prior Surgery: Must be ≥ 2 weeks from prior surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Steroids: Must be on a stable steroid dose for 7 days prior to study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Organ Function Requirements:All patients must have adequate organ function defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Hematologic Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hemoglobin: &gt; 8.0 gm/dl (may transfuse PRBCs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. ANC: &gt; 750/mm3 Must be at least 7days after last dose of growth factor&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Platelet Count: &gt; 50,000 (transfusion independent; ≥ 7 days from last transfusion)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Renal Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Serum creatinine ≤ 2 x normal for age (see below) or Creatinine clearance/GFR &gt; 60&#xD;
        cc/min/1.73 m2 [Urine Creatinine (mg/dL)][Volume collected (ml)]/[Serum Creatinine&#xD;
        9mg/dL)][Hours x 60]&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age (years) Maximum Serum Creatinine (mg/dL)&#xD;
&#xD;
        ≤ 5 0.8 &gt; 5 &amp; ≤ 10 1.0 &gt; 10 &amp; ≤ 15 1.2 &gt; 15 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
        Liver Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x ULN for age, AND&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. SGPT (ALT) &lt; 2.5x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. SGOT (AST) &lt; 2.5x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
        Pulmonary Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
        No evidence of dyspnea at rest, no exercise intolerance, and a pulse oximetry ≥ 94% if&#xD;
        there is clinical indication for determination.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Coagulation Function:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Normal PT and PTT at enrollment per institutional range&#xD;
&#xD;
        Reproductive Function:Due to potential teratogenic effects of (poly-ICLC), negative serum&#xD;
        beta-HCG in females, and use of effective contraception in males and females of&#xD;
        childbearing potential, IS REQUIRED.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or lactating females. Women of childbearing age will agree to use&#xD;
             contraception during the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving other experimental immunotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients may not have fever (38.50C) within 7 days of enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No concurrent XRT or chemotherapy is allowed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who, in the opinion of the investigator, may not be able to comply with the&#xD;
             safety monitoring requirements of the study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Donald Durden, MD, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of California Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>RADY Children's Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92123</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30342</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.choa.org/default.aspx?id=1957</url>
    <description>clinical trials database</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.choa.org/</url>
    <description>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.emory.edu</url>
    <description>Emory University</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 23, 2010</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2010</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">August 25, 2010</study_first_posted>
  <disposition_first_submitted>August 4, 2021</disposition_first_submitted>
  <disposition_first_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</disposition_first_submitted_qc>
  <disposition_first_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</disposition_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Atrium Health</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Donald Durden</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Pediatrics</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>glioma</keyword>
  <keyword>pediatrics</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>brain tumor</keyword>
  <keyword>low grade glioma</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glioma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Poly ICLC</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted, but a results disposition has been submitted           -->
</clinical_study>

