<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04857047</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BR-VRNS-CT-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04857047</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Multi Doses Study to Compare the Pharmacokinetics of BR9003A and BR9003 in Healthy Adult Subjects</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open-label, Multiple Doses, Crossover Clinical Study to Compare the Pharmacokinetic Characteristics and the Safety Between Administration of BR9003 and BR9003A in Healthy Adult Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Boryung Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Boryung Pharmaceutical Co., Ltd</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a randomized, multiple doses, crossover clinical study to compare the pharmacokinetic&#xD;
      characteristics and the safety between administration of BR9003 and BR9003A in healthy adult&#xD;
      subjects. Within each period, randomized subjects will be taken 2 dosing regimens of&#xD;
      administrating BR9003 once a day for six days or BR9003A twice a day for six days.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      *Study Objective: After repeated administration of BR9003 2mg and BR9003A 1mg for healthy&#xD;
      adult volunteers, the pharmacokinetic properties and safety are evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Target number of subjects for enrollment (randomization):&#xD;
&#xD;
           24 subjects in total (2 sequence groups(A or B), 12 subjects per sequence group)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Investigational Product&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Control drug: BR9003A 1mg&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Test drug: BR9003 2mg&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Regimen&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Control group: Administration of BR9003A 1mg twice a day for six days&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Test group: Administration of BR9003 2mg once a day for six days&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 31, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">June 28, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">June 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-24,ss</measure>
    <time_frame>0-72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma drug concentration-time curve of BR9003 and BR9003A within 24 hours</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax,ss</measure>
    <time_frame>0-72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum concentration of drug in plasma of BR9003 and BR9003A within 24 hours</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">27</enrollment>
  <condition>Smoking Cessation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>[Period1] administration of BR9003A 1mg twice a day for six days&#xD;
- Wash out for 9days -&#xD;
[Period2] administration of BR9003 2mg once a day for six days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>[Period1] administration of BR9003 2mg once a day for six days&#xD;
- Wash out for 9days -&#xD;
[Period2] administration of BR9003A 1mg twice a day for six days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BR9003 2mg</intervention_name>
    <description>After fasting for at least 10 hours from 10:00 p.m. the previous day, one BR9003 tablet will be administered orally with 150mL of water around 8:30 a.m. after starting breakfast 30 minutes before the scheduled time of administration and finishing it.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BR9003A 1mg</intervention_name>
    <description>After fasting for at least 10 hours from 10:00 p.m. the previous day, one BR9003A tablet will be administered orally with 150mL of water around 8:30 a.m. after starting breakfast 30 minutes before the scheduled time of administration and finishing it. Another BR9003A tablet will be administered orally with water 150mL around 20:30 after dinner between 18-19:00.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy adults aged 19 to 55 years at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Those who weigh at least 50 kg at the time of screening and have a calculated body&#xD;
             mass index (BMI) within the range of 18.0 to 29.0 kg/m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Determined to be eligible as subjects through physical examination and interview&#xD;
             conducted in accordance with this protocol. In other words, those who have no&#xD;
             congenital or chronic diseases and have no abnormal symptoms or findings based on&#xD;
             medical examination results within the last 3 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Determined to be eligible as subjects as a result of clinical laboratory tests and&#xD;
             electrocardiography performed according to this protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Voluntarily decide to participate in the study and provide written consent to follow&#xD;
             the study directions after listening&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Those who have clinically significant diseases or a history of the diseases associated&#xD;
             with the cardiovascular system, respiratory system, liver, kidney, nervous system,&#xD;
             endocrine system, blood/tumor, psychiatric diseases, or urinary system&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Those who have hypersensitivity reactions or a history of clinically significant&#xD;
             hypersensitivity reactions to drugs containing varenicline, or drugs containing the&#xD;
             same class ingredients, or other drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Those with clinically significant hypotension (systolic blood pressure&#xD;
&#xD;
             ≤ 90mmHg) or hypertension (systolic blood pressure ≥ 150mmHg or diastolic blood&#xD;
             pressure ≥ 95mmHg) at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Those with a history of gastrointestinal diseases (e.g., Crohn's disease, ulcer, etc.)&#xD;
             or gastrointestinal surgery (however, simple appendectomy or hernia repair are&#xD;
             excluded) that may affect the absorption of drugs&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any of the following results in the screening tests&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  AST or ALT &gt; 2 times the upper limit of the normal range&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Total bilirubin &gt; 2.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Estimated glomerular filtration rate (eGFR) &lt; 60 mL/min/1.73m2&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Those who continue to drink alcohol (&gt;21 units/week; 1 unit = 10 g = 12.5 mL of pure&#xD;
             alcohol), or are unable to abstain from drinking during the clinical study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Those who continue to smoke (&gt;10 cigarettes/day) or cannot stop smoking during&#xD;
             hospitalization during the clinical trial period&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Those who have participated in another clinical trial or bioequivalence test (the last&#xD;
             day of administration of the investigational product or bioequivalence test drug)&#xD;
             within 6 months prior to the first administration date&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Those who have donated whole blood within 60 days prior to the first day of&#xD;
             administration or donated blood components (apheresis) within 30 days prior to the&#xD;
             first day of administration or who have received a blood transfusion within 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Those who took any prescription drugs or herbal medicines within 14 days prior to the&#xD;
             first day of administration or any over-the-counter (OTC) drugs within 7 days prior to&#xD;
             the first day of administration (however, if other conditions are appropriate&#xD;
             according to the judgment of the investigator, they may participate in the clinical&#xD;
             trial.)&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Those who took drugs inducing and inhibiting drug-metabolizing enzymes, such as&#xD;
             barbital, within 30 days prior to the study initiation&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Those who have been on a diet (especially grapefruit juice or its products) that may&#xD;
             affect the absorption, distribution, metabolism, and excretion of the drug within 7&#xD;
             days prior to the first day of administration&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Pregnant woman, potentially pregnant woman, or breast-feeding woman&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Those who do not agree to rule out the possibility of their and their spouses' or&#xD;
             sexual partners' pregnancy using a medically acceptable methods of contraception*&#xD;
             throughout the entire period from the date of the first administration of the&#xD;
             investigational product to the end of the clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Those who are unwilling or unable to comply with the dietary and lifestyle guidelines&#xD;
             required for the clinical trial&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Those who have clinically significant abnormalities in the results of other clinical&#xD;
             laboratory tests or who have been determined by the investigator to be ineligible to&#xD;
             participate in the clinical trial due to other reasons (e.g., non-compliance with&#xD;
             instructions, uncooperative attitude, etc.)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>19 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sang-Heon Cho</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Inha University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Inha University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Incheon</city>
        <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Korea, Republic of</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

