<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04855409</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>21012021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04855409</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Neuronal Integrity in Bipolar Depression</brief_title>
  <official_title>Neuronal Integrity and Suicidality in Bipolar Depression: a Diffusion Tensor Imaging Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mehmet Diyaddin Güleken</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Saglik Bilimleri Universitesi Gazi Yasargil Training and Research Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to examine the neurological unity in bipolar depression and to&#xD;
      investigate white matter abnormalities that may contribute to etiology&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Bipolar disorder is a chronic mood disorder which is characterized by repetitive episodes,&#xD;
      usually manifests through adolescence or early adulthood. It has a prevalence of&#xD;
      approximately 2,5% with a 1:1 ratio of male and female. It is a disorder that may disrupt&#xD;
      central nervous system functions such as cognition, thought, perception, affect, judgement,&#xD;
      adaptation to the environment and behavioural regulation. It may manifest with various&#xD;
      clinical onsets. Although etiology of bipolar disorder is still unknown, some biological&#xD;
      factors such as BDNF, oxidative stress and structural changes of brain are proven to have a&#xD;
      role in etiology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Diffusion tensor magnetic resonance imaging (DTI) is a neuroimaging technique that elucidates&#xD;
      abnormalities of brain white matter (WM), based on structural investigation of a tissue via&#xD;
      measurement of diffusion rate and direction of water molecules. This method lets imaging of&#xD;
      white matter tracts, whole anatomical extent and structural integrity of the brain tissue.&#xD;
      So, it can provide data about anatomical connectivity of brain. There are some parameters&#xD;
      used for indicating microstructural integrity of white mat-ter such as fractional anisotropy&#xD;
      (FA) and apparent diffusion coefficient (ADC) in DTI. FA is a measure which reflects&#xD;
      directional coherence of water diffusion, and it is sen¬sitive to microstructural WM&#xD;
      differences. It is defined on a scale ranging from mostly isotro¬pic (when approaching to&#xD;
      zero) indicating poor integrity of the axons to mostly anisotropic (when approaching to 1)&#xD;
      indicating intact WM integrity. ADC is a scalar index of the rate of water diffusion among&#xD;
      different dif¬fusion directions under a Gaussian distribution. A higher value of ADC&#xD;
      indicates lesser restricted diffusion, and it implies fewer organized structures in WM which&#xD;
      supports presence of abnormalities in the structural in¬tegrity of white matter. As it has a&#xD;
      complicated literature, in this study, we aimed to investigate neuronal integrity and its&#xD;
      abnormalities by DTI, which may contribute to the etiology of bipolar depression.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 2011</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">October 2011</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 2011</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brain white matter abnormality</measure>
    <time_frame>Within a day</time_frame>
    <description>The fractional anisotropy and appearent diffusion coefficient parameters of corpus callosum genu and corpus callosum splenium of both groups</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">32</enrollment>
  <condition>Bipolar I Disorder, Most Recent Episode Depressed</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Bipolar Depression</arm_group_label>
    <description>Subjects with bipolar type I disorder depressive episode diagnosed by Structured Clinical Interview for DSM-IV Axis I Disorders (SCID-I)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Healthy</arm_group_label>
    <description>Healthy control subjects matched with bipolar depressive patients by age and sex</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Sixteen subjects with bipolar type I disorder depressive episode diagnosed by SCID-I were&#xD;
        recruited from Psychiatry Department of Harran University Research Hospital, and sixteen&#xD;
        healthy control subjects were enrolled from the hospital staff. Patient and control groups&#xD;
        have been matched by age and sex. A written informed consent was obtained from each&#xD;
        volunteered participant.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged between 18 and 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a diagnosis of bipolar type I disorder depressive episode by Structured&#xD;
             Clinical Interview for DSM-IV Axis I Disorders (SCID-I)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having no other general medical, neurological or psychiatric condition Healthy&#xD;
             controls;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Matched with bipolar depressive patients by age and sex&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having no other general medical, neurological and psychiatric condition&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Bipolar depressive patients and healthy control subjects with any other general&#xD;
             medical, neurological or psychiatric condition, metal implant, severe head injury or&#xD;
             pregnancy&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mustafa Çelik, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Saglik Bilimleri Universitesi Gazi Yasargil Training and Research Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Saglik Bilimleri Universitesi Gazi Yasargil Training and Research Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mehmet Diyaddin Güleken</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Attending Physician</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bipolar Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>There is no plan about sharing individual participant data with other researchers</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

