<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04858841</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A-BR-108-107</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04858841</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Post-stroke Epilepsy: Primary Prophylaxis Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Primary Prevention Study of Post-Ischemic Stroke Epilepsy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Cheng Kung University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Cheng-Kung University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Cheng Kung University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Advance in stroke treatment have resulted in a dramatic reduction in the stroke mortality,&#xD;
      however, the number of stroke survivors living with morbidity has increased significantly. As&#xD;
      we know, post-stroke epilepsy has been identified as a significant clinical issue in stroke&#xD;
      survivors and stroke is the most common cause of epilepsy in older adults and for patients&#xD;
      aged more than 65, post-stroke epilepsy accounts for 30-50% of new-onset seizures. Our&#xD;
      previous study documented seizures during stroke presentation and during hospitalization&#xD;
      would worsen the overall morbidity and mortality, suggesting the importance of awareness in&#xD;
      seizure care in acute ischemic stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As current studies only focus on anti-seizure/anti-convulsion after the appearance of&#xD;
      late-onset seizures, without the intervention of the epileptogenesis, it is important to&#xD;
      develop a potential novel prophylactic treatment on patients with acute severe stroke to&#xD;
      prevent from late occurrence of seizures and epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We have previously done researches on the medications that might have potential of&#xD;
      anti-epileptogenesis in pilocarpine-induced animal models, supporting the concept of&#xD;
      antiepileptogenesis, giving intervention immediately following a brain insult.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of some earlier anecdotal reports or small studies on prophylactic use of&#xD;
      antiepileptic drug (AED) therapy in stroke, either hemorrhagic or ischemic strokes, remain&#xD;
      inconclusive. There still lacks a well-established case-control study on prophylaxis of&#xD;
      post-stroke epilepsy, with the early intervention of AED therapy with potential of&#xD;
      anti-epileptogenesis in the phase of epileptogenesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Based on our clinical experience, and laboratory researches, we have noted two&#xD;
      non-conventional AEDs, levetiracetam (LEV) and perampanel (PER) with potential of&#xD;
      anti-epileptogenesis. It is justified to evaluate if early administration of LEV or PER in&#xD;
      patients with acute major stroke as a prophylactic therapy could hamper the development of&#xD;
      epileptogenesis and the later post-stroke epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We aim to conduct a randomized case-control study to evaluate if early prophylactic&#xD;
      introduction of low dose AED therapy (LEV or PER) in patients with moderate to severe middle&#xD;
      cerebral artery infarct, could prevent the development of post-stroke epilepsy (primary&#xD;
      prevention).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Advance in stroke treatment have resulted in a dramatic reduction in the stroke mortality,&#xD;
      however, the number of stroke survivors living with morbidity has increased significantly.&#xD;
      Among the morbidities, seizures and epilepsy are not uncommon and post-stroke epilepsy has&#xD;
      been identified as a significant clinical issue in stroke survivors. As we know, stroke is&#xD;
      the most common cause of epilepsy in older adults and for patients aged more than 65,&#xD;
      post-stroke epilepsy accounts for 30-50% of new-onset seizures (Tanaka and Ihara, 2017). The&#xD;
      incidence of early seizures (occurring within the first 1-2 weeks of stroke) is between&#xD;
      2.4-5.4% and the risk of post-stroke late seizures (seizures occur later than 14 days of&#xD;
      stroke) is around 7-18% (Shetty, 2013; Tanaka and Ihara, 2017). The stroke severity, location&#xD;
      and type of pathological changes, genetic factors and pre-injury and post-injury exposure to&#xD;
      non-genetic factors such as exposome can divide patients with ischemic stroke into different&#xD;
      susceptibility (Pitkanen et al., 2016) and the standardized morbidity rate of developing&#xD;
      epilepsy is highest during the first year. Our previous study also documented seizures during&#xD;
      stroke presentation and during hospitalization would worsen the overall morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality (Huang et al., 2014), suggesting the importance of awareness in seizure care in&#xD;
      acute ischemic stroke. In addition, studies showed higher National Institutes of Health&#xD;
      Stroke Scale (NIHSS) score, cortical involvement younger age, central nervous system (CNS)&#xD;
      morbidities are associated with higher risk of post-stroke epilepsy (Tanaka and Ihara, 2017).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Occurrence of post-stroke epileptic seizure would lead to long-term poor prognosis and&#xD;
      increased mortality (Bladin et al., 2000; Labovitz et al., 2001), and the post-stroke&#xD;
      epilepsy has a high recurrence rate (Tanaka et al., 2017), which might lead to anxiety and&#xD;
      worsen quality of life in the stroke survivors. As current treatments only focus on&#xD;
      anti-seizure/anti-convulsion, based on our understanding of the epileptogenesis, we aim to&#xD;
      develop a potential prophylactic treatment on patients with acute severe stroke to prevent&#xD;
      from late occurrence of seizures and epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Process of epileptogenesis is classically thought to occur in three phases: first the&#xD;
      occurrence of a precipitating injury or event; second, a 'latent' period during which changes&#xD;
      set in motion by the preceding injury act to transform the previously normal brain into an&#xD;
      epileptic brain; and third, chronic, established epilepsy. It is during the latent period&#xD;
      that the process of acquired epileptogenesis is thought to coalesce, and it is at this point&#xD;
      in the process that interventions might be used to prevent the subsequent development of&#xD;
      epilepsy (Goldberg and Coulter, 2013; Kikuyama et al., 2017). We have previously done&#xD;
      researches on the medications that might have potential of anti-epileptogenesis in&#xD;
      pilocarpine-induced animal models, supporting the concept of anti-epileptogenesis, giving&#xD;
      intervention immediately following a brain insult (Lai et al., 2018, Hung et al., 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential medications with potential of anti-epileptogenesis Based on our clinical&#xD;
      experience, and laboratory researches (Huang et al., 2009, 2013; Lai et al., 2018; Hung et&#xD;
      al., 2019), we have noted two newer AEDs with potential of anti-epileptogenesis. LEV, a&#xD;
      current standard AED with a distinct synaptic vesicle modulating mechanism, has been&#xD;
      demonstrated its potential in ameliorating epileptogenesis (Itoh et al., 2016; Kikuyama et&#xD;
      al., 2017). Synaptic vesicle 2A (SV2A) is considered to play an important role for synaptic&#xD;
      vesicle recycling and neurotransmitter excretion to the synaptic cleft, because mice lacking&#xD;
      SV2A failed to grow, experienced severe seizures, and died within 3 weeks (Crowder et al.,&#xD;
      1999). A clear correlation was seen between the affinity of LEV and its analogues to SV2A and&#xD;
      the potency of their antiseizure protection in the mouse audiogenic model of epilepsy (Lynch&#xD;
      et al., 2004). Furthermore, the LEV-treated adult male Node epileptic rats showed a&#xD;
      significant increase of Bax/Bcl-2 mRNA expression ratio in the prefrontal cortex than the&#xD;
      control group, but no change in the Bax/Bcl-2 mRNA expression ratio in hippocampus,&#xD;
      suggesting the mechanism of acquired anti-epileptogenesis by LEV may be similar to&#xD;
      spontaneous recovery of idiopathic generalized epilepsy during adolescence (Kikuyama et al.,&#xD;
      2017). Our earlier study suggests its broad spectrum of modulating neuronal excitability&#xD;
      (Huang et al., 2009). It is not metabolized through the P-450 hepatic cytochrome system and&#xD;
      has not clinically relevant drug-drug interactions (Rosati et al., 2010). It has also been&#xD;
      suggested as a first-choice drug against post-stroke seizures, based on safety and efficacy&#xD;
      profiles in clinical studies (Belcastro et al., 2008). Thus, it is potentially worth&#xD;
      investigation in primary prevention for patients with acute major stroke.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Perampanel (PER), a current standard antiepileptic drug with a distinct mechanism of&#xD;
      selective non-competitive antagonist of alpha-amino-3-hydroxy-5-methyl-4-isoxazolepropionic&#xD;
      acid (AMPA)-type receptors, has also been demonstrated its efficacy in treatment&#xD;
      wide-spectrum epileptic seizures with good tolerability profile (Tyrlikova et al., 2008).&#xD;
      Based on its block of glutamate excitotoxicity, PER is theoretically capable of modulating&#xD;
      epileptogenesis and it has been demonstrated its potential in ameliorating epileptogenesis&#xD;
      (Mohammad et al., 2019; Dupuis et al., 2017). As we know, the AMPA receptor has become a&#xD;
      therapeutic target due to its involvement in ictogenesis and epileptogenesis. GluA2 subunit&#xD;
      plays a role in calcium permeability. Thereby, AMPA receptor-mediated calcium signaling&#xD;
      increases affects brain excitability. Recent report indicated that perampanel can block both&#xD;
      calcium permeable and calcium in permeable AMPA receptors (Barygin et al., 2016). Our recent&#xD;
      study on PER pharmacology also revealed it, for the first time, could inhibit voltage-gated&#xD;
      sodium channels, suggesting its broad-spectrum properties in modulating neuronal excitability&#xD;
      (Lai et al., 2019). Thus, it is potentially justified to evaluate if early administration of&#xD;
      PER in patients with acute major stroke as a prophylactic therapy could hamper the&#xD;
      development of epileptogenesis and the later post-stroke epilepsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Purpose of our study We aim to investigate if early administration of AEDs with potential&#xD;
      anti-epileptogenesis could prevent the development of post-stroke epilepsy (primary&#xD;
      prevention).&#xD;
&#xD;
      References:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Barygin OI. Inhibition of calcium-permeable and calcium impermeable AMPA receptors by&#xD;
           perampanel in rat brain neurons. Neurosci Lett 2016;633:146-151.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Belcastro V, Costa C, Galletti F, Autuori A, Pierguidi L, Pisani F, Calabresi P,&#xD;
           Parnetti L. Levetiracetam in newly diagnosed late-onset post-stroke seizures: a&#xD;
           prospective observational study. Epilepsy Res 2008;82:223-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Bladin CF, Alexandrov AV, Bellavance A, Bornstein N, Chambers B, Cote R, Lebrun L,&#xD;
           Pirisi A, Norris JW. Seizures after stroke: a prospective multicenter study. Arch Neurol&#xD;
           2000;57:e1617-22.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Crowder KM, Gunther JM, Jones TA, et al. Abnormal neurotransmission in mice lacking&#xD;
           synaptic vesicle protein 2A (SV2A). Proc Natl Acad Sci USA 1999;96:15268-73.&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Dupuis N, Enderlin J, Thomas J, Desnous B, Dournaud P, Allorge D, Auvin S.&#xD;
           Anti-ictogenic and antiepileptogenic properties of perampanel in mature and immature&#xD;
           rats. Epilepsia 2017;58:1985-92.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Goldberg E, Coulter D. Mechanisms of epileptogenesis: a convergence on neural circuit&#xD;
           dysfunction. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14:337-49.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Huang CW, Cheng JT, Tsai JJ, Wu SN, Huang CC. Diabetic hyperglycemia aggravates seizures&#xD;
           and status epilepticus-induced hippocampal damage. Neurotox Res 2009;15:71-81.&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. Huang CW, Tsai JJ, Huang CC, Wu SN. Experimental and simulation studies on the&#xD;
           mechanisms of Levetiracetam-mediated inhibition of delayed-rectifier potassium current&#xD;
           (Kv3.1): Contribution to the firing of action potentials. J Physiol Pharmacol&#xD;
           2009;60:37-47.&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Huang CW, Lai MC, Cheng JT, Tsai JJ, Huang CC, Wu SN. Pregabalin attenuates&#xD;
           excitotoxicity in diabetes. PLOS One 2013;8:e65154-60.&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Huang CW, Saposnik G, Fang J, Steven DA, Burneo JG. Influence of seizures on stroke&#xD;
           outcomes: a large multicenter study. Neurology 2014;82:768-76.&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Hung TY, Chu FL, Wu DC, Wu SN, Huang CW. The protective role of peroxisome&#xD;
           proliferator-activated receptor-gamma in seizure and neuronal excitotoxicity. Mol&#xD;
           Neurobiol 2019;56:5497-506.&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Ikeda K, Sawada M, Morioka H, Kyuzen M, Ebina J, Nagasawa J, Yanagihashi M, Miura K,&#xD;
           Ishikawa Y, Hirayama T, Takazawa T, Kano O, Kawabe K, Iwasaki Y. Clinical Profile and&#xD;
           Changes of Serum Lipid Levels in Epileptic Patients after Cerebral Infarction. J Stroke&#xD;
           Cerebrovasc Dis 2017;26:644-9.&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Itoh K, Ishihara Y, Komori R. Levetiracetam treatment influences blood-brain barrier&#xD;
           failure associated with angiogenesis and inflammatory responses in the acute phase of&#xD;
           epileptogenesis in post-status epilepticus mice. Brain Res 2016;1652:1-13.&#xD;
&#xD;
       14. Kikuyama H, Hanaoka T, Kanazawa T, Yoshida Y, Mizuno T, Toyoda H, Yoneda H. The&#xD;
           Mechanism of Anti-Epileptogenesis by Levetiracetam Treatment is Similar to the&#xD;
           Spontaneous Recovery of Idiopathic Generalized Epilepsy during Adolescence. Psychiatry&#xD;
           Investig 2017;14:844-50.&#xD;
&#xD;
       15. Labovitz DL, Hauser WA, Sacco RL. Prevalence and predictors of early seizure and status&#xD;
           epilepticus after first stroke. Neurology 2001;57:200-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
       16. Lai MC, Hung TY, Lin KM, Sung PS, Wu SJ, Yang CS, Wu YJ, Jsai JJ, Wu SN, Huang CW.&#xD;
           Sodium Metabisulfite: Effects on Ionic Currents and Excitotoxicity. Neurotox Res&#xD;
           2018;34:1-15.&#xD;
&#xD;
       17. Lai MC, Lin KM, Yeh PS, Wu SN, Huang CW. The novel effect of immunomodulator-glatiramer&#xD;
           acetate on epileptogenesis and epileptic seizures. Cell Physiol Biochem 2018;50:150-68.&#xD;
&#xD;
       18. Lai MC, Tzeng RC, Huang CW, Wu SN. The Novel Direct Modulatory Effects of Perampanel, an&#xD;
           Antagonist of AMPA Receptors, on Voltage-Gated Sodium and M-type Potassium Currents.&#xD;
           Biomolecules 2019;9 pii: E638.&#xD;
&#xD;
       19. Lynch BA, Lambeng N, Nocka K, et al. The synaptic vesicle protein SV2A is the binding&#xD;
           site for the antiepileptic drug levetiracetam. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2004;101:9861-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
       20. Mohammad H, Sekar S, Wei Z, Moien-Afshari F, Taghibiglou C. Perampanel but Not&#xD;
           Amantadine Prevents Behavioral Alterations and Epileptogenesis in Pilocarpine Rat Model&#xD;
           of Status Epilepticus. Mol Neurobiol 2019;56:2508-23.&#xD;
&#xD;
       21. Morgenstern LB, Hemphill JC 3rd, Anderson C, Becker K, Broderick JP, Connolly ES Jr,&#xD;
           Greenberg SM, Huang JN, Macdonald RL, Messe SR, Mitchell PH, Selim M, Tamargo RJ.&#xD;
           Guidelines for the Management of Spontaneous Intracerebral Hemorrhage. A Guideline for&#xD;
           Healthcare Professionals From the American Heart Association/American Stroke&#xD;
           Association. Stroke. 2010;41:2108-29.&#xD;
&#xD;
       22. Pitkanen A, Schwartzkroin PA, Moshe SM. Models of seizures and epilepsy. Burlington:&#xD;
           Elsevier Academic Press. 2006.&#xD;
&#xD;
       23. Pitkanen A, Roivainen R, Lukasiuk K. Development of epilepsy after ischemic stroke.&#xD;
           Lancet Neurol 2016;15:185-97.&#xD;
&#xD;
       24. Rosati A, Buttolo L, Stefini R. Efficacy and safety of levetiracetam in patients with&#xD;
           glioma. Arch Neurol 2010;67:343-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
       25. Shetty A. Prospects of levetiracetam as a neuroprotective drug against status&#xD;
           epilepticus, traumatic brain injury, and stroke. Front Neurol 2013;4:1-6.&#xD;
&#xD;
       26. Tanaka T, Ihara M. Post-stroke epilepsy. Neurochem Int 2017;107:219-28.&#xD;
&#xD;
       27. Tyrlikova I, Brazdil M, Rektor I, Tyrlik M. Perampanel as monotherapy and adjunctive&#xD;
           therapy for focal onset seizures, focal to bilateral tonic-clonic seizures and as&#xD;
           adjunctive therapy of generalized onset tonic-clonic seizures. Expert Rev Neurother&#xD;
           2018;18:1-12.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Double-blinded study</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>post-stroke epileptic seizure</measure>
    <time_frame>at least 14 days after stroke</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of epileptic seizure following acute stage of stroke</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">180</enrollment>
  <condition>Middle Cerebral Artery Stroke</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Levetiracetam</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The group receives oral levetiracetam.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Perampanel</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The group receives oral perampanel.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The group receives oral placebo.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Levetiracetam Oral Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Administer levetiracetam powder once a day in eligible patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>Levetiracetam</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>keppra</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Perampanel Oral Product</intervention_name>
    <description>Administer perampanel powder once a day in eligible patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>Perampanel</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>fycompa</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Administer placebo powder once a day in eligible patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with acute MCA infarct (NIHSS &gt; 8) and confirmed by brain MRI studies&#xD;
             (excluding lacunar infarct) during hospital admission&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with prior clinical history of major stroke, significant head injury, brain&#xD;
             tumor, major psychiatric illness, progressive neurodegenerative disorder, CNS&#xD;
             infection, epilepsy, which might be precipitating to seizures or history of use of&#xD;
             AEDs, including LEV or PER, during pregnancy or lactation, history of inadequate&#xD;
             medical compliance, or any other significant major systemic disease with safety&#xD;
             concern, determined by physician&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Chin-Wei Huang, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Cheng-Kung University Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Chin-Wei Huang, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>886-6-2353535</phone>
    <phone_ext>5485</phone_ext>
    <email>huangcw@mail.ncku.edu.tw</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Cheng Kung University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tainan</city>
        <zip>701</zip>
        <country>Taiwan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Chin-Wei Huang, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>886-2353535</phone>
      <phone_ext>5485</phone_ext>
      <email>huangcw@mail.ncku.edu.tw</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Taiwan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 21, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 21, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 21, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Cheng Kung University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Chin-Wei Huang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Stroke</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Epilepsy</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infarction, Middle Cerebral Artery</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Levetiracetam</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

