<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04856254</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>previous cesarean section scar</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04856254</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Clinical and Ultrasound Score for Evaluation of Previous Cesarean Section Scar</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical and Ultrasound Score for Evaluation of Previous Cesarean Section Scar</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mansoura University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mansoura University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cesarean delivery rates have increased dramatically worldwide. In the United States, cesarean&#xD;
      section (CS) rates increased from 5% of all deliveries in 1970 to a high of 31.9% in&#xD;
      2016.Although efforts were made to reduce the number of CS, it failed to achieve the 15% rate&#xD;
      recommended by the World Health Organization (WHO).Repeat CS is the most significant factor&#xD;
      contributing to overall increased CS rates. The primary indication of repeat CS is a prior&#xD;
      CS. The trial of labor after cesarean (TOLAC) is an attempt to reduce CS rates. Several&#xD;
      national medical associations have provided practice guidelines for vaginal birth after&#xD;
      cesarean section (VBAC), but these differ across countries.VBAC is relatively safe when&#xD;
      compared with repeat CS.However, TOLAC rates have dropped significantly worldwide in recent&#xD;
      years.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Brief History taking include: age of patient, gravidity, parity, time interval between&#xD;
      previous cesarean sections and current pregnancy, indication for the previous cesarean&#xD;
      section, and fetal weight of previous delivery with special emphasis on menstrual history for&#xD;
      proper dating and history of previous pregnancy to verify the inclusion or exclusion&#xD;
      criteria.Physical examination include : General examination: for exclusion of presence of any&#xD;
      medical disorders,Obstetric examination include: Fundal level to correlate with gestational&#xD;
      age known by history, Umbilical grip to verify inclusion and exclusion criteria, Scar&#xD;
      tenderness and shape in women who had undergone a previous cesarean section and&#xD;
      investigations that will be performed including the following:basic routine antenatal&#xD;
      investigations of pregnant women including blood group,Rhesus factor, complete blood count,&#xD;
      blood sugar, and urine analysis. abdominal and transvaginal ultrasound will be performed&#xD;
      for:a complete obstetric assessment at full term using TAS to confirm gestational age, fetal&#xD;
      vitality, lie and presentation, amniotic fluid and placental position.Evaluation of the lower&#xD;
      uterine segment using TVS, by measuring its thickness and identifying the echo structure for&#xD;
      beinghomogenous or not . The LUS will be visualized in the sagittal section in the midline&#xD;
      and lateral plane. The measurement will be obtained with the cursors at the urinary bladder&#xD;
      wall- myometrium interface and the myometrium chorioamniotic membrane-amniotic fluid&#xD;
      interface. Three layers can be identified by ultrasonography in a well-developed LUS in a&#xD;
      midline section of sagittal view in a partially filled bladder. They are as follows from&#xD;
      inside outwards:Chorioamniotic membrane with decidualized endometrium, a middle layer of&#xD;
      myometrium and utero-vesical peritoneal reflection juxtaposed to muscularis and mucosa of the&#xD;
      bladder.The lower uterine segment will be visualized in sagittal section in the midline.There&#xD;
      after :150 patients will be evaluated using a measurement value of the clinical and&#xD;
      ultrasound criteria and Follow up of all participants will be followed up till delivery, the&#xD;
      mode of delivery either VBAC or elective repeated lower segment CS according to:History and&#xD;
      clinical examination evaluation: Previous complicated CS or not, time interval between&#xD;
      previous cesarean sections and current pregnancy(less than one year or more than one&#xD;
      year),tender scar or not. US : TAS and TVS include: Lower uterine segment thickness , The&#xD;
      echo structure of the lower uterine segment (Homogenous or nonHomogenous). For follow up of&#xD;
      patient with previous CS include Initial evaluation: Each of the clinical and US parameters&#xD;
      will be scored based on the sum of points is shown in table whatever to complete delivery by&#xD;
      natural means or again by cesarean section.If the score is more than 7 out of 10 a vaginal&#xD;
      birth will tried. On the other hand,Score 7 or less than 7 will be considered an indication&#xD;
      to do repeated elective cesarean section.Careful follow up of patient during trial of labor&#xD;
      after CS [TOLAC] for any possible symptoms and signs of uterine rupture that require&#xD;
      immediate surgical intervention like : bleeding either intra abdominal or vaginal,cessation&#xD;
      of uterine contraction,abnormal uterine contour,abdominal distention,shoulder tip&#xD;
      pain,supraoubic pain,sudden severe abdominal pain may decrease after rupture,tender&#xD;
      abdomen,rapid materinal pulse, low blood pressure,hypovolomic shock if rupture involve major&#xD;
      blood vessels,no fetal presentation on vaginal examination,prolonged fetal bradycardia and&#xD;
      absent fetal heart activity during continuous electronic heart rate monitoring.Careful&#xD;
      examination of patient after vaginal delivery to detect any maternal complication by: local&#xD;
      examination under anesthesia to ensure continuity of cesarean scar and ultrasound evaluation&#xD;
      of scar.The parameters that are evaluated by clinical and ultrasound criteria Clinical and&#xD;
      ultrasound criteria SCORE (2) SCORE (1)Tender scar Not tender (2) Tender (1)Previous&#xD;
      complicated CS Not complicated (2) Complicated (1) ,Echo structure of the LUS Homogenous (2)&#xD;
      Non homogenous (1)Lower uterine segment thickness More than or equal 3.65 mm(2) .more than&#xD;
      3mm to less than 3.65 mm(1)Pregnancy time interval after the CS More than 12 months(2) 12&#xD;
      months or less(1)Total Score (10) (5)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>The pregnant females will be classified according to clinical and ultrasound score as patient suitable to undergo trial of labor after CS [TOLAC] or not suitable for [TOLAC] so undergo from the beginning to elective repeated cesarean section.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Novel score (Mosbah) score for evaluation of previous cesarean section scar</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The aim of this study is to use a novel score (Mosbah score) for evaluation of previous cesarean section scar in pregnant women in order to select the best and most safe mode of delivery by using certain measurments based on clinical findings and ultrasound measurements.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Previous Cesarean Section Scar</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Trial of labor after cesarean section</intervention_name>
    <description>The pregnant females with history of previous cesarean section will be classified according to clinical and ultrasound score as patient suitable to undergo trial of labor after CS [TOLAC]or not suitable for [TOLAC] so undergo from the beginning to elective repeated cesarean section.</description>
    <other_name>Elective repeated cesarean section</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous one cesarean section for non permenant indication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant women without any medical disorders.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gestational age: 36-40 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant woman with singleton pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinically adequate pelvis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal ultrasonographic findings (gestational age, fetal structures and placental&#xD;
             site).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cephalic vertex presentation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients not inlabour.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous repair of ruptured uterus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with history of long-term treatment for infertility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Multiple pregnancies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous operations in uterus rather than cesarean section.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Polyhydramnios and Fetal macrosomia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with bad obstetric history (previous IUFD or difficult delivery).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Disturbance of fetal heart rate (determined with the CTG).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>17 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Faculty of Medicine - Mansoura University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mansoura</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Martin JA, Hamilton BE, Osterman MJK. Births in the United States, 2016. NCHS Data Brief. 2017 Sep;(287):1-8.</citation>
    <PMID>29155684</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>World Health Organization Human Reproduction Programme, 10 April 2015. WHO Statement on caesarean section rates. Reprod Health Matters. 2015 May;23(45):149-50. doi: 10.1016/j.rhm.2015.07.007. Epub 2015 Jul 27.</citation>
    <PMID>26278843</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cheng YW, Eden KB, Marshall N, Pereira L, Caughey AB, Guise JM. Delivery after prior cesarean: maternal morbidity and mortality. Clin Perinatol. 2011 Jun;38(2):297-309. doi: 10.1016/j.clp.2011.03.012.</citation>
    <PMID>21645797</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Foureur M, Ryan CL, Nicholl M, Homer C. Inconsistent evidence: analysis of six national guidelines for vaginal birth after cesarean section. Birth. 2010 Mar;37(1):3-10. doi: 10.1111/j.1523-536X.2009.00372.x.</citation>
    <PMID>20402716</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mansoura University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mahmoud Elsaeed Elgohary</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Trial of labor after cesarean section(TOLAC)&amp; vaginal birth after cesarean section (VBAC)</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

