<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04854317</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0001501/12/05/2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04854317</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Bariatric Endoscopy for Treatment of I and II Grade Obesity</brief_title>
  <official_title>Indications and Patients Selection for Bariatric Endoscopy for Treatment of I and II Grade Obesity: a Single Centre, Prospective, Randomized Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mater Olbia Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Catholic University of the Sacred Heart</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Udine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mater Olbia Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A single-center prospective, randomized controlled study will be conducted in order to&#xD;
      compare the main bariatric endoscopy (BE) techniques in I and II grade obese patients (BMI&#xD;
      &gt;30 and &lt;40 kg/m2) at Gastroenterology and Gastrointestinal Endoscopy Unit, Mater Olbia&#xD;
      Hospital, Qatar Foundation Endowment &amp; Gemelli Foundation, Italy in period June 2020 - June&#xD;
      2022, with the aim to evaluate the safety and efficacy of these procedures.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKROUND Obesity has reached epidemic proportions in the world affecting nowadays, along&#xD;
      with overweight, over a third of the world's population. It is a chronic multifactorial&#xD;
      illness that can lead to potentially life threatening diseases (such as metabolic disorders,&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease, stroke, liver disease, and cancer) that can be prevented and improved&#xD;
      by weight loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A widely accepted option for the treatment of obesity is the endoscopic approach by many&#xD;
      different techniques, ranging from the placement of an intragastric balloon (IGB) to&#xD;
      Endoscopic Sleeve Gastroplasty (ESG Apollo) with Overstitch Endoscopic Suturing Device,&#xD;
      Primary Obesity Surgery Endolumenal 2 (POSE2) and Endoluminal Vertical Gastroplasty (EVG)&#xD;
      with an endoluminal-suturing device (Endomina). Basically, Bariatric Endoscopy (BE) has two&#xD;
      mechanism of action. The first one consists in reduction of the stomach capacity and the&#xD;
      second one is alteration of gastric motility.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The major advantages of BE techniques consist in their lower invasiveness compared to&#xD;
      surgery, reversibility, short hospital stay, and cost-effectiveness. For instance,&#xD;
      laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy (LSG) is the most performed bariatric surgery procedure that&#xD;
      is effective but is associated with important adverse events as bleeding from the staple line&#xD;
      that can occur in up to 5% of the procedures, gastric leak and persistent fistulas that can&#xD;
      occur in up to 8% the LSG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The weight reduction is conditioned by patient gastric capacity and treatment duration but&#xD;
      also the change in the attitude of the patient towards food and physical activity may be&#xD;
      fundamental. It is therefore important that the patient is motivated to lose weight and aware&#xD;
      of the consequences of his behaviour.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As at the moment many endoscopic bariatric techniques are available and most of them are&#xD;
      often interchangeable, it could be important to start clarifying if there are any differences&#xD;
      among them in terms of their safety and efficacy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TYPE OF STUDY Single centre, prospective, randomized controlled study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES Primary objective of the study is to establish a standardized patients selection&#xD;
      method to BE for the treatment of I and II grade obesity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      TRIAL DESIGN All patients with indication to BE will be revised by an internal&#xD;
      multidisciplinary team composed of gastroenterologist, surgeon, dietitian, psychiatrist,&#xD;
      radiologist and endocrinologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before each endoscopic bariatric procedure, the patients will be subjected to a&#xD;
      psychoclinical assessment (a clinical interview along with psychometric tests) to identify&#xD;
      psychopathological conditions which may contraindicate the treatment or personality traits&#xD;
      that may predict a successfull treatment (Millon Clinical Multiaxial Inventory-III, MCMI-III)&#xD;
      ; during this visit it will be also evaluated the patients' food-related behavior (Eating&#xD;
      Problem Checklist EPCL) , their binge eating severity (Binge Eating Scale BES) , various&#xD;
      aspects of body-image perception and body attitudes (Body Uneasiness Test BUT) , the eating&#xD;
      impulsivity (BIS-11 Barratt Impulsiveness Scale BIS-11) , and the patients' quality of life&#xD;
      based on a combination of generic and specific instruments (Obesity Related Well-Being&#xD;
      questionnaire ORWELL 97) , collateral QoL measures (as the Short Form of SF-36 health Survey,&#xD;
      SF-12 and BAROS Bariatric Analysis and Reporting Outcome System) , together with the&#xD;
      patients' own intervention; major endocrine disorders will be excluded and an&#xD;
      esophagogastroduodenoscopy will be performed in order to exclude also endoscopic&#xD;
      contraindications to the endoscopic bariatric procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before each endoscopic bariatric procedure patients also will get their first dietician&#xD;
      examination while at hospital. During the first visit, all patients will be subjected to a&#xD;
      clinical interview in order to estimate their calories intake, their eating and taste habits&#xD;
      and their level of physical activity, then will be collected anthropometric data (height,&#xD;
      weight, circumferences) in order to calculate Body Mass Index (BMI), Waist/Hips ratio (WHR)&#xD;
      and cardiovascular risk. Furthermore the dietician will identify a goal for each patient in&#xD;
      terms of weight loss and physical activity improvement per week, reinforcing successful&#xD;
      outcomes and rewarding good behaviors, also through the involvement of patients family&#xD;
      members as social support. Just after the endoscopic bariatric procedure patients will be&#xD;
      given a two months refeeding protocol, different depending on endoscopic procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before the preliminary esophagogastroduodenoscopy a blood and stool sample will be collected&#xD;
      in order to establish the initial ormonal and microbiota asset for each patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A liver ultrasound with elastography will be performed in order to evaluate the degree of&#xD;
      steatosis. A transit study examination and a barium x-ray will be performed in order to test&#xD;
      the motility and the size of the stomach before the endoscopic bariatric procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After informed consent will be obtained, patients will be randomly enrolled to each&#xD;
      procedure, according a software released by the GraphPad Software Company.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each procedure will be performed by two skilled endoscopists in obesity procedures and with&#xD;
      an anaesthesiologist support for monitoring, deep sedation or general anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The patients undergoing the bariatric procedure will be randomly divided as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ¼ patients will be treated with adjustable or nonadjustable fluid-filled IGB (placed&#xD;
           into the gastric cavity through the mouth by a gastroscope and filled with 690 ml of&#xD;
           saline and 10 ml methylene blue solution in order to diagnose an eventual asymptomatic&#xD;
           rupture of the intragastric device) lasting in situ for 1 year;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ¼ patients will be treated with ESG (created by a series of endoluminally placed&#xD;
           free-hand, full-thickness, closely spaced sutures through the gastric wall from the&#xD;
           pre-pyloric antrum to the gastroesophageal junction by using an endoscopic suturing&#xD;
           device called Overstitch. This procedure reduces the entire stomach along the greater&#xD;
           curvature, to form an endoscopically created sleeve);&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ¼ patients will be treated with POSE2 (large, overtube-style platform that has 4 working&#xD;
           channels that can accommodate a slim endoscope and 3 specialized instruments to place&#xD;
           transmural tissue anchor plications in parts of the gastric body);&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  ¼ patients will be treated with EVG (by using an over-the-scope triangulation platform&#xD;
           attached to an endoscope, anterior-to-posterior greater curvature plications are&#xD;
           applied).&#xD;
&#xD;
      After the procure the patients will undergo a dietician check each 1.5 months till 6 months,&#xD;
      then each 3 months till two years. Just after the first follow-up patients will be given a&#xD;
      new customized food plan. During each dietician check will be collected new anthropometric&#xD;
      data and patients will be trained to reduce calories intake, to increase physical activity,&#xD;
      to self-monitoring, to slower eating and they will undergo a nutritional education in order&#xD;
      to obtain behavior-change intervention. During dietician checks, the patients will be&#xD;
      interviewed regarding their quality of life according the Weiner's Bariatric Quality of Life&#xD;
      Index , their behavior change about diet and calories intake and will be collected new&#xD;
      anthropometric data in order to evaluate the % of total body weight loss (%TBW) and the Δ&#xD;
      Body Mass Index (ΔBMI). dietician checks will be performed by a dietician who is skilled both&#xD;
      in dietician support and behavioral therapy for obese patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore during the follow-up patients will also undergo a psychological visits, with the&#xD;
      same timing of the dietician checks (each 1.5 months till 6 months, then each 3 months till&#xD;
      two years), in order to evaluate the compliance to the previous given instructions, to&#xD;
      reinforce good eating behaviors and, after a psychoclinical reassessment through some of the&#xD;
      above mentioned tests, to give a psychological support in case of need.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will undergo also a gastroenterological visit 1.5 months later the endoscopic&#xD;
      bariatric procedure and then each 3 months till 1 year to assess any possible adverse event&#xD;
      to the procedure or to modify therapy in case of symptoms not well controlled.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A liver ultrasound with elastography, a transit study examination and a barium x-ray will be&#xD;
      performed 6 months after the procedure in order to evaluate any change in hepatic steatosis,&#xD;
      motility and size of the stomach.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An esophagogastroduodenoscopy will be performed 1 year later the endoscopic bariatric&#xD;
      procedure for BIB removal (as requested in these cases) or to check sutures and plications&#xD;
      condition and stomach integrity in those patients who underwent gastroplasty techniques.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood and stool samples will be collected 30±15 90±15, 180±15, 270±15 and 360±15 days after&#xD;
      each endoscopic bariatric procedure in order to evaluate hormonal and microbiota&#xD;
      modifications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PATIENTS At least seventy-six adult patients with I or II grade obesity eligible for&#xD;
      endoscopic bariatric therapy will retrospectively, randomly and consecutively enrolled in one&#xD;
      Endoscopy Unit: Mater Olbia Hospital (Olbia, Italy).&#xD;
&#xD;
      SAMPLE SIZE Assuming from the literature that the bariatric endoscopic techniques considered&#xD;
      in our protocol have similar results in the short-term period (i.e. 15-20% of % Total Body&#xD;
      Weight Loss), while hypothesising relevant differences in the long-term period, a total&#xD;
      sample size of 76 patients will be sufficient to detect a difference of means among the 4&#xD;
      groups, assuming an effect size of 40%, a power of 80% and a significance level of 5%.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STATISTICS Descriptive analyses included medians and ranges for continuous variables and&#xD;
      frequencies and percentages for categorical data. Variables were analyzed using the&#xD;
      Shapiro-Wilk test to determine if they were normally distributed. Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney test&#xD;
      was used to compare interval data not conforming to a normal distribution. Data will be&#xD;
      compared by Student's t test, analysis of variance (ANOVA) or the non-parametric Mann-Whitney&#xD;
      U test, as appropriate. Categorical variables will be analyzed using χ2 test or Fisher's&#xD;
      exact test, as appropriate. Correlations between continuous measures will be inspected using&#xD;
      Pearson's (r) or Spearman's (ρ) correlation, as appropriate. For multiple-comparison the&#xD;
      Bonferroni correction (pc) was used. A P-value of &lt; 0.05 was considered to be statistically&#xD;
      significant. A complete-case analysis has been conducted. All data were analyzed with STATA&#xD;
      version 12 (StataCorp, College Station, Tex).&#xD;
&#xD;
      INFORMED CONSENT STATEMENT All patients were required to give informed consent to the study.&#xD;
      All clinical data will be obtained after each patient agreed to treatment by written consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DATA RETENTION Data will be retained by the Mater Olbia Hospital in the electronic archive&#xD;
      provided for each patient during their first admission at Hospital, as it always happens for&#xD;
      all patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      INSURANCE All patients will be covered by the regular insurance provided by the Mater Olbia&#xD;
      Hospital for inpatients and outpatients as the same steps are scheduled also for each patient&#xD;
      who should undergo an endoscopic bariatric procedure out of this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 19, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 19, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>safety in terms of occurrance major complications during endoscopic bariatric procedures</measure>
    <time_frame>intra-procedural</time_frame>
    <description>bleeding (YES/NO), perforation (YES/NO), fistula (YES/NO)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>safety in terms of occurrance of major complications after endoscopic bariatric procedures</measure>
    <time_frame>12, 24, 48 hours after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>bleeding (YES/NO), perforation (YES/NO), fistula (YES/NO)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pain procedure-related</measure>
    <time_frame>the day before the procedure, at 12, 24, 48 hours after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>NRS pain scale (0-10 points, where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain imaginable)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>prolonged pain procedure-related</measure>
    <time_frame>at 1,3,6,9,12 months after procedure</time_frame>
    <description>NRS pain scale 0-10 points (where 0 is no pain and 10 is the worst pain imaginable)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>vomit procedure-related</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12, 24, 48 hours and at 1,3,6,9,12 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>PONV vomit scale 0-3 points (0= no vomit, 1=1 episodes per day, 2= 2 episodes per day, 3= 3 or more episodes per day)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>nausea procedure-related</measure>
    <time_frame>at 12, 24, 48 hours and at 1,3,6,9,12 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>PONV nausea intensity scale 0-3 points (0= no nausea, 1=sometimes, 2= often or most of the time, 3= all of the time)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>quality of life of endoscopic bariatric procedures</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month before the procedure and 1,3,6,9,12,18,24,36,48 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>BAROS QoL Scale (BAROS questionnaire)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>percent of total body weight loss (%TBW) after the procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>at 90±15, 180±15, 270±15 and 360±15, 540±30, 720±30 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the percent of total body weight loss (%TBW) after each endoscopic bariatric procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>change of Body Mass Index (ΔBMI)</measure>
    <time_frame>at 90±15, 180±15, 270±15 and 360±15, 540±30, 720±30 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>change of Body Mass Index (ΔBMI) after each endoscopic bariatric procedure</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>integrity of the stitches of endoscopic gastroplasty techniques</measure>
    <time_frame>at 6,12,24,48 months</time_frame>
    <description>percent of stitches remained in site</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>integrity of the intragastric balloon</measure>
    <time_frame>at 1, 3, 6 months</time_frame>
    <description>rupture of the intragastric balloon</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>procedure time differences among the procedures used</measure>
    <time_frame>intra-procedural</time_frame>
    <description>procedure time (minutes)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>quantity of devices and accessories used during the procedures</measure>
    <time_frame>intra-procedural</time_frame>
    <description>number of suturing systems, needles, threads, sutures and cinchs</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>hepatic steatosis</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day before the procedure and 1,3,12, 24 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>quantification of the hepatic steatosis before and after the procedure by elastography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>gastric diameters</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month before the procedure and 1,3,12, 24, 48 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>antero-posterior (in cm) and superior-inferior (in cm) diameters before and after the procedure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>gastric emptying</measure>
    <time_frame>1 month before the procedure and 1,3,12, 24, 48 months after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>gastric emptying (in minutes) before and after the procedure by gastroeintestinal series with contrast after a light meal (sandwich).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>microbiota mutations</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day before and at 90±15, 180±30, 270±30, 360±30 and 720±30 days after the procedure</time_frame>
    <description>microbiota composition before and after each endoscopic bariatric procedure by DANAGENEMICROBIOME Fecal DNA kit (DanaGen-Bioted, S.L.) and Qubit 4.0 fluorometer (Life Technologhies).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Obesity</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing adjustable or nonadjustable fluid-filled intragastric balloon placement</arm_group_label>
    <description>Obese patients with I and II grade obesity (BMI &gt;30 and &lt;40 kg/m2) and previous multiple failed attempts of diet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing Endoscopic Sleeve Gastroplasty</arm_group_label>
    <description>Obese patients with I and II grade obesity (BMI &gt;30 and &lt;40 kg/m2) and previous multiple failed attempts of diet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing Endoluminal Vertical Gastroplasty</arm_group_label>
    <description>Obese patients with I and II grade obesity (BMI &gt;30 and &lt;40 kg/m2) and previous multiple failed attempts of diet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing Primary Obesity Surgical Endolumenal 2</arm_group_label>
    <description>Obese patients with I and II grade obesity (BMI &gt;30 and &lt;40 kg/m2) and previous multiple failed attempts of diet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Endoscopic gastroplasty or Intragastric balloon placement</intervention_name>
    <description>Endoscopic bariatric procedures</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing Endoluminal Vertical Gastroplasty</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing Endoscopic Sleeve Gastroplasty</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing Primary Obesity Surgical Endolumenal 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients undergoing adjustable or nonadjustable fluid-filled intragastric balloon placement</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Apollo Overstitch Sx</other_name>
    <other_name>Endomina</other_name>
    <other_name>POSE2</other_name>
    <other_name>Orbera365</other_name>
    <other_name>Spatz3</other_name>
    <other_name>Medsil</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      blood; feces.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        patients with I and II grade obesity&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age &gt; 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acceptance of written informed consent to undergo an endoscopic bariatric therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  I and II grade obesity: BMI 30-34.99 with many failed attempts at noninvasive weight&#xD;
             loss and with obesity-related diseases; BMI 35-39.99 with many failed attempts at&#xD;
             noninvasive weight loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  coagulation problems (such as platelet &lt; 30000, INR &gt;1.8), chronic kidney disease,&#xD;
             heart disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  any other contraindication for endoscopic bariatric procedure;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who do not give their consent to the enrollment in the study or are&#xD;
             incompetent, unconscious or unable to express their consent for any reason;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients suffering from any condition which precludes compliance with study&#xD;
             instructions;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient has any allergy or other known contraindication or intolerance to the&#xD;
             medications used in the study for the preparation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  women who are either pregnant or nursing at the time of screening, or are of&#xD;
             child-bearing potential and do not practice acceptable methods of contraception;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient suffers from a life threatening condition.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Salvatore F. Vadalà di Prampero, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Gastroenterology and GI Endoscopy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Milutin Bulajic, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Gastroenterology and GI Endoscopy</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Salvatore F. Vadalà di Prampero, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>00393492666795</phone>
    <email>salvatore.vadala@materolbia.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mater Olbia Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Olbia</city>
        <zip>07026</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Salvatore F. Vadalà di Prampero, MD, Phd</last_name>
      <phone>00393492666795</phone>
      <email>salvatore.vadala@materolbia.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hruby A, Hu FB. The Epidemiology of Obesity: A Big Picture. Pharmacoeconomics. 2015 Jul;33(7):673-89. doi: 10.1007/s40273-014-0243-x. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25471927</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kopelman PG. Obesity as a medical problem. Nature. 2000 Apr 6;404(6778):635-43. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10766250</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yasawy MI, Al-Quorain AA, Hussameddin AM, Yasawy ZM, Al-Sulaiman RM. Obesity and gastric balloon. J Family Community Med. 2014 Sep;21(3):196-9. doi: 10.4103/2230-8229.142977.</citation>
    <PMID>25374473</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>ASGE Bariatric Endoscopy Task Force; ASGE Technology Committee, Abu Dayyeh BK, Edmundowicz SA, Jonnalagadda S, Kumar N, Larsen M, Sullivan S, Thompson CC, Banerjee S. Endoscopic bariatric therapies. Gastrointest Endosc. 2015 May;81(5):1073-86. doi: 10.1016/j.gie.2015.02.023. Epub 2015 Mar 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25828245</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>ASGE Bariatric Endoscopy Task Force and ASGE Technology Committee, Abu Dayyeh BK, Kumar N, Edmundowicz SA, Jonnalagadda S, Larsen M, Sullivan S, Thompson CC, Banerjee S. ASGE Bariatric Endoscopy Task Force systematic review and meta-analysis assessing the ASGE PIVI thresholds for adopting endoscopic bariatric therapies. Gastrointest Endosc. 2015 Sep;82(3):425-38.e5. doi: 10.1016/j.gie.2015.03.1964. Epub 2015 Jul 29. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26232362</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gómez V, Woodman G, Abu Dayyeh BK. Delayed gastric emptying as a proposed mechanism of action during intragastric balloon therapy: Results of a prospective study. Obesity (Silver Spring). 2016 Sep;24(9):1849-53. doi: 10.1002/oby.21555. Epub 2016 Jul 28.</citation>
    <PMID>27465076</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abu Dayyeh BK, Acosta A, Camilleri M, Mundi MS, Rajan E, Topazian MD, Gostout CJ. Endoscopic Sleeve Gastroplasty Alters Gastric Physiology and Induces Loss of Body Weight in Obese Individuals. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017 Jan;15(1):37-43.e1. doi: 10.1016/j.cgh.2015.12.030. Epub 2015 Dec 31.</citation>
    <PMID>26748219</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nielsen AW, Helm MC, Kindel T, Higgins R, Lak K, Helmen ZM, Gould JC. Perioperative bleeding and blood transfusion are major risk factors for venous thromboembolism following bariatric surgery. Surg Endosc. 2018 May;32(5):2488-2495. doi: 10.1007/s00464-017-5951-9. Epub 2017 Nov 3.</citation>
    <PMID>29101558</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Berger ER, Clements RH, Morton JM, Huffman KM, Wolfe BM, Nguyen NT, Ko CY, Hutter MM. The Impact of Different Surgical Techniques on Outcomes in Laparoscopic Sleeve Gastrectomies: The First Report from the Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery Accreditation and Quality Improvement Program (MBSAQIP). Ann Surg. 2016 Sep;264(3):464-73. doi: 10.1097/SLA.0000000000001851.</citation>
    <PMID>27433904</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Inaba CS, Koh CY, Sujatha-Bhaskar S, Silva JP, Chen Y, Nguyen DV, Nguyen NT. One-Year Mortality after Contemporary Laparoscopic Bariatric Surgery: An Analysis of the Bariatric Outcomes Longitudinal Database. J Am Coll Surg. 2018 Jun;226(6):1166-1174. doi: 10.1016/j.jamcollsurg.2018.02.013. Epub 2018 Mar 16.</citation>
    <PMID>29551698</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ricca V, Mannucci E, Moretti S, Di Bernardo M, Zucchi T, Cabras PL, Rotella CM. Screening for binge eating disorder in obese outpatients. Compr Psychiatry. 2000 Mar-Apr;41(2):111-5.</citation>
    <PMID>10741889</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marano G, Cuzzolaro M, Vetrone G, Garfinkel PE, Temperilli F, Spera G, Dalle Grave R, Calugi S, Marchesini G; QUOVADIS Study Group. Validating the Body Uneasiness Test (BUT) in obese patients. Eat Weight Disord. 2007 Jun;12(2):70-82.</citation>
    <PMID>17615491</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fossati A, Di Ceglie A, Acquarini E, Barratt ES. Psychometric properties of an Italian version of the Barratt Impulsiveness Scale-11 (BIS-11) in nonclinical subjects. J Clin Psychol. 2001 Jun;57(6):815-28.</citation>
    <PMID>11344467</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mannucci E, Ricca V, Barciulli E, Di Bernardo M, Travaglini R, Cabras PL, Rotella CM. Quality of life and overweight: the obesity related well-being (Orwell 97) questionnaire. Addict Behav. 1999 May-Jun;24(3):345-57.</citation>
    <PMID>10400274</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Oria HE, Moorehead MK. Bariatric analysis and reporting outcome system (BAROS). Obes Surg. 1998 Oct;8(5):487-99.</citation>
    <PMID>9819079</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Weiner S, Sauerland S, Fein M, Blanco R, Pomhoff I, Weiner RA. The Bariatric Quality of Life index: a measure of well-being in obesity surgery patients. Obes Surg. 2005 Apr;15(4):538-45.</citation>
    <PMID>15954234</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mater Olbia Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Salvatore F. Vadalà di Prampero</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Weight</keyword>
  <keyword>Obese</keyword>
  <keyword>Endoscopic Sleeve Gastroplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Endoluminal Vertical Gastroplasty</keyword>
  <keyword>Primary Obesity Surgical Endolumenal 2</keyword>
  <keyword>Intragastric balloon</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Obesity</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

