<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04855214</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-02</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04855214</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating the Experience of Upper Limb Prosthesis Use</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Impact of Prosthetic Device Features on the Experience of Prosthesis Use</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Louis Stokes VA Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>United States Department of Defense</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Louis Stokes VA Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Our goal is to understand the critical factors associated with outcome acceptance following&#xD;
      upper limb loss. We aim to develop a unified theoretical model that describes the&#xD;
      psychosocial experience of upper limb prosthesis use and predicts outcome acceptance&#xD;
      following upper limb loss. This conceptual framework will enable clinicians and researchers&#xD;
      to evaluate and predict patient outcomes following limb loss, and to design interventions&#xD;
      that improve outcomes. The proposed two-year study is a mixed methods (qualitative and&#xD;
      quantitative) study using an observational design. The qualitative component of the study&#xD;
      will involve data collection through telephone interviews with 18 participants and analyses&#xD;
      using a grounded theory approach with constant comparison methods. The quantitative component&#xD;
      involves administration of standardized measures quantifying constructs of the theoretical&#xD;
      model in 120 participants and analyses to produce a structural equation model of outcome&#xD;
      acceptance. Participants will include persons with unilateral acquired upper limb loss at the&#xD;
      trans radial or trans humeral level who use currently available prosthetic devices.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background Use of an upper limb prosthesis can improve function and quality of life, but&#xD;
      these devices are frequently abandoned or used only intermittently. Two critical reasons for&#xD;
      abandonment identified by prosthesis rejecters are insufficient prosthesis functionality and&#xD;
      insufficient sensory feedback. Living with major limb loss is a complex experience involving&#xD;
      multiple physical, psychological, and social factors. While many studies have investigated&#xD;
      the needs and design priorities of prosthesis users, few have investigated how prosthesis&#xD;
      features interact with other psychosocial aspects of the prosthesis use experience and&#xD;
      overall attitude towards or acceptance of the device (outcome acceptance). To provide better&#xD;
      prosthetic device options and improve rehabilitation outcomes, we must understand the&#xD;
      relationships between prosthesis functional and sensory capabilities, the subjective&#xD;
      experience of the prosthesis, and outcome acceptance following limb loss.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective Our goal is to understand the critical factors associated with outcome acceptance&#xD;
      following upper limb loss. We aim to develop a unified theoretical model that describes the&#xD;
      psychosocial experience of upper limb prosthesis use and predicts outcome acceptance&#xD;
      following upper limb loss. This conceptual framework will enable clinicians and researchers&#xD;
      to evaluate and predict patient outcomes following limb loss, and to design interventions&#xD;
      that improve outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aims&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Specific Aim 1: Assess the impact of the experience of prosthesis dexterity and control&#xD;
           on outcome acceptance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Specific Aim 2: Assess the impact of sensory feedback experience on outcome acceptance.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Specific Aim 3: Refine the theoretical model derived from qualitative analyses by&#xD;
           exploring the quantitative relationships between aspects of the model of outcome&#xD;
           acceptance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypotheses Qualitative analyses will yield a theoretical model of outcome acceptance that&#xD;
      includes psychosocial factors and prosthetic device factors related to dexterity, control,&#xD;
      and sensory feedback. We hypothesize that experiences of prosthesis dexterity, control, and&#xD;
      sensory feedback will both directly influence and modulate psychosocial factors of prosthesis&#xD;
      use and user attitudes. We hypothesize that quantitative data collected through survey&#xD;
      research will triangulate findings from the qualitative analyses, confirm the directionality&#xD;
      of the conceptual relationships, and predict the relative weightings of relationships.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design The proposed study is a mixed methods (qualitative and quantitative) study using&#xD;
      an observational design. The qualitative component of the study will involve data collection&#xD;
      through telephone interviews with 18 participants and analyses using a grounded theory&#xD;
      approach with constant comparison methods. The quantitative component involves administration&#xD;
      and analyses of standardized measures quantifying constructs of the theoretical model in 120&#xD;
      participants and use of these measures in a structural equation model of outcome acceptance.&#xD;
      Participants will include persons with unilateral acquired upper limb loss at the trans&#xD;
      radial or trans humeral level who use currently available prosthetic devices.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 16, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Experience Measure (PEM)</measure>
    <time_frame>Two years</time_frame>
    <description>Measures the participant's perception of various psychosocial outcomes including self-efficacy, embodiment, body image, prosthesis efficiency, and social touch. It is rated 0-4, where a higher score in each sub-scale indicates a better outcome.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">138</enrollment>
  <condition>Prosthesis User</condition>
  <condition>Amputation</condition>
  <condition>Upper Limb Amputation at the Wrist</condition>
  <condition>Upper Limb Amputation Above Elbow (Injury)</condition>
  <condition>Upper Limb Amputation Below Elbow (Injury)</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Body-powered Prosthesis User</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals who use a prosthesis that relies on a system of cables or harnesses which are operated using other parts of the body like the shoulders, chest, or elbows.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single degree-of-freedom (DOF) myoelectric prosthesis users</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals who use a myoelectric prosthesis that can perform only one movement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Multi-DOF myoelectric prosthesis users</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals who use a myoelectric prosthesis that can perform more than one movement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sensory Augmentation</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals who experience augmented prosthesis sensory feedback through vibrating devices or pressure bladders, using electrical stimulation applied to the residual limb, or using neural implants.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Qualitative Analysis</intervention_name>
    <description>Mixed methods analysis of the user's experience with upper limb prosthetics.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Body-powered Prosthesis User</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Multi-DOF myoelectric prosthesis users</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sensory Augmentation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single degree-of-freedom (DOF) myoelectric prosthesis users</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Mixed Methods</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The proposed study will recruit a total of 138 persons with unilateral upper limb loss at&#xD;
        the trans radial or trans humeral level. Participants may be users of any currently&#xD;
        available prosthetic device brand, model, or terminal device, as long as their prosthesis&#xD;
        can be classified into one of the four groups : 1) body-powered prosthesis users, 2) single&#xD;
        degree-of-freedom (DOF) myoelectric prosthesis users, 3) multi-DOF myoelectric prosthesis&#xD;
        users, and 4) user's who experience augmented sensory feedback in their prosthesis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to give verbal informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to speak and understand English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unilateral acquired trans-radial or trans-humeral amputee&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least six months from time of limb loss&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current user of an upper limb prosthesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of the device they will be describing for at least six months (with the exception&#xD;
             of sensory augmentation)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant hearing impairment which would prevent telephone communication.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwillingness or inability to discuss experiences with prostheses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emotional disturbance related to discussion the prosthesis or limb loss&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Dustin J Tyler, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Louis Stokes VA Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alesia N Lambert, BS</last_name>
    <phone>440-645-8710</phone>
    <email>axl854@case.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Melissa S Schmitt, BSN, RN</last_name>
    <phone>216-791-3800</phone>
    <phone_ext>63801</phone_ext>
    <email>Melissa.Schmitt@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Louis Stokes VA Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cleveland</city>
        <state>Ohio</state>
        <zip>44106</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Holly Henry</last_name>
      <phone>216-791-3800</phone>
      <phone_ext>64657</phone_ext>
      <email>Holly.Henry@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 22, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Louis Stokes VA Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dustin J.Tyler PhD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Career Scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Upper Limb Prosthesis User</keyword>
  <keyword>Survey</keyword>
  <keyword>Interview</keyword>
  <keyword>User Experience</keyword>
  <keyword>Body-powered</keyword>
  <keyword>Myoelectric</keyword>
  <keyword>Multiple degree of freedom</keyword>
  <keyword>Sensory Feedback</keyword>
  <keyword>Prosthetic device features</keyword>
  <keyword>Upper Limb Loss</keyword>
  <keyword>Amputee</keyword>
  <keyword>Outcome Acceptance</keyword>
  <keyword>Qualitative Research</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified data will be made available upon request.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

