<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04852549</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Elif Aleyna Yazgan</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04852549</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Oculomotor Exercises on Volleyball Players</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Oculomotor Exercises on Balance, Dynamic Visual Acuity and Performance in Volleyball Players</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The researcher aimed to investigate the effects of oculo-motor exercises on dynamic visual&#xD;
      acuity, balance and performance of volleyball players whose performance can be improved with&#xD;
      visual skills training.&#xD;
&#xD;
      H0: Oculo-motor exercises applied to volleyball players are effective on dynamic visual&#xD;
      acuity, balance and performance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      H1: Oculo-motor exercises have no effect on dynamic visual acuity, balance and performance in&#xD;
      volleyball players.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study on the Effect of Oculo-Motor Exercises on Dynamic Visual Acuity, Balance and&#xD;
      Performance in Volleyball Players was ethically approved by the &quot;Istanbul Medipol University&#xD;
      Non-Invasive Ethics Committee&quot; with file number 10840098-604.01.01-E.14171 on 16.04.2020. The&#xD;
      study included 52 female volleyball players aged 16-26 who played participants for at least 3&#xD;
      years without interruption. Power analysis was performed using the 3.1.9.5 version of the&#xD;
      G-Power program to determine the number of individuals to be included in the study. Type-1&#xD;
      was accepted as 0.05 and power ratio as 80%. Effect size 0.8 was taken. According to the&#xD;
      results of the power analysis, the number of participants required to be included in the&#xD;
      study was determined as 52.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants; Age, height, weight, gender, body mass index, dominant side, position played in&#xD;
      volleyball, number of weekly training, daily training time, previous sports injuries,&#xD;
      education status, smoking and alcohol use, accompanying illnesses were questioned. FBT and&#xD;
      YBT were used for balance evaluations, and Nelson's Hand Reaction Test was used for reaction&#xD;
      times. In addition, Dynamic Visual Acuity and Vertical Jumping distances were evaluated twice&#xD;
      before and after treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants included in the study, the control group continued their routine ball training&#xD;
      after the evaluations, while the intervention group continued with the oculo-motor training&#xD;
      for 4 weeks, 6 days a week, in the morning and evening, for 10 minutes, 2 times a day, in&#xD;
      addition to normal ball training. they did the exercises. While doing the exercises,&#xD;
      individuals were taught to focus on the purpose they held in their hands, move their head,&#xD;
      and aim fast enough to see the image clearly. Two repetitions each week were added to the&#xD;
      exercise numbers. Ten seconds rest between two sets and five seconds rest between movements.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">November 20, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">April 6, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">March 5, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The group of the cases meeting the criteria was determined by the numbers determined by the randomizer program in the &quot;Research Randomiser&quot; web site.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will be made after 4 weeks of training.</time_frame>
    <description>Static balance of the individuals was evaluated by Flamingo Balance Test (FDT). A wooden stick of 50 cm length, 5 cm height and 3 cm width was used in the test. Dynamic balance changes of individuals were evaluated with YDT. In the measurement of dynamic balance with Y Balance Test (YDT), the amount of reaching out on the dominant sides of all individuals was measured.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Reaction time</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will be made after 4 weeks of training.</time_frame>
    <description>Reaction time Nelson hand reaction test was used.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Dynamic visual acuity</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will be made after 4 weeks of training.</time_frame>
    <description>In fact, dynamic vision is defined as the ability to detect details when there is a relative movement between the observer and the target object. It was measured by reading the numbers during neck rotation. A PowerPoint containing 10 slides, each of which randomly had 5 numbers, was used to measure dynamic vision (the size of all numbers was 12 to 20 at the center of the page). Each page had 5 numbers with the same font and each person evaluated 10 pages</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Vertical jump</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will be made after 4 weeks of training.</time_frame>
    <description>Vertical jump test was used.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">52</enrollment>
  <condition>Athlete</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No intervention group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control group continued with routine training after evaluations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oculomotor exercise group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>After the evaluation, the intervention group performed oculo-motor exercises for 4 weeks, 6 days a week, morning and evening, twice a day for 10 minutes, in addition to normal ball training. While doing the exercises, individuals were taught to focus on the purpose they held in their hands, move their head, and aim fast enough to see the image clearly. Two repetitions each week were added to the exercise numbers. Ten seconds rest between two sets and five seconds rest between movements.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oculomotor exercise</intervention_name>
    <description>While holding the head in the middle position, holding two colored objects in both hands, looking at the object in the right hand without turning the head, counting up to 10 and looking at the object in the left hand and counting up to 10,&#xD;
While holding a fixed head in the middle position and holding a colored object in the right hand, following the object with the eyes while moving the right hand from right to left without turning the head and returning,&#xD;
With the head fixed in the middle position, with the right hand on the left, eyes are fixed on the hand-held colored object and turn the head to the right and left.&#xD;
The head will be fixed in the middle position, the eyes will be fixed on the colored object held in the right or left hand and the arm and the head will be turned to opposite directions.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oculomotor exercise group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Being in the age range of 16-26&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Playing licensed volleyball for at least 3 years without interruption&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have normal vision and hearing&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having a direct blow to the lower or upper extremity in the past month&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  People with musculoskeletal disorders may experience balance (forward head posture).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refractive defects&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of ankle fracture&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Double-sided ankle sprain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Vision problems&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of lower extremity surgery in the last 6 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>26 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pınar Kaya Ciddi</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>İstanbul Medipol University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Elif Aleyna Yazgan</name>
      <address>
        <city>İstanbul</city>
        <zip>3434</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Istanbul Medipol University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>elif yazgan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Volleyball</keyword>
  <keyword>Balance</keyword>
  <keyword>Performance</keyword>
  <keyword>visual acuity</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

