<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04859374</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Be-Home-Pain</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04859374</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Chronic Pain and Conditioned Pain Modulation After on Line-behavioral Approach</brief_title>
  <acronym>Be-Home-Pain</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Home- Behavioral Approach by Mindfulness Added to Pharmacological Treatment on Endogenous Pain Modulation in Patients With Chronic Pain: Results at Long-term (Be-Home-Pain)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione I.R.C.C.S. Istituto Neurologico Carlo Besta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione I.R.C.C.S. Istituto Neurologico Carlo Besta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Chronic pain is a disabling condition associated with progressive changes and decline in&#xD;
      psychological wellbeing. According with a modern conceptualization, pain has to be considered&#xD;
      a biopsychosocial disorder where biological, affective, social and psychological aspects are&#xD;
      strictly connected. Although this new conceptualization, the implementation of an integral&#xD;
      systems approach of psychological tenets into treatments for chronic pain are limited.&#xD;
      Concerning treatments of chronic pain condition, the literature of the last years has&#xD;
      demonstrated how clinical benefit can be improved when traditional therapies are combined&#xD;
      with behavioral approaches in particular mindfulness. Systemic quantitative-somatosensory&#xD;
      testing of Conditioned Pain Modulation (CPM) can be considered a measure of endogenous&#xD;
      modulation of pain and it has been used in different clinical experiences to evaluate the&#xD;
      effectiveness of different pain treatments even if non pharmacological approaches.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Chronic pain is a disabling condition associated with progressive changes and decline in&#xD;
      psychological wellbeing. The burden of this condition is significant and also the&#xD;
      epidemiological impact. According with a modern conceptualization, pain has to be considered&#xD;
      a biopsychosocial disorder where biological, affective, social and psychological aspects are&#xD;
      strictly connected. Although this new conceptualization, the implementation of an integral&#xD;
      systems approach of psychological tenets into treatments for chronic pain are limited.&#xD;
      Concerning treatment of chronic pain condition, the literature of the last years has&#xD;
      demonstrated how clinical benefit can be improved when traditional therapies are combined&#xD;
      with behavioral approaches in particular mindfulness, that help patients to become more&#xD;
      conscious about their symptoms and able to manage pain without medication.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Systemic quantitative-somatosensory testing of Conditioned Pain Modulation (CPM) can be&#xD;
      considered a measure of endogenous modulation of pain and it has been used in different&#xD;
      clinical experiences to evaluate the effectiveness of different pain treatments even if non&#xD;
      pharmacological approaches Aim of this study: A group of patients suffering from Chronic&#xD;
      Migraine and Chronic Neuropathic Pain will be studied and followed with a specific&#xD;
      mindfulness protocol, added to traditional pharmacological therapy, performed on-line for 8&#xD;
      weeks. In order to determine if the behavioral approach can improve their clinical condition&#xD;
      patients will be followed for 12 months after treatments with regular visits every 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Also, in order to assess the integrity and improvement of the endogenous pain inhibitory&#xD;
      control a conditioned pain modulation paradigm will be performed at baseline and at 3, 6, 12&#xD;
      months. Patients will perform a baseline evaluation of thermal pain and mechanical pain&#xD;
      tresholds using the quantitative sensory methods, including the determination of&#xD;
      heat-generated temporal summation. Then, at baseline and at 3, 6, 12 months follow up, the&#xD;
      CPM paradigm will be performed using two heat painful stimuli, a tonic heat stimulus as&#xD;
      conditioning stimulus and a phasic heat stimulus as test stimuli.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be treated by traditional pharmacological therapies added to behavioral&#xD;
      approach (mindfulness on line by using a specific platform (STARLEAF)) (TAU/MIND) Eight&#xD;
      weekly one-hour video-sessions of mindfulness practice will be scheduled for patients;&#xD;
      instructions to manage pain and to encourage the use of strategies for pain management will&#xD;
      be given.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Moreover, instructions for behavioral approach and mindfulness, to practice every day will be&#xD;
      given: daily standardized mindfulness sessions of 12 minutes, by smartphone, recorded by the&#xD;
      expert who generally manages their sessions at the hospital will be scheduled for patients&#xD;
      Neuropsychological assessment will be provided at baseline and at every follow up Clinical,&#xD;
      neurophysiological and neuropsychological results will be compared to those obtained from&#xD;
      another group of patients treated by traditional pharmacological treatment (TAU) This&#xD;
      preliminary study will be conducted on 35 patients with diagnosis of CM and Chronic&#xD;
      Neuropathic Pain performed at our center.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific questionnaires for cognitive assessment and disability, catastrophizing attitude,&#xD;
      anxiety, depression, acceptance, pain coping will be performed at baseline and repeated at&#xD;
      every follow up ( PCS; GSE; HADS; CPAQ; AAQ; MAAS). The pain diary will be checked too with&#xD;
      scheduled NSR evaluation. The questionnaires will be repeated at every follow up and the pain&#xD;
      diary will be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results will be collected at baseline up to 12 months after treatment for both groups.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
    <masking_description>None (Open Label)</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of pain intensity</measure>
    <time_frame>From the first visit to the first follow up at 3 months till the last follow up at 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mean NRS (Numerical Rating Scale evaluation from the Daily diary card ) difference of at least 2 points on the scale(the scale range is from 0=no pain to 10 =maximum pain perceived) between MIND/TAU and TAU groups assessed by the daily diary card.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of pain frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Decrease in pain frequency, (days of pain per month) assessed by Daily Diary Card.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of medication intake</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Decrease of number of symptomatic medications per month assessed by Daily Diary Card.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurophysiological indexes</measure>
    <time_frame>3, 6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Changes in neurophysiological indexes evaluated by quantitative sensory test for conditioned pain modulation analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological measures - coping strategies</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Pain Catastrophizing Scale-Italian, PCS-I (Monticone et al., 2012)&#xD;
cut-off: 0 - 30 normal ranges &gt; 30 abnormal</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological measures - Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>General Self-Efficacy Scale, GSE ( (Schwarzer et al., 1995)&#xD;
cut off: 0 - 10 abnormal 10 - 40 normal ranges</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological measures - Mood</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale, HADS (Costantini et al., 1999)&#xD;
cut-off: total score 0 -7 = normal total score &gt; 7 = impairment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychological measures - Mindfulness specific tests</measure>
    <time_frame>6 and 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Mindful Awareness Attention Scale, MAAS (Veneziani et al., 2015) for mindfulness attitude for patients randomized in the MIND/TAU group&#xD;
cut-off: 15 - 90 normal ranges</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">35</enrollment>
  <condition>Migraine</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Any pharmacological therapy used for managing chronic pain or chronic migraine</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>TAU plus behavioral approach</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Any pharmacological therapy used for managing chronic pain or chronic migraine added with behavioral approach (mindfulness) delivered on line and smart phone for 6 weekly sessions</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfullness</intervention_name>
    <description>Behavioral approach (mindfulness) delivered on line and smart phone for 6 weekly sessions</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAU plus behavioral approach</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>treatment as usual (TAU) (pharmacological)</intervention_name>
    <description>Any pharmacological therapy used for managing chronic pain or chronic migraine</description>
    <arm_group_label>TAU plus behavioral approach</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual (TAU)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of chronic Migraine and Chronic Neuropathic Pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Co-existent severe medical or psychiatric illnesses&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of opioids during the 3 months before the inclusion into the protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Practice of mindfulness in the last 12 months&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Licia Grazzi, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39022394</phone>
    <phone_ext>2366</phone_ext>
    <email>licia.grazzi@istituto-besta.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Renato Mantegazza, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39022394</phone>
    <phone_ext>2321</phone_ext>
    <email>crc@istituto-besta.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Chronic Pain;</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Migraine;</keyword>
  <keyword>Conditioned Pain Modulation;</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness;</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Chronic Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

