<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04853849</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CECE2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04853849</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Treatment of Overactive Bladder With a Digital Conversational Agent: the MOTIVATION Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>MOTIVATION</acronym>
  <official_title>Treatment of Overactive Bladder With a Digital Conversational Agent: the MOTIVATION Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Renalis</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Renalis</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a proof of concept study for a digital therapeutic designed to provide first-line&#xD;
      behavioral modification therapy for overactive bladder.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The investigators seek to evaluate a commercial digital therapeutic, called CeCe, designed to&#xD;
      provide first-line behavioral modification therapy for overactive bladder (OAB). This digital&#xD;
      platform provides daily contact with the user to maximize compliance. It allows a provider to&#xD;
      administer behavioral modification treatment while minimizing in-office visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators expect that a proportion of participants using Cece will experience&#xD;
      significant and satisfactory improvement in their voiding symptoms, to the point where no&#xD;
      further treatment is necessary. Others will require additional treatment with the usual&#xD;
      therapies such physical therapy and medications, per clinical standards.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will download CeCe to their smart phones and interact with the program for 8&#xD;
      weeks. Participant consent and specific instructions will be provided during study enrollment&#xD;
      and through the app. Study outcomes are collected through the program via in-app&#xD;
      questionnaires and voiding diaries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 50 participants will be recruited. They will be compensated a total sum of $175;&#xD;
      $50 at completion of an initial set of questionnaires, $50 at completion of 4 week follow-up&#xD;
      questionnaires, and $75 at completion of 8 week follow-up.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change of overactive bladder quality of life measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 4 weeks, and 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>International Consultation on Incontinence Questionnaire Overactive Bladder Quality of Life questionnaire (ICIQ-OAB-QoL) is a 26 item questionnaire evaluating quality of life (QoL) in patients with overactive bladder. Scores range from 25-160, with greater values indicating increased impact on quality of life.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in symptoms of Overactive bladder</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 4 weeks, and 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>OAB-SS is a symptom assessment questionnaire designed to quantify OAB symptoms. The questionnaire consists of 4 questions. The score ranges from 0-15 with higher score indicating more severe OAB symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in general health state</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 4 weeks, and 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>SF-36 is a 36 item questionnaire measuring general health. Scores range from 0-100 with higher scores indicating more favorable health state.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global impression of improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>At 4 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient Global Impression of Improvement (PGI-I) is a global index used to rate the response of a condition to a therapy. Scores range from 1-7, with higher values (5-7) indicating higher degree is improvement and lower values (1-3) indicating worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Global impression of improvement</measure>
    <time_frame>At 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Patient Global Impression of Improvement (PGI-I) is a global index used to rate the response of a condition to a therapy. Scores range from 1-7, with higher values (5-7) indicating higher degree is improvement and lower values (1-3) indicating worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, 4 weeks, and 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>General Anxiety Disorder 7 item (GAD-7) questionnaire is a measure for assessing generalized anxiety disorder. Score ranges from 0-21 with high scores representing more severe depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usability</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>System Usability Scale (SUS) is a 10 item questionnaire for measuring the usability. Scores range from 0-100, with higher scores indicating better usability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usability</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Nelson's Attributes of Usability (NAU) is a 19 item questionnaire measuring usability. Scores range from 0-50, with higher scores indicating better usability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Usability</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Chatbot Usability Questionnaire (CUQ) is a 16 item questionnaire measuring usability of a chatbot. Scores range from 0-100, with higher scores indicating better usability</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobile device proficiency</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Mobile Device Proficiency Questionnaire (MDPQ-16) is a 16 item survey. Scores range from 8.5 - 40, with higher values indicating greater proficiency with mobile devices.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Overactive Bladder</condition>
  <condition>Urge Incontinence</condition>
  <condition>Pelvic Floor Disorders</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Research will be conducted at all University Hospital sites that have a member of the&#xD;
        Female Pelvic Medicine and Reconstructive Surgery division seeing patients. This includes&#xD;
        UH Richmond, UH Bedford, St. Johns Westshore Medical Center, Landerbook Medical Center, UH&#xD;
        Portage Urology, UH Geauga Urology, UHCMC, and UH Westlake. Women 40 years or older with&#xD;
        overactive bladder will be screened for and offered study enrollment by the study&#xD;
        investigators at each of the above sites.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of overactive bladder with urgency urinary incontinence, with or without&#xD;
             nocturia/nocturnal enuresis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Symptoms of mixed urinary incontinence if urgency incontinence is the predominant&#xD;
             complaint&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Post-void residual &lt;100ml&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Access to a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal urinalysis without evidence of UTI, gross or microscopic hematuria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Greater than 6 months since receiving intradetrusor injection of botulinum toxin&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently undergoing sacral neuromodulation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not currently receiving pharmacotherapy for overactive bladder&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 40 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Mixed incontinence with predominant stress urinary incontinence symptoms&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of chronic pelvic pain&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  symptoms of dysuria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of interstitial cystitis/painful bladder syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Reported &gt;2 UTI in 6 months or &gt;3 in 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not have access to a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of neurogenic bladder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Gross or microscopic hematuria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has diagnosis of dementia, cognitive impairment or other neurologic condition which&#xD;
             impairs decision making&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current Pharmacotherapy or neuromodulation therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Less than 6 months since intradetrusor botulinum toxin injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has decreased mobility or ambulation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has post-void residual &gt;100 mL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has BMI &gt; 40 kg/m^2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to voluntarily contract the pelvic floor muscles (a 0/5 in strength).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has &gt;4/10 pain with palpation of levator ani, coccygeus, pyriformis, obturator&#xD;
             internus or perineal body&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>40 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>David Sheyn, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospitals Cleveland Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yufan Chen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>510-364-2122</phone>
    <email>brandon@renalis.health</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Missy Lavender</last_name>
    <email>Missy@renalis.health</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brown K, Hilton P. The incidence of detrusor instability before and after colposuspension: a study using conventional and ambulatory urodynamic monitoring. BJU Int. 1999 Dec;84(9):961-5.</citation>
    <PMID>10571620</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reynolds WS, McPheeters M, Blume J, Surawicz T, Worley K, Wang L, Hartmann K. Comparative Effectiveness of Anticholinergic Therapy for Overactive Bladder in Women: A Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Obstet Gynecol. 2015 Jun;125(6):1423-1432. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000000851. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26000514</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ostaszkiewicz J, Johnston L, Roe B. Timed voiding for the management of urinary incontinence in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004;(1):CD002802. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>14973993</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ostaszkiewicz J, Johnston L, Roe B. Habit retraining for the management of urinary incontinence in adults. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2004;(2):CD002801. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15106179</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Roe B, Ostaszkiewicz J, Milne J, Wallace S. Systematic reviews of bladder training and voiding programmes in adults: a synopsis of findings from data analysis and outcomes using metastudy techniques. J Adv Nurs. 2007 Jan;57(1):15-31. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17184371</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kandadai P, O'Dell K, Saini J. Correct performance of pelvic muscle exercises in women reporting prior knowledge. Female Pelvic Med Reconstr Surg. 2015 May-Jun;21(3):135-40. doi: 10.1097/SPV.0000000000000145.</citation>
    <PMID>25349943</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Meister MR, Sutcliffe S, Ghetti C, Chu CM, Spitznagle T, Warren DK, Lowder JL. Development of a standardized, reproducible screening examination for assessment of pelvic floor myofascial pain. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2019 Mar;220(3):255.e1-255.e9. doi: 10.1016/j.ajog.2018.11.1106. Epub 2018 Dec 7.</citation>
    <PMID>30527941</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stewart WF, Corey R, Herzog AR, et al. Prevalence of overactive bladder in women: results from the NOBLE program. International Urogynecology Journal 2001; 12: pp. S66</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Digital therapeutic</keyword>
  <keyword>Overactive bladder</keyword>
  <keyword>Urge incontinence</keyword>
  <keyword>Pelvic floor disorders</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Urinary Bladder, Overactive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pelvic Floor Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Urinary Incontinence, Urge</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

