<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04852952</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>REC/00931 Qandeel</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04852952</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cross-cultural Translation of Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) Into Local Languages of Pakistan</brief_title>
  <official_title>Cross-cultural Translation of Oswestry Disability Index (ODI) Into Local Languages of Pakistan</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Riphah International University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Riphah International University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Descriptive analytical study to translate the Oswestry Disability Index into local languages&#xD;
      of Pakistan that are, Pashto, Urdu, Punjabi, Sindhi, and Balochi languages. Along with&#xD;
      validation of the translated versions by evaluating their validity and reliability in the&#xD;
      people of Pakistan, speaking respective languages and suffering from low back pain. No such&#xD;
      study has been previously conducted in the Pakistan region which translates the scale and&#xD;
      follows the proper cross-cultural adaptation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Condition or disease: Musculoskeletal disorders and disabilities caused by Low back pain,&#xD;
      Non-probability Purposive Sampling would be used. The study will be conducted in relevant&#xD;
      areas of Pakistan.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      As in the original study the main purpose of the Oswestry Disability Index is explained as to&#xD;
      assess pain-related disability in persons with low back pain (LBP). The target population for&#xD;
      the Oswestry are 3: acute, subacute, and chronic back pain client groups; with various&#xD;
      conservative, surgical, and behavioural intervention groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Oswestry Disability Index is one of the principal condition-specific outcome measures&#xD;
      used for the investigation of low back musculoskeletal disorders. It is a self-administered&#xD;
      questionnaire and consists of ten sections that are designed to assess the limitations of&#xD;
      various daily life activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each section is scored on a 0-5 scale, 5 is for maximum disability. The index is calculated&#xD;
      by dividing the total score by the total possible score, which is multiplied by 100 and&#xD;
      expressed as a percentage. Thus, for every unanswered question, the denominator is reduced by&#xD;
      5. If a patient marks two or more statements in a question, the highest-scoring statement is&#xD;
      recorded as a true indication of disability. The questionnaire takes 3.5-5 min to complete&#xD;
      andapproximately1 min to score.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At present worldwide there are a lot of health care workers who are using the Oswestry&#xD;
      Disability Index for low back pain assessment and this scale is also providing good&#xD;
      measurement but this scale is in the English language and there are a lot of people here in&#xD;
      Pakistan who don't understand English. Pakistan is a country with different languages and&#xD;
      cultures. The most commonly spoken and understood languages in Pakistan are Urdu the national&#xD;
      language of Pakistan, Pashto, Punjabi, Sindhi, and Balochi. Therefore it is highly needed to&#xD;
      translate this questioner into different languages so that the patient would be able to&#xD;
      answer them easily according to their understanding. The validity and reliability of the&#xD;
      translated versions will also be checked.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The translation and cultural adaptation processes would start after obtaining approval from&#xD;
      the developer of the original Oswestry Disability Index scale. This would be done according&#xD;
      to WHO guidelines. Translation will be done by symmetrical category. The purpose will be to&#xD;
      gain uniformity in the translation of tool in both the Target language and Source language.&#xD;
      This will involve 5 steps. (Forward translation, synthesis 1, Back translation, synthesis 2&#xD;
      and pilot testing.) Phase 2 would be done according to the standard guidelines in which&#xD;
      psychometric properties will be measured.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 27, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 23, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Oswestry disability Index translated versions</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Self report versions. The scores for all questions answered are summed, then multiplied by two to obtain the index (range 0 to 100). Zero is equated with no disability and 100 is the maximum disability possible.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reliability of translated versions of Oswestry disability Index</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the reliability of cross-culturally adapted and the Oswestry disability Index translated versions in patients with the back pain of respective languages۔ Reliability or reproducibility refers to the ability of a measure to produce the same results when administered at two intervals between different visits of the patient. Thus this will be measured through test re-test reliability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Validity of translated versions of Oswestry disability Index</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>To determine the validity of cross-culturally adapted and the translated Oswestry disability Index versions in patients with the back pain of respective languages۔ Validity is how accurate the results are. Thus this will be measured through various parameters to validate the translated versions as appropriate and applicable.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">576</enrollment>
  <condition>Low Back Pain</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        1000&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient both female and male having age group equal or &gt;18.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should be capable to complete the questionnaire without any help.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed with nonspecific low back pain for more than 3 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any serious conditions like neurological conditions which would not allow the patient&#xD;
             to fill the questionnaire independently, any infection, tumour, spinal surgery, or any&#xD;
             other rheumatological disease will be excluded.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Imran Amjad, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Riphah International University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Imran Amjad, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>03324390125</phone>
    <email>imran.amjad@riphah.edu.pk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Qandeel hamidullah Khan, MS-SPT</last_name>
    <phone>03335735947</phone>
    <email>drqandeelhamidullahkhan@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Riphah International University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Islamabad</city>
        <state>Fedral</state>
        <zip>44000</zip>
        <country>Pakistan</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Imran Amjad, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+92 332 4390125</phone>
      <email>imran.amjad@riphah.edu.pk</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Sidra Naqvi, MSNMPT*</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Pakistan</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17304141/</url>
    <description>Development of Brazilian version of ODI scale</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Joshi VD, Raiturker PP, Kulkarni AA. Validity and reliability of English and Marathi Oswestry Disability Index (version 2.1a) in Indian population. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2013 May 15;38(11):E662-8. doi: 10.1097/BRS.0b013e31828a34c3.</citation>
    <PMID>23380824</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Yakut E, Düger T, Oksüz C, Yörükan S, Ureten K, Turan D, Frat T, Kiraz S, Krd N, Kayhan H, Yakut Y, Güler C. Validation of the Turkish version of the Oswestry Disability Index for patients with low back pain. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2004 Mar 1;29(5):581-5; discussion 585.</citation>
    <PMID>15129077</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mousavi SJ, Parnianpour M, Mehdian H, Montazeri A, Mobini B. The Oswestry Disability Index, the Roland-Morris Disability Questionnaire, and the Quebec Back Pain Disability Scale: translation and validation studies of the Iranian versions. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2006 Jun 15;31(14):E454-9.</citation>
    <PMID>16778675</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Low Back Pain</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

