<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04858074</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UI/EC/20/0320</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04858074</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Study to Investigate the Effect of Hypoestes Rosea Powder in Parkinson's Disease</brief_title>
  <acronym>PECKO-D</acronym>
  <official_title>A Proof of Concept Study to Investigate the Effect of 100% Hypoestes Rosea Powder in Parkinson's Disease Using mPower2.0 as a Quantitative Assessment Tool (PECKO-D).</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Ibadan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Ibadan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Parkinson's disease (PD) is a progressive neurological disease characterized by resting&#xD;
      tremors, limb stiffness, impaired balance, and slow movement. There is no known cure for PD&#xD;
      although levo-3,4 dihydroxyphenylalanine (L-DOPA) and dopamine agonists are effective for&#xD;
      improving PD symptoms in the early years following diagnosis. Hypoestes rosea is an evergreen&#xD;
      shrub which has anti-inflammatory, anticancer and antimalarial properties. Recent studies&#xD;
      showed that the active pharmaceutical ingredient (API) of Hypoestes rosea, Hypoestoxide, was&#xD;
      effective in modifying disease progression in a transgenic mouse model of PD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to determine the efficacy of Hypoestoxide, as contained in Hypoestes&#xD;
      rosea dry leaf powder, in improving motor symptoms in consenting PD patients. The study&#xD;
      design is a double-blind, placebo-controlled cross-over trial involving 30 patients with mild&#xD;
      to moderate disease (Stages 1-3 of Hoehn and Yahr scale over an 8-week period. The symptoms&#xD;
      of the participants will be monitored using mobile phones with an established quantitative&#xD;
      assessment tool, mPower2.0, which was previously developed for monitoring symptoms and&#xD;
      disease progression in PD patients. In addition, the motor examination component of the&#xD;
      International Movement Disorders Society scale will be administered and correlated with the&#xD;
      finding on the mobile phone. The outcome measure is an improvement in the motor variables of&#xD;
      the study participants with a 10% change from baseline over the 8 weeks of using Hypoestes.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Justification Age-associated disorders are increasing in many low- and middle-income&#xD;
      countries due to population ageing and changing lifestyles. PD is a devastating condition&#xD;
      which, in the advanced stages, is associated with immobility and uncontrollable tremors. Life&#xD;
      then becomes miserable for the sufferers. Unfortunately, there is no cure for the disease&#xD;
      except control of symptoms with medications. Any treatment combination that leads to better&#xD;
      symptom control will go a long way in improving the quality of life for PD patients. This&#xD;
      proof of concept study, if successful will give a new lease on life to PD patients. Hence it&#xD;
      is considered worthwhile to treat PD patients with a new compound that is contained in a&#xD;
      local plant that is readily available and holds promise for efficacy based on its mode of&#xD;
      action specifically in reducing the formation of alpha synuclein which underlies the neuronal&#xD;
      death in PD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OBJECTIVES OF THE STUDY&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of this study is to determine the efficacy of Hypoestoxide, as contained in Hypoestes&#xD;
      rosea dry leaf powder, in improving motor symptoms in consenting PD patients over an 8-week&#xD;
      period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To determine the efficacy of Hypoestes rosea in improving motor performance of PD&#xD;
           patients through traditional clinical evaluation, use of the selected components of the&#xD;
           Motor Examination section of the International Movement Disorders Society Scale and the&#xD;
           computer software application (mPower2.0 app)&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  To document the side effect profile of the herbal product&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methodology Study site: University College Hospital, Ibadan Study design: Single-center,&#xD;
      randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial Study Type: Interventional (Clinical&#xD;
      Trial) Allocation: Randomized Masking: Double Primary Purpose: Treatment Study participants:&#xD;
      Patients with mild to moderate Parkinson's disease symptoms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility Criteria Ages eligible for study: 30 years and older (Adult, older adult) Sexes&#xD;
      Eligible for Study: All Accepts healthy volunteers: No Sample size: Being a proof-of-concept&#xD;
      study, 30 PD patients will participate in this phase of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Willing and able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Willingness and ability to comply with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  PD diagnosis must be confirmed by bradykinesia plus one of the other cardinal signs&#xD;
           (resting tremor, rigidity, postural instability) being present.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age &gt;30 years&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Men and women with mild to moderate PD: Hoehn and Yahr scale stages 1 - 3. Participants&#xD;
           may be on current therapeutic agents (including levodopa, dopamine agonists,&#xD;
           anticholinergics, amantadine or selegiline) to treat PD symptoms at the time of&#xD;
           enrollment and may remain on these agents throughout the 5-month study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Women of childbearing potential (i.e., those not postmenopausal or surgically sterile)&#xD;
           may participate provided that they are using adequate birth control methods for the&#xD;
           duration of the study. Women of childbearing potential must have a negative pregnancy&#xD;
           test at baseline and be non-lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion:&#xD;
&#xD;
      • Subjects with advanced, severe disease, including those with dementia, severe&#xD;
      osteoarthritis, allergies, stroke, and visual impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Presence of atypical PD syndromes due to drugs (e.g., metoclopramide, flunarizine),&#xD;
           metabolic identified neurogenetic disorders (e.g., Wilson's disease), encephalitis, or&#xD;
           other degenerative diseases (e.g., progressive supranuclear palsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Any clinically significant medical condition (e.g., active neoplasm, angina) or&#xD;
           laboratory abnormality, which would in the judgement of the investigator interfere with&#xD;
           the subjects' ability to participate in the study or be followed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Procedure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this study, participants with mild to moderate PD, whether treated or untreated, will be&#xD;
      randomized into one of two study arms following an initial baseline assessment to determine&#xD;
      motor activity status of each participant as follows:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Baseline Determination: Measurement of motor activities of all participants will be&#xD;
      determined for 3 weeks while on regular PD medication(s). The International Movement&#xD;
      Disorders Society Scale - Motor Examination (10 selected items on Slowness, Posture, Tremor,&#xD;
      Rigidity and Gait) will be utilized for the quantitation of the motor activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Drug arm: 15 patients will receive 4 capsules each containing 350 mg orally twice a day of&#xD;
      Peko-D Forte for 8 weeks as add-on therapy to patients' regular PD medication(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Placebo arm: 15 participants will receive 4 capsules orally twice a day of USP-grade starch&#xD;
      for 8 weeks as add-on to regular PD medication(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Wash-Out: Wash-out will be for a duration of 4 weeks in which patients assigned to both arms&#xD;
      will take no capsules.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Switch over: Following the wash-out period, the Peko-D Forte group will receive 4&#xD;
      capsules of USP-grade starch powder taken orally twice a day for 8 weeks. The placebo group&#xD;
      will receive 4 capsules of Peko-D Forte taken orally twice a day for 8 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Symptoms of the participants will be monitored using traditional clinical evaluation and&#xD;
      daily using mobile phones installed with an established quantitative assessment tool,&#xD;
      mPower2.0, previously developed for monitoring symptoms and disease progression in PD&#xD;
      patients.26 Once enrolled and given the smartphones and mPower2.0 app, the participants will&#xD;
      be asked to perform four (4) separate study tasks daily during the baseline determination&#xD;
      period and throughout the treatment period: gait, tremor, tapping and balance. The&#xD;
      International Movement Disorders Society Scale (MDS) - Motor Examination (10 selected items&#xD;
      on Slowness, Posture, Tremor, Rigidity and Gait) will be utilized for the quantitation of the&#xD;
      motor activities. Data collected using mPower2.0 and the MDS - Motor items will then be&#xD;
      analyzed for significant changes in symptom severity relative to baseline status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOME MEASURE: 10% Mean change in motor assessment parameters using the International&#xD;
      Movement Disorders Society Scale - selected motor examination items while on the Hypoestes.&#xD;
      This equates to 1- to 2-point improvement in motor performance over a 2-month period on&#xD;
      Hypoestes in the absence of side effects which will be monitored using pharmacovigilance&#xD;
      tools.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Total duration of study: 5 months (2 months on active drugs, 2 months on placebo with one&#xD;
      month wash-out period in-between)&#xD;
&#xD;
      The protocol for the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
      PROOF OF CONCEPT STUDY: to investigate the effect of Peko-D Forte (100% Hypoestes rosea&#xD;
      powder) in Parkinson's Disease using mPower2.0 as a quantitative assessment tool.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
      Serial Number: Hospital Number:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Name:&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Address:&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Phone number:&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Gender: Male Female&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Age (in years) Date of Birth (if known):&#xD;
&#xD;
           CLINICAL DETAILS:&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Age at diagnosis of PD:&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. DURATION OF DISEASE AT DIAGNOSIS&#xD;
&#xD;
        8. What are the predominant symptoms? (check all that apply) I) Tremor _______ ii)&#xD;
           Stiffness _______iii) Slowness ______iv) Postural instability_______&#xD;
&#xD;
        9. Stage of the disease (from Hoehn and Yahr Scale): _______________ I Unilateral disease&#xD;
           only II Bilateral mild disease III Bilateral disease + early impairment of postural&#xD;
           stability IV Severe disease requiring considerable assistance V Confinement to&#xD;
           wheelchair or bed unless aided&#xD;
&#xD;
       10. Medical co-morbidities i) Hypertension --------- ii) Diabetes Mellitus________ iii)&#xD;
           Heart failure_______iv) Chronic lung disease_________ v) Osteoarthritis _______vi)&#xD;
           Glaucoma______ VII) Others_________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
       11. Current medications and dosages:&#xD;
&#xD;
           I) L-Dopa + carbidopa ii) Anticholinesterase iii) DOPA-agonists (specify) iv) Others&#xD;
           (specify)&#xD;
&#xD;
       12. Medication Side effects (if any)&#xD;
&#xD;
       13. Any major disability experienced - Yes No IF Yes, check where check whichever is&#xD;
           applicable: Cognitive ______ On and off phenomenon_____ Neuropathic pain_________&#xD;
           Dyskinesia____________ others______________&#xD;
&#xD;
      WILLINGNESS TO PARTICIPATE IN STUDY: Yes No&#xD;
&#xD;
      PECKO-D Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective assessment of motor and non-motor- features in PD patients&#xD;
&#xD;
      The MDS-sponsored Revision of the Unified Parkinson's Disease Rating Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. Posture: Instructions to examiner: Posture is assessed with the patient standing erect&#xD;
      after arising from a chair, during walking, and while being tested for postural reflexes. If&#xD;
      you notice poor posture, tell the patient to stand up straight and see if the posture&#xD;
      improves (see option 2 below). Rate the worst posture seen in these three observation points.&#xD;
      Observe for flexion and side-to-side leaning.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Not quite erect, but posture could be normal for older person.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Definite flexion, scoliosis or leaning to one side, but patient can correct&#xD;
           posture to normal posture when asked to do so.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Stooped posture, scoliosis or leaning to one side that cannot be corrected&#xD;
           volitionally to a normal posture by the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Flexion, scoliosis or leaning with extreme abnormality of posture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2. Global spontaneity of movement (body bradykinesia) Instructions to examiner: This global&#xD;
      rating combines all observations on slowness, hesitancy, and small amplitude and poverty of&#xD;
      movement in general, including a reduction of gesturing and of crossing the legs. This&#xD;
      assessment is based on the examiner's global impression after observing for spontaneous&#xD;
      gestures while sitting, and the nature of arising and walking.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
      1: Slight: Slight global slowness and poverty of spontaneous movements. 2: Mild: Mild global&#xD;
      slowness and poverty of spontaneous movements. 3: Moderate: Moderate global slowness and&#xD;
      poverty of spontaneous movements. 4: Severe: Severe global slowness and poverty of&#xD;
      spontaneous movements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      3. Rigidity: Instructions to examiner: Rigidity is judged on slow passive movement of major&#xD;
      joints with the patient in a relaxed position and the examiner manipulating the limbs and&#xD;
      neck. First, test without an activation maneuver. Test and rate neck and each limb&#xD;
      separately. For arms, test the wrist and elbow joints simultaneously. For legs, test the hip&#xD;
      and knee joints simultaneously. If no rigidity is detected, use an activation maneuver such&#xD;
      as tapping fingers, fist opening/closing, or heel tapping in a limb not being tested. Explain&#xD;
      to the patient to go as limp as possible as you test for rigidity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No rigidity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Rigidity only detected with activation maneuver.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Rigidity detected without the activation maneuver, but full range of motion is&#xD;
           easily achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Rigidity detected without the activation maneuver; full range of motion is&#xD;
           achieved with effort.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Rigidity detected without the activation maneuver and full range of motion not&#xD;
           achieved.&#xD;
&#xD;
      4. Finger tapping: Instructions to examiner: Each hand is tested separately. Demonstrate the&#xD;
      task, but do not continue to perform the task while the patient is being tested. Instruct the&#xD;
      patient to tap the index finger on the thumb 10 times as quickly AND as big as possible. Rate&#xD;
      each side separately, evaluating speed, amplitude, hesitations, halts, and decrementing&#xD;
      amplitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Any of the following: a) the regular rhythm is broken with one or two&#xD;
           interruptions or hesitations of the tapping movement; b) slight slowing; c) the&#xD;
           amplitude decrements near the end of the 10 taps.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Any of the following: a) 3 to 5 interruptions during tapping; b) mild slowing; c)&#xD;
           the amplitude decrements midway in the 10-tap sequence.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Any of the following: a) more than 5 interruptions during tapping or at least&#xD;
           one longer arrest (freeze) in ongoing movement; b) moderate slowing; c) the amplitude&#xD;
           decrements starting after the 1st tap.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Cannot or can only barely perform the task because of slowing, interruptions, or&#xD;
           decrements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      5. Toe tapping Instructions to examiner: Have the patient sit in a straight-backed chair with&#xD;
      arms, both feet on the floor. Test each foot separately. Demonstrate the task, but do not&#xD;
      continue to perform the task while the patient is being tested. Instruct the patient to place&#xD;
      the heel on the ground in a comfortable position and then tap the toes 10 times as big and as&#xD;
      fast as possible. Rate each side separately, evaluating speed, amplitude, hesitations, halts,&#xD;
      and decrementing amplitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Any of the following: a) the regular rhythm is broken with one or two&#xD;
           interruptions or hesitations of the tapping movement; b) slight slowing; c) amplitude&#xD;
           decrements near the end of the ten taps.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Any of the following: a) 3 to 5 interruptions during the tapping movements; b)&#xD;
           mild slowing; c) amplitude decrements midway in the task.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Any of the following: a) more than 5 interruptions during the tapping&#xD;
           movements or at least one longer arrest (freeze) in ongoing movement; b) moderate&#xD;
           slowing; c) amplitude decrements after the 1st tap.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Cannot or can only barely perform the task because of slowing, interruptions or&#xD;
           decrements.&#xD;
&#xD;
      6. Arising from a chair Instructions to examiner: Have the patient sit in a straight-backed&#xD;
      chair with arms, with both feet on the floor and sitting back in the chair (if the patient is&#xD;
      not too short). Ask the patient to cross his/her arms across the chest and then to stand up.&#xD;
      If the patient is not successful, repeat this attempt up to a maximum of two more times. If&#xD;
      still unsuccessful, allow the patient to move forward in the chair to arise with arms folded&#xD;
      across the chest. Allow only one attempt in this situation. If unsuccessful, allow the&#xD;
      patient to push off using his/her hands on the arms of the chair. Allow a maximum of three&#xD;
      trials of pushing off. If still not successful, assist the patient to arise. After the&#xD;
      patient stands up, observe the posture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems. Able to arise quickly without hesitation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Arising is slower than normal; or may need more than one attempt; or may need to&#xD;
           move forward in the chair to arise. No need to use the arms of the chair.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Pushes self up from the arms of the chair without difficulty.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Needs to push off, but tends to fall back; or may have to try more than one&#xD;
           time using the arms of the chair, but can get up without help.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Unable to arise without help.&#xD;
&#xD;
      7. Gait Instructions to examiner: Testing gait is best performed by having the patient&#xD;
      walking away from and towards the examiner so that both right and left sides of the body can&#xD;
      be easily observed simultaneously. The patient should walk at least 10 meters (30 feet), then&#xD;
      turn around and return to the examiner. This item measures multiple behaviors: stride&#xD;
      amplitude, stride speed, height of foot lift, heel strike during walking, turning, and arm&#xD;
      swing, but not freezing. Observe posture for item 1&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Independent walking with minor gait impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Independent walking but with substantial gait impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Requires an assistance device for safe walking (walking stick, walker) but not&#xD;
           a person.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Cannot walk at all or only with another person's assistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      8. Postural Stability Instructions to examiner: The test examines the response to sudden body&#xD;
      displacement produced by a quick, forceful pull on the shoulders while the patient is&#xD;
      standing erect with eyes open and feet comfortably apart and parallel to each other. Test&#xD;
      retropulsion. Stand behind the patient and instruct the patient on what is about to happen.&#xD;
      Explain that s/he is allowed to take a step backwards to avoid falling. There should be a&#xD;
      solid wall behind the examiner, at least 1-2 meters away to allow for the observation of the&#xD;
      number of retropulsive steps. The first pull is an instructional demonstration and is&#xD;
      purposely milder and not rated. The second time the shoulders are pulled briskly and&#xD;
      forcefully towards the examiner with enough force to displace the center of gravity so that&#xD;
      patient MUST take a step backwards. The examiner needs to be ready to catch the patient, but&#xD;
      must stand sufficiently back so as to allow enough room for the patient to take several steps&#xD;
      to recover independently. Do not allow the patient to flex the body abnormally forward in&#xD;
      anticipation of the pull. Observe for the number of steps backwards or falling. Up to and&#xD;
      including two steps for recovery is considered normal, so abnormal ratings begin with three&#xD;
      steps. If the patient fails to understand the test, the examiner can repeat the test so that&#xD;
      the rating is based on an assessment that the examiner feels reflects the patient's&#xD;
      limitations rather than misunderstanding or lack of preparedness. Observe standing posture.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No problems. Recovers with one or two steps.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: 3-5 steps, but subject recovers unaided.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: More than 5 steps, but subject recovers unaided.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Stands safely, but with absence of postural response; falls if not caught by&#xD;
           examiner.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Very unstable, tends to lose balance spontaneously or with just a gentle pull on&#xD;
           the shoulders.&#xD;
&#xD;
      9. Rest tremor amplitude Instructions to examiner: This and the next item have been placed&#xD;
      purposefully at the end of the examination to allow the rater to gather observations on rest&#xD;
      tremor that may appear at any time during the exam, including when quietly sitting, during&#xD;
      walking, and during activities when some body parts are moving but others are at rest. Score&#xD;
      the maximum amplitude that is seen at any time as the final score. Rate only the amplitude&#xD;
      and not the persistence or the intermittency of the tremor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As part of this rating, the patient should sit quietly in a chair with the hands placed on&#xD;
      the arms of the chair (not in the lap) and the feet comfortably supported on the floor for 10&#xD;
      seconds with no other directives. Rest tremor is assessed separately for all four limbs and&#xD;
      also for the lip/jaw. Rate only the maximum amplitude that is seen at any time as the final&#xD;
      rating. Extremity ratings&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No tremor.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: &lt; 1 cm in maximal amplitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: ≥ 1 cm but &lt; 3 cm in maximal amplitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: ≥ 3 cm but &lt; 10 cm in maximal amplitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: ≥ 10 cm in maximal amplitude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      10. Constancy of rest tremor Instructions to examiner: This item receives one rating for all&#xD;
      rest tremor and focuses on the constancy of rest tremor during the examination period when&#xD;
      different body parts are variously at rest. It is rated purposefully at the end of the&#xD;
      examination so that several minutes of information can be coalesced into the rating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      0: Normal: No tremor.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Slight: Tremor at rest is present ≤ 25% of the entire examination period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Mild: Tremor at rest is present 26-50% of the entire examination period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Moderate: Tremor at rest is present 51-75% of the entire examination period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Severe: Tremor at rest is present &gt; 75% of the entire examination period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Total Score: (out of 40)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any abnormality on neurological&#xD;
      examination?:--------------------------------------------------------------------------------&#xD;
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&#xD;
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&#xD;
      ---------------------------------------&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood Pressure:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Pulse:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weight:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization:: A. Active medication: B. Placebo&#xD;
&#xD;
      Mobile Phone serial number: __________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow up data:&#xD;
&#xD;
      I) First review at 8 weeks:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Date scheduled and time:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any reported side effects?: ____________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any benefits noted subjectively?__________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other comments: ________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assess motor performance using the MDS Scale- Record the score_______&#xD;
&#xD;
      II) 4-week washout period: (No study medications to be administered)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any comments________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      III) Cross-over for 8 weeks with change of study medications (Placebo to active and vice&#xD;
      versa)&#xD;
&#xD;
      Date scheduled and time:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compliance&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any side effects? ____________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any benefits noted? __________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other comments: ________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assess motor performance using MDS scale: Record the score_______&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study completed: Yes No (If No, give reasons) _____________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Date completed:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Any comments__________________________________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Name and signature of investigator_____________________________________&#xD;
&#xD;
      Date: ----------------------------&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 20, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1/Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Crossover Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-blind, placebo-controlled cross-over study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Data recorded by computer application remotely. Investigator will not be aware of patient group; the active and placebo medications are alike</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>motor manifestations</measure>
    <time_frame>eight weeks</time_frame>
    <description>10% Mean change in motor assessment parameters using the International Movement Disorders Society Scale - selected motor examination items while on the Hypoestes. This equates to 1- to 2-point improvement in motor performance over a 2-month period</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Parkinson Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Active medication- PECKO-D</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be randomly allocated to experimental drug</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Corn-Starch will be administered as placebo agent</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hypoestoxide</intervention_name>
    <description>Its active pharmaceutical ingredient (API) is Hypoestoxide, discovered in 1983, which was recently shown to be active against alpha synuclein and was very effective in modifying disease progression in a transgenic mouse model of PD</description>
    <arm_group_label>Active medication- PECKO-D</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PECKO-D forte</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Willingness and ability to comply with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PD diagnosis must be confirmed by bradykinesia plus one of the other cardinal&#xD;
                  signs (resting tremor, rigidity, postural instability) being present.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Age &gt;30 years&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Men and women with mild to moderate PD: Hoehn and Yahr scale stages 1 - 3.&#xD;
                  Participants may be on current therapeutic agents (including levodopa, dopamine&#xD;
                  agonists, anticholinergics, amantadine or selegiline) to treat PD symptoms at the&#xD;
                  time of enrollment and may remain on these agents throughout the 5-month study&#xD;
                  period.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Women of childbearing potential (i.e., those not postmenopausal or surgically&#xD;
                  sterile) may participate provided that they are using adequate birth control&#xD;
                  methods for the duration of the study. Women of childbearing potential must have&#xD;
                  a negative pregnancy test at baseline and be non-lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Subjects with advanced, severe disease, including those with dementia, severe&#xD;
             osteoarthritis, allergies, stroke, and visual impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of atypical PD syndromes due to drugs (e.g., metoclopramide,&#xD;
                  flunarizine), metabolic identified neurogenetic disorders (e.g., Wilson's&#xD;
                  disease), encephalitis, or other degenerative diseases (e.g., progressive&#xD;
                  supranuclear palsy).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Any clinically significant medical condition (e.g., active neoplasm, angina) or&#xD;
                  laboratory abnormality, which would in the judgement of the investigator&#xD;
                  interfere with the subjects' ability to participate in the study or be followed&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>30 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>85 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Adesola Ogunniyi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>College of Medicine, University of Ibadan, Nigeria</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Adesola Ogunniyi, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+2348038094173</phone>
    <email>aogunniyi@com.ui.edu.ng</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Catherine Falade, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+2348033264593</phone>
    <email>cfalade@com.ui.edu.ng</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Ibadan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>ADESOLA OGUNNIYI</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Motor symptoms</keyword>
  <keyword>Hoehn and Yahr Stages 1-3</keyword>
  <keyword>Hypoestes</keyword>
  <keyword>Sub-Saharan Africa</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Parkinson Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Sociodemographic and clinical details as well as recordings of the mPower app will be made available</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Immediately data analysis is completed and for the next 12 months</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>participants, research collaborators, monitoring and evaluation team</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>http://www.com.ui.edu.ng</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

