<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04852055</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2008002779</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>3U54AG063546-02S1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04852055</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of a COVID-specific Advance Care Planning Intervention</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of a COVID-specific Advance Care Planning Intervention on Documentation of Advance Directives and Goals of Care</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Brown University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute on Aging (NIA)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Brown University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The intervention being studied is an advance care planning intervention. The trial has three&#xD;
      arms: usual care, information only, and information with clinician follow-up call.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Eligible patients whose assisted living centers are randomized to the information only arm&#xD;
      will receive a letter from their clinician with links to informational video. Eligible&#xD;
      patients whose assisted living centers are randomized to the information plus clinician&#xD;
      follow-up arm will receive the letter and a structured follow-up call from their clinician.&#xD;
      Eligible patients whose assisted living centers are randomized to the usual care arm have&#xD;
      advance care planning discussions with a clinician at admission, annually, and sometimes with&#xD;
      a hospitalization or other change in condition.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Do-Not-Resuscitate</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of residents with do-not-resuscitate orders documented in the electronic health record at end of follow-up, comparisons between usual care and each experimental arm (two comparisons)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Do-Not-Hospitalize</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of residents in each arm with do-not-hospitalize or comfort care orders documented in the electronic health record at end of follow-up, comparisons between usual care and each experimental arm (two comparisons)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Advance Care Planning Billing</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of residents in each arm with current procedural terminology billing code for advance care planning during follow-up based on Medicare claims data, comparisons between usual care and each experimental arm (two comparisons)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of residents with any hospital transfer during follow-up based on Medicare claims data, comparisons between usual care and each experimental arm (two comparisons)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3000</enrollment>
  <condition>Dementia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients and proxies in assisted living centers randomized to the usual care arm have advance care planning discussions with a clinician at admission, annually, and sometimes with a hospitalization or other change in condition. There is no standardized decision- or conversation-support tools used to have these discussions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Information Only</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients and proxies in assisted living centers randomized to the information only arm will receive a letter from their clinician with a link to an educational video describing the goals of care and how specific treatment decisions align with these goals. Patients and proxies will also continue to receive usual care advance care planning conversations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Information and Clinician Outreach</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients and proxies in assisted living centers randomized to the information and clinician outreach arm will receive the letter from their clinician with a link to an educational video describing the goals of care and how specific treatment decisions align with these goals. Clinicians will also call patients and proxies to have a structured advance care planning conversation within a month of sending the educational materials.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Advance Care Planning Video</intervention_name>
    <description>Clinical assistants determine who is the correct person to receive the informational materials. If the patient is the correct recipient, clinicians will send the informational materials to the patient at the assisted living center. If the proxy is the correct recipient, the clinical assistant will determine whether or not the proxy is using the existing online portal. If the proxy is using the portal, the informational materials will be sent electronically. If the proxy does not access the portal, the informational materials will be sent to their residences.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Information Only</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Advance Care Planning Video and Conversation</intervention_name>
    <description>The same process will be used to send materials through the portal as described in the Information Only arm. For the follow-up discussion, clinicians will speak to either the patient or the proxy (or both). Clinicians will receive basic advance care planning training and a structured conversation guide to facilitate these conversations.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Information and Clinician Outreach</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria: Partnering assisted living center with at least 20 patients with a&#xD;
        dementia diagnosis (based on International Classification of Diseases, version 10 codes)&#xD;
        who are not on hospice and do not have comfort care or do-not-hospitalize orders at&#xD;
        baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria: Partnering assisted living center with less than 20 patients with a&#xD;
        dementia diagnosis (based on International Classification of Diseases, version 10 codes)&#xD;
        who are not on hospice and do not have comfort care or do-not-hospitalize orders at&#xD;
        baseline&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vincent Mor, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Brown University, School of Public Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ellen McCreedy, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(401) 863-7345</phone>
    <email>ellen_mccreedy@brown.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Ann Reddy, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>(401) 863-7345</phone>
    <email>ann_reddy@brown.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 16, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Brown University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vincent Mor</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Florence Pirce Grant University Professor, Professor of Health</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>assisted living facilities; dementia; advance care planning</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dementia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

