<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05024344</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>ANES-01-072021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05024344</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>ESP Block vs Control for Pain Control Following Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy</brief_title>
  <official_title>Erector Spinae Plane Block Versus Control for Pain Control Following Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy: A Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo Controlled Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Tennessee Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Tennessee Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to investigate the use of the erector spinae (ESP) block in&#xD;
      reducing the morphine milligram equivalent (MME) consumption post percutaneous&#xD;
      nephrolithotomy. Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. - Determine if there is a significant effect on post percutaneous nephrolithotomy MME&#xD;
           consumption with the usage of an ESP block vs. saline control.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. - Determine if there is a significant effect on reported pain levels with the use of an&#xD;
           ESP block vs. saline control in post percutaneous nephrolithotomies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a double-blind, randomized control trial involving 128 subjects undergoing an&#xD;
      elective percutaneous nephrolithotomy. All subjects who meet all inclusion and exclusion&#xD;
      criteria will be equally randomized on the day of the procedure by operating room pharmacy&#xD;
      into either the ESP block or the control block. An interim analysis at the sample size&#xD;
      required for a large effect size (n = 52, with n = 26 in each treatment arm) will be&#xD;
      performed. In order to blind the anesthesiologist performing the block, the control arm will&#xD;
      be equally randomized by the pharmacist at the time of distributing the pre-filled syringes&#xD;
      for the ESP block procedure. Randomization will occur with the use of a random number&#xD;
      generator with 1:1 ESP:Control allocation ratio.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be followed at Pre-op and the 24-h, 48-h, 7 days and 30 days post operatively&#xD;
      to assess the quality of recovery utilizing the Quality of Recovery-15 (QoR-15)&#xD;
      questionnaire, VAS pain scale, and opioid consumption. Intraoperative MMEs, PACU MMEs, total&#xD;
      MME's, FLACC scores at 30 minutes/1 hour VAS scores at 1 hour/2 hours/6 hours/24 hours, PACU&#xD;
      LOS, hospital LOS, time to first flatus will be documented in patient chart, reviewed by&#xD;
      study personnel and uploaded into a password protected database on the UTMCK server.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All aspects of the study and consent forms will be IRB approved prior to implementation.&#xD;
      Potential candidates will be selected for consent based on chart review and surgery&#xD;
      scheduling.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The Surgeon will initially approach potential subjects and provide them with a copy of&#xD;
           the consent form to take home and read prior to pre-anesthesia testing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the subject's pre-anesthesia testing appointment, the research staff will explain the&#xD;
           risks and benefits of the study, answer any questions, and obtain consent to&#xD;
           participate.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The Biostatistician will randomize the subjects with a random number generator. Once&#xD;
           randomized, a blinded package labeled &quot;ESP&quot; or &quot;Control&quot; will be delivered to the&#xD;
           regional anesthesia team containing the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      ESP&#xD;
&#xD;
      Active group:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. One 30mL syringe containing 29mL of 0.5% ropivacaine and 4mg of dexamethasone- labeled&#xD;
           &quot;ESP Block&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. One 30mL syringe containing 30mL of preservative free normal saline- labeled &quot;wound&#xD;
           infiltration&quot; Sham group&#xD;
&#xD;
      1. One 30mL syringe containing 30mL of 0.5% ropivacaine- labeled &quot;wound infiltration&quot; 2. One&#xD;
      30mL syringe containing 30mL of preservative free normal saline- labeled &quot;ESP Block&quot;&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The pharmacist will create a table pre-populated with the randomization assignments with&#xD;
           space to fill out patient information and medication information on the day of surgery.&#xD;
           This chart will be in paper form and kept in a research binder in the OR pharmacy. When&#xD;
           a patient is consented for the RCT, the treatment group will be chosen based on the&#xD;
           numbers assigned a priori. Each qualifying patient will be documented on the subsequent&#xD;
           row in the table, maintaining the original order of randomization as dictated by the&#xD;
           statistician. Based on the assignment, the pharmacy technician will be instructed as to&#xD;
           which products to make in the sterile hood. The pharmacist will verify that the products&#xD;
           were made appropriately and will label the syringes according to assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Operating room pharmacy will hand the anesthesiologist a blinded package with one&#xD;
           prefilled syringe for the regional block that will either contain 30mL of 0.5%&#xD;
           ropivacaine with 4mg of dexamethasone or preservative free normal saline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The regional anesthesiologist will perform the ESP block using standard protocols and&#xD;
           procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age, BMI, duration of operation, EBL, intraoperative MMEs, PACU MMEs, 48 hours&#xD;
           post-operative MMEs, total MME's, FLACC scores at 30 minutes/1 hour VAS scores at 1&#xD;
           hour/2 hours/6 hours/24 hours, PACU LOS, hospital LOS, time to first flatus will be&#xD;
           documented in patient chart and reviewed by study personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  QoR-15, MME consumption, and VAS will be assessed at Pre-op, 24-h, 48-h, 7 and 30 days&#xD;
           by study staff. Data will be uploaded into a database kept on secured password protected&#xD;
           computers on the UTMCK server.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  All patient identifiers will be removed prior to data analysis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 9, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption (MME)</measure>
    <time_frame>First 24 hours postoperative</time_frame>
    <description>Opioid consumption (MME) in the first 24 hours postoperative</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital LOS</measure>
    <time_frame>Number of days in hospital (inpatient) from day of surgery (day 1) until discharge post-surgery in 24 hour increments up to 30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Hospital length of stay</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>VAS score</measure>
    <time_frame>First 24 hours after surgery.</time_frame>
    <description>Mean Visual Analog Scale (VAS) score in the first 24 hours after surgery. VAS measures the amount of pain that a patient feels ranging across a continuum from none(0) to an extreme amount of pain(10) on a chart.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid use during first 24 hours after surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>MMEs (morphine milligram equivalent) administered during first 24 hours post surgery</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>QoR-15</measure>
    <time_frame>24 hours, 48 hours, 7 days, and 30 days after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>Quality of Recovery -15 at 24 hours, 48 hours, 7 days, and 30 days after surgery. QoR-15 measures how a patient feels they are recovering after surgery using a 15 item survey rated 0 (none of the time-poor) to 10 (all of the time-excellent).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid use during 30 days post hospital discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>MMEs administered/consumed during 30 day period post hospital discharge</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">128</enrollment>
  <condition>Nephrolithotomy, Percutaneous</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>ESP Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>One 30mL syringe containing 30mL of 0.5% ropivacaine and 4 mg of dexamethosone-</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Sham Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>One 30mL syringe containing 30mL of preservative free normal saline</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Erector Spinae Plane Block</intervention_name>
    <description>The Anesthesiologist will use ultrasound-guided technique and inject 30mL of 0.5% ropivacaine with 4 mg of dexamethasone or saline placebo control into the erector spinae muscle, superficial to the tips of the thoracic transverse processes</description>
    <arm_group_label>ESP Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Sham Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ropivacaine 0.5% Injectable Solution</intervention_name>
    <description>The Anesthesiologist will use ultrasound-guided technique and inject 30mL of 0.5% ropivacaine with 4 mg of dexamethasone or saline placebo control into the erector spinae muscle, superficial to the tips of the thoracic transverse processes</description>
    <arm_group_label>ESP Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone</intervention_name>
    <description>The Anesthesiologist will use ultrasound-guided technique and inject 30mL of 0.5% ropivacaine with 4 mg of dexamethasone or saline placebo control into the erector spinae muscle, superficial to the tips of the thoracic transverse processes</description>
    <arm_group_label>ESP Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults, male and female greater than or equal to 18 years of age and undergoing&#xD;
             non-emergent percutaneous nephrolithotomy Monday through Friday between the hours of&#xD;
             6:00AM and 4:00PM.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants of childbearing potential will be required to provide a negative&#xD;
             pregnancy test.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ability to understand and teach back consent for the procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willingness to sign consent for procedure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English speaking.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Emergent surgery status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Local infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to local anesthetics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recreational drug use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to provide informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy or breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Guillain-Barre' Syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Underlying medical conditions that would post a significant risk to the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Opioid use &gt;90 days in the year leading up to surgery.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jason Buehler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Tennessee Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jason Buehler, MD</last_name>
    <phone>865-305-9220</phone>
    <email>jbuehler@utmck.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Aimee Pehrson</last_name>
    <phone>865-305-5432</phone>
    <email>apehrson@utmck.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Tennessee Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Knoxville</city>
        <state>Tennessee</state>
        <zip>37920</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aimee Pehrson</last_name>
      <phone>865-305-5432</phone>
      <email>apehrson@utmck.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dundar G, Gokcen K, Gokce G, Gultekin EY. The Effect of Local Anesthetic Agent Infiltration Around Nephrostomy Tract On Postoperative Pain Control After Percutaneous Nephrolithotomy: A single-centre, randomised, double-blind, placebocontrolled clinical trial. Urol J. 2018 Nov 17;15(6):306-312. doi: 10.22037/uj.v0i0.4145.</citation>
    <PMID>29681047</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>De Cassai A, Bonvicini D, Correale C, Sandei L, Tulgar S, Tonetti T. Erector spinae plane block: a systematic qualitative review. Minerva Anestesiol. 2019 Mar;85(3):308-319. doi: 10.23736/S0375-9393.18.13341-4. Epub 2019 Jan 4.</citation>
    <PMID>30621377</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tulgar S, Selvi O, Ozer Z. Clinical experience of ultrasound-guided single and bi-level erector spinae plane block for postoperative analgesia in patients undergoing thoracotomy. J Clin Anesth. 2018 Nov;50:22-23. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinane.2018.06.034. Epub 2018 Jun 23.</citation>
    <PMID>29940470</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kwon WJ, Bang SU, Sun WY. Erector Spinae Plane Block for Effective Analgesia after Total Mastectomy with Sentinel or Axillary Lymph Node Dissection: a Report of Three Cases. J Korean Med Sci. 2018 Nov 5;33(45):e291. doi: 10.3346/jkms.2018.33.e291.</citation>
    <PMID>31044575</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ibrahim M, Elnabtity AM. Analgesic efficacy of erector spinae plane block in percutaneous nephrolithotomy : A randomized controlled trial. Anaesthesist. 2019 Nov;68(11):755-761. doi: 10.1007/s00101-019-00673-w. Epub 2019 Oct 16.</citation>
    <PMID>31620856</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Govender S, Mohr D, Van Schoor AN, Bosenberg A. The extent of cranio-caudal spread within the erector spinae fascial plane space using computed tomography scanning in a neonatal cadaver. Paediatr Anaesth. 2020 Jun;30(6):667-670. doi: 10.1111/pan.13864. Epub 2020 Apr 22.</citation>
    <PMID>32267041</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ugras MY, Toprak HI, Gunen H, Yucel A, Gunes A. Instillation of skin, nephrostomy tract, and renal puncture site with ropivacaine decreases pain and improves ventilatory function after percutaneous nephrolithotomy. J Endourol. 2007 May;21(5):499-503.</citation>
    <PMID>17523902</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Tsui BCH, Fonseca A, Munshey F, McFadyen G, Caruso TJ. The erector spinae plane (ESP) block: A pooled review of 242 cases. J Clin Anesth. 2019 Mar;53:29-34. doi: 10.1016/j.jclinane.2018.09.036. Epub 2018 Oct 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30292068</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ropivacaine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>April 1, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/44/NCT05024344/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>April 1, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/44/NCT05024344/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

