<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05029310</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>148684</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05029310</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Patiromer on Pharmacokinetics of Immunosuppresive Drugs in Renal Transplant Recipients</brief_title>
  <acronym>TACPAT</acronym>
  <official_title>Effects of Patiromer on Pharmacokinetics of Immunosuppresive Drugs in Renal Transplant Recipients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Oslo University Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Oslo University Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patiromer lowers potassium effectively in patients with hyperkalemia and chronic kidney&#xD;
      disease. Patients with a kidney transplant usually have reduced renal function and may also&#xD;
      develop hyperkalemia. However, potential interactions between immunosuppressive medications&#xD;
      and patiromer have not been evaluated. These interactions could involve change in AUC of&#xD;
      immunosuppressive drugs, such as calcineurin inhibitors or mycophenolate, or increased risk&#xD;
      of hypomagnesemia, since both tacrolimus and patiromer have this potential side effect. We&#xD;
      wish to evaluate potential interactions to ensure safe use of this drug in the transplant&#xD;
      population.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Patients with a kidney transplant may develop hyperkalemia. This could be due to different&#xD;
      mechanisms. In some patients it could be due to reduced kidney function. In others, it could&#xD;
      be secondary to renal tubular acidosis type 4 caused by necessary medications used after&#xD;
      transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The most important medicines contributing to hyperkalemia after kidney transplantation are&#xD;
      calcineurin inhibitors which are a compulsory part of the immunosuppressive regimen, ACE&#xD;
      inhibitors or ARBs in patients with hypertension, and trimethoprim-sulfa, which is used as&#xD;
      infection prophylaxis in all patients during the first 6 months after transplantation. In the&#xD;
      weeks after renal transplantation around 5-10% of transplant patients at our institution at&#xD;
      some point develop hyperkalemia above the limit where some type of management of hyperkalemia&#xD;
      would be indicated. As the drugs mentioned above can rarely or not at all be withdrawn after&#xD;
      transplantation, most doctors will either observe the hyperkalemia untreated or try to lower&#xD;
      the potassium level.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In outpatients with s-potassium of 5 - 6.5, urgent management is usually not necessary.&#xD;
      However, some kind of intervention is still indicated, to make sure that the potassium will&#xD;
      decrease during the next days. Patiromer could be an interesting alternative in those kidney&#xD;
      transplanted patients that are in this category. We are not aware of any published studies&#xD;
      describing the use of patiromer in the transplant population. We intend to investigate if&#xD;
      there is any pharmacokinetic interaction between patiromer and immunosuppressive drugs&#xD;
      affecting the blood concentration of the latter.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Patients already taking tacrolimus start treatment with patiromer. After seven days tacrolimus kinetics are studied. Seven days after discontinuation of patiromer, tacrolimus kinetics are repeated.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>study potential interaction between patiromer and tacrolimus</measure>
    <time_frame>two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Log-transformed AUC0-tau of tacrolimus between patiromer vs. no patiromer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine effect of patiromer on potassium concentration.</measure>
    <time_frame>two weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Delta-value change of serum potassium from start of treatment to 7 days after start of treatment, and delta-value change of serum potassium from 7 days after start of treatment to 7 days after end of treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">13</enrollment>
  <condition>Hyperkalemia</condition>
  <condition>Kidney Transplant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>All patients use both patiromer and tacrolimus</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Pharmacokinetic investigation of tacrolimus performed in bothe the presence and absence of patiromer for all patients.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Patiromer Oral Product</intervention_name>
    <description>interaction study</description>
    <arm_group_label>All patients use both patiromer and tacrolimus</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Renal transplant recipients, at least 3 weeks after transplantation, who receive&#xD;
             Tacrolimus as part of their immunosuppressive therapy, with stabile tacrolimus dose&#xD;
             and trough tacrolimus concentration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Recipients 18 years of age or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hyperkalemia (K&gt;5 and &lt;6,0)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Concomitant treatment with: diltiazem, verapamil, fenytoin, carbamazapin, fluconazole,&#xD;
             ketoconazole, vorikonazole, erythromycin, clarithromycin, resonium-calcium, and/or&#xD;
             sodium zirconium cyclosilicate.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Constipation, defined as fewer than three bowel movements per week.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Hypomagnesemia less than 0.6 mmol/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Serum potassium level of greater than 6.0 mEq/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Increased immunologic risk patient (DSA, ABO-incompatible transplant).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy or suspected pregnancy (pregnancy is excluded at time of transplantation by&#xD;
             measuring HCG, kidney transplanted patients should not become pregnant before at least&#xD;
             one year after transplant, and no transplanted patient has ever become pregnant during&#xD;
             the first weeks after transplantation. They are all informed regarding different types&#xD;
             of contraception). Fertile women will be tested for pregnancy before inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Hypersensitivity/allergy to patiromer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Other serious medical or psychiatric condition likely to interfere with participation.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Geir Mjøen, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>MD</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rasmus Kirkeskov Carlsen, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+4723070000</phone>
    <email>r.k.carlsen@studmed.uio.no</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Oslo University Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Geir Mjøen</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>kidney transplant</keyword>
  <keyword>Hyperkalemia</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hyperkalemia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>no plan</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

