<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05028595</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Hepatic MRI</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05028595</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluation of Hepatic Affection in Hemodialysis Patients With Iron Overload in Assiut University Hospital</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Hepatic Affection in Hemodialysis Patients With Iron Overload in Assiut University Hospital</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Aim of the work&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Assessment of hepatic affection in patients with ESRD (end stage renal disease) on&#xD;
           regular dialysis with iron indices suggesting iron overload.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Comparison between HCV -negative HD patients with high and normal TSAT as regard liver&#xD;
           iron concentration(LIC) and degree of fibrosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Anemia is a common complication in patients with chronic kidney disease (CKD) . The main&#xD;
      cause of anemia is the inadequate production of erythropoietin. Iron deficiency is another&#xD;
      common cause of anemia in these patients . Inflammation is another hallmark of CKD that may&#xD;
      lead to a &quot;functional&quot; iron deficient anemia .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first treatment used to correct anemia in CKD patients was blood transfusion. However,&#xD;
      the risk of transfusion reaction, transmission of infectious agents and iron overload&#xD;
      triggered the search for a better treatment of anemia .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Nowadays, the gold standard treatment for anemia in CKD patients is the administration of&#xD;
      erythropoiesis stimulating agents (ESAs), associated with iron supplementation . Although the&#xD;
      majority of the patients respond to ESA therapy, about 10% of CKD patients are&#xD;
      hypo-responsive . One of the causes for hypo-responsiveness to ESAs is iron deficiency,&#xD;
      either absolute or functional . A ferritin value lower than 30 ng/mL in men or lower than 15&#xD;
      ng/mL in women are consistent with absolute iron deficiency ; a serum ferritin concentration&#xD;
      higher than 300 ng/mL, along with anemia, indicates a functional iron deficiency, as it&#xD;
      usually occurs in CKD patients .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The &quot;Clinical Practice Guideline for Anemia in Chronic Kidney Disease&quot; from KDIGO stated that&#xD;
      CKD patients with anemia should first start iron therapy rather than ESAs .&#xD;
&#xD;
      The Dialysis Outcomes and Practice Patterns Study (DOPPS) showed that the number of HD&#xD;
      patients with IV iron supplementation increased in most countries and the doses prescribed to&#xD;
      these patients also increased in the past 10-15 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The liver is the main site of iron storage, and the liver iron concentration (LIC) is closely&#xD;
      correlated with total body iron stores in patients with secondary forms of hemosiderosis such&#xD;
      as thalassemia major, sickle cell disease, and genetic hemochromatosis . Non-invasive&#xD;
      techniques for estimating liver iron stores have been developed to avoid liver biopsy,&#xD;
      including the superconducting quantum interference device (SQUID), quantitative computed&#xD;
      tomography, and MRI .&#xD;
&#xD;
      More than one study show that 84% of the HD patients had hepatic iron overload, and in 30% of&#xD;
      them iron overload was severe; moreover, iron liver content correlated with infused iron .&#xD;
&#xD;
      In spite of the widespread use of IV iron supplementation in HD patients, the safest dosing&#xD;
      strategy is still poorly clarified, as well as its relation with serum ferritin levels, iron&#xD;
      overload and mortality risk.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 20, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 30, 2020</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 30, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of hepatic affection in patients with ESRD (end stage renal disease) on regular dialysis with iron indices suggesting iron overload.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>MRI for abdomen was done .patient on supine position and multiple cuts were taken</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison between HCV -negative HD patients with high and normal TSAT as regard liver iron concentration(LIC) and degree of fibrosis.</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Assesment of degree of hepatic fibrosis by fibroscan machine ,Patients on supine position and sonar probe placed between ribs9-11 to asses degree of fibrosis</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatic Injury</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        PT with ESRD on regular haemodialysis&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eighty patients with end-stage kidney disease (ESKD) on regular hemodialysis for more&#xD;
             than two years were enrolled in the study with normal serum ferritin level at the&#xD;
             start of dialysis&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with one or more of the following conditions were excluded;&#xD;
             non-dialysis-dependent chronic kidney disease patients (NDD-CKD), iron deficiency&#xD;
             anaemia (diagnosed based on iron studies included serum iron, ferritin and total iron&#xD;
             binding capacity), other causes of hemochromatosis such as genetic type, or&#xD;
             hemochromatosis secondary to hemolytic anemia, hepatitis B virus infection, and human&#xD;
             immunodeficiency virus infection. Moreover, patients with additional causes of liver&#xD;
             disease, including non-alcoholic fatty liver disease, primary sclerosing cholangitis,&#xD;
             primary biliary cholangitis, etc. were excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other exclusion criteria included active malignancy, heart failure, use of&#xD;
        immunosuppressive drugs, previous liver transplantation, and patients who are below 18 year&#xD;
        of age&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Marwa Abokresha</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assuit</city>
        <zip>71511</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stauffer ME, Fan T. Prevalence of anemia in chronic kidney disease in the United States. PLoS One. 2014 Jan 2;9(1):e84943. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0084943. eCollection 2014.</citation>
    <PMID>24392162</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ribeiro S, Belo L, Reis F, Santos-Silva A. Iron therapy in chronic kidney disease: Recent changes, benefits and risks. Blood Rev. 2016 Jan;30(1):65-72. doi: 10.1016/j.blre.2015.07.006. Epub 2015 Aug 18. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26342303</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nangaku M, Eckardt KU. Pathogenesis of renal anemia. Semin Nephrol. 2006 Jul;26(4):261-8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>16949463</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Costa E, Lima M, Alves JM, Rocha S, Rocha-Pereira P, Castro E, Miranda V, do SF, Loureiro A, Quintanilha A, Belo L, Santos-Silva A. Inflammation, T-cell phenotype, and inflammatory cytokines in chronic kidney disease patients under hemodialysis and its relationship to resistance to recombinant human erythropoietin therapy. J Clin Immunol. 2008 May;28(3):268-75. doi: 10.1007/s10875-007-9168-x.</citation>
    <PMID>18205031</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>do Sameiro-Faria M, Ribeiro S, Costa E, Mendonça D, Teixeira L, Rocha-Pereira P, Fernandes J, Nascimento H, Kohlova M, Reis F, Amado L, Bronze-da-Rocha E, Miranda V, Quintanilha A, Belo L, Santos-Silva A. Risk factors for mortality in hemodialysis patients: two-year follow-up study. Dis Markers. 2013;35(6):791-8. doi: 10.1155/2013/518945. Epub 2013 Nov 24.</citation>
    <PMID>24347799</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Łukaszyk E, Łukaszyk M, Koc-Żórawska E, Tobolczyk J, Bodzenta-Łukaszyk A, Małyszko J. Iron Status and Inflammation in Early Stages of Chronic Kidney Disease. Kidney Blood Press Res. 2015;40(4):366-73. doi: 10.1159/000368512. Epub 2015 Jun 20.</citation>
    <PMID>26160488</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ibrahim HN, Ishani A, Guo H, Gilbertson DT. Blood transfusion use in non-dialysis-dependent chronic kidney disease patients aged 65 years and older. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2009 Oct;24(10):3138-43. doi: 10.1093/ndt/gfp213. Epub 2009 May 18.</citation>
    <PMID>19451656</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Drüeke TB, Parfrey PS. Summary of the KDIGO guideline on anemia and comment: reading between the (guide)line(s). Kidney Int. 2012 Nov;82(9):952-60. doi: 10.1038/ki.2012.270. Epub 2012 Aug 1. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22854645</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuwahara M, Mandai S, Kasagi Y, Kusaka K, Tanaka T, Shikuma S, Akita W. Responsiveness to erythropoiesis-stimulating agents and renal survival in patients with chronic kidney disease. Clin Exp Nephrol. 2015 Aug;19(4):598-605. doi: 10.1007/s10157-014-1023-9. Epub 2014 Sep 3.</citation>
    <PMID>25183365</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>National Kidney Foundation. K/DOQI clinical practice guidelines for chronic kidney disease: evaluation, classification, and stratification. Am J Kidney Dis. 2002 Feb;39(2 Suppl 1):S1-266.</citation>
    <PMID>11904577</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marwa M.Abokresha</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principle investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Iron Overload</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

