<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05021328</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HBCH-RT-2021-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05021328</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Toripalimab Combined With Anlotinib and SBRT in Patients With Untreated Brain Metastases of Driven Gene-negative NSCLC</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase Ib Study on Toripalimab Combined With Anlotinib and SBRT for Patients With Untreated Brain Metastases of Driven Gene-negative Non-small Cell Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hubei Cancer Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hubei Cancer Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to explore the efficacy and safety of toripalimab combined with&#xD;
      anlotinib and SBRT for non-driver gene mutation untreated brain metastases non-small Cell&#xD;
      Lung Cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Brain metastases (BM) develop in 22-54% of NSCLC patients during the disease course. NSCLC&#xD;
      patients with BM with a median overall survival (OS) of 2-3 months when treated with systemic&#xD;
      corticosteroid alone, and a median OS of 10-12 months when treated with brain radiation&#xD;
      therapy. Recently, several studies have reported the benefits of epidermal growth factor&#xD;
      receptor (EGFR) tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKIs) for EGFR mutation NSCLC patients with BM.&#xD;
      The median OS of EGFR mutation patients with BM significantly improved with TKIs treatment,&#xD;
      which ranged from 11.8 to 18.8 months. However, for the EGFR wide-type NSCLC patients with&#xD;
      BM, the prognosis remains poor.&#xD;
&#xD;
      JS-001 is the first monoclonal antibody (mAb) against programmed cell death protein-1 (PD-1)&#xD;
      approved by the China Food and Drug Administration (CFDA) into the clinical trails.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Anlotinib hydrochloride is a multi-target receptor tyrosine kinase inhibitor that has&#xD;
      significant inhibitory activity against angiogenesis related kinases such as VEGFR1/2/3,&#xD;
      FGFR1/2/3, and other tumor related kinases such as PDGFR /, C-Kit, Ret, etc. (e.g., Met,&#xD;
      FGFR1/2/3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The previously study (2021 EMSO congress abstract) found that Apatinib, another kind of&#xD;
      tyrosine kinase inhibitor that selectively inhibits the VEGFR-2, combined with brain&#xD;
      radiation therapy could improve mOS time to 17 months in lung cancer patients with BMs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, the investigators initiated this study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of&#xD;
      toripalimab combined with anlotinib and SBRT for non-driver gene mutation untreated brain&#xD;
      metastases non-small Cell Lung Cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Treatment-related adverse events</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 24 month</time_frame>
    <description>AEs per Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE V5.0)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial response rate (iORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>4 weeks after Radiotherapy.</time_frame>
    <description>Proportion of patients with a complete or partial response in intracranial metastases as measured using RECIST 1.1 criteria (modified for brain metastases - bm RECIST).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Intracranial progression-free survival (iPFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Tumor assesment at 4 weeks and 12 weeks after radiotherapy, and then every 12 weeks, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time from randomisation to progression of intracranial disease or death from any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Local Control Rate (LCR)</measure>
    <time_frame>Tumor assesment at 4 weeks and 12 weeks after radiotherapy, and then every 12 weeks, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Local recurrence is defined as the onset or progression of nodular contrast grafting within the resection cavity according to the Response Assessment in Neuro-Oncology Brain Metastases (RANO-BM) criteria.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Tumor assesment at 4 weeks and 12 weeks after radiotherapy, and then every 12 weeks, up to 24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as the time from randomisation to death from any cause</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>NSCLC</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Induction therapy (D1-D21): SBRT 7Gy✖️5 QD, D1-D5 + Toripalimab 240mg iv drip D1 + Anlotinib 12mg, QD, PO, D1-D14；&#xD;
Maintenance (D22~1year): Toripalimab 240mg iv drip D1 Q3W + Anlotinib 12mg, QD, PO, D1-D14, Q3W, until progression (up to approximately 1 year)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT and Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Induction therapy (D1-D21): SBRT 7Gy✖️5 QD, D1-D5 + Anlotinib 12mg, QD, PO, D1-D14；&#xD;
Maintenance (D22~1year): Toripalimab 240mg iv drip D1 Q3W + Anlotinib 12mg, QD, PO, D1-D14, Q3W, until progression (up to approximately 1 year)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Toripalimab</intervention_name>
    <description>Toripalimab 240mg, ivgtt, d1, q3w.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT and Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>JS001</other_name>
    <other_name>Toripalimab Injection</other_name>
    <other_name>Teruipuli dankang Zhusheye</other_name>
    <other_name>TuoYI</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Anlotinib</intervention_name>
    <description>Anlotinib 12 mg/d, d1-14, q3w.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT and Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>AL3818</other_name>
    <other_name>Anlotinib Hydrochloride Capsules</other_name>
    <other_name>FuKeWei</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SBRT 7Gy✖️5 QD</intervention_name>
    <description>SBRT 7Gy✖️5 QD</description>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Anlotinib combined with SBRT and Toripalimab</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 to 70 years old, no gender limit；&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Pathologically or cytologically confirmed non-small cell lung cancer, stage IV tumor&#xD;
             with initial brain metastasis diagnosed by imaging 2 weeks before enrollment, ≤ 5&#xD;
             intracranial metastases (the patient's primary tumor disease has not received systemic&#xD;
             treatment, or the patient has received systemic treatment for more than 6 months, for&#xD;
             example, brain metastasis 6 months after postoperative adjuvant chemotherapy for lung&#xD;
             cancer);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Negative driver genes (EGFR, ALK, ROS1, etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. ECOG PS score: 0～1;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. The expected survival time ≥ 3 months;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. American Radiotherapy Oncology Group (RTOG) neurological status score: 0-1;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Intracranial metastases can be measured and evaluated by MRI;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Intracranial lesions are suitable for stereotactic radiotherapy based on the linear&#xD;
             accelerator;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Able to independently complete neurocognitive tests;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Able to complete the QOL questionnaire independently;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Female subjects with fertility should undergo a urine or serum pregnancy test within&#xD;
             72 hours before receiving the first study drug administration, and prove to be&#xD;
             negative, and are willing to use effectively during the test period to 3 months after&#xD;
             the last administration Methods of contraception. For male subjects whose partners are&#xD;
             women of childbearing age, effective methods of contraception should be used during&#xD;
             the trial and within 3 months after the last administration;&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. The functions of important organs meet the following requirements (no blood components&#xD;
             and cell growth factors are allowed to be used 2 weeks before the start of the&#xD;
             research treatment): Absolute Neutrophil Count (ANC) ≥1.5×10 E+9/L, Hemoglobin (HB)&#xD;
             ≥9g/dL, Platelets (PLT)≥90×10 E+9/L, Serum Albumin (ALB)≥2.8g/dL, Total Bilirubin&#xD;
             (TBIL) ≤1.5 ULN, ALT、AST≤2.5 UILN(If abnormal liver function is caused by liver&#xD;
             metastasis, ≤5 ULN), Serum creatinine sCr≤1.5 ULN, endogenous creatinine clearance&#xD;
             ≥50ml/min (Cockcroft-Gault formula) , Normal thyroid function;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. The patients joined the study voluntarily and signed an informed consent form (ICF).&#xD;
             They had good compliance and cooperated with follow-up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Brain metastases are located in the brain stem or other locations, which makes&#xD;
             radiotherapy unsuitable;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Brain metastasis with hemorrhage or leptomeningeal disease;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. There is known evidence that patients have mutations in any of the genes above EGFR,&#xD;
             ROS-1, ALK;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients who cannot undergo MRI examination due to metal implants or claustrophobia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Currently participating in interventional clinical research and treatment, or&#xD;
             receiving other research drugs or treatment with research equipment within 4 weeks&#xD;
             before the first administration;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Accept solid organ or blood system transplantation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Past treatment history of CTLA-4, PD-1 or PD-L1 immune checkpoint inhibitors;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Suffer from active autoimmune diseases that require hormone or immunomodulatory&#xD;
             treatment, such as rheumatoid arthritis, ankylosing spondylitis, type I diabetes,&#xD;
             psoriasis, vitiligo, immune-related thyroid dysfunction, etc. (hormone replacement Can&#xD;
             be included after treatment is normal);&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Suffer from acute or chronic infectious diseases, such as hepatitis B, hepatitis C,&#xD;
             tuberculosis, and HIV;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Allergic to research drug ingredients&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Active infection or fever of unknown cause occurred during the screening period and&#xD;
             before the first administration&gt; 38.5℃ (according to the judgment of the investigator,&#xD;
             the subject can be included in the group due to fever caused by the tumor);&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Suffer from uncontrolled clinical symptoms or diseases of the heart, such as:(1) Heart&#xD;
             failure above NYHA II; (2) Unstable angina pectoris; (3) Myocardial infarction&#xD;
             occurred within 1 year; (4) Patients with clinically significant supraventricular or&#xD;
             ventricular arrhythmia requiring clinical intervention;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Suffer from high blood pressure and cannot be well controlled by antihypertensive&#xD;
             medication (systolic blood pressure ≥150 mmHg or diastolic blood pressure ≥100 mmHg);&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Abnormal blood coagulation function (INR&gt;2.0, PT&gt;16s), have a bleeding tendency or are&#xD;
             receiving thrombolytic therapy, and allow preventive use of low-dose aspirin and&#xD;
             low-molecular-weight heparin;&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Obvious coughing up blood or hemoptysis of 10ml or more per day in the 2 months before&#xD;
             enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Have significant clinically significant bleeding symptoms or have a clear bleeding&#xD;
             tendency within 3 months before enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Have received anti-tumor monoclonal antibodies (mAb) within 4 weeks before using the&#xD;
             study drug for the first time, or the adverse events caused by the previously received&#xD;
             drug have not recovered (ie ≤ grade 1 or reached the baseline level). Note: Except for&#xD;
             subjects with ≤ Grade 2 neuropathy or ≤ Grade 2 hair loss, if the subject has&#xD;
             undergone major surgery, the toxic reaction and/or complications caused by the&#xD;
             surgical intervention must be fully recovered before starting treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Live vaccines have been vaccinated within 4 weeks before the first use of the study&#xD;
             drug. Inactivated virus vaccines for seasonal influenza and injections are allowed,&#xD;
             but live attenuated influenza vaccines for nasal use are not allowed;&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Past history of head trauma, diseases of the central nervous system and neurological&#xD;
             function defects; suffering from intracranial organic diseases with poor drug control&#xD;
             effects, such as cerebral infarction, intracranial vascular malformations, etc.;&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. The investigator judged other situations not suitable for inclusion in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Guang Han, MD</last_name>
    <phone>13886048178</phone>
    <email>hg7913@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hubei Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Wuhan</city>
        <state>Hubei</state>
        <zip>430079</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Han Guang, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Han Guang, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Hubei Cancer Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>HAN GUANG</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Brain metastasis</keyword>
  <keyword>Toripalimab</keyword>
  <keyword>Anlotinib</keyword>
  <keyword>SBRT</keyword>
  <keyword>Drive gene negative</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Neoplasm Metastasis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Brain Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

