<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05027048</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>62206</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05027048</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Calcium Chloride for Prevention of Blood Loss During Intrapartum Cesarean Delivery</brief_title>
  <acronym>CALBLOC</acronym>
  <official_title>Calcium Chloride for Prevention of Blood Loss From Uterine Atony During Intrapartum Cesarean Delivery (CALBLOC): a Double Blind, Randomized, Placebo Controlled Trial and Nested Population Pharmacokinetic and Pharmacodynamic Analysis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Stanford University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Stanford University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Postpartum hemorrhage (PPH) is the leading cause of maternal morbidity and mortality&#xD;
      worldwide. Up to 80% of PPH is caused by uterine atony, the failure of the uterine smooth&#xD;
      muscle to contract and compress the uterine vasculature after delivery. Laboratory and&#xD;
      epidemiological studies show that low extracellular and serum calcium levels, respectively,&#xD;
      decrease uterine contractility. A pilot study performed by the investigators supports the&#xD;
      hypothesis that intravenous calcium chloride is well tolerated and may have utility in&#xD;
      preventing uterine atony. The proposed research will establish the relationship between&#xD;
      uterine tone and calcium through a clinical trial with an incorporated pharmacokinetic and&#xD;
      pharmacodynamic (PK/PD) study. In a randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind trial,&#xD;
      investigators will establish the effect of 1 gram of intravenous calcium chloride upon&#xD;
      quantitative blood loss and uterine tone during cesarean delivery in parturients with high&#xD;
      risk of uterine atony. Investigators will concurrently collect serial venous blood samples to&#xD;
      measure calcium for PK/PD modeling in this pregnant study cohort. High-quality clinical&#xD;
      research and development of novel therapeutics to manage uterine atony are critical to reduce&#xD;
      the high maternal morbidity and mortality from PPH.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This randomized controlled trial (RCT) assesses calcium chloride as a novel intervention to&#xD;
      prevent hemorrhage from uterine atony with nested PK/PD analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PPH is the leading cause of maternal morbidity and mortality worldwide. Uterine atony,&#xD;
      defined as failure of the uterus to adequately contract after placental delivery, causes&#xD;
      approximately 80% of PPH. Current medications used to prevent or treat uterine atony are&#xD;
      limited by poor efficacy, adverse side effects, expense, and contraindications to use. As&#xD;
      such, there is a critical need for effective, safe, and inexpensive pharmacologic measures&#xD;
      for uterine atony.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intravenous calcium chloride is an inexpensive, shelf-stable drug with good biologic and&#xD;
      epidemiological plausibility to treat and/or prevent uterine atony. Calcium is already&#xD;
      frequently utilized in obstetric anesthesia for indications such as hypocalcemia from massive&#xD;
      transfusion and overcoming magnesium toxicity. Multiple in vitro studies have demonstrated&#xD;
      that adequate extracellular calcium levels are necessary for forceful myometrial contraction&#xD;
      in response to oxytocin. Epidemiological studies show that low ionized calcium levels predict&#xD;
      the development of severe postpartum hemorrhage in a dose-response fashion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators recently conducted a 40-patient placebo-controlled, double-blind pilot RCT&#xD;
      assessing a one-gram dose of intravenous calcium chloride as a novel agent to prevent uterine&#xD;
      atony during cesarean delivery. This pilot demonstrated the feasibility of enrollment and&#xD;
      good patient tolerance of the intervention. Moreover, there were trends suggestive of&#xD;
      efficacy of calcium to prevent uterine atony in patients who received calcium as compared to&#xD;
      placebo infusion (p=0.07, relative risk 0.38, 95% CI 0.15-1.07, number needed to treat 3.3).&#xD;
      Building upon the promising results from the pilot study, the aims of this study are to:&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 1: Establish the effect of a calcium chloride infusion on blood loss and uterine tone&#xD;
      during cesarean delivery in parturients at heightened risk for uterine atony in a&#xD;
      double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis: Calcium chloride infusion will reduce quantitative blood loss (QBL, primary&#xD;
      outcome) and improve a numerical rating score for uterine tone (secondary outcome) compared&#xD;
      to placebo without significant safety or tolerability concerns.&#xD;
&#xD;
      AIM 2: Measure pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of intravenous calcium chloride in&#xD;
      pregnant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Establishing the pharmacokinetics of intravenous calcium chloride in parturients is of&#xD;
      relevance whether or not it is shown to be effective in preventing atony in Aim 1, given the&#xD;
      multiple indications for calcium administration in obstetric patients. Meanwhile,&#xD;
      pharmacodynamic modeling of calcium's effect upon uterine tone will allow quantification of&#xD;
      calcium's effect on myometrial function. Investigators will generate a pharmacokinetic and&#xD;
      pharmacodynamic model for calcium in pregnancy that includes estimates of covariate effects&#xD;
      and intra-and inter-individual variability using non-linear mixed effects modeling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Significance: If calcium chloride, an inexpensive, widely available drug, has efficacy in the&#xD;
      prevention or treatment of uterine atony, it has the potential to decrease the leading cause&#xD;
      of maternal morbidity and mortality. Investigators will also leverage the intervention tested&#xD;
      in the RCT, the infusion of calcium chloride, to define the pharmacokinetics and&#xD;
      pharmacodynamics of calcium in pregnant women at term. This has potential relevance in&#xD;
      defining approaches for administering calcium in various obstetrical contexts and will&#xD;
      facilitate dose optimization.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">January 2023</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double blind, placebo controlled randomized clinical trial with 1:1 allocation</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>The patient, obstetrician, anesthesiologist, and clinical research staff will be blinded to the intervention. Drugs will be labeled only as &quot;study drug&quot;</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantitative Blood Loss</measure>
    <time_frame>measurement occurs at conclusion of operating room case</time_frame>
    <description>Standardized volumetric and gravimetric assessment of blood loss during cesarean. Note: will analyze all participants, but planned subgroup analysis will also occur excluding patients with non-atonic reasons for blood loss including hysterotomy extension, placental abruption, cervical or vaginal laceration, etc</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Uterine tone numerical rating score</measure>
    <time_frame>2, 7, and 12 minutes after fetal delivery. The absolute 12 minute score as well as delta from 12-2 and 12-7 minute scores will be analyzed</time_frame>
    <description>Uterine tone assessment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Second line uterotonic requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>within 4 hours of delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Yes/no: did the patient require treatment with methylergonovine, carboprost, and/or misoprostol for uterine atony</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fluid requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>Operating room duration, usually 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Total crystalloid required during cesarean delivery in mL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total oxytocin bolus requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>Cesarean duration, usually about 2 hours</time_frame>
    <description>Total dose oxytocin bolus during cesarean</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Transfusion requirement</measure>
    <time_frame>96 hours of delivery</time_frame>
    <description>Yes/no and total units packed red blood cells</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacokinetics of calcium chloride</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 4 hours of study drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>analyzed in NONMEM using serial venous blood gas ionized calcium levels from willing participants</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pharmacodynamic effect of calcium upon uterine tone NRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Within 20 minutes of study drug administration</time_frame>
    <description>also analyzed in NONMEM</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Uterine Atony</condition>
  <condition>Uterine Atony With Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Postpartum Hemorrhage</condition>
  <condition>Cesarean Section Complications</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Calcium chloride</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1 gram of calcium chloride in total volume 60mL with sterile saline, delivered over 10 minute controlled infusion at a constant rate (360mL/hour) beginning 2 minutes after fetal delivery and 1 minute after delayed cord clamp.&#xD;
This intervention occurs IN ADDITION TO standard care with oxytocin 2 unit bolus and infusion at 7.5 units per hour which begins immediately after fetal delivery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Saline placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>60mL sterile saline, delivered over 10 minute controlled infusion at a constant rate (360mL/hour) beginning 2 minutes after fetal delivery and 1 minute after delayed cord clamp.&#xD;
This intervention occurs IN ADDITION TO standard care with oxytocin 2 unit bolus and infusion at 7.5 units per hour which begins immediately after fetal delivery.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Calcium chloride</intervention_name>
    <description>See arm description above</description>
    <arm_group_label>Calcium chloride</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>see arm description above</description>
    <arm_group_label>Saline placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient had a trial of labor for vaginal delivery prior to cesarean&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient received an oxytocin infusion for labor augmentation or induction prior to&#xD;
             cesarean&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  renal dysfunction with serum Cr &gt;1.0 mg/dL&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  known underlying cardiac condition&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  treatment with digoxin within the last 2 weeks for a maternal or fetal indication&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  treatment with a calcium channel blocker medication within 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hypertension necessitating intravenous antihypertensive medication within 24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  emergent case in which study participation could in any way impede patient care by the&#xD;
             judgement of the obstetrician, anesthesiologist, or bedside nurse&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jessica Ansari, MD</last_name>
    <phone>760-845-0328</phone>
    <email>jansari@stanford.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Brendan Carvalho, FRCA MBBCh</last_name>
    <phone>650-861-8607</phone>
    <email>carvalb@stanford.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 18, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Stanford University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Jessica Ansari, MD</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>calcium chloride</keyword>
  <keyword>uterine atony</keyword>
  <keyword>postpartum hemorrhage</keyword>
  <keyword>cesarean delivery</keyword>
  <keyword>intrapartum cesarean</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Postpartum Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Uterine Inertia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hemorrhage</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Calcium</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

