<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05027308</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TAK-633-3008</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>U1111-1267-3327</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05027308</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Teduglutide in Japanese Children With Short Bowel Syndrome Who Are 4 Months or Older</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3, Open-label Safety Study of Teduglutide in Japanese Pediatric Patients With Short Bowel Syndrome Who Are Dependent on Parenteral Support, Aged 4 Months of Corrected Gestational Age or Older, and Requiring the Dosing of 1.25 mg Formulation</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Takeda</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Takeda</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The main aims of the study are to check for side effects from teduglutide.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will receive a daily injection of teduglutide just under the skin (subcutaneous)&#xD;
      for 24 weeks. Then they are followed up for another 4 weeks. Participants may be able to&#xD;
      repeat this treatment if they meet specific criteria. The study doctors will check for side&#xD;
      effects from teduglutide until it becomes commercially available.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 23, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Treatment-emergent Adverse Events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>An AE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical investigation subject administered a drug; it does not necessarily have to have a causal relationship with this treatment. TEAEs were defined as any AEs whose onset occurred, severity worsened, or intensity increased after receiving the investigational product.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>An SAE is defined as any untoward medical occurrence that at any dose: Results in death, Is life threatening, Requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization, Results in persistent or significant disability/incapacity, Leads to a congenital anomaly /birth defect, Is the other important medical event.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Adverse Events of Special Interest (AESIs)</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>An AESI, whether serious or non-serious, is one of scientific and medical concern specific to the compound or program, for which ongoing monitoring and rapid communication by the investigator to the sponsor may be appropriate.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Clinically Significant Abnormalities in Vital Signs Reported as an Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Vital signs include systolic and diastolic blood pressure, heart rate and body temperature.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Z-Score of Body Weight</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>The Z-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Z-Score of Height</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>The Z-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Z-Score of Head Circumference</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>The Z-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Z-Score of Weight-for-Length</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>The Z-score indicates the number of standard deviations away from the mean.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Clinically Significant Laboratory Safety Data Reported as an Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Laboratory safety data includes biochemistry, hematology and urinalysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Significant Change in Urine Output Reported as an Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Urine and stool output will be recorded and calculated in the output diary over a 48-hour period of parenteral support (PS) and enteral nutrition (EN) stability before every site visit and within 1 week of implementing a change in the PS prescription.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Significant Change in Stool Output Reported as an Adverse Event</measure>
    <time_frame>From start of study drug administration up to end of study (EOS) (up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Urine and stool output will be recorded and calculated in the output diary over a 48-hour period of PS and EN stability before every site visit and within 1 week of implementing a change in the PS prescription.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in PS Volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, multiple timepoints after dose (Week 1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 28), and end of study (EOS: up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>PS (parenteral nutrition or intravenous fluids) will be considered for managing nutritional support in terms of volume and calories during the treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Percent Change From Baseline in PS Volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, multiple timepoints after dose (Week 1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 28), and end of study (EOS: up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Percent change from baseline in PS volume will be calculated as follows; (PS volume at each point [Week 1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 28] - PS volume at baseline)/ PS volume at baseline *100 (percent). PS (parenteral nutrition or intravenous fluids) will be considered for managing nutritional support in terms of volume and calories during the treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants who Demonstrate at least 20 Percent (%) Reduction From Baseline in PS Volume</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, multiple timepoints after dose (Week 1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 28), and end of study (EOS: up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>PS (parenteral nutrition or intravenous fluids) will be considered for managing nutritional support in terms of volume and calories during the treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants who Achieved Enteral Autonomy</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, multiple timepoints after dose (Week 1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 28), and end of study (EOS: up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>Achieving enteral autonomy is defined as complete weaning off PS. PS (parenteral nutrition or intravenous fluids) will be considered for managing nutritional support in terms of volume and calories during the treatment period. Number of participants who achieved enteral autonomy at each time will be reported.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Days per Week of PS</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, multiple timepoints after dose (Week 1, 2, 4, 8, 12, 16, 20, 24, and 28), and end of study (EOS: up to Week 28)</time_frame>
    <description>PS (parenteral nutrition or intravenous fluids) will be considered for managing nutritional support in terms of volume and calories during the treatment period.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5</enrollment>
  <condition>Short Bowel Syndrome</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Teduglutide 0.05 milligram per kilogram (mg/kg)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive teduglutide 0.05 mg/kg (0.025 mg/kg for participants with moderate or greater renal impairment) subcutaneous (SC) injection once daily for 24 weeks followed by no treatment period for 4 weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Teduglutide</intervention_name>
    <description>Teduglutide 0.05 mg/kg SC injection</description>
    <arm_group_label>Teduglutide 0.05 milligram per kilogram (mg/kg)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>TAK-633</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female pediatric patient of corrected gestational age 4 months or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body weight at the time of screening and baseline visits of at least 5 kg and &lt;10 kg&#xD;
             for participants with normal renal function or mild renal impairment (estimated&#xD;
             glomerular filtration rate &gt;=50 mL/min/1.73 m^2), OR at least 10 kg and &lt;20 kg for&#xD;
             participants with moderate or greater renal impairment (estimated glomerular&#xD;
             filtration rate &lt;50 mL/min/1.73 m^2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Diagnosis of short bowel syndrome (SBS) with intestinal failure, defined as dependence&#xD;
             on PS to provide at least 30% of fluid or caloric needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Participants to have stable PS for at least 1 month prior to screening as assessed by&#xD;
             the investigator. Stable PS is defined as inability to significantly reduce parenteral&#xD;
             nutrition/intravenous fluid (PN/IV) support, usually associated with minimal or no&#xD;
             advance in enteral feeds (ie, 10% or less change in PN or advance in feeds), assessed&#xD;
             by the investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. A parent/guardian who is not capable of understanding or not willing to adhere to the&#xD;
             study visit schedule and other protocol requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinically significant intestinal obstruction, active or recurrent pancreatic or&#xD;
             biliary disease, or dysmotility that prevents the advancement of enteral intake.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Intestinal malabsorption due to a genetic condition, such as cystic fibrosis,&#xD;
             microvillus inclusion disease, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Severe, known dysmotility syndrome, such as pseudo-obstruction or persistent, severe,&#xD;
             active gastroschisis-related dysmotility, that is the primary contributing factor to&#xD;
             feeding intolerance and inability to reduce PS, prior to screening. Dysmotility is&#xD;
             defined as severe if it is expected to limit the advancement of enteral feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Major gastrointestinal (GI) surgical intervention including significant intestinal&#xD;
             resection or bowel lengthening procedure within 3 months prior to screening (insertion&#xD;
             of feeding tube, anastomotic ulcer repair, minor intestinal resections =&lt;10 cm and&#xD;
             endoscopic procedures are allowed).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Cardiac disease that makes the patient vulnerable to changes in fluid status.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. History of cancer or known cancer predisposition syndrome, such as juvenile polyposis&#xD;
             or Beckwith-Wiedemann syndrome, or first degree relative with early onset of GI cancer&#xD;
             (including hepatobiliary and pancreatic cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Concurrent treatment with glucagon-like peptide-2 (GLP-2), human growth hormone, or&#xD;
             analogs of these hormones within 6 months prior to the screening visit, or concurrent&#xD;
             treatment with octreotide, GLP-1 analogs, or enteral glutamine within 30 days prior to&#xD;
             the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Concurrent treatment with biological therapy (eg, anti-tumor necrosis factor&#xD;
             [anti-TNF]) for active Crohn's disease within 6 months prior to the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Participation in a clinical study using an experimental drug (other than glutamine or&#xD;
             omegaven) within 3 months or 5.5 half-lives of the experimental drug, whichever is&#xD;
             longer, prior to the screening visit and for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Known or suspected intolerance or hypersensitivity to the study drug, closely related&#xD;
             compounds, or any of the stated ingredients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Signs of active, severe, or unstable clinically significant hepatic impairment during&#xD;
             the screening period as meeting at least 2 of any of the following parameters:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. International normalized ratio &gt;1.5 not corrected with parenteral vitamin K&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Platelet count &lt;100×10^3/mcrL due to portal hypertension&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Presence of clinically significant gastric or esophageal varices&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Cirrhosis&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Persistent cholestasis defined as conjugated bilirubin &gt;4 mg/dL (&gt;68 mcr mol/L)&#xD;
                  over a 2-week period during screening&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Total bilirubin &gt;=2x upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt;=3x ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &gt;=3x ULN&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Months</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Study Director</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Takeda</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Takeda Contact</last_name>
    <phone>+1-877-825-3327</phone>
    <email>medinfoUS@takeda.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Short Bowel Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Teduglutide</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>De-identified individual participant data from this particular study will not be shared as there is a reasonable likelihood that individual patients could be reidentified (due to the limited number of study participants/study sites).</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

