<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05022771</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PMG1015-AUS-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05022771</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A First in Human Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Immunogenicity of PMG1015</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1A, First in Human, Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled, Single Ascending Dose Study to Evaluate the Safety, Tolerability, Pharmacokinetics and Immunogenicity of PMG1015 in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pulmongene Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pulmongene Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 1A, first in human, randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled, dose&#xD;
      escalation study of PMG1015 in healthy adult volunteers. PMG1015 is a monoclonal antibody,&#xD;
      being developed as a novel therapeutic treatment for patients with Idiopathic Pulmonary&#xD;
      fibrosis (IPF). This study aims to evaluate the safety, tolerability, pharmacokinetics and&#xD;
      immunogenicity of PMG1015 after Single ascending doses (SAD).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Participants will be enrolled and randomized into 1 of 6 cohorts in a double-blind manner.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of Treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>An Adverse Event (AE) is any event, side-effect or any untoward medical occurrence in a clinical study participant, temporally associated with the use of a medicinal product, whether or not considered related to the medicinal product. TEAEs are AEs that occur following the start of treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The severity of Treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>TEAEs are AEs that occur following the start of treatment.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The incidence of Serious adverse events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>A serious adverse event (SAE) is defined as an AE occurring during any study phase and at any dose of IP (active or placebo) that results in death; is life threatening; requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization; results in persistent disability/incapacity; results in congenital anomaly/birth defect.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The severity of Serious adverse events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1- Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>A serious adverse event (SAE) is defined as an AE occurring during any study phase and at any dose of IP (active or placebo) that results in death; is life threatening; requires inpatient hospitalization or prolongation of existing hospitalization; results in persistent disability/incapacity; results in congenital anomaly/birth defect.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with abnormally clinical vital signs</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1- Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Vital signs include pulse rate (PR), blood pressure (BP), respiratory rate (RR) and tympanic temperature (T)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with abnormal clinically significant 12-lead electrocardiogram (ECG) parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>All ECG tracings will be reviewed by the PI or designee and assessed for clinical significance.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with abnormal clinically significant clinical laboratory results</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1- Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical laboratory test include hematology, coagulation, biochemistry, and urinalysis.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>MTD of PMG1015 in healthy participants</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1- Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum tolerated dose of PMG1015 in healthy participants</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with abnormal clinically significant results from physical examination</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Complete physical examination include, general appearance, head, eyes, ears, nose, throat, dentition, thyroid, chest (heart, lungs), abdomen, skin, neurological, extremities, back, neck, musculoskeletal, and lymph nodes.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the serum-concentration time curve (AUC) from time zero (from the start of infusion time) to the last time point with measurable analyte concentration (AUC0-t)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC) from time 0 to time of last quantifiable concentration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC from time zero to infinity (AUC0-∞)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC) from time 0 (from the start of infusion) extrapolated to infinity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine %AUCexp</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>The percentage of the AUC that has been extrapolated beyond the last observed data point</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine Cmax</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum observed serum PMG1015 concentration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine Tmax, derived from serum concentration of each dose of PMG1015</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>Time to maximum observed concentration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine t1/2</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>Terminal elimination half life summarized by dosing regimen</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent total body clearance (CL)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>CL is the measure of the rate at which a drug is metabolized or eliminated by normal biological processes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent volume of distribution during the terminal phase (Vz)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>Vz is defined as the theoretical volume in which the total amount of drug would need to be uniformly distributed to produce the desired plasma concentration of a drug.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Apparent terminal elimination rate constant (λz or kel)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85.</time_frame>
    <description>λz is calculated using log-linear regression of the terminal portions of the plasma concentrations versus time curves.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Levels of ADA</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1-Day 85</time_frame>
    <description>Anti-drug antibody levels in blood</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>6</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">46</enrollment>
  <condition>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1a</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive either Dose level 1 of PMG1015 or Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1b</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive either Dose level 2 of PMG1015 or Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1c</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive either Dose level 3 of PMG1015 or Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1d</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive either Dose level 4 of PMG1015 or Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1e</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive either Dose level 5 of PMG1015 or Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1f</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Subjects will receive either Dose level 6 of PMG1015 or Placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PMG1015 Dose 1</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 1 of PMG1015</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1a</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PMG1015</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PMG1015 Dose 2</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 2 of PMG1015</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1b</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PMG1015</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PMG1015 Dose 3</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 3 of PMG1015</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1c</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PMG1015</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PMG1015 Dose 4</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 4 of PMG1015</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1d</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PMG1015</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PMG1015 Dose 5</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 5 of PMG1015</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1e</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PMG1015</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>PMG1015 Dose 6</intervention_name>
    <description>Dose level 6 of PMG1015</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1f</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PMG1015</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Placebo to match</description>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1a</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1b</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1c</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1d</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1e</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Single Ascending Doses Cohort 1f</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy male or non-pregnant, non-lactating female volunteers, between 18 and 60 years&#xD;
             of age, inclusive at the time of informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index (BMI) between 17.5 and 32.0 kg/m2 (inclusive) and body weight between&#xD;
             50 and 100 kg for males and between 45 and 100 kg for females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. No clinically significant clinical laboratory values (Hematology, coagulation,&#xD;
             biochemistry and urinalysis) at the discretion of the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Females of child bearing potential must use an acceptable, highly effective double&#xD;
             contraception and have a negative pregnancy test at Screening and Day-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Documented evidence of surgical sterilization at least 6 months prior to screening for&#xD;
             women or vasectomy at least 90 days prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Women not of child bearing potential must be menopausal for &gt;/= 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Males must not donate sperms for at least 90 days after PMG1015 administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History or evidence of clinically significant condition, including but not limited to&#xD;
             any cardiovascular, gastrointestinal, endocrinologic, hematologic, psychiatric, renal&#xD;
             disease, musculoskeletal, infectious, or neurological condition or any chronic medical&#xD;
             condition and/or other major disease, as determined by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A PR &lt; 40 or &gt; 100 beats per minute, mean systolic blood pressure (SBP) &gt; 140 mmHg, or&#xD;
             mean diastolic blood pressure (DBP) &gt; 95 mmHg .&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. A mean corrected QT interval using Fridericia's formula (QTcF) interval at Screening &gt;&#xD;
             450 ms in males and &gt; 470 ms in females. If the mean QTcF exceeds these limits, one&#xD;
             additional triplicate ECG will be performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any clinically significant abnormalities in rhythm, conduction, or morphology of the&#xD;
             resting ECG and any abnormalities in the 12-lead ECG that, in the judgment of the PI,&#xD;
             may interfere with the interpretation of QTc-interval changes, including abnormal ST-T&#xD;
             wave morphology or left ventricular hypertrophy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Alanine aminotransferase (ALT), aspartate aminotransferase (AST), or creatinine &gt; 1.5&#xD;
             × the upper limit of the normal range (ULN) or total bilirubin or lymphocyte counts &gt;&#xD;
             ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participants with a positive toxicology screening panel or alcohol breath test on&#xD;
             Screening/Day-1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Participants with a history of substance abuse or dependency or history of&#xD;
             recreational IV drug use over the last 2 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Plasma donation/Blood donation or significant blood loss within 60 days prior to the&#xD;
             first IP administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Use of any IP (including other investigational mAb products) or investigational&#xD;
             medical device within 30 days prior to Screening or 5 half-lives of the product&#xD;
             (whichever is the longest) or participation in more than 4 investigational drug&#xD;
             studies within 1 year prior to screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Major surgery (general anesthetic) within 3 months or minor surgery (local anesthetic)&#xD;
             within 1 month prior to IP administration, or planned surgery during the study period,&#xD;
             which is determined by the PI to be clinically relevant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Fever or symptomatic bacterial or viral infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Participants who have received live vaccines or attenuated vaccines within 1 month&#xD;
             before dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Participants with any active malignancy or history of malignancy within 5 years prior&#xD;
             to enrolment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Use of any other prescription medications.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. History of anaphylaxis, allergic reactions to the excipients of IP, asthma.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Positive blood screen for HIV1/2 antibody, Hepatitis B surface antigen, hepatitis C&#xD;
             virus, or syphilis at screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Participants with an inability to tolerate venous access.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Pregnant or lactating at Screening or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at&#xD;
             any time during the study, including the follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. An employee of Pulmongene or Novotech (Australia) Pty Ltd.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Participant is unwilling to abstain from alcohol beginning 48 hours prior to admission&#xD;
             to the CRU and while resident at the CRU.&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Any other condition or finding that in the opinion of the PI or designee would put the&#xD;
             participant or study conduct at risk.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Richard Friend</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nucleus Network</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ning Wu</last_name>
    <phone>+86 18228071008</phone>
    <email>ning_wu@pulmongene.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Wenxiu Qu</last_name>
    <phone>+86 18940257027</phone>
    <email>wenxiu_qu@pulmongene.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Q-Pharm Pty Ltd, Clive Berghofer Cancer Research Centre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Herston</city>
        <state>Queensland</state>
        <zip>4006</zip>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

