<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05025774</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PEDS-2021-29482</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05025774</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Fitness and Lung Function Among Survivors of Heart Transplant, Leukemia and Infant BPD Through Exercise</brief_title>
  <acronym>FLASHLITE</acronym>
  <official_title>Fitness and Lung Function Among Survivors of Heart Transplant, Leukemia and Infant Bronchopulmonary Dysplasia (BPD, Also Known as Chronic Lung Disease of Prematurity) Through Exercise (FLASHLITE)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Masonic Cancer Center, University of Minnesota</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Masonic Cancer Center, University of Minnesota</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study aims to more accurately assess cardiac function, ventilation and exercise capacity&#xD;
      in a non-invasive fashion, and to better characterize exercise intolerance in the setting of&#xD;
      three populations of individuals with chronic diseases of childhood (acute lymphoblastic&#xD;
      leukemia (ALL), chronic lung disease (CLD) of prematurity, and post-heart transplant (HT))&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Physical activity in childhood is an integral part of maintaining health and quality of life.&#xD;
      Children who participate in routine physical activity are more likely to maintain a healthy&#xD;
      body weight and are less likely to have heart disease, type 2 diabetes and high blood&#xD;
      pressure as adults. Children with chronic disease are often limited from full participation&#xD;
      in exercise for various reasons -perceived physical limitations, either from the patient and&#xD;
      family or from their medical provider, or because of symptoms which cause exercise to feel&#xD;
      uncomfortable. As the number of children living and aging with chronic disease continues to&#xD;
      grow, the researchers are hoping to expand the current exercise testing capabilities for both&#xD;
      clinical care and research in order to (i) provide data to permit formulation of&#xD;
      evidence-based guidelines for exercise in chronic childhood disease; (ii) improve&#xD;
      understanding of limitations to exercise in this growing population; (iii) learn long-term&#xD;
      implications of chronic childhood disease as these individuals enter adulthood.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Peak O2 intake during test exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>3-4 hours during the onetime study visit day</time_frame>
    <description>Maximal cardiopulmonary exercise testing (CPX) will be completed on cycle ergometer to determine peak oxygen uptake, a measure of cardiorespiratory fitness</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure of Cardiac output during test exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>3-4 hours during the onetime study visit day</time_frame>
    <description>Cardiac output is measured using C2H2 open-circuit breathing technique: a mass spectrometer medical gas analyzer will measure gas concentration continuously, yielding serial Stroke Volume measurements during incremental exercise. Cardiac output is the product of heart rate and stroke volume</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of expiratory flow limitation (EFL)</measure>
    <time_frame>3-4 hours during the onetime study visit day</time_frame>
    <description>The proportion of expiratory flow limitation (EFL) during exercise while tracking dyspnea and perceived exertion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Association between cardiac function and patient reported outcomes of perceived fitness</measure>
    <time_frame>3-4 hours during the onetime study visit day</time_frame>
    <description>Logistic regression will be used to understand associations between cardiac function and patient reported outcomes of perceived fitness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">90</enrollment>
  <condition>Chronic Lung Disease</condition>
  <condition>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease</condition>
  <condition>Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</condition>
  <condition>Heart Transplant</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Case</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adolescent or young adult acute lymphoblastic leukemia survivor, OR living with chronic lung disease of prematurity, OR living with heart transplant</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>14-25 years old healthy individuals who are ambulatory without assistance. We may enroll younger subjects but we wish to subjects to match our patient population</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical activity</intervention_name>
    <description>Participant Reported Physical Activity and Outcomes (completed via REDCap or on paper)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Case</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples Without DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood sample specimens will be saved for future use investigating biomarkers and/or Blood&#xD;
      will be drawn from each participant and then separated and frozen as serum and mononuclear&#xD;
      cells. Samples will be stored in the Department of Pediatrics freezers on the University of&#xD;
      Minnesota Twin Cities campuses. All samples will be labeled with a unique participant ID&#xD;
      number and no personal or identifiable data. Samples will be maintained for up to 5 years.&#xD;
      Planned analysis include biomarker assessments. Samples will only be accessible to&#xD;
      individuals listed on the IRB approval for this study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The case participants are the ALL survivors, CLD due to prematurity patients, and post-HT&#xD;
        recipients. The control participants can be medical students, UMN staff's children,&#xD;
        UMN/Fairview staff, medical residents and undergraduate or graduate students. The remaining&#xD;
        controls will be from other UMMCH clinics with conditions unlikely to impact exercise&#xD;
        capacity such as dermatology, orthopedics or sports medicine and the University Children's&#xD;
        Clinic. Approval will be granted from the treating physician before approaching the control&#xD;
        participants&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Acute lymphoblastic leukemia survivor, OR living with chronic lung disease of&#xD;
                  prematurity, OR living with heart transplant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  8-25 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Height: ≥ 48 inches&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ambulatory without assistance&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Normotensive (&lt;95th percentile for age; okay if managed with antihypertensive&#xD;
                  medication)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SpO2 &gt;92%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALL survivor specific: must have completed therapy ≥ 3 months prior to study&#xD;
                  entry&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Controls&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  8-25 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Height: ≥ 48 inches&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Ambulatory without assistance&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  English speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No history of arrhythmia or known cardiac dysfunction at baseline&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Normotensive (&lt;95th percentile for age; okay if managed with antihypertensive&#xD;
                  medication)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  SpO2 &gt;95%&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not pregnant&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cases:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  ALL specific: received cranial radiation, bone marrow transplant recipients&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Investigator or patient's primary physician deems the patient unsuitable for the&#xD;
                  study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Controls:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  History of malignancy, CLD or HT or any other diagnosis which may reduce&#xD;
                  cardiorespiratory function&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Investigator deems the patient unsuitable for the study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>8 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>25 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pianosi Paolo, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Masonic Children's Hospital, University of Minnesota</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Char Napurski, MPH, CCRP</last_name>
    <phone>612-626-2140</phone>
    <email>bake0257@umn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pianosi Paolo, MD</last_name>
    <email>ppianosi@umn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 15, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Quality of life</keyword>
  <keyword>Lung function</keyword>
  <keyword>Fitness</keyword>
  <keyword>Exercise</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Leukemia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Precursor Cell Lymphoblastic Leukemia-Lymphoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Lung Diseases, Obstructive</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Disease, Chronic Obstructive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

