<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05023863</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PHLCLINICAL</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05023863</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Alpha Lipoic Acid on the Incidence and Severity of Radiotherapy-Induced Oral Mucositis in Head and Neck Cancer Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Alpha Lipoic Acid on the Incidence and Severity of Radiotherapy-Induced Oral Mucositis in Head and Neck Cancer Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ain Shams University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ain Shams University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      A prospective, randomized, controlled, single-blinded study will be conducted at Clinical&#xD;
      Oncology department, Ain Shams University Hospitals, assessing the effect of Alpha Lipoic&#xD;
      Acid on the incidence and severity of radiotherapy induced oral mucositis in Head and Neck&#xD;
      cancer patients.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      All patients presenting to the Clinical Oncology department, Ain Shams University Hospitals,&#xD;
      will be assessed for eligibility as follow:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Age &gt;18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diagnosis of stage I, II, III or IV squamous cell carcinoma, nasopharyngeal carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Measurable disease on CT scan at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Planned to receive radiotherapy with a total dose 60 grays or more divided on 30&#xD;
           fractions with or without cisplatin (100 mg/m2, administered intravenously every 21 days&#xD;
           for three cycles or 40 mg/m2 administered weekly for up to 7 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adequate liver function (liver transaminases level &lt; 3 times upper normal limits and&#xD;
           total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times upper normal limits).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adequate kidney function (estimated glomerular filtration rate &gt;60 ml/min).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Adequate bone marrow function (WBCs count &gt; 3000 cells/mm3, ANC count &gt;1500 cells/mm3&#xD;
           and platelets count &gt; 100,000 cells/mm3).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be excluded if they have any of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Diagnosis of Thyroid cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Presence of other primary cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Treatment with alpha lipoic acid for any other indication.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Allergy to alpha lipoic acid.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Pregnant or lactating women. Eligible patients will be randomized to either… Alpha&#xD;
           Lipoic Acid Group (intervention group): 35 patients will receive radiation therapy with&#xD;
           or without platinum-based chemotherapy in addition to alpha lipoic acid 600 mg tablets&#xD;
           twice daily (throughout the radiotherapy period). The medication will be brought from&#xD;
           EVA company ( an Egyptian drug company ) under the trade name of thiotacid 600 mg&#xD;
           tablets.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Control Group: 35 Patients will receive radiation therapy with or without platinum-based&#xD;
      chemotherapy plus placebo tablets of thiotacid throughout the radiation period&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients will be followed up weekly to assess the incidence and severity of radiation&#xD;
      induced oral mucositis using the radiotherapy oncology group criteria also blood samples will&#xD;
      be drawn at baseline , after three weeks (middle of radiation period) at the end of radiation&#xD;
      period to asses changes in CRP and TAC levels&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A prospective, randomized, controlled, single blinded study</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and severity of radiation induced oral mucositis</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>The patients will be followed up during the whole period of radiation and up to six weeks after radiation to evaluate the incidence and severity of radiation induced mucositis. Severity will be assessed by the oncologist using radiotherapy oncology group criteria (RTOG criteria)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to develop grade III or IV radiation induced oral mucositis:</measure>
    <time_frame>4 months</time_frame>
    <description>For each patient, the time from the start of radiotherapy till the development of grade III or IV RIOM will be recorded.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">70</enrollment>
  <condition>Radiation-Induced Mucositis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Alpha Lipoic Acid Group (intervention group)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>35 patients will receive radiation therapy with or without platinum-based chemotherapy in addition to alpha lipoic acid 600 mg tablets twice daily (throughout the radiotherapy period). .</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>35 Patients will receive radiation therapy with or without platinum-based chemotherapy in addition to placebo tablets twice daily (throughout the radiotherapy period)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alpha Lipoic Acid 600 MG Oral Tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>Alpha Lipoic Acid (ALA) is a drug which has been used in treatment of diabetic neuropathy . It act through enhancing nitric oxide-mediated endothelium-dependent vasodilation, thus improving microcirculation in patients with diabetic polyneuropathy. It is considered a safe drug, generally with a daily dose of 200 to 2400 mg/day is considered tolerable without significant side effects. Only gastrointestinal tracts side effects like nausea, vomiting, dyspepsia and abdominal pain have been described in some clinical trials. Also FDA experts confirm its safety and efficacy in humans</description>
    <arm_group_label>Alpha Lipoic Acid Group (intervention group)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo tablets</intervention_name>
    <description>placebo tablets of the same generic of active drug which contain all the same ingredients as active tablets except alpha lipoic acid</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Radiation</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>radiation or concurrent chemoradiation</intervention_name>
    <description>radiation or concurrent radiotherapy plus platinum-based chemotherapy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Alpha Lipoic Acid Group (intervention group)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  • Age &gt;18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diagnosis of stage I, II, III or IV squamous cell carcinoma, nasopharyngeal&#xD;
                  carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Measurable disease on CT scan at baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Planned to receive radiotherapy with a total dose 60 grays or more divided on 30&#xD;
                  fractions with or without cisplatin (100 mg/m2, administered intravenously every&#xD;
                  21 days for three cycles or 40 mg/m2 administered weekly for up to 7 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate liver function (liver transaminases level &lt; 3 times upper normal limits&#xD;
                  and total bilirubin &lt; 1.5 times upper normal limits).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate kidney function (estimated glomerular filtration rate &gt;60 ml/min).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Adequate bone marrow function (WBCs count &gt; 3000 cells/mm3, ANC count &gt;1500&#xD;
                  cells/mm3 and platelets count &gt; 100,000 cells/mm3).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ● Diagnosis of Thyroid cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Presence of other primary cancers.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Treatment with alpha lipoic acid for any other indication.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Allergy to alpha lipoic acid.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Pregnant or lactating women.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Bishoy Anwar Rizk-Allah, bachelor</last_name>
    <phone>01228016836</phone>
    <email>bishoyanwar.rezk@pharma.asu.edu.eg</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ain Shams University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Al Abdan M. Alfa-lipoic acid controls tumor growth and modulates hepatic redox state in Ehrlich-ascites-carcinoma-bearing mice. ScientificWorldJournal. 2012;2012:509838. Epub 2012 May 1.</citation>
    <PMID>23002387</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bloomer WD, Hellman S. Normal tissue responses to radiation therapy. N Engl J Med. 1975 Jul 10;293(2):80-3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>1093032</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eisenhauer EA, Therasse P, Bogaerts J, Schwartz LH, Sargent D, Ford R, Dancey J, Arbuck S, Gwyther S, Mooney M, Rubinstein L, Shankar L, Dodd L, Kaplan R, Lacombe D, Verweij J. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur J Cancer. 2009 Jan;45(2):228-47. doi: 10.1016/j.ejca.2008.10.026.</citation>
    <PMID>19097774</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Elsabagh HH, Moussa E, Mahmoud SA, Elsaka RO, Abdelrahman H. Efficacy of Melatonin in prevention of radiation-induced oral mucositis: A randomized clinical trial. Oral Dis. 2020 Apr;26(3):566-572. doi: 10.1111/odi.13265. Epub 2020 Jan 15.</citation>
    <PMID>31869853</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gillison ML. Human papillomavirus-related diseases: oropharynx cancers and potential implications for adolescent HPV vaccination. J Adolesc Health. 2008 Oct;43(4 Suppl):S52-60. doi: 10.1016/j.jadohealth.2008.07.002. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18809146</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Jung JH, Jung J, Kim SK, Woo SH, Kang KM, Jeong BK, Jung MH, Kim JH, Hahm JR. Alpha lipoic acid attenuates radiation-induced thyroid injury in rats. PLoS One. 2014 Nov 17;9(11):e112253. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0112253. eCollection 2014. Erratum in: PLoS One. 2015;10(6):e0131147.</citation>
    <PMID>25401725</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim H, Yoo WS, Jung JH, Jeong BK, Woo SH, Kim JH, Kim SJ. Alpha-Lipoic Acid Ameliorates Radiation-Induced Lacrimal Gland Injury through NFAT5-Dependent Signaling. Int J Mol Sci. 2019 Nov 13;20(22). pii: E5691. doi: 10.3390/ijms20225691.</citation>
    <PMID>31766286</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kim JH, Jeong BK, Jang SJ, Yun JW, Jung MH, Kang KM, Kim TG, Woo SH. Alpha-Lipoic Acid Ameliorates Radiation-Induced Salivary Gland Injury by Preserving Parasympathetic Innervation in Rats. Int J Mol Sci. 2020 Mar 25;21(7). pii: E2260. doi: 10.3390/ijms21072260.</citation>
    <PMID>32218158</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kusiak A, Jereczek-Fossa BA, Cichońska D, Alterio D. Oncological-Therapy Related Oral Mucositis as an Interdisciplinary Problem-Literature Review. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2020 Apr 3;17(7). pii: E2464. doi: 10.3390/ijerph17072464. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32260309</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Logan RM, Stringer AM, Bowen JM, Gibson RJ, Sonis ST, Keefe DM. Serum levels of NFkappaB and pro-inflammatory cytokines following administration of mucotoxic drugs. Cancer Biol Ther. 2008 Jul;7(7):1139-45. Epub 2008 Apr 29.</citation>
    <PMID>18535404</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lott IT, Doran E, Nguyen VQ, Tournay A, Head E, Gillen DL. Down syndrome and dementia: a randomized, controlled trial of antioxidant supplementation. Am J Med Genet A. 2011 Aug;155A(8):1939-48. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.34114. Epub 2011 Jul 7.</citation>
    <PMID>21739598</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Mallick S, Benson R, Rath GK. Radiation induced oral mucositis: a review of current literature on prevention and management. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2016 Sep;273(9):2285-93. doi: 10.1007/s00405-015-3694-6. Epub 2015 Jun 27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26116012</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Marur S, Forastiere AA. Head and Neck Squamous Cell Carcinoma: Update on Epidemiology, Diagnosis, and Treatment. Mayo Clin Proc. 2016 Mar;91(3):386-96. doi: 10.1016/j.mayocp.2015.12.017. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26944243</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Moreira PI, Harris PL, Zhu X, Santos MS, Oliveira CR, Smith MA, Perry G. Lipoic acid and N-acetyl cysteine decrease mitochondrial-related oxidative stress in Alzheimer disease patient fibroblasts. J Alzheimers Dis. 2007 Sep;12(2):195-206. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>17917164</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pearman TP, Beaumont JL, Paul D, Abernethy AP, Jacobsen PB, Syrjala KL, Von Roenn J, Cella D. Evaluation of treatment- and disease-related symptoms in advanced head and neck cancer: validation of the national comprehensive cancer network-functional assessment of cancer therapy-head and neck cancer symptom index-22 (NFHNSI-22). J Pain Symptom Manage. 2013 Jul;46(1):113-20. doi: 10.1016/j.jpainsymman.2012.06.004. Epub 2012 Sep 25.</citation>
    <PMID>23017622</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reljanovic M, Reichel G, Rett K, Lobisch M, Schuette K, Möller W, Tritschler HJ, Mehnert H. Treatment of diabetic polyneuropathy with the antioxidant thioctic acid (alpha-lipoic acid): a two year multicenter randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial (ALADIN II). Alpha Lipoic Acid in Diabetic Neuropathy. Free Radic Res. 1999 Sep;31(3):171-9.</citation>
    <PMID>10499773</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sayed R, El Wakeel L, Saad AS, Kelany M, El-Hamamsy M. Pentoxifylline and vitamin E reduce the severity of radiotherapy-induced oral mucositis and dysphagia in head and neck cancer patients: a randomized, controlled study. Med Oncol. 2019 Nov 21;37(1):8. doi: 10.1007/s12032-019-1334-5.</citation>
    <PMID>31748905</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Siddiqui F, Movsas B. Management of Radiation Toxicity in Head and Neck Cancers. Semin Radiat Oncol. 2017 Oct;27(4):340-349. doi: 10.1016/j.semradonc.2017.04.008. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28865517</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sonis ST. Pathobiology of oral mucositis: novel insights and opportunities. J Support Oncol. 2007 Oct;5(9 Suppl 4):3-11. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>18046993</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ziegler D, Nowak H, Kempler P, Vargha P, Low PA. Treatment of symptomatic diabetic polyneuropathy with the antioxidant alpha-lipoic acid: a meta-analysis. Diabet Med. 2004 Feb;21(2):114-21.</citation>
    <PMID>14984445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ain Shams University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Bishoy Anwar</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>principal investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Head and Neck cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Alpha Lipoic Acid</keyword>
  <keyword>Mucositis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Head and Neck Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mucositis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Thioctic Acid</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

