<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05023525</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HSK31858-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05023525</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Single Ascending Dosed of HSK31858 in Healthy Volunteers</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Double-blind, Placebo-controlled Study of the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Single Ascending Dosed of HSK31858 in Healthy Volunteers</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Haisco Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Haisco Pharmaceutical(Australia) Pty Ltd.</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Haisco Pharmaceutical Group Co., Ltd.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase I, single-dose escalation clinical trial for HSK31858 conducted in healthy&#xD;
      volunteers. The safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics of HSK31858 tablet in healthy&#xD;
      volunteers will be evaluated using a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial&#xD;
      design.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 28, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The number and severity of treatment emergent adverse events (TEAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after dosing</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the safety and tolerability of single oral dose of HSK31858 in healthy adult volunteers</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cmax</measure>
    <time_frame>within 15 minutes before administration until 72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Maximum concentration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Tmax</measure>
    <time_frame>within 15 minutes before administration until 72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Time to maximum concentration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>AUC0-last</measure>
    <time_frame>within 15 minutes before administration until until 72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Area under the drug concentration-time curve, from time 0h to 72h</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>t½</measure>
    <time_frame>within 15 minutes before administration until 72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent terminal half-life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>CL/F</measure>
    <time_frame>within 15 minutes before administration until 72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent total clearance of drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Vd/F</measure>
    <time_frame>within 15 minutes before administration until 72 hours after administration</time_frame>
    <description>Apparent volume of distribution after oral administration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>HSK31858, single dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>5 cohorts with single doses starting with 5 mg HSK31858 as tablet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebe, single dose</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>5 cohorts with matching placebo to HSK31858 as tablet.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>HSK31858, tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>Starting dose in single ascending dose: 5 mg</description>
    <arm_group_label>HSK31858, single dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo, tablet</intervention_name>
    <description>Matching placebo</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebe, single dose</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Must have given written informed consent before any study-related activities are&#xD;
             carried out and must be able to understand the full nature and purpose of the trial,&#xD;
             including possible risks and adverse effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Adult males and females, 18 to 55 years of age (inclusive) at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Body mass index ≥ 18.0 and ≤ 30.0 kg/m2, with a body weight ≥ 50 kg at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Be nonsmokers (including tobacco, e-cigarettes, and marijuana) for at least 1 month&#xD;
             prior to first study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Medically healthy without clinically significant abnormalities at Screening and&#xD;
             predose on Day 1, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Physical examination without any clinically relevant findings.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Systolic blood pressure in the range of 90 to 140 mmHg and diastolic blood&#xD;
                  pressure in the range of 50 to 90 mmHg after 5 minutes in supine position.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Heart rate in the range of 50 to 100 bpm after 5 minutes rest in supine position.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Body temperature, between 35.0°C and 37.7°C.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. No clinically significant findings in serum chemistry, hematology, coagulation,&#xD;
                  and urinalysis tests as deemed by the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Conventional 12-lead ECG recording in triplicate (the mean of triplicate measurements&#xD;
             will be used to determine eligibility at Screening and predose on Day 1) consistent&#xD;
             with normal cardiac conduction and function, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Normal sinus rhythm with HR between 50 and 100 bpm, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QT interval corrected using the Fridericia method (QTcF) between 350 to 450 msec&#xD;
                  for male subjects and 350 to 470 msec for female subjects, inclusive.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  QRS duration of &lt; 120 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  PR interval of ≤ 210 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Electrocardiogram morphology consistent with healthy cardiac ventricular&#xD;
                  conduction and normal rhythm, and with measurement of the QT interval.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No family history of short or long QT syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  No history of risk factors for torsade de pointes or the diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Women of childbearing potential must be non-pregnant and non-lactating, and must use&#xD;
             an acceptable, highly effective double contraception from Screening until at least 30&#xD;
             days after last dose, including the Follow-up period. Double contraception is defined&#xD;
             as a condom AND one other form of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Established hormonal contraception (OCPs, long-acting implantable hormones,&#xD;
                  injectable hormones).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A vaginal ring or an IUD.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Documented evidence of surgical sterilization at least 6 months prior to&#xD;
                  Screening (e.g., tubal occlusion, hysterectomy, bilateral salpingectomy, or&#xD;
                  bilateral oophorectomy for women or vasectomy for men [with appropriate&#xD;
                  post-vasectomy documentation of the absence of sperm in semen] provided the male&#xD;
                  partner is a sole partner).&#xD;
&#xD;
             Women not of childbearing potential must be postmenopausal for ≥12 months.&#xD;
             Postmenopausal status will be confirmed through testing of follicle-stimulating&#xD;
             hormone (FSH) levels ≥ 40 IU/L at Screening for amenorrhoeic female subjects. Females&#xD;
             who are abstinent from heterosexual intercourse will also be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Periodic abstinence (e.g., calendar, ovulation, symptothermal, post-ovulation methods)&#xD;
             and withdrawal are not considered highly effective methods of birth control. Subject&#xD;
             complete abstinence for the duration of the study and for 1 month after the last study&#xD;
             treatment is acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
             Female subjects who are in same sex relationships are not required to use&#xD;
             contraception.&#xD;
&#xD;
             WOCBP must have a negative pregnancy test at Screening and Day 1 and be willing to&#xD;
             have additional pregnancy tests as required throughout the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Male subjects must be surgically sterile (&gt; 30 days since vasectomy with no viable&#xD;
             sperm), abstinent, or if engaged in sexual relations with a WOCBP, the subject and his&#xD;
             partner must be surgically sterile (e.g., tubal occlusion, hysterectomy, bilateral&#xD;
             salpingectomy, bilateral oophorectomy) or using an acceptable, highly effective&#xD;
             contraceptive method from Screening until study completion, including the Follow-up&#xD;
             period. Acceptable methods of contraception include the use of condoms and the use of&#xD;
             an effective contraceptive for the female partner that includes: OCPs, long-acting&#xD;
             implantable hormones, injectable hormones, a vaginal ring, or an IUD. Subjects with&#xD;
             same sex partners (abstinence from penile-vaginal intercourse) are eligible when this&#xD;
             is their preferred and usual lifestyle. Males must not donate sperm for at least 90&#xD;
             Days after the last dose of study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Have suitable venous access for blood sampling.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Be willing and able to comply with all study assessments and adhere to the protocol&#xD;
             schedule and restrictions.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects must have no relevant dietary restrictions and be willing to consume standard&#xD;
             meals provided during the confinement period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History or presence of significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal,&#xD;
             hematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, immunologic, dermatologic or neurological&#xD;
             disease, including any acute illness or surgery within the past 3 months determined by&#xD;
             the PI to be clinically relevant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. A primary diagnosis of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease or asthma as deemed by&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subjects has increased risk of infection:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. History and/or presence of tuberculosis (TB).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Body temperature of &gt; 37.7℃.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Blood neutrophil count &lt;1.7 × 109/L, or white blood cell count &lt; 4.0×109/L&#xD;
                  (Screening and Day -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Is in high risk-group (i.e., men who have had unprotected sex with men, women who&#xD;
                  have had sex without a condom with men who have sex with men, people who have had&#xD;
                  sex without a condom with a person who has lived or travelled in Africa, people&#xD;
                  who inject drugs, people who have had sex without a condom with somebody who has&#xD;
                  injected drugs, people who have caught another sexually transmitted infection,&#xD;
                  people who have received a blood transfusion while in Africa, eastern Europe, the&#xD;
                  countries of the former Soviet Union, Asia or central and southern America) for&#xD;
                  human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection within the last 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Other latent or chronic infections (e.g., recurrent sinusitis, genital or ocular&#xD;
                  herpes, urinary tract infection) or at risk of infection (surgery, trauma, or&#xD;
                  significant infection) within 3 months of Screening, or history of skin abscesses&#xD;
                  within 3 months of Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
               6. Clinically significant lower respiratory tract infection not resolved within&#xD;
                  4weeks prior to Screening, as determined by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
               7. Volunteers with active malignancy or neoplastic disease in the previous 5 years&#xD;
                  other than superficial basal cell carcinoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
               8. Disease history suggesting abnormal immune function or use of or plans to use&#xD;
                  systemic immunosuppressive (e.g., corticosteroids, methotrexate, azathioprine,&#xD;
                  cyclosporine) or immunomodulating medications (e.g., interferon) during the study&#xD;
                  or within 4 months prior to the first study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
               9. Volunteers who have received live or live-attenuated vaccine in the 4 weeks prior&#xD;
                  to dosing.&#xD;
&#xD;
              10. High-sensitivity C-reactive protein &gt; upper limit of normal (ULN) at Screening&#xD;
                  and on Day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Some subjects lacking functional Dipeptidyl peptidase 1 (DPP1) enzyme have been&#xD;
             described to have periodontitis and palmoplantar hyperkeratosis:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Subjects with signs of current gingivitis/periodontitis. Gingival evaluation (by&#xD;
                  inspection) will be performed by a dental hygienist or trained study physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Subjects with a history of hyperkeratosis or erythema in palms or soles.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Liver function test results (i.e., aspartate aminotransferase [AST], alanine&#xD;
             aminotransferase [ALT], and gamma glutamyl transferase [GGT]) and total bilirubin&#xD;
             elevated more than 1.2 fold above the ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Positive test results for active HIV, hepatitis B surface antigen (HBsAg) or hepatitis&#xD;
             C virus (HCV) antibodies (Abs).&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Presence or having sequelae of gastrointestinal, liver, kidney, or other conditions&#xD;
             known to interfere with the absorption, distribution, metabolism, or excretion of&#xD;
             drugs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Estimated creatinine clearance (CrCl) &lt; 60 mL/min using the Cockcroft-Gault formula or&#xD;
             serum creatinine more than 1.5-fold above the ULN.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of alcohol abuse within 12 months prior to first study drug administration or&#xD;
             positive alcohol breath test. Regular alcohol consumption defined as &gt; 21 alcohol&#xD;
             units per week (where 1 unit = 284 mL of beer, 25 mL of 40% spirit or a 125 mL glass&#xD;
             of wine). Subject is unwilling to abstain from alcohol beginning 48 hours prior to&#xD;
             admission to the CRU and during the confinement period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of substance abuse within 12 months prior to first study drug administration&#xD;
             or positive drug test results. Subjects with a positive toxicology Screening panel&#xD;
             (urine test including qualitative identification of barbiturates, THC, amphetamines,&#xD;
             benzodiazepines, opiates, and cocaine).&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Use of any prescription or over-the-counter medication (including herbal products,&#xD;
             diet aids, and hormone supplements) within 14 days or 5 half-lives of the medication&#xD;
             (whichever is longer) prior to the first study drug administration, except occasional&#xD;
             use of paracetamol. Use of any IP or investigational medical device within 30 days&#xD;
             prior to Screening, or 5 half-lives of the product (whichever is the longest).&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Demonstrated clinically significant (required intervention e.g., emergency room visit,&#xD;
             epinephrine administration) allergic reactions (e.g., food, drug, or atopic reactions,&#xD;
             asthmatic episodes) which, in the opinion of the Investigator, would interfere with&#xD;
             the volunteer's ability to participate in the trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Known hypersensitivity to any of the study drug ingredients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. For women of childbearing potential, a positive serum pregnancy test at Screening or a&#xD;
             positive urine pregnancy test with confirmatory serum pregnancy test on Day -1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Donation of blood or plasma within 30 days prior to first study drug administration,&#xD;
             or loss of whole blood of more than 500 mL within 30 days prior to randomization, or&#xD;
             receipt of a blood transfusion within 1 year of first study drug administration.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Participation in another investigational clinical trial within 60 days prior to the&#xD;
             first study drug administration and participation in more than 4 investigational drug&#xD;
             studies within 1 year prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any other condition or prior therapy that in the opinion of the PI would make the&#xD;
             volunteer unsuitable for this study, including inability to cooperate fully with the&#xD;
             requirements of the study protocol or likelihood of noncompliance with any study&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Is an employee of an Investigator or Sponsor or an immediate relative of an&#xD;
             Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Pregnant or lactating at Screening or planning to become pregnant (self or partner) at&#xD;
             any time during the study, including the Follow-up period.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. History of life-threatening infection (e.g., meningitis).&#xD;
&#xD;
         21. Infections requiring parenteral antibiotics within the 6 months prior to Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
         22. Healthy volunteers with tattoos.&#xD;
&#xD;
         23. Use of any IP or investigational medical device within 30 days prior to Screening, or&#xD;
             5 half-lives of the product (whichever is the longest) or participation in more than 4&#xD;
             investigational drug studies within 1 year prior to Screening.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ofer Gonen</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Nucleus Network Pty Ltd</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Yan Liu</last_name>
    <phone>+86 18782948571</phone>
    <email>liuyanlc@haisco.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Xu Wang</last_name>
    <phone>+86 13671811021</phone>
    <email>wangxu1@haisco.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Nucleus Network Pty Ltd</name>
      <address>
        <city>Melbourne</city>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ofer Gonen</last_name>
      <phone>0390768960</phone>
      <email>o.gonen@nucleusnetwork.com.au</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ofer Gonen</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 16, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HSK31858</keyword>
  <keyword>NCFBE</keyword>
  <keyword>health</keyword>
  <keyword>phase I</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

