<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05028075</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>848844</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05028075</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Health Care Workers and Mental Health</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluating the Effectiveness of an Enhanced Digital Mental Health Care Delivery System</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Pennsylvania</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Pennsylvania</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this proposal is to deploy digital health interventions to bring timely,&#xD;
      easily accessible resources and care to address the mental health and well-being needs of&#xD;
      HCWs with direct patient care that are experiencing the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic and&#xD;
      its economic, financial, and social sequelae at present and presumably for years to come.&#xD;
      This proposal will evaluate the effectiveness of an enhanced digital mental health care&#xD;
      delivery system (Cobalt), any differential effect by race and gender and, through qualitative&#xD;
      interviews, how those interventions are perceived.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Factorial Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Depressive symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Patient health questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9) (Kroenke, Spitzer, &amp; Williams, 2001) is a multipurpose instrument for screening, diagnosing, monitoring and measuring the severity of depression. The PHQ-9 incorporates DSM-IV depression diagnostic criteria with other leading major depressive symptoms into a brief self-report tool. PHQ-9 is brief and useful in clinical practice. The PHQ-9 is completed by the patient in minutes and is rapidly scored by the clinician. The PHQ-9 is a freely available mood-rating questionnaire consisting of nine questions mirroring DSM-IV depression diagnostic criteria. The PHQ-9 has shown diagnostic validity in a study of 3,000 adult patients. Each item is rated on a scale of 0 to 3, giving a maximum score of 24. Cut-off scores are used to label depression severity as: 0 to 4, minimal depression; 5 to 9, mild depression; 10 to 14, moderate depression; 15 to 19, moderately severe depression; 20 to 24, severe depression.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>GAD-7 is a 7-item anxiety scale. It has good reliability, as well as criterion, construct, factorial, and procedural validity. Each item is rated according to the frequency of the described problem. The responses are scored as follows: 0 = not at all, 1 = several days, 2 = more than half the days, 3 = nearly every day with a maximum score of 21 Scores are interpreted as 5 to 9, mild anxiety; 10 to 14, moderate anxiety; and 15 and above, severe anxiety. The GAD-7 showed good reliability and criterion, construct, factorial, and procedural validity in a study carried out in 15 primary care clinics. The GAD-7 is a valid and efficient tool for screening for GAD and assessing its severity in clinical practice and research.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Well-being</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Well-being index (WBI) is a nine-question survey validated for use in Health Care Worker populations and considered important to health systems in managing the well-being of their workforce.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Work productivity</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate work productivity, we will use the World Health Organization Health and Work Performance Questionnaire (HPQ) short form. The HPQ is a validated self-report instrument designed to estimate the workplace costs of health problems with regard to reduced job performance, absence due to sickness, and work-related injuries and accidents. We will administer the short form which is an 11-question survey focused on absenteeism and presenteeism.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Satisfaction with care</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months</time_frame>
    <description>Client Satisfaction with Care (CSQ)-8 is a brief 8-item unidimensional well-established scale for assessing patients' satisfaction with overall outpatient health care. It has been shown to be reliable and valid in assessing care across a range of settings</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1250</enrollment>
  <condition>Depressive Symptoms</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <condition>Well-Being</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete baseline surveys at enrollment and then complete subsequent surveys (depression, anxiety, well-being, satisfaction with access to care, work productivity, hours of direct patient care, percent of time providing care for patients with COVID-19) at enrollment; 0 months and then again at 6 months. The primary endpoint is assessed at 6 months. A secondary endpoint of persistence of effect is measured 3 months later-9 months post initiation.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will complete baseline surveys at enrollment and then complete subsequent surveys (depression, anxiety, well-being, satisfaction with access to care, work productivity) at enrollment; 0 months and then again at 6 months. The primary endpoint is assessed at 6 months. A secondary endpoint of persistence of effect is measured 3 months later-9 months post initiation. The intervention group receives usual Cobalt plus: 1) monthly automated text messaging reminders and links to Cobalt resources 2) intermittent mental health assessments which triage individuals to an opt-out appointment based on their results. For the monthly automated text messaging reminders, we will assess how well these are delivered by assessing how often: links are clicked on, text messages receive a response, and participants request to stop receiving texts. For the opt out appointments, we will assess how often appointments are fulfilled or cancelled.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cobalt +</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will complete baseline surveys at enrollment and then complete subsequent surveys (depression, anxiety, well-being, satisfaction with access to care, work productivity) at enrollment; 0 months and then again at 6 months. The primary endpoint is assessed at 6 months. A secondary endpoint of persistence of effect is measured 3 months later-9 months post initiation. The intervention group receives usual Cobalt plus: 1) monthly automated text messaging reminders and links to Cobalt resources 2) intermittent mental health assessments which triage individuals to an opt-out appointment based on their results. For the monthly automated text messaging reminders, we will assess how well these are delivered by assessing how often: links are clicked on, text messages receive a response, and participants request to stop receiving texts. For the opt out appointments, we will assess how often appointments are fulfilled or cancelled.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Regular, daily access to an smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to communicate fluently in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Provide direct patient care at University of Pennsylvania / Penn Medicine. This&#xD;
             includes health care workers like physicians, nurses, certified nursing assistants,&#xD;
             lab technicians, radiology technicians, physical therapist, occupational therapist,&#xD;
             pharmacists, pharmacy technicians, patient registration staff, receptionists/patient&#xD;
             intake coordinators, environmental and food service personnel approximately 4&#xD;
             hours/week. This averages 192 hours/ 48 weeks in a year) in the study time frame.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Not aged 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Does not have regular, daily access to a smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Unable to communicate fluently in English&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Does not provide direct patient care at University of Pennsylvania / Penn Medicine.&#xD;
             This includes health care workers like physicians, nurses, certified nursing&#xD;
             assistants, lab technicians, radiology technicians, physical therapist, occupational&#xD;
             therapist, pharmacists, pharmacy technicians, patient registration staff,&#xD;
             receptionists/patient intake coordinators, environmental and food service personnel&#xD;
             approximately 4 hours/week. This averages 192 hours/ 48 weeks in a year) in the study&#xD;
             time frame.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Not willing to sign the informed consent document&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Lauren Southwick, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>2674280125</phone>
    <email>lauren.southwick@pennmedicine.upenn.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 7, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Depression</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cobalt</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

