<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05028946</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TILS-014</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2021-002698-24</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05028946</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Oral Foralumab in Participants With Moderate to Severely Active Crohn's Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase IB Multiple Ascending Dose Study of Safety and Tolerability of Orally Administered Foralumab, a Fully Human Anti-CD3 Monoclonal Antibody, in Subjects With Moderate to Severely Active Crohn's Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Tiziana Life Sciences, PLC</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Tiziana Life Sciences, PLC</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The primary objective of this study is to establish the safety and tolerability of multiple&#xD;
      ascending doses (MAD) of foralumab enteric coated capsules administered orally, once daily&#xD;
      for 5 days per week over 2 weeks in participants with moderate to severely active Crohn's&#xD;
      Disease (CD).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Four different doses of foralumab enteric coated capsules will be studied for safety and&#xD;
      tolerability in a MAD format. Participants in the sequential MAD cohorts will receive&#xD;
      treatment when the safety data of one cohort are reviewed by the Data Safety Monitoring Board&#xD;
      (DSMB) and are deemed favorable to proceed with the next treatment in the subsequent cohort.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 28, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 7, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 7, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of Participants With Adverse Events (AEs) and Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 up to Day 14</time_frame>
    <description>Adverse events categorized and graded via CTCAE</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change From Baseline in Crohn's Disease Activity Index (CDAI) Score at Day 5 and Day 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline, Day 5 and Day 12</time_frame>
    <description>The CDAI score is used to quantify the symptoms of participants with Crohn's Disease. CDAI scores generally range from 0 to 600 points. A score of 150 or below indicates remission and a score above 450 indicates extremely severe disease. A decrease in CDAI over time indicates improvement in disease activity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>4</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">16</enrollment>
  <condition>Crohn's Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: Foralumab Dose Level 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive foralumab enteric coated capsules at dose level 1, administered orally once daily for 2 weeks (5 consecutive days in each week with a 2-day undosed safety assessment period after each 5 day treatment period).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: Foralumab Dose Level 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive foralumab enteric coated capsules at dose level 2, administered orally once daily for 2 weeks (5 consecutive days in each week with a 2-day undosed safety assessment period after each 5 day treatment period).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: Foralumab Dose Level 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive foralumab enteric coated capsules at dose level 3, administered orally once daily for 2 weeks (5 consecutive days in each week with a 2-day undosed safety assessment period after each 5 day treatment period).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 4: Foralumab Dose Level 4</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will receive foralumab enteric coated capsules at dose level 4, administered orally once daily for 2 weeks (5 consecutive days in each week with a 2-day undosed safety assessment period after each 5 day treatment period).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Foralumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Foralumab will be administered per dose and schedule specified in the arm description.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 1: Foralumab Dose Level 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 2: Foralumab Dose Level 2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 3: Foralumab Dose Level 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort 4: Foralumab Dose Level 4</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Human anti-CD3 monoclonal antibody (mAb)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has been diagnosed with active CD as confirmed by endoscopic examination&#xD;
             with histological confirmation for at least 12 weeks before the screening visit; only&#xD;
             study participant who has endoscopic examination by colonoscopy of disease location&#xD;
             that includes ileocolon and/or colon and who has a Simple Endoscopic Score for Crohn's&#xD;
             Disease (SES-CD) ≥3 will be enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a CDAI ≥220 but ≤450 points (that is, participant has moderate to&#xD;
             severely active disease despite current treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is naïve to anti-CD3 therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-smoker or use of nicotine or other nicotine-containing products (snuff, chewing&#xD;
             tobacco, cigars, pipes, e-cigarettes or nicotine-replacement products such as nicotine&#xD;
             chewing gum and nicotine plasters) will not be allowed from 3 months before the&#xD;
             screening visit until the final follow-up visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant's current regimen of concomitant medication(s) falls within the&#xD;
             definitions provided in the protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant must weigh ≥50 kg at the time of signing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Male or female&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Sexually active male participant must agree to use highly effective contraception&#xD;
                  as detailed in of this protocol during the treatment period and for at least 10&#xD;
                  weeks after the last dose of study medication (or longer if required by local&#xD;
                  approved label).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. A female participant is eligible to participate if she is not pregnant, not&#xD;
                  breastfeeding, and at least one of the following conditions applies:&#xD;
&#xD;
             i) Not a woman of childbearing potential (WOCBP). ii) A WOCBP who agrees to follow the&#xD;
             guidance for highly effective contraception during the treatment period and for at&#xD;
             least 10 weeks after the last dose of study medication (or longer if required by local&#xD;
             approved label).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has symptomatic coronavirus disease of 2019 (COVID-19) or a positive&#xD;
             severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) test result prior to&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a suspected or confirmed diagnosis of ulcerative colitis (UC),&#xD;
             indeterminate colitis, ischemic colitis, radiation colitis, diverticular disease&#xD;
             associated with colitis, or microscopic colitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with any known fistula involving the gastrointestinal (GI) tract (except&#xD;
             for perianal fistula).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with symptomatic stricturing type disease at the time of the screening&#xD;
             visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had an extensive colonic resection, subtotal or total colectomy,&#xD;
             diagnosis of short bowel syndrome or a history of &gt;3 small bowel resections.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a functional colostomy or ileostomy. Exception: A participant who has&#xD;
             had a temporary stoma in the past, which has been reversed, may be enrolled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has had a surgical bowel resection within 6 months before the screening&#xD;
             visit or is planning any resection at a time while enrolled in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with clinical suspicion of intra-abdominal abscess(es). If a participant&#xD;
             receives treatment for the abscess, they may be rescreened.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant currently requires or is anticipated to require surgical intervention for&#xD;
             CD during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a current or recent history (within 6 months before the screening&#xD;
             visit) of clinically relevant renal, hepatic, hematological, GI (other than CD),&#xD;
             endocrine, pulmonary, neurological, or cerebral disease including blood dyscrasia (for&#xD;
             example, pancytopenia, aplastic anemia), demyelinating disease (for example, multiple&#xD;
             sclerosis, myelitis, optic neuritis), or ischemic heart disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has known history of or current clinically active infection with&#xD;
             histoplasma, coccidioides, paracoccidioides, pneumocystis, tuberculous mycobacteria,&#xD;
             nontuberculous mycobacteria, blastomyces, aspergillus, legionella, or listeria.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant with evidence of an acquired or congenital immunodeficiency state,&#xD;
             including, but not limited to, known human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) infection,&#xD;
             agammaglobulinemia, organ transplantation, T cell deficiencies, or human T cell&#xD;
             lymphotropic virus type 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of chronic or recurrent infections (more than 3 episodes&#xD;
             requiring antibiotics/antivirals during the preceding year), recent serious or&#xD;
             life-threatening infection within the 4 weeks prior to the screening visit (including&#xD;
             Herpes zoster), infection requiring intravenous (IV) antibiotic use within the 4 weeks&#xD;
             prior to the screening visit or oral antibiotic use within the 2 weeks prior to the&#xD;
             screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a concurrent malignancy or a history of any malignancy at any time&#xD;
             (including nonmelanoma skin cancer).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has concurrent bowel dysplasia or a history of bowel dysplasia in the 5&#xD;
             years before the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of a lymphoproliferative disorder, including lymphoma, or&#xD;
             signs and symptoms suggestive of lymphoproliferative disease at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a known hypersensitivity to any excipients of the investigational&#xD;
             medicinal product (IMP) or its ingredients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is currently receiving chronic concomitant systemic antibiotic therapy for&#xD;
             diseases other than CD or acne.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant received any live (includes attenuated) vaccination within the 10 weeks&#xD;
             prior to the screening visit or intending to receive during the study (inactivated&#xD;
             vaccinations are permitted at any time prior to and during the study) or within 3&#xD;
             months after last dose of certolizumab pegol (CZP) or foralumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a positive fecal laboratory test result for enteric pathogens and/or&#xD;
             ova and parasites at the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant who has evidence of, or treatment for clostridium difficile infection or&#xD;
             other intestinal pathogen, within 28 days prior to first dose of study medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Venkat Renukuntla</last_name>
    <phone>+1267-810-9994</phone>
    <email>vrenukuntla@tizianalifesciences.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Vaseem Palejwala</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 30, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Anti-CD3 Monoclonal Antibody</keyword>
  <keyword>Inflammatory bowel disease</keyword>
  <keyword>Oral anti-CD3</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Crohn Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Muromonab-CD3</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

