<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05027425</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UCCC-GI-21-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05027425</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Durvalumab (MEDI4736) and Tremelimumab for Hepatocellular Carcinoma in Patients Listed for a Liver Transplant</brief_title>
  <official_title>Durvalumab (MEDI4736) and Tremelimumab for Hepatocellular Carcinoma in Patients Listed for a Liver Transplant</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Davendra Sohal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Cincinnati</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Immunotherapy can safely downstage patients and achieve durable systemic disease control to&#xD;
      improve clinical outcomes in HCC patients undergoing liver transplant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      ESR-20-21010 is a single-arm, open-label, Phase II, multicenter clinical trial designed to&#xD;
      evaluate the safety and efficacy of durvalumab and tremelimumab for the treatment of&#xD;
      hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC) patients who have cirrhosis or portal hypertension and are&#xD;
      listed for a liver transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The key eligibility requirements include HCC within UCSF criteria, Child-Pugh score of up to&#xD;
      7, and ECOG PS of 0 or 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients will be treated with the immunotherapy combination for up to 4 months. After a&#xD;
      minimum 28 day washout, they will undergo locoregional therapy per institutional standards.&#xD;
      Eventually, after a minimum 72-day washout from the end of immunotherapy, they will undergo&#xD;
      liver transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary endpoint is proportion of patients experiencing post-transplant rejection (within&#xD;
      30 days of transplant). A total of 30 patients are to be enrolled, to allow at least 20&#xD;
      transplants for adequate primary endpoint analysis. An interim analysis after 10 patients&#xD;
      will be performed to ensure safety. If there are untoward safety signals, study&#xD;
      modification/discontinuation will be discussed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2030</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2025</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Single-arm, open-label, Phase II, multicenter clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cellular rejection rates</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 30 days post transplant</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the safety of immunotherapy for treatment of HCC in patients listed for a liver transplant, with respect to cellular rejection rates</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse events during treatment, and graft loss and mortality rates</measure>
    <time_frame>Treatment, and up to 30 days post transplant</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the safety of immunotherapy for treatment of HCC in patients listed for a liver transplant, with respect to adverse events during treatment, and graft loss and mortality rates up to 30 days after transplant;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiologic responses via RECIST 1.1 and/or mRECIST</measure>
    <time_frame>Survival follow up will continue for 5 years after end of Treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of immunotherapy for treatment of HCC in patients listed for a liver transplant, with respect to radiologic responses</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Pathologic responses via explanted liver assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>Survival follow up will continue for 5 years after end of Treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of immunotherapy for treatment of HCC in patients listed for a liver transplant, with respect to Pathologic responses</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence-free survival and overall survival outcomes based on survival follow up reporting</measure>
    <time_frame>Survival follow up will continue for 5 years after end of Treatment</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the efficacy of immunotherapy for treatment of HCC in patients listed for a liver transplant, with respect to Survival outcomes</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Hepatocellular Carcinoma</condition>
  <condition>Cirrhosis</condition>
  <condition>Portal Hypertension</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Durvalumab + Tremelimumab + Liver Transplant</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will be treated with the immunotherapy combination for up to 4 months. After a minimum 28 day washout, they will undergo locoregional therapy per institutional standards. Eventually, after a minimum 72-day washout from the end of immunotherapy, they will undergo liver transplant.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Durvalumab</intervention_name>
    <description>1500 mg IV, Q4W</description>
    <arm_group_label>Durvalumab + Tremelimumab + Liver Transplant</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>MEDI4736</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tremelimumab</intervention_name>
    <description>300 mg IV, 1 dose on day 1 of only the first cycle</description>
    <arm_group_label>Durvalumab + Tremelimumab + Liver Transplant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Liver Transplant</intervention_name>
    <description>minimum 72-day washout from the end of immunotherapy, patients will undergo liver transplant.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Durvalumab + Tremelimumab + Liver Transplant</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Hepatocellular carcinoma, diagnosed either by biopsy or by combination of cirrhosis&#xD;
             and imaging criteria (contrast-enhanced CT or MRI).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Tumor within UCSF criteria for transplant: either one lesion ≤6.5 cm; or up to 3&#xD;
             lesions, none &gt;4.5 cm, with a total diameter ≤8 cm, with no vascular invasion and no&#xD;
             evidence of extrahepatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patient evaluated by institutional Liver Transplant team and listed for transplant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At least 1 lesion, not previously irradiated, that qualifies as a RECIST 1.1 target&#xD;
             lesion (TL) at baseline. Tumor assessment by computed tomography (CT) scan or magnetic&#xD;
             resonance imaging (MRI) must be performed within 28 days prior to randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. No prior therapy for HCC at any time.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Age ≥18 years at the time of study entry.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. ECOG score of 0 or 1&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Child-Pugh Score of 5, 6, or 7&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Body weight &gt;30 kg&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Patients must have adequate organ and marrow function as defined in protocol&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Capable of giving signed informed consent which includes compliance with the&#xD;
             requirements and restrictions listed in the informed consent form (ICF) and in this&#xD;
             protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Patient is willing and able to comply with the protocol for the duration of the study&#xD;
             including undergoing treatment and scheduled visits and examinations including follow&#xD;
             up.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Extrahepatic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Variceal bleeding during 3 months prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any autoimmune disease deemed a risk in the setting of immunotherapy per treating&#xD;
             physician's judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Any other illness or patient condition deemed a medical or logistical barrier for&#xD;
             protocol therapy per treating physician's judgment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Concurrent enrollment in another clinical study, unless it is an observational&#xD;
             (non-interventional) clinical study or during the follow-up period of an&#xD;
             interventional study&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Participation in another clinical study with an investigational product during the&#xD;
             last 12 months Patients who have received other investigational agents previously who&#xD;
             are no longer receiving these investigational agents may be eligible at the discretion&#xD;
             of the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Major surgical procedure (as defined by the Investigator) within 28 days prior to the&#xD;
             first dose of IP. Note: Local surgery of isolated lesions for palliative intent is&#xD;
             acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. History of allogenic organ transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of another primary malignancy except for:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Malignancy treated with curative intent and with no known active disease ≥5 years&#xD;
                  before the first dose of IP and of low potential risk for recurrence&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Adequately treated non-melanoma skin cancer or lentigo maligna without evidence&#xD;
                  of disease&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Adequately treated carcinoma in situ without evidence of disease&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Active or prior documented autoimmune or inflammatory disorders (including&#xD;
             inflammatory bowel disease [e.g., colitis or Crohn's disease], diverticulitis [with&#xD;
             the exception of diverticulosis], systemic lupus erythematosus, Sarcoidosis syndrome,&#xD;
             or Wegener syndrome [granulomatosis with polyangiitis, Graves' disease, rheumatoid&#xD;
             arthritis, hypophysitis, uveitis, etc.]). The following are exceptions to this&#xD;
             criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients with vitiligo or alopecia&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients with hypothyroidism (e.g., following Hashimoto syndrome) stable on&#xD;
                  hormone replacement&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Any chronic skin condition that does not require systemic therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Patients without active disease in the last 5 years may be included but only&#xD;
                  after consultation with the study physician&#xD;
&#xD;
               5. Patients with celiac disease controlled by diet alone&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Uncontrolled intercurrent illness, including but not limited to, ongoing or active&#xD;
             infection, symptomatic congestive heart failure, uncontrolled hypertension, unstable&#xD;
             angina pectoris, cardiac arrhythmia, interstitial lung disease, serious chronic&#xD;
             gastrointestinal conditions associated with diarrhea, or psychiatric illness/social&#xD;
             situations that would limit compliance with study requirement, substantially increase&#xD;
             risk of incurring AEs or compromise the ability of the patient to give written&#xD;
             informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of leptomeningeal carcinomatosis&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. History of active primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Active infection including tuberculosis (clinical evaluation that includes clinical&#xD;
             history, physical examination and radiographic findings, and TB testing in line with&#xD;
             local practice), hepatitis B (known positive HBV surface antigen (HBsAg) result),&#xD;
             hepatitis C, Patients with a past or resolved HBV infection (defined as the presence&#xD;
             of hepatitis B core antibody [anti-HBc] and absence of HBsAg) are eligible. Patients&#xD;
             positive for hepatitis C (HCV) antibody are eligible only if polymerase chain reaction&#xD;
             is negative for HCV RNA.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Current or prior use of immunosuppressive medication within 14 days before the first&#xD;
             dose of durvalumab or tremelimumab. The following are exceptions to this criterion:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Intranasal, inhaled, topical steroids, or local steroid injections (e.g., intra&#xD;
                  articular injection)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Systemic corticosteroids at physiologic doses not to exceed 10 mg/day of&#xD;
                  prednisone or its equivalent&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Steroids as premedication for hypersensitivity reactions (e.g., CT scan&#xD;
                  premedication)&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Receipt of live attenuated vaccine within 30 days prior to the first dose of IP. Note:&#xD;
             Patients, if enrolled, should not receive live vaccine while receiving IP and up to 30&#xD;
             days after the last dose of IP.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Female patients who are pregnant or breastfeeding or male or female patients of&#xD;
             reproductive potential who are not willing to employ effective birth control from&#xD;
             screening to 180 days after the last dose of durvalumab + tremelimumab combination&#xD;
             therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Known allergy or hypersensitivity to any of the study drugs or any of the study drug&#xD;
             excipients.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Prior randomization or treatment in a previous durvalumab and/or tremelimumab clinical&#xD;
             study regardless of treatment arm assignment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Judgment by the investigator that the patient is unsuitable to participate in the&#xD;
             study and the patient is unlikely to comply with study procedures, restrictions and&#xD;
             requirements.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Davendra Sohal, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Cincinnati</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Davendra Sohal, MD</last_name>
    <phone>(513) 558-2361</phone>
    <email>sohalda@ucmail.uc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Christine Vollmer, MBA</last_name>
    <email>mccordce@ucmail.uc.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 17, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Cincinnati</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Davendra Sohal</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Transplant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Hepatocellular</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Hypertension, Portal</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Durvalumab</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Tremelimumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

