<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05028348</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EMN29</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05028348</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Study of Combination of Selinexor, Pomalidomide, and Dexamethasone (SPd) Versus Elotuzumab, Pomalidomide, and Dexamethasone (EloPd) in Subject With Previously Treated Multiple Myeloma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 3 Randomized, Open-label Trial of Selinexor, Pomalidomide, and Dexamethasone (SPd) Versus Elotuzumab, Pomalidomide, and Dexamethasone (EloPd) in Patients With Relapsed or Refractory Multiple Myeloma (RRMM)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>European Myeloma Network</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Karyopharm Therapeutics Inc</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>European Myeloma Network</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This phase 3 randomized, open-label multicenter trial will compare the efficacy, safety and&#xD;
      the impact on health-related quality of life (HR-QoL) of SPd versus EloPd in&#xD;
      pomalidomide-naïve patients with MM who have received 1 to 4 prior anti-MM regimens and been&#xD;
      treated with an immunomodulatory imide drug (IMiD), proteasome inhibitor (PI) and an&#xD;
      anti-CD38 monoclonal antibody (mAb).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2028</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival (PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>from randomization to the date of disease progression or death (approximately up to 5 years)</time_frame>
    <description>from date of randomization until the date of first confirmed progressive disease (PD), per IMWG response criteria, or death due to any cause, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall Response Rate (ORR)</measure>
    <time_frame>from screening until end of treatment/progressive disease (approximately up to 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>defined as any response ≥PR (i.e., PR [partial response], VGPR [very good partial response], CR ([complete response], or sCR [stringent complete response])</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Overall survival (OS)</measure>
    <time_frame>From randomization until death from any cause (up to 3 years after end of treatment)</time_frame>
    <description>Overall Survival</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response</measure>
    <time_frame>screening, Day 1 of each treatment cycle (each cycle is 28 days), at end of treatment, and every 3 months up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of response (PR or better), duration of CR, duration of sCR, and duration of minimal residual disease (MRD) -negative status, are calculated from the date of the initial documentation of a response (PR or better), or CR or better, or sCR, or MRD-negative status to the date of the first documented evidence of disease progression, as defined in the IMWG criteria, whichever occurs first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time to response</measure>
    <time_frame>screening, Day 1 of each treatment cycle (each cycle is 28 days), at end of treatment, and every 3 months up to 3 years</time_frame>
    <description>Time to response (PR or better), time to CR/sCR are defined as the time from randomization to date of initial response (or initial CR/sCR)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression-free survival on the next line of therapy (PFS2)</measure>
    <time_frame>the time from randomization to progression on the next line of treatment or death, whichever comes first., assessed up to approx. 5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Progression-free survival on the next line of therapy (PFS2) is defined as the time from randomization to progression on the next line of treatment or death, whichever comes first.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in European Organization for Research and Treatment of Cancer Quality of Life Questionnaire 30-item Core module (EORTC QLQ-C30) score and the difference between-treatment arms</measure>
    <time_frame>screening, Day 1 of each treatment cycle (each cycle is 28 days), at end of treatment (up to 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC QLQ-C30 is a 30-item questionnaire containing both single and multi-item measures. These include five functional scales (Physical, Role, Cognitive, Emotional, and Social Functioning), three symptom scales (Fatigue, Pain, and Nausea/Vomiting), a Global Health Status/ Quality-of-Life (QoL) scale, and six single items (Constipation, Diarrhea, Insomnia, Dyspnea, Appetite Loss, and Financial Difficulties). The scores ranges from 0-100, a high score for functional scales and for Global Health Status/QoL represent better functioning ability or Health-Related Quality-of-Life (HRQoL), whereas a high score for symptom scales and single items represents significant symptomatology.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in EORTC QLQ- 20-item Multiple Myeloma module (MY-20) score and the difference between-treatment arms</measure>
    <time_frame>screening, Day 1 of each treatment cycle (each cycle is 28 days), at end of treatment (approximately up to 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>The EORTC QLQ-MY20 is a supplement to the QLQ-C30 instrument used in subjects with MY. The module comprises 20 questions that address four myeloma-specific HRQoL domains: Disease Symptoms, Side Effects of Treatment, Future Perspective, and Body Image. A high score for Disease Symptoms and Side Effects of Treatment represents a high level of symptomatology or problems, whereas a high score for Future Perspective and Body Image represents better outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EQ-5D-5L health utility values and the difference between-treatment arms</measure>
    <time_frame>screening, Day 1 of each treatment cycle (each cycle is 28 days), at end of treatment (approximately up to 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>The EQ-5D-5L is a 5 item questionnaire that assesses 5 domains including mobility, self care, usual activities, pain/discomfort, and anxiety/depression plus a visual analog scale rating &quot;health today&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>safety and tolerability of SPd versus EloPd in patients with RRMM</measure>
    <time_frame>continuously from screening untill 30 days after last study treatment. (approximately up to 2 years)</time_frame>
    <description>Safety and tolerability of study treatment will be evaluated based on occurrence, nature and severity of adverse events as categorized by the Common Terminology Criteria of Adverse Events (CTCAE) v5.0</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">280</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Myeloma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Selinexor, pomalidomide and dexamethasone (SPd)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Selinexor will be given as an oral dose 60 mg (3 20 mg tablets) once weekly (QW) on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of each 28-day cycle.&#xD;
Pomalidomide will be given as an oral 4 mg dose QD on Days 1 to 21 of each 28-day cycle.&#xD;
Patients ≤75 years:&#xD;
o Dexamethasone will be given as an oral 40 mg dose QW on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of each 28-day cycle. Dose may be divided over 2 days at the Investigator's discretion.&#xD;
Patients &gt; 75 years:&#xD;
Dexamethasone will be given as an oral 20 mg dose QW on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of each 28-day cycle. Dose may be divided over 2 days at the Investigator's discretion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Elotuzumab, Pomalidomide and Dexamethasone (EloPd)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Elotuzumab will be given IV 10 mg/kg on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of cycle 1 and 2 then 20 mg/kg on Day 1 of cycles ≥3 of each 28-day cycle.&#xD;
Pomalidomide will be given as an oral 4 mg dose once a day (QD) on Days 1 to 21 of each 28-day cycle.&#xD;
Patients ≤75 years:&#xD;
Dexamethasone 28 mg PO + 8 mg IV on days of elotuzumab dosing&#xD;
Dexamethasone 40 mg PO on non-elotuzumab days (e.g., days 8, 15, and 22 of cycle 3 and beyond). Dose may be divided over 2 days at the Investigator's discretion.&#xD;
Patients &gt;75 years:&#xD;
Dexamethasone 8 mg PO + 8 mg IV on days of elotuzumab dosing&#xD;
Dexamethasone 20 mg PO on non-elotuzumab dosing weeks (e.g., days 8, 15, and 22 of cycle 3 and beyond). Dose may be divided over 2 days at the Investigator's discretion.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Selinexor</intervention_name>
    <description>Selinexor will be given as an oral dose 60 mg (3 20 mg tablets) QW on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Selinexor, pomalidomide and dexamethasone (SPd)</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>KPT-330</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Elotuzumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Elotuzumab will be given IV 10 mg/kg on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of cycle 1 and 2 then 20 mg/kg on Day 1 of cycles ≥3 of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Elotuzumab, Pomalidomide and Dexamethasone (EloPd)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pomalidomide</intervention_name>
    <description>Pomalidomide will be given as an oral 4 mg dose QD on Days 1 to 21 of each 28-day cycle.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Elotuzumab, Pomalidomide and Dexamethasone (EloPd)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Selinexor, pomalidomide and dexamethasone (SPd)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dexamethasone Oral</intervention_name>
    <description>Dexamethasone will be given as an oral 40 mg dose QW on Days 1, 8, 15, and 22 of each 28-day cycle. Preferred dosing of dexamethasone is 40 mg QW for patients who are ≤75 years of age (20 mg QW for &gt;75-year-old patients at the Investigator's discretion) before QW dosing of selinexor, however, it may be divided over 2 days at the Investigator's discretion.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Elotuzumab, Pomalidomide and Dexamethasone (EloPd)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Selinexor, pomalidomide and dexamethasone (SPd)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Relapsed or refractory MM with measurable disease per IMWG guidelines as defined by at&#xD;
             least 1 of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Serum M-protein ≥0.5 g/dL (≥5 g/L) by serum electrophoresis (SPEP) or, for&#xD;
                  immunoglobulin (Ig) A or D myeloma, by quantitative serum IgA or IgD levels&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Urinary M-protein excretion ≥200 mg/24 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Serum free light chain (FLC) ≥100 mg/L, provided that the FLC ratio is abnormal&#xD;
                  (normal FLC ratio: 0.26 to 1.65)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Received at least 1 and no more than 4 prior anti-MM regimens. Induction therapy&#xD;
             followed by stem cell transplant and consolidation/maintenance therapy will be&#xD;
             considered as 1 regimen.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients must have prior therapy which must include and anti-CD3 mAb, and ≥2&#xD;
             consecutive cycles of the following agents given alone or in combinations:&#xD;
             lenalidomide, proteasome inhibitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients must have prior therapy with anti-CD38 mAb in one of the following ways:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Received anti-CD38 mAb as their immediate last treatment prior to study entry&#xD;
                  (50% of patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Received prior anti-CD38 mAb other than in immediate last treatment prior to&#xD;
                  study entry (50% of patients)&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status of ≤2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Resolution of any clinically significant non-hematological toxicities (if any) from&#xD;
             previous treatments to Grade ≤1 by Cycle 1 Day 1 (C1D1). Patients with Grade 2&#xD;
             non-hematological toxicities may be included following approval from the Medical&#xD;
             Monitor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Adequate hepatic function within 28 days prior to C1D1:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Total bilirubin &lt;2 × upper limit of normal (ULN) (except patients with Gilbert's&#xD;
                  syndrome who must have a total bilirubin of &lt;3 × ULN)&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Aspartate aminotransferase (AST) and alanine aminotransferase (ALT) &lt;2.5 × ULN&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Adequate renal function within 28 days prior to C1D1 (estimated creatinine clearance&#xD;
             [CrCl] of ≥15 mL/min (not requiring dialysis), calculated using the formula of&#xD;
             Cockcroft and Gault or measured by 24-hour urine collection).&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Adequate hematopoietic function within 7 days prior to C1D1 defined as absolute&#xD;
             neutrophil count ≥1.5 x 109/L , hemoglobin ≥8.5 g/dL, and platelet count ≥100 x 109/L&#xD;
             (patients for whom &lt;50% of bone marrow nucleated cells are plasma cells) or ≥75 x&#xD;
             109/L (patients for whom ≥50% of bone marrow nucleated cells are plasma cells).&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Patients receiving hematopoietic growth factor support, including erythropoietin,&#xD;
                  darbepoetin, granulocyte-colony stimulating factor (G-CSF), granulocyte&#xD;
                  macrophage-colony stimulating factor (GM-CSF), and platelet stimulators (e.g.,&#xD;
                  eltrombopag, romiplostim, or interleukin-11) must have a 2-week interval between&#xD;
                  growth factor support and the Screening assessments, but they may receive growth&#xD;
                  factor support during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Patients must have:&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  At least a 2-week interval from the last red blood cell (RBC) transfusion&#xD;
                       prior to the Screening hemoglobin assessment, and&#xD;
&#xD;
                    -  At least a 1-week interval from the last platelet transfusion prior to the&#xD;
                       Screening platelet assessment.&#xD;
&#xD;
             However, patients may receive RBC and/or platelet transfusions as clinically indicated&#xD;
             per institutional guidelines during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Female patients of childbearing potential must have a negative serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             within 10 to 14 days and a second test within 24 hours prior to the first dose of&#xD;
             study treatment. Female patients of childbearing potential and fertile male patients&#xD;
             who are sexually active must use highly effective methods of contraception throughout&#xD;
             the study and for 3 months following the last dose of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Age ≥18 years at the time of signing informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Written informed consent signed in accordance with federal, local, and institutional&#xD;
             guidelines.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Patients must be able and willing to take enteric-coated aspirin according to clinical&#xD;
             practice, or if history of prior thrombotic disease, must be fully anticoagulated with&#xD;
             warfarin (international normalized ratio [INR] 2-3) or be treated with full-dose, low&#xD;
             molecular weight heparin, as if to treat deep venous thrombosis (DVT)/pulmonary&#xD;
             embolism (PE) at the Investigator's discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Smoldering MM.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Plasma cell leukemia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Documented active systemic amyloid light chain amyloidosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Active central nervous system MM.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Prior treatment with a selective inhibitor of nuclear export (SINE) compound,&#xD;
             including selinexor.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Prior treatment with pomalidomide and/or elotuzumab.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Any concurrent medical condition or disease that is likely to interfere with study&#xD;
             procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Uncontrolled active infection requiring parenteral antibiotics, antivirals, or&#xD;
             antifungals within 1 week prior to C1D1. Patients on prophylactic antibiotics or with&#xD;
             a controlled infection within 1 week prior to C1D1 are acceptable.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Known intolerance, hypersensitivity, or contraindication to any of the study&#xD;
             treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Radiation, chemotherapy, or immunotherapy or any other anticancer therapy including&#xD;
             investigational therapies and high dose dexamethasone [i.e., 40 mg daily for 4 days&#xD;
             per week]) ≤2 weeks prior to C1D1. Patients on long-term glucocorticoids during&#xD;
             Screening do not require a washout period but must be able to tolerate the specified&#xD;
             dexamethasone dose in this study.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Prior autologous stem cell transplantation &lt;60 days or allogeneic stem cell&#xD;
             transplantation &lt;4 months prior to C1D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Major surgery within 4 weeks prior to C1D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Active graft versus host disease after allogeneic stem cell transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Pregnant or breastfeeding females.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. In the opinion of the Investigator, patients who are below their ideal body weight and&#xD;
             would be unduly impacted by changes in their weight.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Clinically significant cardiac disease, including:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Myocardial infarction within 6 months before C1D1, or unstable or uncontrolled&#xD;
                  disease/condition related to or affecting cardiac function (e.g., unstable&#xD;
                  angina, congestive heart failure, New York Heart Association Class III-IV).&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Uncontrolled cardiac arrhythmia (CTCAE v. 5.0 Grade 2 or higher) or clinically&#xD;
                  significant ECG abnormalities.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Screening 12-lead ECG showing a baseline QT interval as corrected by Fridericia's&#xD;
                  formula (QTcF) &gt;470 msec.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. Any active gastrointestinal dysfunction interfering with the patient's ability to&#xD;
             swallow tablets, or any active gastrointestinal dysfunction that could interfere with&#xD;
             absorption of study treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Any active, serious psychiatric, medical, or other conditions/situations that, in the&#xD;
             opinion of the Investigator, could interfere with treatment, compliance, or the&#xD;
             ability to give informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Contraindication to any of the required concomitant drugs or supportive treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Patients unwilling or unable to comply with the protocol.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>European Myeloma Network (EMN)</last_name>
    <phone>+31 107033123</phone>
    <email>chiara.pautasso@emnitaly.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU Hôpital Claude Huriez</name>
      <address>
        <city>Lille</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHRU Hôtel Dieu</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nantes</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Hôpital Saint Antoine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>La Pitié</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Paris Necker</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Poitiers - Pôle régional de Cancérologie</name>
      <address>
        <city>Poitiers</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Pôle IUCT Oncopole CHU</name>
      <address>
        <city>Toulouse</city>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg - Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Heidelberg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Heidelberg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Cologne</name>
      <address>
        <city>Köln</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Münster</name>
      <address>
        <city>Münster</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Hospital of Würzburg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Würzburg</city>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Alexandra General Hospital -Department of Clinical Therapeutics N.K. Univ. of Athens</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>General Hospital of Athens&quot;Euaggelismos&quot;</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>St Savvas Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Athens</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University General Hospital of Patras</name>
      <address>
        <city>Patras</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Theagenion Cancer Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Thessaloníki</city>
        <country>Greece</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliero-Universitaria Ospedali Riuniti Umberto I - G.M. Lancisi - G. Salesi Di Ancona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ancona</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O. Papa Giovanni XXIII</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bergamo</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bologna</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bologna</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ASST Spedali Civili di Brescia - Ematologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Brescia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Brescia</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedale Oncologico 'A. Businco'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cagliari</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Az.Osp. Di Careggi_Dh ematologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Firenze</city>
        <zip>50134</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O.U. Policlinico S. Martino - Ematologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Genova</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital IRST</name>
      <address>
        <city>Meldola</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O.U. Policlinico 'G. Martino'</name>
      <address>
        <city>Messina</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O.U. Maggiore della Carità di Novara</name>
      <address>
        <city>Novara</city>
        <zip>28100</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ospedale S. Eugenio</name>
      <address>
        <city>Roma</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O. S. Maria</name>
      <address>
        <city>Terni</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>A.O.U. Città della Salute e della Scienza di Torino - SC Ematologia U</name>
      <address>
        <city>Torino</city>
        <zip>10126</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Azienda Ospedaliera Universitaria di Udine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Udine</city>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Erasmus MC</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rotterdam</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Clinic I Provincial de Barcelona</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ICO Hospitalet</name>
      <address>
        <city>Barcelona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Madrid</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. General Universitario Morales Meseguer</name>
      <address>
        <city>Murcia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clínica Universidad de Navarra (CUN)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Pamplona</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hospital Universitario de Salamanca</name>
      <address>
        <city>Salamanca</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H. Universitario Marqués de Valdecilla</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santander</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo Hospitalario Universitario de Santiago (CHUS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago De Compostela</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>H.U. La Fe</name>
      <address>
        <city>Valencia</city>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
    <country>Germany</country>
    <country>Greece</country>
    <country>Italy</country>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>August 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 31, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Myeloma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Neoplasms, Plasma Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pomalidomide</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Elotuzumab</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

