<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT05025670</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TRAIT-BOR-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT05025670</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Tracking Response in Advance of Investigational Trials, Borderline Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>TRAIT-BOR</acronym>
  <official_title>Tracking Response in Advance of Investigational Trials, Borderline Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Adams Clinical</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Adams Clinical</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      TRAIT-BOR is an open-label psychotherapy treatment study for adults who meet the diagnostic&#xD;
      criteria for Borderline Personality Disorder (BPD) and are seeking enrollment in a clinical&#xD;
      trial of a novel compound to treat BPD. The current study seeks to determine if there are&#xD;
      therapeutic benefits to more infrequent, short term, or longer term supportive psychotherapy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 5, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stability of symptoms and treatment response as defined as change in total scores on the Agitation-Aggression Psychiatric Inventory - Clinician Report (AAPI-CR) from Baseline/Day 0 to End of Cycle (EOC)/Day 90.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total scores on the AAPI-CR range from 11 to 275, with higher scores indicating higher levels of agitation and aggression.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Stability of symptoms and treatment response as defined as change in total scores on the self-report Borderline Personality Disorder Checklist (BPDCL) from Baseline/Day 0 to End of Cycle (EOC)/Day 90.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total scores on the BPDCL range from 47 to 235, with higher scores indicating greater symptom severity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who have clinically significant agitation and aggression symptoms, as defined as AAPI-CR Agitation and Aggression (A/A) subscale score ≥ 16 and sum of the A/A subscale severity scores ≥ 6.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stability of symptoms and treatment response as defined as change in total score on the Zanarini Rating Scale for Borderline Personality Disorder (ZAN-BPD) from Baseline/Day 0 to End of Cycle (EOC)/Day 90.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Total scores on the ZAN-BPD range from 0 to 36, with higher scores indicating greater symptom severity.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stability of symptoms and treatment response as defined as change in total scores on the AAPI-CR from Baseline/Day 0 to End of Study (EOS)/Day 224.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Stability of symptoms and treatment response as defined as change in total scores on the BPDCL from Baseline/Day 0 to End of Study (EOS)/Day 224.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who fail to reach response to a brief course of monthly supportive psychotherapy treatment after 3 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as either AAPI-CR Total score ≥ 16 by EOC/Day 90 or &lt; 25% decrease in AAPI-CR Total Score from Baseline/Day 0 to EOC/Day 90 and verified by clinician-rated assessment as indicated by a CGI ≥ 4 at EOC/Day 90.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who fail to reach response to longer term monthly supportive psychotherapy treatment after 8 months.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as either AAPI-CR Total score ≥ 16 by EOS/Day 224 or &lt; 25% decrease in AAPI-CR Total Score from Baseline/Day 0 to EOS/Day 224 and verified by clinician-rated assessment as indicated by a CGI ≥ 4 at EOS/Day 224.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who show a partial response to monthly brief or longer term supportive psychotherapy treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as ≥ 25% to &lt; 50% reduction in AAPI-CR Total Score from Baseline/Day 0 to EOC/Day 90 and ≥ 25% to &lt; 50% reduction in AAPI-CR Total Score from Baseline/Day 0 to EOS/Day 224.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who show a clinically significant response to brief monthly supportive psychotherapy treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>90 days</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as ≥ 50% reduction in AAPI-CR Total Score from Baseline/Day 0 to EOC/Day 90 and verified by clinician-rated assessment as indicated by a CGI ≤ 3 at EOC/Day 90.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who show a clinically significant response to longer term monthly supportive psychotherapy treatment.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Defined as ≥ 50% reduction in AAPI-CR Total Score from Baseline/Day 0 to EOS/Day 224 and verified by clinician-rated assessment as indicated by a CGI ≤ 3 at EOS/Day 224.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The initial prevalence of comorbid psychiatric symptoms as assessed by the Mini-International Neuropsychiatric Inventory (MINI).</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The proportion of participants who elect to add psychopharmacologic treatment to their monthly supportive psychotherapy by enrolling in an industry-sponsored clinical trial for BPD at the site.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 52 weeks</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Borderline Personality Disorder</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Supportive psychotherapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will receive monthly 30-45 minute supportive psychotherapy sessions. Supportive psychotherapy is an integrative and eclectic psychotherapeutic approach, based upon the individual's needs and symptoms. It draws from elements of a variety of psychotherapeutic disciplines, including cognitive-behavior, psychodynamic, and interpersonal therapies.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults aged 18 to 65 years old, who meet criteria for BPD, and who have expressed interest&#xD;
        in participating in a clinical trial of an investigational product for treatment of BPD.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has signed an ICF prior to any study-specific procedures being performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a diagnosis of Borderline Personality Disorder, per DSM-5 criteria, as&#xD;
             confirmed on the MINI, and ≥ 16 AAPI-CR total score.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is in good physical health, and, in the opinion of the investigator, is a&#xD;
             suitable candidate for treatment with monthly supportive psychotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is 18 to 65 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  For participants already receiving psychotherapy, including Dialectical Behavioral&#xD;
             Therapy (DBT), they must continue their regular course of treatment for the duration&#xD;
             of the current study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant is pregnant, breast-feeding, or planning to become pregnant.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history or presence of a clinically significant hepatic, renal, gastrointestinal,&#xD;
             cardiovascular, endocrine, respiratory, immunologic, hematologic, dermatologic, or&#xD;
             neurologic abnormality, which in the opinion of the investigator may impact&#xD;
             participant safety or study results.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has a history of any psychiatric condition other than BPD, which in the&#xD;
             opinion of the investigator is primary, or any other psychiatric or neurologic&#xD;
             disorder or symptom that could pose undue risk to the participant or compromise the&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participant who represents an acute suicidal risk in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator, as defined by a &quot;yes&quot; response to suicidal ideation on questions 4 or 5,&#xD;
             or answer &quot;yes&quot; to suicidal behavior questions on the CSSR-S within 90 days of&#xD;
             screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any participant who represents an acute homicidal risk in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Moderate or severe substance use disorder within 90 days prior to screen, according to&#xD;
             DSM-5 criteria that in the opinion of the investigator could pose undue risk to the&#xD;
             participant, or compromise the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any condition that, in the opinion of the investigator, makes the participant&#xD;
             unsuitable for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who require ongoing treatment with typical antipsychotics.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jenicka Engler, PsyD</last_name>
    <phone>617-755-8542</phone>
    <email>jengler@adamsclinical.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Adams Clinical</name>
      <address>
        <city>Watertown</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02472</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Jenicka Engler, PsyD</last_name>
      <phone>617-744-8542</phone>
      <email>jengler@adamsclinical.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>August 20, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>August 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">August 27, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 17, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Personality Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Borderline Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

