<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04571190</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>07121971</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04571190</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>An Adapted Mindfulness-based Stress Reduction Program for High-risk Pregnancies</brief_title>
  <official_title>An Adapted Mindfulness-based Stress Reduction Program for High-risk Pregnancies - a Protocol for a Randomized Feasibility Study in a Danish Hospital-based Outpatient Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Aarhus</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Copenhagen University Hospital, Amager-Hvidovre, Denmark</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Aarhus</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This protocol is for a feasibility study of an adapted mindfulness-based stress reduction&#xD;
      (MBSR) program for high-risk pregnant women. The aim is to address the need for more&#xD;
      evidence-based options for mental healthcare in pregnancy. MBSR has good evidence in reducing&#xD;
      stress, anxiety and depression in both clinical and non-clinical populations, but has not yet&#xD;
      been adapted for high-risk pregnancies. The purpose is to evaluate the feasibility,&#xD;
      acceptability and potential intervention effects of an adapted MBSR program compared to usual&#xD;
      care to inform a randomized controlled trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This protocol is for a feasibility study of an adapted mindfulness-based stress reduction&#xD;
      (MBSR) program for high-risk pregnant women attending a hospital-based outpatient clinic&#xD;
      specialized in antenatal care for high-risk pregnancies. A history of a mental disorder&#xD;
      and/or severe psychosocial problems that may pose a risk to the health of the mother and&#xD;
      fetus are reasons for referral to the clinic. The protocol is part of the Good start to&#xD;
      family life study and the primary aim is to address the need of high-risk pregnant women and&#xD;
      care providers for a wider array of evidence-based options to address prenatal mental health&#xD;
      care needs. Mindfulness-based interventions are promising interventions for mental disorders&#xD;
      with performance equivalent to evidence-based treatments, such as cognitive behavioral&#xD;
      therapy and antidepressant medication for some disorders. Moreover, it is an acceptable&#xD;
      intervention for pregnant women. A history of any psychopathology or psychosocial&#xD;
      adversities, including low social support and abuse, are predictors of mental disorders&#xD;
      during and after pregnancy with little diagnostic specificity. Mental disorders or symptoms&#xD;
      often continue after birth emphasizing the need for early intervention and prevention. The&#xD;
      intention of teaching mindfulness to this group of pregnant women is thus to engage and&#xD;
      strengthen their internal resources for optimizing recovery or prevent relapse of mental&#xD;
      health disorders during the perinatal period, and to teach skills that may aid the formation&#xD;
      of a healthy mother-child relationship.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives of the feasibility study are thus to assess the: (1) acceptance of study&#xD;
      participation among at-risk pregnant women; (2) acceptance of allocated interventions; (3)&#xD;
      number of referrals to psychiatric treatment during the study period; (4) risk of bias: loss&#xD;
      to follow-up in the study arms; acceptance and compliance with the intervention, i.e.&#xD;
      attending ≥ 5 sessions; (5) the extent of missing data leading to missing outcomes, and (6)&#xD;
      indications of potential intervention effects. The adapted MBSR program will be referred to&#xD;
      as prenatal MBSR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is conducted at Copenhagen University Hospital, Hvidovre, Denmark. The design is a&#xD;
      single-center feasibility trial comparing prenatal MBSR as add on to usual care with a&#xD;
      waitlist control group receiving usual care alone. High-risk pregnant women around 18 weeks&#xD;
      gestation (n = 60) will be recruited for the study provided that they are not diagnosed with&#xD;
      a major psychiatric illness, psychosis, current substance abuse or suicidality. Participants&#xD;
      will be randomized in a1:1 ratio to prenatal MBSR or usual care.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Teaching the skills of mindfulness meditation to a vulnerable group of pregnant women could&#xD;
      prove as a viable and non-pharmacological approach to improve mental health and provide&#xD;
      support in the transition to parenthood. The outcomes of the feasibility study will inform&#xD;
      the design of a fully powered randomized controlled trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The design is a single-center feasibility trial comparing prenatal MBSR as add on to usual care with usual care alone. Participants will be randomized in a 1:1 ratio to an intervention or waitlist control group. Participants in the waitlist control group will be offered participation in a MBSR program after a three months follow-up period. Mindfulness training in the control group will thus be initiated postnatal.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Group affiliation will be concealed for the researcher performing the statistical analyses. Participants will be informed that the overall purpose of the study is to examine the feasibility, acceptability and effect of prenatal MBSR and they are thus not blind to group allocation.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Perceived Stress Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Perceived Stress Scale 10-item version (PSS-10) is a global measure of the perception of stress. Scores range from 0 - 40 with higher scores pointing to more perceived stress. The Danish consensus version of the PSS-10 can be used in clinical research settings and has good psychometric properties.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Edinburgh Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Edinburgh Depression Scale (EDS) is a widely used screening questionnaire containing questions on how the respondent has felt in the past seven days. Scores range from 0 - 30. A higher score points to more depressive symptoms, and a score of 11 has been suggested as the optimal cut-off for depression according to both DSM-5 and ICD-10 criteria The EDS has been validated as a screening instrument for prenatal and postpartum depression showing good psychometric properties.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Depression, Anxiety Stress Scales</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Depression, Anxiety Stress Scales - 21 (DASS-21) has three subscales designed to discriminate between depression, anxiety and stress in the last week. The DASS excludes somatic items such as sleep disturbance, lack of energy and poor concentration, which may not be valid markers in pregnancy or the postpartum period. Response to each item is rated on a four-point Likert scale ranging from 'never' to 'very much/most of the time'. Scores are calculated for each subscale and higher scores point to more symptoms of stress, anxiety or depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>WHO-5</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The WHO-5 is a short and generic global rating scale measuring subjective well-being. It consists of five statements and the respondent is asked to rate how well each of the statements applies to him or her when considering the last 14 days. Final scores range from 0 - 100 with higher scores representing greater well-being. The scale has adequate validity both as a screening tool for depression and as an outcome measure in clinical trials and has been applied successfully across a wide range of study fields.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prenatal Reflective functioning</measure>
    <time_frame>From baselineResponses are rated on a scale from 7 (strongly agree) to 1 (strongly disagree). to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Parental reflective functioning refers to the caregiver's capacity to reflect upon his/her own internal mental experiences as well as those of the child. The Prenatal Parental Reflective Functioning Questionnaire (P-PRFQ) is a recently developed 14-item questionnaire for assessing early parental mentalizing capacity. Responses are rated on a scale from 7 (strongly agree) to 1 (strongly disagree). The raw scores range from 14 - 98 and the index sum from 1 - 7. Higher score indicates higher prenatal mentalizing capacity. The P-PRFQ has shown good initial psychometric properties.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The Experiences Questionnaire: subscale for decentering</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>Decentering reflects the capacity to take a nonjudgmental and accepting stance regarding one´s thoughts and emotions as opposed to identifying with them. The decentering subscale of the experiences questionnaire consists of 11 items with a total score ranging from 11 - 55. Higher scores indicate higher decentering. Initial support has been found for reliability and validity of the scale as a measure of decentering.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The Five Facet Mindfulness Questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Five Facet Mindfulness Questionnaire (FFMQ) assesses five general facets of being mindful in daily life: observing, describing, acting with awareness, non-reactivity to inner experience, and non-judging of inner experience. Items are rated on a five-point Likert scale ranging from 1 (never or very rarely true) to 5 (very often or always true). Each facet score range from 8 - 40 or from 7 - 35. Higher scores suggest higher levels of mindfulness.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Compassion</measure>
    <time_frame>From baseline to three-months follow-up</time_frame>
    <description>The Self-Compassion Scale measures the ability to have a healthy stand towards oneself that does not involve evaluations of self-worth. The scale consists of 16 items and responses are given on a 5-point scale from 1 (almost never) to 5 (almost always). Higher scores indicate more self-compassions. The psychometric properties of the scale has been extensive evaluated.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Pregnancy, High Risk</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prenatal MBSR</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The prenatal MBSR program consists of nine two-hour sessions including teachings in mindfulness meditation and yoga. The program is taught by an experienced MBSR instructor with relevant clinical expertise.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard clinical practice, usual care (TAU), imply routine pregnancy visits to the outpatient antenatal clinic at Copenhagen University Hospital, Hvidovre and to a General Practitioner. Usual care include a multidisciplinary approach involving preventive counselling by midwifes, physicians and social workers throughout the pregnancy and follow-up until the early post-partum period.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prenatal MBSR</intervention_name>
    <description>Prenatal MBSR is an adaptation to the original MBSR program. The essential program elements characterizing MBSR is maintained and integrated with the particular context and specific needs of this group of pregnant women. Adaptations to the MBSR program draw upon both empirical data as well as existing research and theory.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prenatal MBSR</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Mindfulness-based stress reduction</other_name>
    <other_name>MBSR</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Due date no sooner than three months from start of the mindfulness program&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  able to speak and write Danish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  available for group intervention scheduled sessions. Being unavailable for two or more&#xD;
             sessions is reason for exclusion from study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  written informed consent to study criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  concurrent substance abuse&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  schizophrenia, psychosis, PTSD, schizotypal personality disorder or other major&#xD;
             psychiatric disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  suicidality&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sine S Skovbjerg, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>26357227</phone>
    <phone_ext>45</phone_ext>
    <email>sine.skovbjerg@clin.au.dk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Lone Fjorback, PhD</last_name>
    <email>lone.overby.fjorback@clin.au.dk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Copenhagen University Hospital, Amager-Hvidovre</name>
      <address>
        <city>Copenhagen</city>
        <state>Capital Region</state>
        <zip>2650</zip>
        <country>Denmark</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sine Skovbjerg</last_name>
      <phone>26357227</phone>
      <email>sine.skovbjerg@clin.au.dk</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Denmark</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stein A, Pearson RM, Goodman SH, Rapa E, Rahman A, McCallum M, Howard LM, Pariante CM. Effects of perinatal mental disorders on the fetus and child. Lancet. 2014 Nov 15;384(9956):1800-19. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(14)61277-0. Epub 2014 Nov 14. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25455250</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wielgosz J, Goldberg SB, Kral TRA, Dunne JD, Davidson RJ. Mindfulness Meditation and Psychopathology. Annu Rev Clin Psychol. 2019 May 7;15:285-316. doi: 10.1146/annurev-clinpsy-021815-093423. Epub 2018 Dec 10. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30525995</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Crane RS, Brewer J, Feldman C, Kabat-Zinn J, Santorelli S, Williams JM, Kuyken W. What defines mindfulness-based programs? The warp and the weft. Psychol Med. 2017 Apr;47(6):990-999. doi: 10.1017/S0033291716003317. Epub 2016 Dec 29.</citation>
    <PMID>28031068</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kuyken W, Warren FC, Taylor RS, Whalley B, Crane C, Bondolfi G, Hayes R, Huijbers M, Ma H, Schweizer S, Segal Z, Speckens A, Teasdale JD, Van Heeringen K, Williams M, Byford S, Byng R, Dalgleish T. Efficacy of Mindfulness-Based Cognitive Therapy in Prevention of Depressive Relapse: An Individual Patient Data Meta-analysis From Randomized Trials. JAMA Psychiatry. 2016 Jun 1;73(6):565-74. doi: 10.1001/jamapsychiatry.2016.0076.</citation>
    <PMID>27119968</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dhillon A, Sparkes E, Duarte RV. Mindfulness-Based Interventions During Pregnancy: a Systematic Review and Meta-analysis. Mindfulness (N Y). 2017;8(6):1421-1437. doi: 10.1007/s12671-017-0726-x. Epub 2017 Apr 17. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>29201244</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ludwig DS, Kabat-Zinn J. Mindfulness in medicine. JAMA. 2008 Sep 17;300(11):1350-2. doi: 10.1001/jama.300.11.1350.</citation>
    <PMID>18799450</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Luyten P, Fonagy P. The neurobiology of mentalizing. Personal Disord. 2015 Oct;6(4):366-79. doi: 10.1037/per0000117. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26436580</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pajulo M, Tolvanen M, Karlsson L, Halme-Chowdhury E, Öst C, Luyten P, Mayes L, Karlsson H. THE PRENATAL PARENTAL REFLECTIVE FUNCTIONING QUESTIONNAIRE: EXPLORING FACTOR STRUCTURE AND CONSTRUCT VALIDITY OF A NEW MEASURE IN THE FINN BRAIN BIRTH COHORT PILOT STUDY. Infant Ment Health J. 2015 Jul-Aug;36(4):399-414. doi: 10.1002/imhj.21523. Epub 2015 Jun 19.</citation>
    <PMID>26096692</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cohen S, Kamarck T, Mermelstein R. A global measure of perceived stress. J Health Soc Behav. 1983 Dec;24(4):385-96.</citation>
    <PMID>6668417</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cox JL, Holden JM, Sagovsky R. Detection of postnatal depression. Development of the 10-item Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale. Br J Psychiatry. 1987 Jun;150:782-6.</citation>
    <PMID>3651732</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Smith-Nielsen J, Matthey S, Lange T, Væver MS. Validation of the Edinburgh Postnatal Depression Scale against both DSM-5 and ICD-10 diagnostic criteria for depression. BMC Psychiatry. 2018 Dec 20;18(1):393. doi: 10.1186/s12888-018-1965-7.</citation>
    <PMID>30572867</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lovibond PF, Lovibond SH. The structure of negative emotional states: comparison of the Depression Anxiety Stress Scales (DASS) with the Beck Depression and Anxiety Inventories. Behav Res Ther. 1995 Mar;33(3):335-43.</citation>
    <PMID>7726811</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee D. The convergent, discriminant, and nomological validity of the Depression Anxiety Stress Scales-21 (DASS-21). J Affect Disord. 2019 Dec 1;259:136-142. doi: 10.1016/j.jad.2019.06.036. Epub 2019 Jun 30.</citation>
    <PMID>31445339</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Topp CW, Østergaard SD, Søndergaard S, Bech P. The WHO-5 Well-Being Index: a systematic review of the literature. Psychother Psychosom. 2015;84(3):167-76. doi: 10.1159/000376585. Epub 2015 Mar 28. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>25831962</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fonagy P, Luyten P, Moulton-Perkins A, Lee YW, Warren F, Howard S, Ghinai R, Fearon P, Lowyck B. Development and Validation of a Self-Report Measure of Mentalizing: The Reflective Functioning Questionnaire. PLoS One. 2016 Jul 8;11(7):e0158678. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0158678. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>27392018</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Fresco DM, Moore MT, van Dulmen MH, Segal ZV, Ma SH, Teasdale JD, Williams JM. Initial psychometric properties of the experiences questionnaire: validation of a self-report measure of decentering. Behav Ther. 2007 Sep;38(3):234-46. Epub 2007 Apr 24.</citation>
    <PMID>17697849</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Baer RA, Smith GT, Lykins E, Button D, Krietemeyer J, Sauer S, Walsh E, Duggan D, Williams JM. Construct validity of the five facet mindfulness questionnaire in meditating and nonmeditating samples. Assessment. 2008 Sep;15(3):329-42. doi: 10.1177/1073191107313003. Epub 2008 Feb 29.</citation>
    <PMID>18310597</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pommier E, Neff KD, Tóth-Király I. The Development and Validation of the Compassion Scale. Assessment. 2020 Jan;27(1):21-39. doi: 10.1177/1073191119874108. Epub 2019 Sep 13.</citation>
    <PMID>31516024</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Billingham SA, Whitehead AL, Julious SA. An audit of sample sizes for pilot and feasibility trials being undertaken in the United Kingdom registered in the United Kingdom Clinical Research Network database. BMC Med Res Methodol. 2013 Aug 20;13:104. doi: 10.1186/1471-2288-13-104.</citation>
    <PMID>23961782</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Eldridge SM, Chan CL, Campbell MJ, Bond CM, Hopewell S, Thabane L, Lancaster GA; PAFS consensus group. CONSORT 2010 statement: extension to randomised pilot and feasibility trials. Pilot Feasibility Stud. 2016 Oct 21;2:64. eCollection 2016.</citation>
    <PMID>27965879</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 27, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Prenatal mental health</keyword>
  <keyword>Pregnancy, High Risk</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness-based stress reduction</keyword>
  <keyword>MBSR</keyword>
  <keyword>Prenatal mindfulness-based stress reduction</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

