<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04578873</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Qpex-101</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04578873</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase 1 Oral QPX7831 SAD and MAD in Healthy Adults</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase 1, Randomized, Double-Blind, Placebo-Controlled, Ascending Single- and Multiple-Dose Study of the Safety, Tolerability, and Pharmacokinetics of Oral QPX7831 in Healthy Adult Subjects</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Qpex Biopharma, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Qpex Biopharma, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This Phase 1 study will assess the safety, tolerability, and pharmacokinetics (PK) of&#xD;
      QPX7831, a beta-lactamase inhibitor, when administered orally in single ascending doses and&#xD;
      in multiple ascending doses to heathy adult subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Qpex Biopharma, Inc. is developing an oral dosage form that delivers QPX7728, a new&#xD;
      boron-based beta-lactamase inhibitor with activity against both serine and&#xD;
      metallo-beta-lactamases, for oral treatment in combination with a beta-lactam antibiotic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To assess the safety and tolerability of QPX7831 when administered orally in single&#xD;
           ascending doses (SAD) and in multiple ascending doses (MAD) to healthy adult subjects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. To assess the PK of single and multiple doses of oral QPX7831 when administered to&#xD;
           healthy adult subjects to determine if the target exposures identified in preclinical&#xD;
           studies can be attained in healthy adult subjects.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">April 13, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Sequential Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Double-blind, placebo-controlled, sequential, ascending single-and multiple-dose design</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>matched oral placebo capsule</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of Treatment -Emergent Adverse events by subject and by cohort (single dose, multiple doses)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with Treatment-Emergent AEs by subject, by cohort, severity and relationship to treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of patients with changes from baseline in safety parameters</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients with changes in safety parameters before and after dosing by subject and cohort</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peak plasma Concentration measurements by subject and by cohort (Cmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be performed between the cohorts for Cmax. Mean graphical presentation of the data will be reported. Statistical analysis of exposure parameters will be performed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Time concentration data measurements by subject and by cohort (Tmax)</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be performed between the cohorts for Tmax.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Area under the plasma concentration versus time curve (AUC) between cohorts</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison will be performed between the cohorts for AUC. Mean graphical presentation of the data will be reported. Statistical analysis of exposure parameters will be performed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Urine PK amount excreted by subject and by cohort</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Urine PK parameters such as amount excreted will be calculated from urinary excretion data</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Urine PK % dose excreted by subject and by cohort</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 17 days</time_frame>
    <description>Urine PK parameters such as amount of % dose excreted will be calculated from urinary excretion data</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Bacterial Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>QPX7831 SAD Cohorts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>oral, single ascending dose (or placebo)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>QPX7831 MAD Cohorts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>oral, multiple ascending dose (or placebo)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>QPX7831</intervention_name>
    <description>capsule</description>
    <arm_group_label>QPX7831 MAD Cohorts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>QPX7831 SAD Cohorts</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>placebo comparator</intervention_name>
    <description>oral matched placebo capsule</description>
    <arm_group_label>QPX7831 MAD Cohorts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>QPX7831 SAD Cohorts</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Healthy adult males and/or females of non-childbearing potential, 18 to 55 years of&#xD;
             age (inclusive) at the time of screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Body mass index (BMI) ≥ 18.5 and ≤ 29.9 (kg/m2) and weight between 55.0 and 100.0 kg&#xD;
             (inclusive).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Medically healthy with clinically insignificant screening results (e.g., laboratory&#xD;
             profiles, medical histories, electrocardiograms [ECGs], physical examination) as&#xD;
             assessed by the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Voluntarily consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Male volunteers must agree to use a condom when engaging in any sexual activity from&#xD;
             study check-in through 30 days following the last administration of the study drug,&#xD;
             and to not donate sperm during this same period of time. If engaging in sexual&#xD;
             activity with a female partner of childbearing potential, an additional method of&#xD;
             birth control must be used. Approved additional methods of birth control include:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Intra-uterine device (IUD) in place for at least 3 months prior to Day 1 through&#xD;
                  30 days following the final dosing of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Barrier method (diaphragm) for at least 14 days prior to Day 1 through 30 days&#xD;
                  following dosing of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Stable hormonal contraceptive for at least 3 months prior to Day 1 through 30&#xD;
                  days following dosing of the study drug.&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Surgical sterilization (vasectomy) at least 6 months prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Females of non-childbearing potential with serum FSH levels ≥ 40 mIU/mL are either&#xD;
             postmenopausal (defined as 12 months spontaneous amenorrhea) or have undergone one of&#xD;
             the following sterilization procedures at least 6 months prior to Day 1 (and is&#xD;
             documented):&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. Bilateral tubal ligation;&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Hysterectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Hysterectomy with unilateral or bilateral oophorectomy;&#xD;
&#xD;
               4. Bilateral oophorectomy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History or presence of significant cardiovascular, pulmonary, hepatic, renal,&#xD;
             hematological, gastrointestinal, endocrine, immunologic, dermatologic, neurological,&#xD;
             or psychiatric disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Positive urine drug/alcohol testing at screening or check-in (Day -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Positive testing for human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), hepatitis B surface antigen&#xD;
             (HBsAg), or hepatitis C antibodies (HCV).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History or presence of alcoholism or drug abuse within the 2 years prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Use of more than 5 packs/week of cigarettes (or equivalent amount of&#xD;
             nicotine-containing product) within 6 months prior to Day 1. Subjects must agree to&#xD;
             refrain from smoking for the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Excessive intake of alcohol, defined as an average daily intake of greater than 2&#xD;
             standard drinks for women and 4 standard drinks for men; 1 bottle of beer (375mL) is&#xD;
             equivalent to approximately 1.4 standard drinks, 1 glass of spirits (30mL) is&#xD;
             equivalent to approximately 1 standard drink and 1 glass (150mL) of wine is equivalent&#xD;
             to approximately 1.5 standard drinks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Use of any prescription medication (with the exception of hormone replacement therapy&#xD;
             for females) within 14 days prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Use of any over the counter (OTC) medication, including herbal products, probiotics&#xD;
             and vitamins, within the 7 days prior to Day 1. Up to 2 grams per day of paracetamol&#xD;
             is allowed for acute events at the discretion of the PI.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Use of antacids, H2 receptor blockers or proton pump inhibitors within 7 days prior to&#xD;
             Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Documented hypersensitivity reaction or anaphylaxis to any medication&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Blood donation or significant blood loss (i.e., &gt; 500 mL) within 56 days prior to Day&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Plasma donation within 7 days prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Participation in another investigational clinical trial within 30 days prior to Day 1&#xD;
             or within 5 half-lives of the previous investigational drug, whichever is longer.&#xD;
&#xD;
         14. Females who are pregnant or lactating.&#xD;
&#xD;
         15. Surgery within the past three months prior to Day 1 determined by the PI to be&#xD;
             clinically relevant.&#xD;
&#xD;
         16. Any acute illness within 30 days prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
         17. QTcF interval &gt;450 msec for males and &gt;470 for females or history of prolonged QT&#xD;
             syndrome at screening or check-in (Day -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
         18. Calculated creatinine clearance less than 80 mL/min (Cockcroft-Gault method) at&#xD;
             screening or check-in (Day -1).&#xD;
&#xD;
         19. Subjects who have any clinically significant abnormalities on laboratory values at&#xD;
             screening or check-in (Day -1), in particular:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. White blood cell count &lt; 3,000/mm3, hemoglobin &lt; 11g/dL.&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. Absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1,200/mm3 or platelet count &lt; 120,000/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. Liver function abnormalities at screening or check-in (Day -1) (defined by an&#xD;
                  elevation in bilirubin, AST or ALT 1.5 x ULN of the normal range for subjects&#xD;
                  based on age and sex).&#xD;
&#xD;
         20. Any other condition or prior therapy, which, in the opinion of the PI, would make the&#xD;
             subject unsuitable for this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>55 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jeffery Loutit, MBChB</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Qpex Biopharma, Inc.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Elizabeth E Morgan</last_name>
    <phone>858-500-8388</phone>
    <email>lmorgan@qpexbio.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>WCCT Global</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cypress</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>90630</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sarabeth Alonso, CCRP</last_name>
      <phone>714-252-0700</phone>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Youngjun David Kim, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CMAX</name>
      <address>
        <city>Adelaide</city>
        <state>South Australia</state>
        <country>Australia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Katherine Mudge</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Australia</country>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>October 1, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 19, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 19, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 20, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>beta-lactamase inhibitor</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bacterial Infections</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

