<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04572776</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>STI-RTX-300x</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04572776</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Phase 3 Study to Assess Resiniferatoxin vs Standard of Care for the Treatment of Intractable Cancer Pain</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Multicenter, Randomized, 2-Arm, Phase 3 Study to Assess the Efficacy and Safety of a Single Epidural Administration of Resiniferatoxin Versus Standard of Care (SoC) for the Treatment of Intractable Pain Associated With Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sorrento Therapeutics, Inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sorrento Therapeutics, Inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a Phase 3 study to assess the safety and efficacy of a single epidural administration&#xD;
      of Resiniferatoxin versus standard of care for the treatment of intractable pain associated&#xD;
      with cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study is a multicenter, randomized Phase 3 study to assess the safety and efficacy of a&#xD;
      single epidural administration of Resiniferatoxin versus standard of care (SOC) for the&#xD;
      treatment of intractable pain associated with cancer. Subjects will be followed for 12 weeks&#xD;
      after treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Withdrawn</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    To be replaced by a different protocol&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Follow-up visit examinations will be performed by a blinded outcomes assessor.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in worst pain as assessed using the Numeric Pain Rating Scale (NPRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline to Week 4 in the intensity of worst pain over the previous 24 hours in the area targeted for treatment as measured by the 11-point NPRS (0-10 where 0 is no pain and 10 is worst pain imaginable)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in worst pain as assessed using the NPRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Weeks 8 and 12</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline to Weeks 8 and 12 in the intensity of worst pain over the previous 24 hours in the area targeted for treatment as measured by the 11-point NPRS (0-10 where 0 is no pain and 10 is worst pain imaginable)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in area under the curve (AUC) of worst pain as assessed using the NPRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>AUC calculated on change from baseline through Week 4 in worst pain in the target pain location over the previous 24 hours, using the NPRS (0-10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and severity of adverse events (AEs)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline through Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and severity of AEs assessed using the Common Terminology Criteria for Adverse Events (CTCAE) criteria</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Quality of Life (QOL) as assessed using the modified Brief Pain Inventory-Short Form (BPI-SF)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Change in Quality of Life from baseline to week 4 based on total score from the BPI-SF, modified to record the target pain treated with study drug</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of response in subjects who experienced ≥20% decrease from baseline in worst pain as assessed using the NPRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Randomization through Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Duration of response defined as time from ≥20% decrease from baseline in worst pain score in the target pain location to ≥20% increase from the nadir of the worst pain score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in intensity of average pain as assessed using the NPRS</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline to Week 4</time_frame>
    <description>Change from baseline to Week 4 in the intensity of average pain over the previous 24 hours in the target pain location as measured by the NPRS (0-10)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">0</enrollment>
  <condition>Pain, Intractable</condition>
  <condition>Pain Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Resiniferatoxin</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Single dose of Resiniferatoxin (25 mcg in 3 mL) injected epidurally</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard of care treatment as determined by the investigator</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resiniferatoxin</intervention_name>
    <description>Resiniferatoxin is a TRPV-1 agonist which works by specifically ablating nociceptive nerve fibers.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Resiniferatoxin</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>RTX</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard of Care</intervention_name>
    <description>Standard of care for intractable pain with the exception of intra-thecal pump placement as determined by the investigator.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>SOC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Histologically confirmed clinical diagnosis of advanced cancer or metastasis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain in the target area (lower thoracic or chest level down to lower extremities) most&#xD;
             likely attributed to cancer as per Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pain severity at the target area is moderate-to-severe, defined as worst pain ≥6 on&#xD;
             the NPRS during screening (average of the 3 days prior to Day 1), despite available&#xD;
             pain therapy or analgesia. Subjects with multiple sites of pain are eligible as long&#xD;
             as the intensity of pain at the intended target location for treatment fulfills the&#xD;
             score of ≥6 and can be differentiated from other areas.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must report NPRS scores in the daily diary for at least 3 days prior to Day 1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be at least 18 years of age or older at Screening.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has reasonable expectation that they will be able to complete the study&#xD;
             (through at least the week 4 visit).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Life expectancy of at least 6 months at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Minimum Karnofsky score of 50 at screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sexually active female participants of childbearing potential must be willing to use&#xD;
             an effective method of contraceptive method to avoid pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must have provided written informed consent which includes signing the institutional&#xD;
             review board approved consent form prior to participating in any study related&#xD;
             activity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be willing and capable of understanding and cooperating with the requirements of&#xD;
             the study, including the ability to perform/undergo all required assessments for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must be able to understand, and complete study related forms and adequately&#xD;
             communicate with the investigator and/or site staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing or have plans to undergo changes to current cancer treatment from 7 days&#xD;
             prior to Day 1 to 4 weeks after Day 1. Continuation of existing anti-cancer therapy&#xD;
             without any planned change in dose or regimen is permitted. Participants may receive&#xD;
             new cancer therapy 4 weeks after Day 1 including investigational agents in another&#xD;
             clinical trial while participating in this study. If participating in another trial,&#xD;
             it is requested that the subject agree to continue clinic visits and completion of&#xD;
             patient diaries in this trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with leptomeningeal metastases in the lumbar area.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Level of intended epidural injection is in the site of prior lumbar spine surgical&#xD;
             procedures, such as posterior spinal fusions, that could impair the ability to perform&#xD;
             the injection, as assessed by the Investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of increased intracranial pressure as determined by symptoms, history,&#xD;
             physical examination, and/or magnetic resonance imaging (MRI).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with an intra-thecal pump implanted within 2 weeks of the baseline visit will&#xD;
             be excluded. Pump placement during the study will not be permitted for 4 weeks after&#xD;
             the study drug is administered; and existing pump medications cannot be changed during&#xD;
             that same initial 4 week period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has evidence of a non-correctable coagulopathy or hemostasis problem at Screening (V1)&#xD;
             or Baseline (V2) as defined by:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prothrombin Time/International Normalized Ratio ≥1.3 times upper limit of normal (ULN)&#xD;
             range with blood drawn within 1 week of the planned injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Partial thromboplastin time ≥1.5times upper limit of normal (ULN) with blood drawn&#xD;
             within 1 week of the planned injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &lt;75,000 cells/mm3 with blood drawn within 1 week of the planned&#xD;
             injection. Participants must stop any anticoagulant (e.g., warfarin) or antiplatelet&#xD;
             (e.g., aspirin) before and during IP administration according to acceptable medical&#xD;
             guidelines. Participants with abnormal PT or PTT at Screening, but whose PT or PTT is&#xD;
             expected to normalize once anticoagulation is held, are eligible as long as the PT or&#xD;
             PTT has normalized prior to the planned injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with a total neutrophil count &lt;750 cells/mm3 at Screening (V1) or&#xD;
             Baseline (V2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is febrile or has other evidence of an infection within 24 hours of the planned&#xD;
             injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Has an allergy or hypersensitivity to capsaicin, or radiographic contrast agents used&#xD;
             in diagnostic imaging studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female participants who are pregnant at Screening (V1) or Day 1 (V2), are planning on&#xD;
             becoming pregnant, or are currently breastfeeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with any medical condition that, in the Investigator's opinion, could&#xD;
             adversely impact study participation or safety, the conduct of the study, or interfere&#xD;
             with the pain assessments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants with additional loci of pain above the midthoracic level or other pain&#xD;
             disorder due to noncancer etiology at Screening (V1), unless both the investigator and&#xD;
             the subject are clearly able to distinguish this pain from the target pain due to&#xD;
             cancer.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-study related minor surgical procedure ≤2 days or major surgical procedure ≤7 days&#xD;
             prior to the Screening Visit. In all cases, the subject must be sufficiently recovered&#xD;
             and stable prior to IP administration on D1.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participants who have not recovered from any toxicities from previous chemotherapy,&#xD;
             hormone therapy, immunotherapy, or radiotherapies that are Grade 3 or higher by CTCAE.&#xD;
             Participants are eligible if the toxicities are Grade 2 or less, as long as all other&#xD;
             inclusion/exclusion criteria are fulfilled.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Arterial thrombi (including stroke), myocardial infarction, admission for unstable&#xD;
             angina, within 3 months prior to Screening (V1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence or history of bleeding disorder, i.e., any hemorrhage or bleeding event of&#xD;
             CTCAE &gt;Grade 2 within 4 weeks prior to D1.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Monica Luchi, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Sorrento Therapeutics</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <verification_date>November 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 29, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>November 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">November 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>pain</keyword>
  <keyword>cancer pain</keyword>
  <keyword>intractable pain</keyword>
  <keyword>RTX</keyword>
  <keyword>resiniferatoxin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cancer Pain</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pain, Intractable</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

