<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04570592</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>USM/JEPeM/1809426</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04570592</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Granisetron vs Granisetron and Dexamethasone on the Reduction of Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</brief_title>
  <official_title>Granisetron vs Granisetron and Dexamethasone on the Reduction of Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting After Caesarean Section With Intrathecal Morphine: A Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universiti Sains Malaysia</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universiti Sains Malaysia</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Intrathecal morphine (ITM) has proven to be excellent in reducing postoperative pain.&#xD;
      However, its use has commonly been associated with the occurrence of postoperative nausea and&#xD;
      vomiting (PONV). In recent years, the combination therapy of antiemetics comprising of a&#xD;
      serotonin receptor antagonist and corticosteroid has been implemented to diminish the&#xD;
      occurrence of PONV. Despite being routinely used, the evidence in the efficacy of this&#xD;
      combination in parturients are conflicting and lacking. In this study, we wish to compare the&#xD;
      efficacy between the combination therapy of granisetron plus dexamethasone versus granisetron&#xD;
      alone on the occurrence of postoperative nausea and vomiting (PONV) in 126 parturients&#xD;
      undergoing elective Caesarean delivery supplemented with intrathecal morphine.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      126 parturients aged between 18 and 45 years old who falls within the American Society of&#xD;
      Anaesthesiology (ASA) physical status I and II undergoing Caesarean deliveries from the 1st&#xD;
      of October 2020 till the 1st of April 2021 will be enrolled. Informed and written consent&#xD;
      shall be obtained on recruitment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will be randomised using a computer-generated randomisation software using block&#xD;
      size 3 into 2 groups; group A and group B each consisting of 63 subjects. The order of&#xD;
      interventions within each block was random as determined by computer random number generator.&#xD;
      This technique was chosen to ensure similar numbers of patients in each group at any point&#xD;
      during the study. Both patients and the assessors of PONV which is the Acute Pain Service&#xD;
      (APS) team will be blinded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are subjected to fasting 6 hours prior to surgery with clear fluid allowed up to 2&#xD;
      hours before surgery. Intravenous (IV) metaclopromide 10mg, IV ranitidine 50mg and mist&#xD;
      sodium citrate 30 mls will be administered as part of the acid aspiration prophylaxis.&#xD;
      Standard monitoring with continuous noninvasive blood pressure monitoring (NIBP),&#xD;
      electrocardiogram (ECG), respiratory rate and pulse oximetry (SpO2) will be implemented&#xD;
      throughout anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ringer's lactate solution 10ml/kg will be infused for coloading to mitigate hypotension post&#xD;
      spinal anaesthesia. Spinal anaesthesia will be administered in the upright position,&#xD;
      implementing a height-based dose for heavy bupivacaine 0.5% administration. Based on the&#xD;
      subject's height, those who are less than 150cm, 151-154cm and those who are more than 155cm&#xD;
      will receive 1.5mls, 1.7mls and 1.9mls heavy bupivacaine 0.5% (AstraZeneca) respectively.&#xD;
      Fentanyl 15-20 mcg and morphine 0.1 mg are added to supplement the spinal anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      On the completion of spinal anaesthesia, 4 mg of dexamethasone will be administered to&#xD;
      parturients in group A while group B received 1ml of normal saline injected intravenously.&#xD;
      1mg of IV granisetron will be administered to both groups of subjects after cord clamping.&#xD;
      These drugs will be given by the anaesthetist administering the spinal anaethesia. The&#xD;
      anaesthetist in charge is not blinded as this is of paramount importance in ensuring patients&#xD;
      safety should any complication arises during the delivery of anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Post surgery, subjects will be monitored in the recovery area for an hour. To supplement ITM&#xD;
      as the postoperative analgesia, tablet paracetamol 1g qid and voltaren 50mg tds will be&#xD;
      provided to patients postoperatively. The use of opioid is avoided during the first 24 hours&#xD;
      of intrathecal morphine administration. Patients will be monitored for complications of ITM&#xD;
      for 24 hours and assessments will be carried out by the APS team which include an anaesthetic&#xD;
      medical officer and 2 staff nurses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessments are made at 1 hour post surgery, 4 hourly for 12 hours post surgery up to 24&#xD;
      hours after surgery. Episodes of nausea, retching and vomiting will be elicited by direct&#xD;
      questioning and recorded at each assessors' visit. Nausea is described as an unpleasant&#xD;
      sensation related to the urge to vomit. Retching is defined as an involuntary effort to vomit&#xD;
      but without the expulsion of the gastric contents, while vomiting is the when expulsion of&#xD;
      gastric contents occur.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The requirement of rescue antiemetics at each time interval will also be documented. Rescue&#xD;
      antiemetic is given when a patient developed one or more episodes of vomiting. IV ondansetron&#xD;
      4 mg is given to group A while either IV dexamethasone 4mg or iv ondansetron is given to&#xD;
      group B. Subsequent requirement of antiemetics will be decided based on the anaesthetist&#xD;
      discretion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size is calculated based the assumption that the combination of a serotonin receptor&#xD;
      antagonist with a corticosteroid would be superior than its monotherapy and thus, the&#xD;
      addition of dexamethasone to granisetron would reduce the incidence of PONV from 20% to 3.3%.&#xD;
      From the calculation using PS software, the sample required for each group is 57, and with&#xD;
      the additional 10% for dropout rate, this study required 63 patients in each group, giving a&#xD;
      total of 126 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data analysis will be performed using SPSS version 27 for MAC. The incidences of nausea,&#xD;
      retching, vomiting and the use of rescue antiemetic will be analysed using Chi-Square test.&#xD;
      Data is presented as percentage and a p-value of &lt;0.05 is considered statistically&#xD;
      significant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparing the incidence of post operative nausea and vomiting (PONV)</measure>
    <time_frame>From 1 to 24 hour post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the incidence of nausea, retching and vomiting at 1 hour, 4 hourly for 12 hours and at 24 hours postoperatively between parturients receiving combination therapy of Granisetron plus Dexamethasone versus that of Granisetron alone</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparing the requirement of rescue antiemetic between both groups</measure>
    <time_frame>From 1 to 24 hour post operatively</time_frame>
    <description>To compare the requirement of rescue antiemetic between 1 hour, 4 hourly for 12 hours and at 24 hours postoperatively between parturients receiving combination therapy of Granisetron plus Dexamethasone versus that of Granisetron alone</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">126</enrollment>
  <condition>PONV</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Granisetron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Granisetron 1 mg (1ml) + Normal saline 1ml</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Granisetron and Dexamethasone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Granisetron 1mg (1ml) + Dexamethasone 4mg (1ml)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Granisetron 1 Mg/mL Intravenous Solution And Dexamethasone 4mg</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparing PONV incidences in both arms</description>
    <arm_group_label>Granisetron and Dexamethasone</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Treatment group</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Granisetron 1 Mg/mL Intravenous Solution</intervention_name>
    <description>Comparing PONV incidences in both arms</description>
    <arm_group_label>Granisetron</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  American Society of Anaesthesiologists (ASA) I-II category&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  2 risks factors or more for PONV according to Apfel Score.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unfit for spinal anaesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Coagulopathy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Uncorrected hypovolemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Indeterminate neurologic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Infection at site of injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Raised intracranial pressure(ICP)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Morbidly obese patients, BMI&gt; 40 kg/m2 according to ICD-10 (International Statistical&#xD;
             Classification of Diseases 10)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients allergic towards morphine.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindicated for antiemetics use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Granisetron: allergy towards Granisetron, prolonged QT interval&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Ondansetron: allergy towards ondansetron, prolonged QT interval&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Dexamethasone: allergy towards Dexamethasone, uncontrolled Diabetes Mellitus (DM).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>Parturients</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Farah Nasuha Mohd Daut</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universiti Sains Malaysia, Health Campus, Kubang Kerian, Kelantan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universiti Sains Malaysia, Health Campus</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kubang Kerian</city>
        <state>Kelantan</state>
        <zip>16150</zip>
        <country>Malaysia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Associate Professor W Mohd Nazarudin W Hassan</last_name>
      <phone>09-7673000</phone>
      <phone_ext>6105</phone_ext>
      <email>nazarudin@usm.my</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Malaysia</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gwirtz KH, Young JV, Byers RS, Alley C, Levin K, Walker SG, Stoelting RK. The safety and efficacy of intrathecal opioid analgesia for acute postoperative pain: seven years' experience with 5969 surgical patients at Indiana University Hospital. Anesth Analg. 1999 Mar;88(3):599-604.</citation>
    <PMID>10072014</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Sfeir S, Mansour N. Post operative analgesia with intrathecal morphine. Middle East J Anaesthesiol. 2005 Feb;18(1):133-9.</citation>
    <PMID>15830768</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dahl JB, Jeppesen IS, Jørgensen H, Wetterslev J, Møiniche S. Intraoperative and postoperative analgesic efficacy and adverse effects of intrathecal opioids in patients undergoing cesarean section with spinal anesthesia: a qualitative and quantitative systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Anesthesiology. 1999 Dec;91(6):1919-27. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10598635</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Apfel CC, Korttila K, Abdalla M, Kerger H, Turan A, Vedder I, Zernak C, Danner K, Jokela R, Pocock SJ, Trenkler S, Kredel M, Biedler A, Sessler DI, Roewer N; IMPACT Investigators. A factorial trial of six interventions for the prevention of postoperative nausea and vomiting. N Engl J Med. 2004 Jun 10;350(24):2441-51.</citation>
    <PMID>15190136</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Abouleish E, Rawal N, Fallon K, Hernandez D. Combined intrathecal morphine and bupivacaine for cesarean section. Anesth Analg. 1988 Apr;67(4):370-4.</citation>
    <PMID>3354872</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>September 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 19, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 29, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 29, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 29, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universiti Sains Malaysia</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Farah Nasuha Mohd Daut</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Trainee Anaesthetist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Caesarean</keyword>
  <keyword>Morphine</keyword>
  <keyword>Granisetron</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vomiting</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Postoperative Nausea and Vomiting</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dexamethasone</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Granisetron</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pharmaceutical Solutions</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will be considered for sharing if the data is to be used for related studies.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

