<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04571411</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>scorpion sting in children</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04571411</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Severity of Scorpion Sting in Relation to Hematological Parameters</brief_title>
  <official_title>Severity of Scorpion Sting in Relation to Hematological Parameters</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to investigate the relationship between severity of envenomation and&#xD;
      hematological parameter by detectig initial mean platelet volume (MPV), neutrophil/lymphocyte&#xD;
      ratio (NLR) and platelet/lymphocyte ratio (PLR) in pediatric patients presenting with a&#xD;
      scorpion sting.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Scorpion stings are common emergency events in many parts of the world. It is common in&#xD;
      tropical and subtropical regions. In our locality, Upper Egypt, scorpions still represent and&#xD;
      a life hazard, especially to children .The clinical manifestations of scorpionism are due to&#xD;
      complex interactions between sympathetic and parasympathetic stimulation.This leads to&#xD;
      increased release of neurotransmitters and mediators, resulting in a cascade of pathological&#xD;
      events, involving the nervous system, the cardiovascular and the respiratory system,&#xD;
      eventually leading to death.Scorpionism results in hormonal and biochemical changes with&#xD;
      significant release of catecholamines, increased angiotensin II and inhibition of insulin&#xD;
      secretion .The symptoms and signs of envenomation are usually more severe in children,&#xD;
      especially younger ones. Local pain represent 66 to 90 percent of stings which is practically&#xD;
      immediate, of varying intensity ranging from mild to very intense. It is characterized by&#xD;
      tingling, burning, or stinging. Regardless of the severity of envenoming, pain and&#xD;
      paresthesia may persist at the site or at the affected limb for several days .Systemic&#xD;
      effects become apparent in 10 to 33 percent of patients.After envenomation, symptoms may&#xD;
      begin immediately and typically progress to maximum severity within 5 hours. The clinical&#xD;
      effects of stings are characterized, cardiovascular, neurological and gastrointestinal&#xD;
      effects .Cardiovascular effects are atrial tachycardia, ventricular extrasystoles, T-wave&#xD;
      inversion, ST-T wave changes, bundle-branch block. Catecholamine-induced myocarditis and&#xD;
      myocardial ischemia results in pulmonary edema and cardiogenic shock.Cardiovascular effects&#xD;
      are atrial tachycardia, ventricular extrasystoles, T-wave inversion, ST-T wave changes,&#xD;
      bundle-branch block. Catecholamine-induced myocarditis and myocardial ischemia results in&#xD;
      pulmonary edema and cardiogenic shock..Gastrointestinal effects: are vomiting, abdominal pain&#xD;
      and diarrhea. Also acute pancreatitis has been reported.Cardiovascular toxic effects and&#xD;
      acute pulmonary edema are the most important complications of scorpion stings and the most&#xD;
      frequent cause of death in the first 24 hours after the sting .Gastrointestinal effects: are&#xD;
      vomiting, abdominal pain and diarrhea. Also acute pancreatitis has been&#xD;
      reported.Cardiovascular toxic effects and acute pulmonary edema are the most important&#xD;
      complications of scorpion stings and the most frequent cause of death in the first 24 hours&#xD;
      after the sting .&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The aim of this study is to investigate the relationship between severity of envenomation and hematological parameter</measure>
    <time_frame>baseline</time_frame>
    <description>All patient will be conducted to:&#xD;
full history including: (Age, gender, weight, time and date of presentation&#xD;
Full examination including : local&#xD;
General Cardiac examination Chest examination</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Scorpion Stings</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>CBC</intervention_name>
    <description>The aim of this study is to investigate the relationship between severity of envenomation and hematological parameter by detectig initial mean platelet volume (MPV), neutrophil/lymphocyte ratio (NLR) and platelet/lymphocyte ratio (PLR) in pediatric patients presenting with a scorpion sting.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        study on children stung by scorpion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  a) Patients presented with scorpion sting&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All other envenomation or intoxications&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yasser Gamal Abl Elrahman, lecture</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sarah Osama Mohamed, master</last_name>
    <phone>01026662002</phone>
    <email>saso_monier_2020@yahoo.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Azza Ahmed Eltayeb, professor</last_name>
    <phone>01006863277</phone>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Adiguzel S, Ozkan O, Inceoglu B. Epidemiological and clinical characteristics of scorpionism in children in Sanliurfa, Turkey. Toxicon. 2007 May;49(6):875-80. Epub 2007 Jan 10.</citation>
    <PMID>17286998</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Shamoon Z, Peterfy RJ, Hammoud S, Khazaeni B. Scorpion Toxicity. 2021 Aug 12. StatPearls [Internet]. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2021 Jan-. Available from http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK430928/</citation>
    <PMID>28613678</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chippaux JP. Estimating the global burden of snakebite can help to improve management. PLoS Med. 2008 Nov 4;5(11):e221. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.0050221.</citation>
    <PMID>18986211</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ahmed AE, Abdel-Baseer KA, Saad K, Hassan AF, El-Houfey AA. Endocrinological and biochemical changes of scorpionism in children in Upper Egypt. Ther Adv Endocrinol Metab. 2015 Oct;6(5):210-6. doi: 10.1177/2042018815593034.</citation>
    <PMID>26445643</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ait Laaradia M, El Hidan MA, Marhoume F, Bouimeja B, Oufquir S, Sokar Z, Boumezzough A, Chait A. Buthus lienhardi venom and pathophysiological effects at the histological, hematological, biochemical and motor skills levels. Toxicon. 2018 May;146:106-113. doi: 10.1016/j.toxicon.2018.03.001. Epub 2018 Mar 9.</citation>
    <PMID>29526539</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Horoz ÖÖ, Yıldızdaş D, Aslan N, Gökay SS, Ekinci F, Erdem S, Haytoğlu Z, Sertdemir Y, Yılmaz HL. Is there any relationship between initial hematological parameters and severity of scorpion envenomation? Turk J Pediatr. 2020;62(3):394-404. doi: 10.24953/turkjped.2020.03.006.</citation>
    <PMID>32558413</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Cupo P. Clinical update on scorpion envenoming. Rev Soc Bras Med Trop. 2015 Nov-Dec;48(6):642-9. doi: 10.1590/0037-8682-0237-2015. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>26676487</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chippaux JP. Management of scorpion stings in Africa and the Mediterranean region. Med Sante Trop. 2016 May 1;26(2):130-3. doi: 10.1684/mst.2016.0571.</citation>
    <PMID>27412972</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 25, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 25, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 1, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 12, 2020</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 14, 2020</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sarah Osama Mohamed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Resident Doctor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Bites and Stings</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Scorpion Stings</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

