<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04578327</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>A3282-W</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>1IK2RX003282-01A2</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04578327</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Investigation of Embodiment for Upper Limb Amputees</brief_title>
  <acronym>NISRL</acronym>
  <official_title>Investigation of Embodiment for Upper Limb Amputees</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>VA Office of Research and Development</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>VA Office of Research and Development</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_unapproved_device>Yes</is_unapproved_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Today, prosthetic hands are numb. They provide no tactile or proprioceptive sensory&#xD;
      information back to the user. The lack of sensory feedback has been shown to reduce the&#xD;
      utility of a prosthesis by half. The prosthesis is seen as a tool, not as an incorporated&#xD;
      part of the body schema. Only now are there chronically-implantable technologies which can&#xD;
      provide physiologically appropriate sensory feedback to upper limb amputees to recreate&#xD;
      tactile and proprioceptive percepts. These sensations are the building blocks to enable the&#xD;
      embodiment of the device. Furthermore, newly developed outcome measures are now available&#xD;
      which can detail the improved embodiment such neural interfaces can create. The&#xD;
      investigator's mission is to enable the embodiment of artificial devices using peripheral&#xD;
      nerve stimulation and thereby close the gap between the experience of our intact&#xD;
      physiological systems and those using prosthetic remedies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This investigation of embodiment for upper limb amputees is organized into three main areas&#xD;
      of work including 1) normative data collection, 2) device development, and 3)&#xD;
      characterization of embodiment using peripheral nerve stimulation. The normative data&#xD;
      collection will quantify the embodiment of conventional cosmetic, body-powered, and&#xD;
      myoelectric prosthetic hand options using a modified Rubber Hand Illusion protocol (Specific&#xD;
      Aim 1). This thrust will ask how does the amount of embodiment vary among conventional&#xD;
      prosthetic hands as well as probe the relationship between agency and embodiment. The device&#xD;
      development project entails the design of multi-modal sensors in order to study full-hand&#xD;
      embodiment (Specific Aim 2). The ability to measure and then elicit sensation on the passive&#xD;
      surfaces of the hand (palm, ulnar border, and dorsal surface) has never been explored. Here,&#xD;
      a multi-modal sensor which can detect proximity, contact, and force will be integrated into a&#xD;
      commercially available prosthetic hand in order to provide detailed measurements across the&#xD;
      palm, ulnar border, and dorsal surfaces in order to study embodiment in more depth. Finally,&#xD;
      the characterization of embodiment using peripheral nerve stimulation will take place over a&#xD;
      multiple subject factorial experiment which quantifies the effects of quantity and spatial&#xD;
      parameters of the peripheral nerve stimulation on the embodiment of prosthetic hands&#xD;
      (Specific Aim 3). This study asks what somatosensory percepts from the hand are most critical&#xD;
      for embodiment by varying the parameters of the peripheral nerve stimulation (quantity and&#xD;
      spatiality) and measuring the level of embodiment in each case.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Leveraging advancements in neural interfaces, biomechatronic devices, and myoelectric control&#xD;
      algorithms, my research mission is to enable the embodiment of artificial devices by&#xD;
      providing physiologically appropriate somatosensory feedback.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 1: How does the amount of embodiment vary among conventional prosthetic hands?.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from Specific Aim 1 will be used to test the following hypotheses: H1a. The body-powered&#xD;
      prosthetic devices are embodied more than passive and myoelectric prosthetic devices. H1b.&#xD;
      Passive cosmetic devices are embodied less than actuated cosmetic devices (agency). H1c.&#xD;
      Body-powered terminal devices are embodied less than myoelectric terminal devices (agency).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Specific Aim 2: Design of Multi-Modal Sensors for Full Hand Sensation (No human subject&#xD;
      experiments.) Specific Aim 3: What somatosensory percepts from the hand are most critical for&#xD;
      embodiment? Data from Specific Aim 3 will be used to test the following hypotheses: H3a. The&#xD;
      maximum number of channels elicits more embodiment than the minimum number. H3b. The sensory&#xD;
      feedback from passive spatial locations of the hand increases the embodiment compared to&#xD;
      sensory feedback just from the grasping spatial locations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2, 2022</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Non-Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Aim 1 - An experiment will take place grouped by the type of prosthesis used by upper limb amputees Aim 3 - An experiment will take place grouped by type of sensory restoration</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Basic Science</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Southampton Hand Assessment Procedure</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Scores the ability of the user to perform activities of daily living using the prosthetic system.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Experience Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Assesses the subject's perspective on the embodiment of the prosthetic system. The Patient Experience Measure (PEM) is a validated outcome measure which uses a survey to identify the experience of the person with amputation. The qualitative and quantitative survey produces outcome measures identifying the patient experience across multiple modalities.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">19</enrollment>
  <condition>Amputation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aim 1</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Data from Specific Aim 1 will be used to test the following hypotheses: H1a. The body-powered prosthetic devices are embodied more than passive and myoelectric prosthetic devices. H1b. Passive cosmetic devices are embodied less than actuated cosmetic devices (agency). H1c. Body-powered terminal devices are embodied less than myoelectric terminal devices (agency).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Aim 3</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Data from Specific Aim 3 will be used to test the following hypotheses: H3a. The maximum number of channels elicits more embodiment than the minimum number. H3b. The sensory feedback from passive spatial locations of the hand increases the embodiment compared to sensory feedback just from the grasping spatial locations.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prosthetic hand</intervention_name>
    <description>Different types of conventional prosthetic limbs will be used by subjects.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aim 1</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Peripheral Nerve Interface</intervention_name>
    <description>Different types of peripheral nerve stimulation will take place</description>
    <arm_group_label>Aim 3</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects will be either able bodied or have an upper limb difference.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Both Veterans and non-Veterans will be eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -No other musculoskeletal injuries.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jacob L. Segil, PhD MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Rocky Mountain Regional VA Medical Center, Aurora, CO</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jacob L Segil, PhD MS</last_name>
    <phone>(303) 399-8020</phone>
    <email>jacob.segil@colorado.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pamela Rice, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>(303) 399-8020</phone>
    <phone_ext>3846</phone_ext>
    <email>Pamela.Rice@va.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rocky Mountain Regional VA Medical Center, Aurora, CO</name>
      <address>
        <city>Aurora</city>
        <state>Colorado</state>
        <zip>80045</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pamela Rice, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>303-399-8020</phone>
      <phone_ext>3846</phone_ext>
      <email>Pamela.Rice@va.gov</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Laurie P Grevious</last_name>
      <phone>(720) 857-5107</phone>
      <email>Laurie.Grevious@va.gov</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jacob L. Segil, PhD MS</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>June 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>July 6, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">June 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>amputation</keyword>
  <keyword>sensation</keyword>
  <keyword>neural interface</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

