<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04570410</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-SR-264</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04570410</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Primary Excision Combined With Preoperative Neoadjuvant and Adjuvant Therapy for Oligometastasis of Urothelial Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>Trials of Primary Excision Combined With Preoperative Neoadjuvant Therapy and Adjuvant Therapy Was Used as a First-line Comprehensive Therapy for Oligometastasis of Urothelial Carcinoma（UC）.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The First Affiliated Hospital with Nanjing Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The First Affiliated Hospital with Nanjing Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      treatment of primary focal resection plus lymph node dissection combined with chemotherapy&#xD;
      and anti-programmed cell death 1(PD-1) for Oligometastasis of urothelial carcinoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed to demonstrate that Whether the perioperative comprehensive treatment&#xD;
      of primary focal resection plus lymph node dissection combined with chemotherapy and&#xD;
      anti-PD-1 can prolong the overall survival of patients, narrow the range of metastatic&#xD;
      lesions and improve the quality of life of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Compared with patients with extensive metastasis, 2-year tumor-specific survival and overall&#xD;
      survival of patients with oligometastatic bladder cancer were significantly increased (53.3%&#xD;
      vs 16.1%)；(51.9% vs. 15.4%).Gemcitabine plus cisplatin (GC) regimen has been shown to bring&#xD;
      clinical benefits in neoadjuvant therapy of metastatic UC（urothelial carcinoma）.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PD-1 inhibitors have been widely used in urothelial carcinoma in recent years, and positive&#xD;
      data have been obtained in both advanced patients and neoadjuvant patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      If successful in this trial, it will serve to provide a therapeutic alternative for this&#xD;
      patient who have oligometastasis of urothelial carcinoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>1 year overall survival(OS) rate</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>the percentage of patients who die of any cause within first year of treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>progression-free survival(PFS)</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>time between the first objective recording of PD(progressive disease) or death from any cause (whichever occurs first) from random group solstice</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">15</enrollment>
  <condition>Bladder Urothelial Carcinoma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup1:Patients who can tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>GC plus Tislelizumab Participants receive GC (Gemcitabine plus cisplatin), in combination with Tislelizumab administered intravenously (IV) every 3 weeks (Q3W) before surgery.Immunotherapy was continued for 6 months after excision of the primary lesion.&#xD;
Intervention/treatment： Biological: Tislelizumab Tislelizumab IV infusion of 200 mg Q3W&#xD;
Biological: GC GC (Gemcitabine plus cisplatin): Gemcitabine 1000mg/m2 D1,D8 iv every 3 weeks Cisplatin70mg/m2,D2,3,4 iv every 3 weeks</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup2:Patients who cannot tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Tislelizumab Participants receive Tislelizumab administered intravenously (IV) every 3 weeks (Q3W) before surgery.Immunotherapy was continued for 6 months after excision of the primary lesion.&#xD;
Intervention/treatment： Biological: Tislelizumab Tislelizumab IV infusion of 200 mg Q3W</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>primary focal resection plus lymph node dissection</intervention_name>
    <description>Primary radical resection plus lymph node dissection was performed in patients with oligometastatic urothelial carcinoma</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup1:Patients who can tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup2:Patients who cannot tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Tislelizumab</intervention_name>
    <description>Tislelizumab IV infusion of 200 mg Q3W</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup1:Patients who can tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup2:Patients who cannot tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>PD-1</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Gemcitabine plus cisplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>GC (Gemcitabine plus cisplatin): Gemcitabine 1000mg/m2 D1,D8 iv every 3 weeks Cisplatin70mg/m2,D2,3,4 iv every 3 weeks</description>
    <arm_group_label>Subgroup1:Patients who can tolerate cisplatin chemotherapy</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>GC</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with oligometastatic urothelial carcinoma, including :patients with T2-T4&#xD;
             with any metastasis(T4NxM1) urothelial carcinoma diagnosed by pathology and evaluated&#xD;
             by imaging; A. a solitary metastatic organ, B. number of metastatic lesions of ≤3, C.&#xD;
             the largest diameter of metastatic foci of ≤5cm, D. absence of liver metastasis.The&#xD;
             researchers assessed the benefits of excision of the primary lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  18 to 75 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Volunteer to participate in the trial, be able to provide a written informed consent,&#xD;
             and understand and agree to comply with the study requirements and evaluation&#xD;
             schedule.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Eastern Cooperative Oncology Group (ECOG) performance status &lt;2&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  International standardized ratio or activated partial thrombin time ≤1.5 upper limit&#xD;
             of normal value (ULN);The calculated creatinine clearance rate was ≥60ml/min;Serum&#xD;
             total bilirubin ≤1.5×ULN;aspartate transaminase(AST), Alanine transaminase(ALT) and&#xD;
             alkaline phosphatase ≤2.5×ULN;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-pregnant or fertile men or women must be willing to take effective contraceptive&#xD;
             measures during the study period and ≥120 days after the last administration of&#xD;
             tislelizumab, and the women should be negative on urine or serum pregnancy test&#xD;
             results less than or equal to 7 days before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous therapy targeted at PD-1, PD-L1, PD-L2, Cytotoxic T-Lymphocyte Associated&#xD;
             Protein 4(CTLA-4)or other antibodies or drugs specifically targeting T cell&#xD;
             synergistic stimulation or checkpoint channels.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other approved systemic anti-cancer therapies or systemic immune modulators (including&#xD;
             but not limited to interferon, interleukin-2, and tumor necrosis factor) were received&#xD;
             within 28 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe chronic or active infections requiring systemic antimicrobial, antifungal, or&#xD;
             antiviral therapy within 14 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Major surgery or major trauma occurred within 28 days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Live vaccine was administered within 28 days before enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Received any herbal or proprietary Chinese medicine used to control cancer in the 14&#xD;
             days prior to enrollment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active autoimmune disease requiring long-term use of large amounts of hormones and&#xD;
             other immunosuppressive agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The researchers identified abnormalities in potassium, sodium, calcium, or&#xD;
             hypoalbuminemia, interstitial lung disease, non-infectious pneumonia, or other&#xD;
             uncontrolled whole-body diseases, including diabetes, hypertension, and cardiovascular&#xD;
             disease, that may affect treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of HIV, hepatitis B virus(HBV)and hepatitis C virus(HCV) infection is known.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A history of known allergic reactions to any of the drugs studied.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Is participating in additional clinical studies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The researcher believes that the patient is not suitable to participate in this study&#xD;
             (such as the treatment that does not meet the patient's greatest benefit, patient&#xD;
             compliance, etc.)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Qiang Lv</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital with Nanjing Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Qikai Wu</last_name>
    <phone>18855179805</phone>
    <email>wuqikaidd@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pengchao Li</last_name>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>The first affiliated hospital of Nanjing Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nanjing</city>
        <state>Jiangsu</state>
        <zip>210000</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Qiang Lu, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>13505196501</phone>
      <email>dxhlvqiang@163.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Pengchao Li, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>13584025756</phone>
      <email>superkulian@aliyun.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Erratum: Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2020 Jul;70(4):313. doi: 10.3322/caac.21609. Epub 2020 Apr 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32767693</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosenberg JE, Carroll PR, Small EJ. Update on chemotherapy for advanced bladder cancer. J Urol. 2005 Jul;174(1):14-20. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>15947569</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bajorin DF, Dodd PM, Mazumdar M, Fazzari M, McCaffrey JA, Scher HI, Herr H, Higgins G, Boyle MG. Long-term survival in metastatic transitional-cell carcinoma and prognostic factors predicting outcome of therapy. J Clin Oncol. 1999 Oct;17(10):3173-81.</citation>
    <PMID>10506615</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hellman S, Weichselbaum RR. Oligometastases. J Clin Oncol. 1995 Jan;13(1):8-10.</citation>
    <PMID>7799047</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Seisen T, Sun M, Leow JJ, Preston MA, Cole AP, Gelpi-Hammerschmidt F, Hanna N, Meyer CP, Kibel AS, Lipsitz SR, Nguyen PL, Bellmunt J, Choueiri TK, Trinh QD. Efficacy of High-Intensity Local Treatment for Metastatic Urothelial Carcinoma of the Bladder: A Propensity Score-Weighted Analysis From the National Cancer Data Base. J Clin Oncol. 2016 Oct 10;34(29):3529-3536. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2016.66.7352.</citation>
    <PMID>27269944</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dong F, Shen Y, Gao F, Xu T, Wang X, Zhang X, Zhong S, Zhang M, Chen S, Shen Z. Prognostic value of site-specific metastases and therapeutic roles of surgery for patients with metastatic bladder cancer: a population-based study. Cancer Manag Res. 2017 Nov 14;9:611-626. doi: 10.2147/CMAR.S148856. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29180897</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Horwich A, Babjuk M, Bellmunt J, Bruins HM, De Reijke TM, De Santis M, Gillessen S, James N, Maclennan S, Palou J, Powles T, Ribal MJ, Shariat SF, Van Der Kwast T, Xylinas E, Agarwal N, Arends T, Bamias A, Birtle A, Black PC, Bochner BH, Bolla M, Boormans JL, Bossi A, Briganti A, Brummelhuis I, Burger M, Castellano D, Cathomas R, Chiti A, Choudhury A, Compérat E, Crabb S, Culine S, De Bari B, DeBlok W, De Visschere PJL, Decaestecker K, Dimitropoulos K, Dominguez-Escrig JL, Fanti S, Fonteyne V, Frydenberg M, Futterer JJ, Gakis G, Geavlete B, Gontero P, Grubmüller B, Hafeez S, Hansel DE, Hartmann A, Hayne D, Henry AM, Hernandez V, Herr H, Herrmann K, Hoskin P, Huguet J, Jereczek-Fossa BA, Jones R, Kamat AM, Khoo V, Kiltie AE, Krege S, Ladoire S, Lara PC, Leliveld A, Linares-Espinós E, Løgager V, Lorch A, Loriot Y, Meijer R, Carmen Mir M, Moschini M, Mostafid H, Müller AC, Müller CR, N'Dow J, Necchi A, Neuzillet Y, Oddens JR, Oldenburg J, Osanto S, Oyen WJG, Pacheco-Figueiredo L, Pappot H, Patel MI, Pieters BR, Plass K, Remzi M, Retz M, Richenberg J, Rink M, Roghmann F, Rosenberg JE, Rouprêt M, Rouvière O, Salembier C, Salminen A, Sargos P, Sengupta S, Sherif A, Smeenk RJ, Smits A, Stenzl A, Thalmann GN, Tombal B, Turkbey B, Vahr Lauridsen S, Valdagni R, Van Der Heijden AG, Van Poppel H, Vartolomei MD, Veskimäe E, Vilaseca A, Vives Rivera FA, Wiegel T, Wiklund P, Williams A, Zigeuner R, Witjes JA. EAU-ESMO consensus statements on the management of advanced and variant bladder cancer-an international collaborative multi-stakeholder effort: under the auspices of the EAU and ESMO Guidelines Committees†. Ann Oncol. 2019 Nov 1;30(11):1697-1727. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdz296.</citation>
    <PMID>31740927</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ogihara K, Kikuchi E, Watanabe K, Kufukihara R, Yanai Y, Takamatsu K, Matsumoto K, Hara S, Oyama M, Monma T, Masuda T, Hasegawa S, Oya M. Can urologists introduce the concept of &quot;oligometastasis&quot; for metastatic bladder cancer after total cystectomy? Oncotarget. 2017 Dec 4;8(67):111819-111835. doi: 10.18632/oncotarget.22911. eCollection 2017 Dec 19.</citation>
    <PMID>29340094</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>November 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 16, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 24, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">September 30, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Oligometastasis</keyword>
  <keyword>PD-1</keyword>
  <keyword>Gemcitabine plus cisplatin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Carcinoma, Transitional Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gemcitabine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

