<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04578314</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>419676143</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04578314</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>RELATE - Efficacy and Feasibility of a Cognitive Behavioural Module for Distressing Auditory Verbal Hallucinations</brief_title>
  <acronym>RELATE</acronym>
  <official_title>RELATE - A Randomized Controlled Trial of a Cognitive Behavioural Module for Distressing Auditory Verbal Hallucinations</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Hamburg-Eppendorf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Leipzig</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Jacobs University Bremen gGmbH</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Hamburg-Eppendorf</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Auditory hallucinations (AH) are associated with distress and reduced functioning.&#xD;
      Psychological interventions show some promising effects on psychopathology but have been less&#xD;
      successful in reducing AH related distress, which patients report to be a priority. Research&#xD;
      suggests that distress is associated with the hearer relating to AH in a passive and&#xD;
      subordinate manner. A novel approach thus teaches assertive responses to AH through the use&#xD;
      of experiential role-plays. A single centre pilot study in the United Kingdom evidenced a&#xD;
      large effect of this approach on AH distress but independent multicentre studies are required&#xD;
      to ascertain effectiveness across different settings. The planned feasibility trial aims to&#xD;
      estimate the expected effect for a subsequent fully powered prospective, randomized,&#xD;
      controlled, parallel-group, two-armed, multicentre, open trial set up to demonstrate that&#xD;
      adding a Relating Module (RM) to Treatment as Usual (TAU) is superior to TAU alone.&#xD;
      Feasibility questions relate to patient recruitment, therapist training and therapy&#xD;
      monitoring in different types of psychological and psychiatric outpatient facilities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Auditory hallucinations (AH) are associated with distress and reduced functioning.&#xD;
      Psychological interventions show some promising effects on psychopathology but have been less&#xD;
      successful in reducing AH related distress, which patients report to be a priority. Research&#xD;
      suggests that distress is associated with the hearer relating to AH in a passive and&#xD;
      subordinate manner. A novel approach thus teaches assertive responses to AH through the use&#xD;
      of experiential role-plays. A single centre pilot study in the United Kingdom evidenced a&#xD;
      large effect of this approach on AH distress but independent multicentre studies are required&#xD;
      to ascertain effectiveness across different settings. The planned feasibility trial aims to&#xD;
      estimate the expected effect for a subsequent fully powered prospective, randomized,&#xD;
      controlled, parallel-group, two-armed, multicentre, open trial set up to demonstrate that&#xD;
      adding a Relating Module (RM) to Treatment as Usual (TAU) is superior to TAU alone.&#xD;
      Feasibility questions relate to patient recruitment, therapist training and therapy&#xD;
      monitoring in different types of psychological and psychiatric outpatient facilities. A total&#xD;
      of 75 patients diagnosed with a schizophrenia spectrum disorder (ICD-10, F2) and persistent&#xD;
      distressing AH will be recruited across 4 sites and receive either 16 50-minute sessions of&#xD;
      RM plus TAU or TAU alone within a 5-months period. Assessments will take place at baseline,&#xD;
      at 5 months (post-intervention) and at 9 months (primary outcome).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>prospective, randomized, controlled, parallel-group, two-armed, multicentre, open trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Psychotic Symptom Rating Scales-AH-Distress factor score (PSYRATS-AH)</measure>
    <time_frame>9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Auditory hallucination associated distress. The distress factor score of the PSYRATS-AH is the primary outcome as this is what has been prioritized by patients and is relevant to functioning. Confirmatory analysis will be conducted based on the intent-to-treat population (ITT), defined on the basis of the ITT principle. The aim is to show that the intervention group is superior to the control meaning that the mean score at 9 months adjusted for the baseline value is lower in the intervention group than in the control group. Lower scores indicate less distress.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time Budget Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Time that ist spent in social and vocational activities</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQuol Quality of Life Scale (EQ-5D-5L)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Columbia Suicide Severity Rating Scale (C-SSRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Patients are interviewed about thoughts of wanting to complete suicide, active suicidal thoughts and intent to act on such thoughts (suicidal ideation, items 1-5) as well as about preparatory acts, aborted, interrupted or actual attempts (suicidal behaviour, 6-9). Completed suicide is rated on item 10. Scores on this scale range from 0 to 43 with higher scores indicating higher suicidal ideation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of rehospitalizations</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Number of hospitalizations after study enrollment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>he Psychotic Symptom Rating Scales - PSYRATS-AH-Frequency</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Frequency of auditory hallucinations. Ranges from 0 to 4 with higher scores indicating higher frequency of auditory hallucinations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient Health Questionnaire-9 (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale measuring depressive symptoms. Total score ranges from 0 to 21with higher scores indicating more severe depressive symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>The Voice and You (VAY)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>To analyse whether the putative intervention effect is explicable by the changes in the processes targeted (improved relating to AH), two self-report scales will measure relating to AH. The VAY is a 29-item measure of interrelating between the hearer and their predominant voice (see above for a description of the development of this measure). Relating is measured across four scales; two concerning the hearer's perception of the relating of the voice-voice dominance and voice intrusiveness; and two concerning the relating of the hearer-hearer distance and hearer dependence. Each item is measured on a four-point scale (0-3). Higher scores indicate more negative relating.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Relating to Voices/Others Questionnaires (APPROVE)</measure>
    <time_frame>5 and 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>The APPROVE consists of two separate scales: A 46-item measure of relating to voices (Approve-Voices); and a 46-item measure of social relating (Approve-Social). The items were preceded by an introductory text inviting participants to &quot;please select the answer that best reflects your typical response to [voices/other people] on the scale 0 (disagree completely) to 10 (agree completely). Where the item is not relevant to you then please select the not applicable (N/A) option&quot;. The following instruction - &quot;When [voices/other people] are being difficult (e.g., treating me badly), I respond by: (...)&quot; is presented before the list of the items (e.g., &quot;Hearing what they are saying but also stating my own views&quot;).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility recruitment</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, approximately two years after recruitment commenced</time_frame>
    <description>Will count the number of patients referred within each site, number of self-referrals within each site, number of referred patients within each site found to be eligible, number and proportion of consenting and eligible participants who attend 5-month and 9 month assessment within each site</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Feasibility completeness</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, approximately 3 years after first participant has been randomized</time_frame>
    <description>Will count the number and proportion of consenting participants within the RM condition who reach the point of therapy 'exposure' (attended at least 8 of 16 therapy sessions), percentage of complete of data sets</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Therapist adherence</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 4 weeks after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>All therapy sessions will be audio-recorded. For the first participant for each therapist, one recording from the early phase of therapy (sessions 1-6) and one recording from a later phase of therapy (sessions 7-14) will be randomly selected by the trial manager. The recordings will be translated, transcribed and sent to Dr Hayward for review. Therapist adherence to the treatment protocol will be assessed by Dr. Hayward who will assess two randomly selected recordings per therapist. Adherence will be rated using an adapted version of the Cognitive Therapy Scale for Psychosis (CTS-psy). Items F, G, and H have been adapted to include relating specific items in place of cognitive therapy (e.g. &quot;Focus on the link between cognition and affect&quot; was replaced with &quot;focus on the effects of the patient engaging in different patterns of relating&quot;).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Safety monitoring</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion; 9 months after baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Will count the number of adverse events and serious adverse events</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">75</enrollment>
  <condition>Verbal Auditory Hallucination</condition>
  <condition>Psychotic Disorders</condition>
  <condition>Psychosis</condition>
  <condition>Schizophrenia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Relating module + Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants in this arm will receive 16 weekly sessions with Relating Therapy (RT) over 5 months in addition to their treatment as usual.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment as usual will include medication management, supportive brief counselling sessions and various types of psychosocial (e.g. social work guided support, peer support) and monitoring provided by Mental Health Services, with individual and family psychological therapies offered occasionally. Individual therapies may include Cognitive Behavior Therapy or psychodynamic interventions.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Relating Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>Relating Therapy (RT) is a symptom-specific behaviourally oriented intervention that targets interpersonal relating as a key mechanism associated with auditory hallucination distress. The aim is that patients learn to relate more assertively within the difficult relationships they have with both the auditory hallucinations and other people. The RT will follow a treatment manual consisting of three phases: 1. Socialization to relating therapy and its implications; 2. Exploration of themes within the relational history of the participant and their experience of relationships with AH, and interpersonal relating within the family and social environment (identifying any prominent themes, such as abuse, disempowerment, or rivalry); 3. Exploration and development of assertive approaches to relating to AH and other people.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Relating module + Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Treatment as usual</intervention_name>
    <description>TAU will include medication management, supportive brief counselling sessions and various types of psychosocial (e.g. social work guided support, peer support) and monitoring provided by Mental Health Services, with individual and family psychological therapies offered occasionally. Individual therapies may include CBT or psychodynamic interventions. To amend for the heterogeneity of TAU across centres, the type and extent of any treatment received will be protocolled at T1 and T2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Relating module + Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment as usual</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participants will;&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. have a diagnosis of a schizophrenia spectrum disorder (ICD-10, F2, confirmed by&#xD;
             SCID-5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. patients will be reporting distressing AH for at least six months (to be beyond the&#xD;
             startle and adjustment phase ) and score ≥ 3 on either item 8 or item 9 of the&#xD;
             PSYRATS-AH;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. be ≥ 16 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. be judged able to understand the full implications of their decision by the&#xD;
             responsible psychiatrist or clinical psychologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Participant must not:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. have AH with a clear organic cause (e.g. brain disease or injury):&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. have exclusively hypnagogic or hypnopompic AH,&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. have a primary diagnosis of acute substance dependence (F1x.2)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. have completed a course of CBT for psychotic symptoms during the past year within&#xD;
             which distressing AH have been targeted&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. be currently participating, or be confirmed to participate in another interventional&#xD;
             study in which they are receiving an intervention which utilizes psychological therapy&#xD;
             ;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. be non-German speaking to the degree that the participant is unable to fully&#xD;
             understand and answer assessment questions or give informed consent;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. be at immediate and serious risk to self or other.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>16 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Tania M Lincoln, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Universität Hamburg</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Matthias Pillny, Dr.</last_name>
    <phone>+4940428384023</phone>
    <email>matthias.pillny@uni-hamburg.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Tania M Lincoln, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
    <email>tania.lincoln@uni-hamburg.de</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universität Leipzig</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leipzig</city>
        <state>Sachsen</state>
        <zip>04109</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Cornelia Exner, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <email>exnerc@uni-leipzig.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Cornelia Exner, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Jacobs University Bremen</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bremen</city>
        <zip>28759</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Thomas Lang, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <email>t.lang@jacobs-university.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Thomas Lang, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Psychotherapeutische Hoschschulambulanz Universität Hamburg</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20146</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anne K Fladung, Dr.</last_name>
      <email>anne.fladung@uni-hamburg.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Tania M Lincoln, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Klinik und Poliklinik für Psychiatrie und Psychotherapie Universitätsklinikum Hamburg-Eppendorf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Hamburg</city>
        <zip>20251</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Candelaria Mahlke, Dr.</last_name>
      <email>c.mahlke@uke.de</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Jürgen Gallinat, Prof. Dr.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>September 18, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>September 30, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">October 8, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 29, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Hamburg-Eppendorf</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Matthias Pillny</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Trial Manager</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Relating therapy</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Hallucinations</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Schizophrenia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychotic Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Mental Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>only upon request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

