<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT01296477</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10-115</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT01296477</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>To Evaluate the Use of ASTHMA IQ in a Primary Care Setting</brief_title>
  <acronym>AIQ</acronym>
  <official_title>Examination of ASTHMA IQ to Improve Patient Outcomes in a Primary Care Setting</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>American Academy of Family Physicians</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>American Academy of Allergy, Asthma, and Immunology</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>American Academy of Family Physicians</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      There is a mounting body of evidence suggesting that there is a large disparity between the&#xD;
      development and the actual implementation of guideline-driven asthma care in primary and&#xD;
      specialty care practices. To address this disparity, the American Academy of Allergy, Asthma&#xD;
      &amp; Immunology (AAAAI) developed a unique, comprehensive and easy-to-use Web-based tool for&#xD;
      clinicians who treat asthma patients called &quot;Asthma Specialist Tool to Help Manage Asthma and&#xD;
      Improve Quality&quot; (Asthma-IQ). This study will examine whether the use of the Asthma IQ&#xD;
      primary care tool will improve asthma care and asthma outcomes using a randomized trial of&#xD;
      the Asthma IQ system versus usual asthma care in the primary care setting over 1 year. At the&#xD;
      end of 1 year, all patients will be managed using the Asthma-IQ tool for an additional year&#xD;
      to determine if the patients managed by usual care in the first year improve when managed in&#xD;
      conjunction with Asthma-IQ. The primary endpoint to determine if the use of the Asthma IQ&#xD;
      tool will improve asthma patient outcomes is quarterly assessments of Asthma Control Test&#xD;
      (ACT) scores via automated / electronic patient survey. The secondary endpoint is asthma&#xD;
      exacerbations and there are a number of exploratory endpoints to further define the clinical&#xD;
      utility of the primary care version of Asthma-IQ. This study will involve recruiting&#xD;
      approximately 20 family medicine offices with approximately 20 patients each, to conduct this&#xD;
      randomized, multiple time point intervention trial. The necessary total recruited patient&#xD;
      sample size is 200 per group. The results of this study will help determine the utility of&#xD;
      Web-based tools to help manage chronic diseases such as asthma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>December 2010</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">September 2015</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">July 2015</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>ACT scores via automated / electronic patient survey</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years (Surveys measured at every 3 months including baseline)</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Asthma exacerbations requiring the use of inhaled corticosteroids via chart reviews and automated survey</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years (Chart reviews performed at every 6 months and surveys measured at every 3 months including baseline)</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">375</enrollment>
  <condition>Asthma</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Asthma IQ Primary Care Tool</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Usual Asthma Care in Primary Care</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The study will recruit approximately 400 patients with chronic persistent asthma. The&#xD;
        required sample size to identify a clinically significant difference in ACT scores from&#xD;
        baseline and between groups requires about 200 patients per group.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female patients, age 12 through 65 years at the time of screening;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Written informed consent obtained from the patient prior to beginning study&#xD;
             procedures;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Documented clinical history of chronic persistent asthma requiring controller therapy;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Able to complete the study period, including follow-up period, of up to approximately&#xD;
             2 years; and&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Willing to forego other forms of experimental treatment and study procedures during&#xD;
             the study and for 30 days after the follow-up period is completed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of any disease, evidence of any current disease (other than asthma), any&#xD;
             finding upon physical examination, or any laboratory abnormality, that, in the opinion&#xD;
             of the investigator, may compromise the safety of the patient in the study or confound&#xD;
             the analysis of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Lung disease other than asthma (e.g., chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, cystic&#xD;
             fibrosis);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Any disease or illness, other than asthma, that is likely to require the use of&#xD;
             systemic corticosteroids during the study period;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Current acute illnesses or evidence of significant active infection, such as fever ≥&#xD;
             38.0°C (100.5°F) within 4 weeks of enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Receipt of any investigational drug therapy within 30 days or any biologic(s) within 5&#xD;
             half-lives prior to screening, except omalizumab for asthma;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Pregnancy at enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Breastfeeding or lactating females;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Elective major surgery planned from screening through study completion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. History of cancer other than basal cell carcinoma of the skin or cervical&#xD;
             carcinoma-in-situ treated with apparent success with curative therapy more than 1 year&#xD;
             prior to enrollment;&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. History of primary immunodeficiency;&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. History within the past year of excessive alcohol intake or drug addiction.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. History of tobacco use of more than 10 pack years;&#xD;
&#xD;
         13. Plans to move from the study site area during the duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Other protocol-defined inclusion/exclusion criteria may apply&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>12 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>AAFP National Research Network</name>
      <address>
        <city>Leawood</city>
        <state>Kansas</state>
        <zip>66211</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2016</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 14, 2011</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 14, 2011</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">February 15, 2011</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 4, 2016</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 4, 2016</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">January 5, 2016</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Asthma</keyword>
  <keyword>ASTHMA IQ tool</keyword>
  <keyword>Asthma Control Test (ACT)</keyword>
  <keyword>EPR-3 Guidelines, Exacerbations</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Asthma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

