<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00256269</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UCI 04-09</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>2004-3849</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00256269</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Oxaliplatin and Irinotecan in Recurrent or Metastatic Esophageal and Gastroesophageal (GE) Junction Carcinoma</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Phase II Study of Weekly Oxaliplatin and Irinotecan in the Treatment of Recurrent or Metastatic Esophageal Carcinoma and Carcinoma of the Gastroesophageal (GE) Junction</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, Irvine</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sanofi</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, Irvine</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The combination of cisplatin and irinotecan has significant anti-tumor activity in esophageal&#xD;
      cancer. Oxaliplatin has been shown to have activity in combination with 5-Fluorouracil (5FU)&#xD;
      and radiation in treatment of locally advanced esophageal cancer. Oxaliplatin also has better&#xD;
      side effects profile than cisplatin and may be able to overcome tumors that have developed&#xD;
      cisplatin resistance. The standard treatment of locally advanced esophageal cancer has been&#xD;
      cisplatin, 5FU and radiation followed by possible esophagectomy. However, a large portion of&#xD;
      these patients will relapse and the tumor may develop resistance to cisplatin and/or the&#xD;
      cumulative toxicity from previous treatment forbids the use of cisplatin again. Weekly&#xD;
      combination of oxaliplatin and irinotecan has been shown to be active and well tolerated in&#xD;
      elderly population with refractory colorectal cancer. Therefore, we propose this phase II&#xD;
      trial of a weekly oxaliplatin and irinotecan to test the effectiveness and the tolerability&#xD;
      of this regimen in metastatic and/or recurrent esophageal cancer.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Esophageal cancer represents the seventh cause of cancer death in American men, and more than&#xD;
      90% of patients diagnosed with esophageal cancer will ultimately die of their disease. In the&#xD;
      United States, 13,900 new cases of esophageal cancer and 13,000 deaths from esophageal cancer&#xD;
      are anticipated in 2003 (Jemal et al, 2003). The lifetime risk of esophageal cancer is 0.8%&#xD;
      for men and 0.3% for women (Ries et al, 2002). The risk increases with age, with a mean age&#xD;
      at diagnosis of 67 years (Ries et al, 2002; Daly et al, 2000). Adenocarcinoma of the&#xD;
      esophagus or gastroesophageal junction, a previously rare disease, is rapidly increasing in&#xD;
      incidence in the United States and western countries and now accounts for more than half of&#xD;
      newly diagnosed disease (Devesa et al, 1998).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Half of patients diagnosed with esophageal cancer present with overt metastatic disease, and&#xD;
      chemotherapy is the mainstay of palliation in this setting. In patients who present initially&#xD;
      with locoregional disease, the majority will eventually develop metastatic disease as well,&#xD;
      with or without local recurrence of disease. Metastatic esophageal carcinoma is an incurable&#xD;
      disease with median survival duration of 4 to 8 months. Combination chemotherapy, most often&#xD;
      cisplatin-based, results in partial responses in 25% to 50% of patients with metastatic&#xD;
      disease and rare complete responses, including a 35% response rate reported for the commonly&#xD;
      used combination of cisplatin and fluorouracil (Ilson et al, 1996). Recent chemotherapy&#xD;
      trials indicate an overlap in response rates for metastatic adenocarcinoma and squamous&#xD;
      carcinoma carcinoma of the esophagus (Ilson et al, 1997). Responses to chemotherapy are&#xD;
      generally short-lived, and toxicity of cisplatin-based chemotherapy, particularly in the&#xD;
      palliation of metastatic disease, is often substantial and underscores the need to identify&#xD;
      new agents in the treatment of esophageal carcinoma.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    Study was terminated by funding entity&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date type="Actual">June 2005</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 7, 2007</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 7, 2007</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the overall response rate</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the overall response rate (complete and partial response) to a weekly combination of oxaliplatin and irinotecan in patients with unresectable or metastatic esophageal cancer or cancer of the gastro-esophageal (GE) junction.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of participants with treatment-related adverse events as assessed by CTCAE v3.0</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the frequency and severity of toxicities associated with this treatment</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Progression Free Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>from date of registration to date of first observation of progressive disease (as outlined in 10.2d), death due to any cause or symptomatic deterioration.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of Time to Death</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Analysis timeline would be from the date of registration to date of death due to any cause.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">4</enrollment>
  <condition>Esophageal Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Gastroesophageal Cancer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Oxaliplatin plus Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: Oxaliplatin-40 mg/m2 IV over 60 minutes Every 21 days. Drug: Irinotecan-60 mg/m2 IV over 60 minutes, immediately following oxaliplatin Every 21 days.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oxaliplatin</intervention_name>
    <description>40 mg/m2 IV over 60 minutes Every 21 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oxaliplatin plus Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Irinotecan</intervention_name>
    <description>60 mg/m2 IV over 60 minutes, immediately following oxaliplatin Every 21 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Oxaliplatin plus Irinotecan</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients must have histologically or cytologically confirmed diagnosis of squamous&#xD;
             cell carcinoma or adenocarcinoma of the esophagus. Patients with tumors of the&#xD;
             gastroesophageal junction were eligible if at least 50% of the tumor involved the&#xD;
             esophagus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have locally advanced (i.e. unresectable) or metastatic disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All sites of disease must be assessed and designated as measurable or non-measurable&#xD;
             disease as documented by CT, MRI, X-ray physical Each of the criteria in the following&#xD;
             section must be met in order for a patient to be eligible for registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients may have received prior radiotherapy if there has been complete recovery from&#xD;
             all radiation-induced toxicities. At least 4 weeks must have been elapsed from the&#xD;
             completion of radiation therapy to the time of registration. If lesions within the&#xD;
             radiation port are to be used to assess response to therapy, those lesions must have&#xD;
             demonstrated clear progression by the criteria outlined in Section 10.2d following&#xD;
             completion of radiation therapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate bone marrow reserve as documented by absolute neutrophil&#xD;
             count (ANC) &gt; 1,500 microliters and platelets &gt; 100,000/microliter obtained within 14&#xD;
             days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have adequate hepatic as documented by serum bilirubin &lt; 1.5 x the&#xD;
             institutional upper limit of normal. Serum transaminase (SGOT or SGPT) must be &lt; 1.5 x&#xD;
             the institutional upper limit of normal serum unless the liver is involved with tumor,&#xD;
             in which case serum transaminase (SGOT or SGPT) must be &lt; 5 x the institutional limit&#xD;
             of normal. These tests must be obtained within 14 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Patients must have a creatinine &lt; 1.5 x the institutional upper limit of normal or a&#xD;
        creatinine clearance of &gt; 30 cc/min calculated using the following formula obtained within&#xD;
        28 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Calculated Creatinine Clearance = (140-age) X wt (kg) X (0.85 if female) 72 X creatinine&#xD;
        (mg/dl)&#xD;
&#xD;
        These tests must have been performed within 28 days prior to registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients must be 18 years of age or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must have a Zubrod performance of 0-2&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have received prior chemotherapy for chemotherapy for advanced or&#xD;
             metastatic esophageal cancer. Chemotherapy given adjuvantly or as a radiosensitizer is&#xD;
             allowed if more than 8 weeks have elapsed since the treatment was completed and they&#xD;
             have recovered from any treatment related toxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients must not have a surgical procedure for esophageal cancer within 4 weeks prior&#xD;
             to registration. Patients must have completely recovered from all surgery prior to&#xD;
             registration.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with any evidence of active or uncontrolled infection, recent myocardial&#xD;
             infection, unstable angina, or life-threatening arrhythmia are not eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with severe psychiatric disorder are not eligible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with known brain metastasis are not eligible. However, brain-imaging studies&#xD;
             are not required for eligibility if the patient has no neurological signs or symptoms.&#xD;
             If brain-imaging studies are performed, they must be negative for disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No other prior malignancy is allowed except for adequately treated basal cell or&#xD;
             squamous cell carcinoma, in situ cervical cancer, or adequately treated Stage I and II&#xD;
             cancer from which the patient is in complete remission, or any other malignancy from&#xD;
             which the patient has been disease-free for 5 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should not have active infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should not have psychological, familial, sociological, or geographical&#xD;
             conditions that do not permit medical follow-up and compliance with study protocol.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Except for cancer-related abnormalities, patients should not have unstable or&#xD;
             pre-existing major medical conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients should not have any immediate life-threatening complications of their&#xD;
             malignancies.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sai-Hong Ignatius Ou, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Chao Family Comprehensive Cancer Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Chao Family Comprehensive Cancer Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Orange</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92868</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>January 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 17, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 17, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 21, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>January 24, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>January 24, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">January 26, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, Irvine</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sai-Hong Ignatius Ou</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>HS Associate Clinical Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Esophageal Cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Gastroesophageal junction cancer</keyword>
  <keyword>Oxaliplatin</keyword>
  <keyword>Irinotecan</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Esophageal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Oxaliplatin</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Irinotecan</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

