<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00254826</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRB00045982</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00254826</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Yellow Fever Virus Vaccine and Immune Globulin Study</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Controlled Double-Blind Trial of the Comparative Viremia, Immunogenicity and Safety of a 17-D Live Attenuated Yellow Fever Vaccine (YF-VAX)Given Alone or in Combination With Human Immune Globulin (Gama STAN S/D)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Sanofi Pasteur, a Sanofi Company</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</agency>
      <agency_class>U.S. Fed</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Emory University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether immune globulin can limit the amount of&#xD;
      yellow fever vaccine virus present in the blood after vaccination without compromising the&#xD;
      immunity associated with the yellow fever vaccine. The study will enroll 80 participants in&#xD;
      two groups of 40 each. The first group will receive the yellow fever vaccine with salt-water&#xD;
      placebo. The second group will receive yellow fever vaccine with immune globulin. The amount&#xD;
      of vaccine virus and immune response in both groups will be compared. Yellow fever vaccine&#xD;
      has been used to protect humans against Yellow Fever Vaccine disease since the 1930s.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This double-blind, randomized outpatient study is designed to determine if human immune&#xD;
      globulin (IG) will limit the viremic response to 17D yellow fever vaccine without&#xD;
      compromising immunogenicity. The yellow fever 17D vaccine YF-VAX® is manufactured in the&#xD;
      United States. The IG, Gama STAN S/D®, is manufactured in the U.S. The study will be&#xD;
      conducted in 80 healthy adults 18-40 years of age in the U.S. Participants will be randomized&#xD;
      to receive YF-VAX® plus saline (40 subjects), or YF-VAX® plus Gama STAN S/D® (40 subjects).&#xD;
      The dose of Gama STAN S/D® will be that used for the prevention of hepatitis A, i.e. 0.06&#xD;
      mL/kg. The lot of Gama STAN S/D® will have been tested and shown to contain yellow fever&#xD;
      neutralizing antibodies at a log neutralizing index of &gt;0.7. Saline will be given to blind&#xD;
      the vaccine administrator and vaccinee as to their treatment group. A stratified&#xD;
      randomization procedure will be used to ensure equal distribution of study medications to&#xD;
      participants by gender. Safety and tolerability will be assessed by comparison of the&#xD;
      incidence of adverse events across the two treatment groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The hypothesis being tested is whether co-administration of yellow fever antibody and yellow&#xD;
      fever vaccine (passive-active immunization) results in effective immunization while reducing&#xD;
      viremia. The effectiveness of use of Gama STAN S/D® in combination with YF-VAX® will be&#xD;
      assessed by a reduction in the viremic response in the vaccinee. Viremia is a measure of&#xD;
      replication of YF 17D virus in host tissues, and absence of viremia indicates that virus&#xD;
      replication in host tissues is abrogated. Abrogation of virus replication is expected to&#xD;
      limit the potential for dissemination of virus and virus invasion of and damage to vital&#xD;
      organs, including the liver and brain. The methods used to quantify viremia will be reverse&#xD;
      transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) and direct plaquing in Vero cell monolayers.&#xD;
      In addition, sera collected pre-vaccination and on blood draws post-vaccination will be&#xD;
      tested for yellow fever neutralizing antibodies to measure immunogenicity. The method used to&#xD;
      detect neutralizing antibodies will be a plaque-reduction neutralization test (PRNT)&#xD;
      performed in Vero cell culture using the constant serum-varying virus technique standardized&#xD;
      by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (Beaty et al., 1989). The PRNT has been recently&#xD;
      validated and used to support Phase 3 clinical trials of YF-VAX® (Monath et al. 2002a). The&#xD;
      primary endpoint will be the comparison of the proportion of subjects without prior yellow&#xD;
      fever immunization in each treatment group who have measurable vaccine virus after&#xD;
      vaccination. The T-cell activation, cytokine response, dendritic cell response and kinetics&#xD;
      and phenotype of natural killer (NK) cells will also be characterized.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study participants will be excluded who have significant underlying medical conditions, a&#xD;
      history of sensitivity to IG, or established contraindications to yellow fever vaccine,&#xD;
      including immunosuppression, thymus disorder, pregnancy, or egg hypersensitivity. These&#xD;
      exclusion criteria represent the major contraindications to the use of Gama STAN S/D® and all&#xD;
      yellow fever vaccines, including YF-VAX®.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study consists of a Screening Period and a Treatment Period. During the Screening Period&#xD;
      (Days -30 to -1), informed consent is obtained, eligibility for study entry is assessed and&#xD;
      baseline tests are performed. Subjects who satisfy all inclusion/exclusion criteria are&#xD;
      eligible to enter the Treatment Period and are randomized to one of the two treatment groups.&#xD;
      On Day 0 subjects will receive either YF-VAX® plus saline, or YF-VAX® plus Gama STAN S/D®.&#xD;
      Subjects return to the clinic for daily visits on day 1, 2, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 14, 30, and 91.&#xD;
      The total duration of participation for an individual subject is approximately 91 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Safety assessments in vaccinated subjects include adverse event reporting and clinical&#xD;
      laboratory evaluations. To ensure thorough reporting of adverse events during the time&#xD;
      interval in which adverse events associated with yellow fever vaccination might be expected&#xD;
      to occur, subjects will be required to complete a study diary for Days 0-28. The study diary&#xD;
      will record both local reactions (i.e., pain, redness, and swelling) and systemic reactions&#xD;
      (i.e., feeling ill [malaise], headache, muscle aches, fever, chills, rash, tiredness, and&#xD;
      other general symptoms). These are the principal symptoms and side effects known to be&#xD;
      associated with yellow fever 17D vaccine. At each visit, study personnel will perform&#xD;
      clinical evaluations and at days 7, 14 and 30 the study staff will review the diary card and&#xD;
      follow up on any adverse events that occurred since vaccination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A sample size for efficacy of 80 participants including 40 subjects in the group receiving&#xD;
      YF-VAX® plus saline and 40 subjects receiving YF-VAX® plus Gama STAN S/D® provides 80% power&#xD;
      in a one-sided test at significance level alpha of 0.05, assuming 93% of subjects not&#xD;
      receiving immune globulin will exhibit detectable viremia and a reduction of 35% (to 61% of&#xD;
      subjects) following administration of immune globulin.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>June 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 2008</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 2008</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Investigator)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the proportion of participants developing viremia between the group receiving the yellow fever vaccine/saline and yellow fever vaccine with human immune globulin.</measure>
    <time_frame>91 Days</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the viremia levels between the group of vaccinees receiving yellow fever vaccine with the group receiving yellow fever vaccine with human immune globulin.</measure>
    <time_frame>91 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the dynamics of T cell activation, cytokine response and dendritic cell response in vaccinees during primary response to yellow fever vaccine to vaccinees given yellow fever vaccine given in combination with human immune globulin.</measure>
    <time_frame>91 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the geometric mean neutralizing antibody titer in the group of yellow fever vaccinees with the group of vaccinees receiving yellow fever vaccine in combination with human immune globulin.</measure>
    <time_frame>91 days</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Viremia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>YF-VAX® plus saline</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: YF-VAX® plus saline</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>17D YF Vaccine plus Ig</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Drug: 17D YF Vaccine plus Ig; one vaccine on day 0</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>YF-VAX® plus saline</intervention_name>
    <description>YF-VAX® plus saine</description>
    <arm_group_label>YF-VAX® plus saline</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>17D YF Vaccine plus Ig,</intervention_name>
    <description>17D YF Vaccine plus Ig, one vaccine on day 0</description>
    <arm_group_label>17D YF Vaccine plus Ig</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to understand and give informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18-40 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No medical contraindications to participation discovered at the screening visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative serologic test for HIV, HCV and Hepatitis B surface antigen at the screening&#xD;
             visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female volunteers of childbearing potential must agree to use effective birth control&#xD;
             throughout the duration of the study. A negative urine pregnancy test must be&#xD;
             documented prior to any injection.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Must weigh at least 110 lbs&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of allergy or history of anaphylaxis to any of the vaccine components&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any history of allergic reaction to human immune globulin or a history of IgA&#xD;
             deficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of hypersensitivity to ingestion of eggs or allergic reaction to vaccines&#xD;
             prepared in eggs or chick embryo cell cultures (e.g. influenza, measles)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected immunodeficiency (e.g. HIV infection, primary immunodeficiency&#xD;
             disorder, leukemia, lymphoma), use of immunosuppressive or antineoplastic drugs&#xD;
             (corticosteroids&gt; 10 mg prednisolone/prednisone, or equivalent, for mare than 14 days&#xD;
             in the last three months). Persons with previous skin cancer or cured non-lymphatic&#xD;
             tumors are not excluded from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any clinically significant chronic medical condition that is considered progressive&#xD;
             including: hypertension, diabetes, gastrointestinal abnormalities (e.g. active peptic&#xD;
             ulcer disease), cardiac, pulmonary, hepatic, renal, or neurologic disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of excessive alcohol consumption, drug abuse, psychiatric conditions, social&#xD;
             conditions, or occupational requirements that in the opinion of the investigator would&#xD;
             preclude compliance with the trial&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receipt of any live or inactivated vaccine between the screening visit and the day 0&#xD;
             visit, or any vaccine within 30 days of a vaccination visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any subject found to be HIV positive, hepatitis B surface antigen positive, or&#xD;
             hepatitis C antibody positive at the time of screening&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any contraindication to intramuscular injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are pregnant, nursing or expect to become pregnant during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administration of a blood product or immune globulin product within 6 months of&#xD;
             injection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of previous yellow fever, West Nile, dengue, St. Louis encephalitis, Japanese&#xD;
             encephalitis or tick-borne encephalitis vaccination or infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Serologic evidence of previous yellow fever, West Nile, dengue, St. Louis&#xD;
             encephalitis, Japanese encephalitis or tick-borne encephalitis vaccination or&#xD;
             infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of travel to a yellow fever endemic zone as defined by the Centers for Disease&#xD;
             Control and Prevention. Health Information for International Travel, 2005-2006&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of thymus disorder or dysfunction, including myasthenia gravis, thymoma,&#xD;
             thymectomy, or DiGeorge syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of an autoimmune disorder&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mark J. Mulligan, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Emory University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Emory Vaccine Center-The Hope Clinic and The Pediatric ID Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Decatur</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30030</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://www.hopeclinic.emory.edu</url>
    <description>Emory Vaccine Center-The Hope Clinic</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>December 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 15, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 15, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 17, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>December 3, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>December 3, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">December 4, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Emory University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mark Mulligan</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Yellow Fever Virus Vaccination</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Viremia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Yellow Fever</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

