<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00257543</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>876-2003</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00257543</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SALT: Alternative Donor Bone Marrow and Cord Blood Transplantation for High Risk Sickle Cell Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>SALT - Alternative Donor Bone Marrow and Cord Blood Transplantation for High Risk Sickle Cell Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Emory University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Emory University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      We hope to gain valuable information about the safety, success of engraftment, and rates of&#xD;
      complications using alternate donor transplantation for children with severe SCD. Crucial&#xD;
      information will be also collected about late effects from alternate donor BMT sickle cell,&#xD;
      providing valuable information to clinicians and families making decisions among&#xD;
      interventions for children with severe sickle cell disease. If successful, alternate donor&#xD;
      transplantation in this setting could pave the way to offering curative treatment to many&#xD;
      more patients with severe SCD.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Unfortunately, less than 1/4th of patients with severe SCD will have a matched sibling donor&#xD;
      that can serve as a BMT donor. This research protocol proposes to study the safety and&#xD;
      usefulness of &quot;alternate donor transplant&quot; (using donors other than matched siblings). We&#xD;
      will offer this treatment to children with severe sickle cell disease that do not have a&#xD;
      matched sibling BMT donor. Alternative donors can be family members who are slightly less&#xD;
      than completely matched, unrelated volunteer donors who are completely matched, and donated&#xD;
      banked umbilical cord blood that is completely or nearly completely matched.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Alternative donor transplant has been performed commonly in patients with cancer, and also&#xD;
      provides curative therapy for several non-malignant diseases (severe immunodeficiency, marrow&#xD;
      failure and metabolic storage diseases). Alternate donor transplants carry higher risks of&#xD;
      complications, including graft-versus-host disease, infection, and graft failure. Therefore,&#xD;
      we will be selective about which patients are invited to participate, limiting eligibility to&#xD;
      those patients that have had a severe SCD related problem (rather than those who are doing&#xD;
      well and are likely to have few SCD related problems), but excluding patients who have such&#xD;
      severe organ damage that they are more likely to die during transplant, and limiting&#xD;
      eligibility to a young age group. A multi-step review algorithm that includes internal, local&#xD;
      and external expert review has been constructed to provide a thorough, safe and ethical&#xD;
      accrual process. We will treat patients using drugs and methods commonly used in alternate&#xD;
      donor transplant for other diseases such as leukemia, and incorporate lessons learned from&#xD;
      our previous experience in BMT for sickle cell by modifying supportive care measures. Special&#xD;
      attention will be given to evaluation of post-BMT effects in this population, as well as&#xD;
      potential reasons for adverse effects (such as graft failure).&#xD;
&#xD;
      We think that Atlanta is a particularly good place to study this kind of transplant for&#xD;
      several reasons. One reason is experience: our program has transplanted more children with&#xD;
      SCD than any other single institution in North America, with excellent outcomes.&#xD;
      Additionally, SCD patients in our area often have been treated on a special red cell&#xD;
      transfusion program that limits the number of people donating the blood; we think this is&#xD;
      likely to reduce the chance of graft failure.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Terminated</overall_status>
  <why_stopped>
    lack of enrollment&#xD;
  </why_stopped>
  <start_date>January 2006</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">August 2012</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">August 2012</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To determine the frequency of donor engraftment after alternate donor transplantation in children with severe sickle cell disease.</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after completion of study accrual</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">3</enrollment>
  <condition>Sickle Cell Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>single arm study</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>this is a single arm study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Alternative donor bone marrow and cord blood</intervention_name>
    <description>bone marrow transplant - alternative donors for bone marrow and cord blood transplants</description>
    <arm_group_label>single arm study</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Hemoglobin SS, hemoglobin SC, or hemoglobin S0 thalassemia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Donor available: Partially (5/6) HLA-matched relative (PMRD), matched (6/6) unrelated&#xD;
             marrow donor or umbilical cord (5/6 or 6/6) of appropriate size (see 6.3.2) , using&#xD;
             high-resolution HLA typing. Donor must not be homozygous for HgbS and must meet&#xD;
             standard donor eligibility criteria of the Blood and Marrow Transplant Program.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Severe SCD, defined by one of the following (modified Walters criteria):&#xD;
&#xD;
        oPrevious (6 months prior) central nervous system event lasting longer than 24 hours, plus&#xD;
        objective imaging evidence of CNS vasculopathy, with or without residual neurologic&#xD;
        findings oFrequent (3 per year for 2 years) painful vaso-occlusive episodes (defined as&#xD;
        episode lasting 4 hours and requiring hospitalization or outpatient treatment with&#xD;
        parenteral narcotics) oRecurrent (3 in lifetime) acute chest syndrome events which have&#xD;
        necessitated exchange transfusion or chronic transfusion therapy. Must have failed a&#xD;
        good-faith trial of hydroxyurea (failure defined as a reduction of less than 50% in the&#xD;
        incidence of vaso-occlusive events over a period of at least 18 months) or have&#xD;
        demonstrated an inability to take the drug due to side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        oAny combination of 3 acute chest syndrome episodes and vaso-occlusive pain episodes&#xD;
        (defined as above) yearly for 3 years. Must have failed a good-faith trial of hydroxyurea&#xD;
        (failure defined as a reduction of less than 50% in the incidence of vaso-occlusive events&#xD;
        over a period of at least 18 months) or have demonstrated an inability to take the drug due&#xD;
        to side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        oStage I or II sickle lung disease oRed-cell alloimmunization (2 antibodies) on chronic&#xD;
        transfusion therapy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        oSuitable HLA-identical relative donor is available oBiopsy proven chronic active&#xD;
        hepatitis, portal fibrosis, or cirrhosis, or serologic evidence of active hepatitis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        oSCD chronic lung disease stage III (see Appendix) oSevere renal dysfunction defined as&#xD;
        &lt;50% of predicted normal GFR for age. oSevere cardiac dysfunction defined as shortening&#xD;
        fraction &lt; 25%. oSevere residual neurologic impairment other than hemiplegia alone, defined&#xD;
        as full-scale IQ 70, quadriplegia or paraplegia, inability to ambulate, inability to&#xD;
        communicate without assistive device, or any impairment resulting in decline of Lansky&#xD;
        performance score to &lt;70%.&#xD;
&#xD;
        oCNS event occurring within 6 months prior to transplant oKarnofsky or Lansky functional&#xD;
        performance score &lt; 70% (see Appendix) oConfirmed HIV seropositivity. oPatient with&#xD;
        unspecified chronic toxicity serious enough to detrimentally affect the patient's capacity&#xD;
        to tolerate bone marrow transplantation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        oPatient or patient's guardian(s) unable to understand the nature and risks inherent in the&#xD;
        BMT process.&#xD;
&#xD;
        oHistory of lack of compliance with medical care that would jeopardize transplant course.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>16 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ann Haight, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Children's Healthcare of Atlanta/Emory University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Children's Healthcare of Altanta</name>
      <address>
        <city>Atlanta</city>
        <state>Georgia</state>
        <zip>30322</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>September 2013</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>November 22, 2005</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>November 22, 2005</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">November 23, 2005</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 16, 2013</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 16, 2013</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">September 17, 2013</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Emory University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ann E. Haight</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>sickle cell disease</keyword>
  <keyword>bone marrow transplant</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Anemia, Sickle Cell</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

