<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT03537209</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Rad 2:5:1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT03537209</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Assessment Root Apex Position of Mandibular Molars and Premolars Linear to Inferior Alveolar Canal Among Egyptian Population Using CBCT</brief_title>
  <official_title>Assessment of Root Apex Position of Mandibular Molars and Premolars Linear to Inferior Alveolar Canal Among a Sample of Egyptian Population Using CBCT: A Cross Sectional Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cairo University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cairo University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Linear relation between premolars and molars root apex and superior border of inferior&#xD;
      alveolar canal&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the study is to assess the linear position between the roots of mandibular&#xD;
      premolars and molars and the superior border of inferior alveolar canal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Population: Adults, male and female from Egyptian population Outcome Variable: Linear&#xD;
      measurement of the distance between root apices of mandibular premolars and molars to the&#xD;
      superior border of IAN.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome Measured Measuring Device Measuring Unit&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary Outcome Distance between root apices of mandibular premolars and molars to inferior&#xD;
      alveolar canal CBCT software Romexis® Millimeters&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research question:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Among the mandibular premolars and molars, which roots are the closest to the inferior&#xD;
      alveolar canal, in sample of Egyptian Population?&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and Methods&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Design: Cross-sectional Study&#xD;
&#xD;
      Setting and Location:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The data collection will be obtained from the data base available at Oral &amp;&#xD;
           Maxillofacial Radiology department at faculty of Dentistry, Cairo University.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. CBCT images will be obtained from Egyptian patients who had CBCT examination as part of&#xD;
           their dental examination, diagnosis or treatment planning during the years 2018.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 162 CBCT scans of mandibular permanent premolars and molars belonging to Egyptian&#xD;
      individuals are selected according to the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  First and second mandibular permanent premolars and molars of Egyptian patients starting&#xD;
           from 18 years, males or females.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Intact roots without fractures or cracks.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Posterior teeth are present and their adjacent and opposing teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Absence of radiological evidence of dental malocclusion that could have altered the&#xD;
           position of premolars or molars.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  CBCT scans of mandibular first and second premolars and molars using 20 x 10 cm FOV,&#xD;
           0.4mm voxel resolution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Evidence of apicectomy or periapical surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Odontogenic or non-odontogenic pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Congenital deformity of the mandible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  External Root resorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Previous history of fracture of the mandible.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Tomographic images of poor quality or artifacts interfering with the detection of&#xD;
           mandibular canal and apical morphology of the teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Variables:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. The crowding and overlapping of the mandibular posterior teeth .&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Extraction of the adjacent or the opposing tooth may cause tilting of the tooth or over&#xD;
           eruption of the opposing tooth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Attrition of the teeth may cause over eruption of the teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. The presence of dental anamolies may influence the position of the tooth to the inferior&#xD;
           alveolar canal.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Sources / Measurements:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Retrospective Data Analysis will be performed after the CBCT images are pooled from the&#xD;
      computer database by convenient sampling technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      CBCT images will be obtained from patients who required CBCT examination as part of their&#xD;
      dental examination, diagnosis or treatment planning without exposing them to unnecessary&#xD;
      radiation dose for the research purpose.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All the CBCT examinations are scanned by Planmeca Promax 3D®, 20 x 10 cm FOV, 0.4 mm voxel&#xD;
      resolution, 90 kVp, 8 mA and 13.5 seconds exposure time.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To assess the shortest distance from the root apices to the border of the inferior alveolar&#xD;
      canal, the multiplanar reconstruction view of the manufacturer's software viewer (Planmeca&#xD;
      Romexis) with its axial, sagittal and coronal plane will be used, and the cross-sectional&#xD;
      images through the mandible will be also used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Cross sectional images will be oriented parallel to the long axis of the tooth, then the&#xD;
      shortest distance from the deepest point of root apices and superior border of the inferior&#xD;
      alveolar canal will be obtained to be examined (Umut et al 2017).&#xD;
&#xD;
      CBCT images will be interpreted by two oral radiologists independently; blinded from&#xD;
      demographic data of the patients and from the results of each other.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All measurements will be assessed, once by the first investigator and then another time two&#xD;
      weeks later for intra-observer reliability. The second investigator will assess the&#xD;
      measurements once for inter-observer reliability.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Then inter-observational and intra-observational variability between the observers will be&#xD;
      evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Bias:&#xD;
&#xD;
      No source of bias.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The aim of the study is to assess the relationship between the roots of mandibular premolars&#xD;
      and molars and the superior border of inferior alveolar canal in Egyptian population. Based&#xD;
      on the previous paper by San Chong,et al,2017,the prevalence of alveolar nerve 78%.Using a&#xD;
      precision of 5, a design effect set at 1 with 95%CI(confidence interval), a total sample size&#xD;
      of 162 will be sufficient. The sample size was calculated by Epi info.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sampling Strategy: The sample will be collected by convenient sampling technique.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Methods:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data will be analyzed using IBM SPSS advanced statistics ( Statisitcal Package for Social&#xD;
      Sciences), version 24 (SPSS Inc.,Chicago,IL). Numerical data will be described as mean and&#xD;
      standard deviation or median and range. Categorical data will be described as numbers and&#xD;
      percantages. Comparsions between male and females for normally distributed numeric variables&#xD;
      will be done using Student's t-test while for non-normally distributed numeric variables will&#xD;
      be done by Mann-Whitney test. Comparisons between categorical variables will be performed&#xD;
      using the chi square test, A p-value less than or equal to 0.05 will be considered&#xD;
      statistically significant. All tests will be tailed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Unknown status</overall_status>
  <last_known_status>Not yet recruiting</last_known_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2018</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2018</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2018</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Distance between root apices of mandibular premolars and molars to inferior alveolar canal</measure>
    <time_frame>2018</time_frame>
    <description>measurement in millimeters using CBCT software Romexis®</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">162</enrollment>
  <condition>Linear Measurement Between Roots of Mandibular Premolars &amp; Molar &amp; IAC</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult Egyptian population&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First and second mandibular permanent premolars and molars of Egyptian patients&#xD;
             starting from 18 years, males or females.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Intact roots without fractures or cracks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Posterior teeth are present and their adjacent and opposing teeth.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of radiological evidence of dental malocclusion that could have altered the&#xD;
             position of premolars or molars.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  CBCT scans of mandibular first and second premolars and molars using 20 x 10 cm FOV,&#xD;
             0.4mm voxel resolution.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of apicectomy or periapical surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Odontogenic or non-odontogenic pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Congenital deformity of the mandible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  External Root resorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous history of fracture of the mandible.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tomographic images of poor quality or artifacts interfering with the detection of&#xD;
             mandibular canal and apical morphology of the teeth.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>May 2018</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 10, 2018</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 24, 2018</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2018</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 24, 2018</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 24, 2018</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 25, 2018</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Cairo University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Farid Medhat</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor of Oral &amp; Maxillofacial Radiology, Faculty of Dentistry</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>May 9, 2018</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/09/NCT03537209/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

