<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT00475943</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>070156</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>07-N-0156</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT00475943</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Movement of Epiglottis During Swallowing</brief_title>
  <official_title>Biomechanics of Human Epiglottal Movement and Inversion</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will examine how the airway closes during swallowing to prevent food or liquid&#xD;
      from entering the voice box or lungs while eating or drinking. It will also test whether&#xD;
      electrical stimulation of muscles in the neck can close the airway as it would close during&#xD;
      swallowing. The long-term goal of this research is to determine the feasibility of a new&#xD;
      approach for helping patients with a severe and life threatening swallowing disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Healthy normal volunteers between 18 and 65 years of age who can swallow normally may be&#xD;
      eligible for this study. Candidates are screened with a medical history, physical&#xD;
      examination, electrocardiogram and nasolaryngoscopy. For the nasolaryngoscopy, the subject's&#xD;
      voice box and epiglottis (flap of tissue that covers the windpipe during swallowing) are&#xD;
      examined using a thin flexible tube with a camera attached that is passed through the nose to&#xD;
      the back of the throat. During the test, speech and other tasks such as singing and whistling&#xD;
      are observed. The camera records the movement of the vocal cords on videotape. This procedure&#xD;
      may be repeated another time during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants undergo the following procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Electrical stimulation of muscles in the neck: The muscles in the neck are stimulated&#xD;
           with brief low-level electrical currents to see if the stimulation can cause the&#xD;
           epiglottis to fold down over the windpipe. Stimulation may be increased to a level where&#xD;
           it feels like a small shock The subject is asked to try to do the muscle stimulation&#xD;
           while swallowing.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Videofluoroscopy (recording swallowing and muscle stimulation during x-ray imaging of&#xD;
           the head): The head and neck are x-rayed while the subject swallows. After the wires&#xD;
           have been inserted for EMG (see below), markers are glued to the tongue and a tube is&#xD;
           inserted through the nose into the esophagus. The movements during swallowing with and&#xD;
           without muscle stimulation are x-rayed and analyzed later to determine how the&#xD;
           stimulation affects the movement of the epiglottis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Electromyography (EMG): Measurement of the electrical activity of muscles in the neck&#xD;
           using fine wires placed through the skin into muscles in the chin.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Manometry: During the videofluoroscopy, a manometer (tube that measures pressures) is&#xD;
           placed through the nose and into the back of the throat at the entry point to the&#xD;
           esophagus. This test shows whether muscle stimulation can fold down the epiglottis.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Surface electromyography (sEMG): The tube used during the videofluoroscopy has small&#xD;
           rings embedded in it that measure muscle activity on the surface of the inside of the&#xD;
           throat.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our objective is to determine the factors that cause epiglottic inversion during normal&#xD;
      deglutition and attempt to recreate this movement by means of muscle stimulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY POPULATION:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We plan to accrue 30 healthy volunteers so that a set of 20 participants will provide&#xD;
      reliable data for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DESIGN:&#xD;
&#xD;
      As an observational study, anatomical movement will be examined with videofluoroscopy during&#xD;
      normal swallows and during stimulation of the thyrohyoid, geniohyoid, hyoglossus, and&#xD;
      styloglossus muscles.&#xD;
&#xD;
      OUTCOME MEASURES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The principal outcome of this study is the distance of epiglottal displacement as measured&#xD;
      from videofluoroscopic images during normal swallowing and muscle stimulation. Secondary&#xD;
      measures are assessed as correlates of epiglottal inversion. These data include motion and&#xD;
      kinematics of other structures, such as the hyo-laryngeal complex and the tongue; tongue base&#xD;
      retraction pressures in the oral-pharynx, the hypopharynx, and the UES; and muscle activity&#xD;
      as measured by surface electromyography in these three locations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date>May 16, 2007</start_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">September 1, 2009</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <enrollment>30</enrollment>
  <condition>Deglutition</condition>
  <condition>Dysphagia</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Included subjects will be healthy adults age 18-65 years with normal swallowing function,&#xD;
        as determined with a medical history and physical examination by an otolaryngologist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria include the following circumstances:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must not have a history of chronic swallowing difficulty or dysfunction.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant volunteers will be excluded due to risks associated with radiation exposure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who are nursing will be excluded.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must not currently be suffering from a psychiatric disorder other than&#xD;
             depression, as evidenced by being under the care of a psychiatrist, or on medications&#xD;
             for treatment of a psychiatric disorder.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of brain injury or neurological disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of epileptic seizure.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of Rheumatic fever, mitral valve prolapse, heart murmurs, or cardiac&#xD;
             arrhythmias as determined by medical history, physical and EKG will disqualify a&#xD;
             subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects must not be taking any medications, including herbal types that can affect&#xD;
             coagulation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subjects will be excluded if they have a history of allergies to lidocaine or any&#xD;
             other anesthetic medication.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center, 9000 Rockville Pike</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Gresham SL. Clinical assessment and management of swallowing difficulties after stroke. Med J Aust. 1990 Oct 1;153(7):397-9.</citation>
    <PMID>2215310</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>DOTY RW, BOSMA JF. An electromyographic analysis of reflex deglutition. J Neurophysiol. 1956 Jan;19(1):44-60.</citation>
    <PMID>13286721</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Logemann JA, Kahrilas PJ, Cheng J, Pauloski BR, Gibbons PJ, Rademaker AW, Lin S. Closure mechanisms of laryngeal vestibule during swallow. Am J Physiol. 1992 Feb;262(2 Pt 1):G338-44.</citation>
    <PMID>1539666</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 1, 2009</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>May 18, 2007</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>May 18, 2007</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Estimate">May 21, 2007</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>June 30, 2017</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 2, 2017</last_update_posted>
  <keyword>Swallowing Disorders</keyword>
  <keyword>Swallowing</keyword>
  <keyword>Videofluoroscopy</keyword>
  <keyword>Dysphagia</keyword>
  <keyword>Epiglottis</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthy Volunteer</keyword>
  <keyword>HV</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Deglutition Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

