<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04742322</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>40641120900005364</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04742322</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy of Bifidobacterium Lactis CCT 7858 in Adults Using Antibiotics</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Using Bifidobacterium Lactis CCT 7858 in Improving Gastrointestinal Symptoms in Adults Using Antibiotics</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense - Unidade Academica de Ciecias da Saude</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense - Unidade Academica de Ciecias da Saude</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To evaluate the effectiveness of the probiotic Bifidobacterium lactis CCT 7858 in preventing&#xD;
      and / or improving gastrointestinal symptoms in adults using antibiotics. For this, a&#xD;
      randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled clinical trial will be carried out. The sample&#xD;
      will be composed of adults who will be recruited in a hospital, who have been hospitalized&#xD;
      and receive a prescription for antibiotics. The individuals will be separated into two&#xD;
      groups: intervention and placebo. 104 patients will be included, 52 for each group. Inclusion&#xD;
      criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      adults of both sexes and aged between 18 and 65 years, who have been recruited within 24&#xD;
      hours after starting antibiotic treatment, the prescribed treatment should be with&#xD;
      antibiotics for a minimum of 9 days and a maximum of 14 days. The informed consent must be&#xD;
      signed before starting the study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Two groups (placebo and intervention) will receive supplementation, the Placebo group will&#xD;
      receive maltodextrin and Intervention group will receive probiotic B. lactis, that should be&#xD;
      consumed for a period of 10 to 14 days depending on the duration of administration of the&#xD;
      antibiotic (should be consumed until 7 day after the last antibiotic).&#xD;
&#xD;
      As a way of ensuring an equal distribution of the number of participants in the study groups&#xD;
      and ensuring that the groups are similar, a randomization by blocks will be carried out and&#xD;
      stratified by sex and age. The program that will be used to generate random numbers is the&#xD;
      Research Randomizer Form v4.0. The packaging of both supplements will be identical except for&#xD;
      the color, which will distinguish maltodextrin from probiotic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Supplements will be delivered by a research collaborator as a way to guarantee blinding.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The probiotic to be supplied will be Bifidobacterium lactis CCT 7858 (GABBIA® Biotechnology&#xD;
      and Development, Santa Catarina, Brazil). The probiotic will be offered in capsule and in the&#xD;
      concentration of 9x10 10 UFC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The groups will be evaluated in two moments: baseline and final.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The evaluation of the individuals will be performed through the collection of the following&#xD;
      data: necessity and duration of antibiotic therapy (type of antibiotic) used while&#xD;
      participating in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood pressure will also be assessed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Body weight will be measured. The body mass index will be calculated&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to verify the tolerance and effectiveness of the supplements, questions regarding&#xD;
      the frequency and consistency of feces will be asked, evaluated using the Bristol scale (1:&#xD;
      separate pieces, 2: segmented sausage shape, 3: cracked sausage shape, 4: smooth and soft&#xD;
      sausage shape, 5: soft pieces, 6: aerated pieces, 7: watery) and gastrointestinal symptoms&#xD;
      (excess flatulence in the rectum, abdominal distention, borborisms, abdominal pain and the&#xD;
      occurrence of vomiting or nausea), will be assessed daily throughout the study period using a&#xD;
      five-point scale (0: none, 1: weak, 2: moderate, 3: strong, 4: very strong).&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, the Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale (GSRS) questionnaire will be used to&#xD;
      assess symptomatic evolution.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before starting the intervention, each participant will record the frequency of defecation,&#xD;
      characteristics and feeling of defecation (as an initial assessment) and daily after the&#xD;
      start of the intervention.&#xD;
&#xD;
      They will fill out a questionnaire about bowel function weekly.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Changes in quality of life during the study will be measured by the SF-36 questionnaire,&#xD;
      which consists of 36 items encompassed in 8 scales or components: functional capacity,&#xD;
      physical aspects, pain, general health, vitality, social aspects, emotional aspects, mental&#xD;
      health and another question of comparative evaluation between the current health conditions&#xD;
      and that of a year ago.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The data will be organized and recorded in a database in the Microsoft Office Excel 2007®&#xD;
      program with double entry. The statistical analysis will be performed in the Statistical&#xD;
      statistical program Package for the Social Sciences (SPSS) version 24.0 for Windows.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Quantitative variables will be described and presented in mean and standard deviation from&#xD;
      the mean if the distribution is symmetrical or in median and interquartile range if it is&#xD;
      asymmetric. Nominal variables will be described in frequency categories as of the appearance&#xD;
      in the described groups. To assess the distribution of data, the Shapiro-Wilk normality test&#xD;
      will be applied. If the data is asymmetric, it will undergo logarithmic normalization or the&#xD;
      non-parametric test will be used.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intragroup changes will be analyzed by the difference (Basal and End) between the&#xD;
      variables, using the paired Student t test or Wilcoxon.&#xD;
&#xD;
      When including 60% of patients, the data will be evaluated by an independent researcher to&#xD;
      check whether the difference estimates are true. If necessary, the sample calculation will be&#xD;
      reassessed&#xD;
&#xD;
      The assessment of treatment adherence will be measured by self-report on the daily assessment&#xD;
      and telephone interviews, and at the end of the study you will be asked to deliver the&#xD;
      supplement package.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 11, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 11, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Decreased diarrhea</measure>
    <time_frame>10 - 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Decreased diarrhea through bristol scale. The Bristol stool scale is a diagnostic medical tool designed to classify the form of human faeces into seven categories. Categories: 1 - 7</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improve in Quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>10-14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Improved quality of life through Short Form 36 Health Survey (SF-36) scale/questionare. The Short Form (36) Health Survey is a 36-item, patient-reported survey of patient health. The SF-36 consists of eight scaled scores, which are the weighted sums of the questions in their section. Each scale is directly transformed into a 0-100 scale on the assumption that each question carries equal weight. The lower the score the more disability.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Improve of gastrointestinal symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>10 - 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Improve of gastrointestinal symptoms through Gastrointestinal Symptom Rating Scale (GSRS). The GSRS is a disease-specific instrument. The 15 items combine into five symptom clusters: Reflux, Abdominal pain, Indigestion, Diarrhoea and Constipation. Each item is rated on a 7-point Likert scale. Scale 7 refers to worse symptoms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">116</enrollment>
  <condition>Surgery</condition>
  <condition>Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>1x capsule/day - maltodextrin, period of 10 to 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>B Lactis</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>1x capsule/day - 9x10x10 UFC, period of 10 to 14 days</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Bifidobacterium Lactis CCT7858</intervention_name>
    <description>Probiotic B Lactis</description>
    <arm_group_label>B Lactis</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Maltodextrin</intervention_name>
    <description>Maltodextrin</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults of both sexes;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Aged between 18 and 65 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  24 hours after starting antibiotic treatment;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Antibiotics tretament for a minimum of 3 days and a maximum of 14 days;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent must be signed before starting the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  blood pressure is outside the normal range (systolic blood pressure&gt; 140, systolic&#xD;
             blood pressure &lt;90, diastolic&gt; 90);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of heart disease, including heart valve disease or heart surgery, any&#xD;
             implantable device;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  continuous or recent use of antibiotic therapy in the 30 days prior to the first&#xD;
             administration of the study supplement;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ostomates or users of parenteral nutrition;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  immunosuppressive therapy or any health condition that causes immunosuppression&#xD;
             (including hematology malignancies, AIDS);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Crohn's disease or ulcerative colitis;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous infection with Clostridium difficile documented less than 3 months before the&#xD;
             start of the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  history of daily consumption of probiotics, fermented milk;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  individuals known to have demonstrated a previous reaction, including anaphylaxis, to&#xD;
             any substance in the study product composition;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  individuals with active diarrhea (3 or more liquid stools per 24 hour period);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnant women at the time of recruitment or planning to become pregnant during the&#xD;
             study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with concomitant participation in another clinical trial.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>GABBIA Biotecnologia</name>
      <address>
        <city>Criciuma</city>
        <state>Santa Catarina</state>
        <zip>88390000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Gabriel Alves de Jesus, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+55 48 84250211</phone>
      <email>gabriel@gabbia.com.br</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 21, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidade do Extremo Sul Catarinense - Unidade Academica de Ciecias da Saude</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Felipe Dal Pizzol</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Clinical Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>probiotic</keyword>
  <keyword>antibiotic</keyword>
  <keyword>B lactis</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

