<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04745286</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20210106</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04745286</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of Small-dose S-ketamine on Anesthesia-induced Atelectasis in Anesthetized Patients Accessed by Pulmonary Ultrasound</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effects of Small-dose S-ketamine on Anesthesia-induced Atelectasis in Patients Undergoing General Anesthesia Accessed by Pulmonary Ultrasound：Study Protocol for a Randomized, Double-blinded Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Beijing Tiantan Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Beijing Tiantan Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Background: Atelectasis occurs in the majority of patients with general anesthesia, which can&#xD;
      lead to postoperative pulmonary complications (PPCs) and affect the postoperative outcome.&#xD;
      However, there is still no exact method to prevent it though agents. S-ketamine may prevent&#xD;
      atelectasis due to its airway smooth muscle relaxation and anti-inflammatory effects. Lung&#xD;
      ultrasound is a portable and reliable bedside imaging technology for diagnosing&#xD;
      anesthesia-induced atelectasis. Here, we intend to assess whether small-dose of S-ketamine&#xD;
      can reduce the incidence of atelectasis after intubation under general anesthesia using lung&#xD;
      ultrasound, in order to prevent the early formation of perioperative atelectasis and&#xD;
      perioperative pulmonary complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: The trial is a single institution, prospective, randomized controlled, parallel&#xD;
      grouping, double-blind study. From October 2021 to March 2022, 100 patients (18-60 years old)&#xD;
      scheduled for elective surgery will be recruited from Beijing Tiantan Hospital, Capital&#xD;
      Medical University, and randomly assigned to the S-ketamine group (Group S) and the normal&#xD;
      saline group (Group N) at a ratio of 1:1. The label-masked agents will be given 5 minutes&#xD;
      before induction and all patients will undergo a standardized general anesthesia protocol.&#xD;
      Related data will be collected at three time point: after radial artery puncture (T1), 15&#xD;
      minutes after tracheal intubation (T2) and before extubation (T3). The primary outcome will&#xD;
      be the total LUS scores at T2. Secondary outcomes include LUS scores in 6 chest regions at&#xD;
      T2; total LUS scores at T3; arterial blood-gas analysis results (PaCO2, PaO2) and PaO2/FiO2&#xD;
      at T2 and T3, plateau pressure(Pplat) and dynamic lung compliance (Cdyn) at T2 and T3; the&#xD;
      incidence of postoperative complications associated with S-ketamine and postoperative&#xD;
      pulmonary complications (PPCs) 2 and 24 hours after surgery；.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Discussion: This trial aims to explore whether a simple and feasible application of&#xD;
      S-ketamine before the induction of general anesthesia can prevent atelectasis. The results of&#xD;
      this study may provide new ideas and direct clinical evidence for the prevention and&#xD;
      treatment of perioperative pulmonary complications during anesthesia.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Key words: atelectasis, S-ketamine, ultrasound, RCT, protocol&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Early Phase 1</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>total lung sonography scores(LUS) scores at T2</measure>
    <time_frame>T2：at the time of tracheal intubation</time_frame>
    <description>Using SonoSite M-Turbo with a 5-12 MHz linear transducer,patients will be scanned and scored in the supine position following the lung ultrasound method described by Sun L and colleagues. Briefly, six regions will be scanned on in each hemithorax. Scans 1 and 2 will be performed at the midline of the clavicle, scans 3 and 4 will be performed in the axilla midline. The intercostal scans (Scans 5-6) will be performed in the fifth and sixth intercostal spaces of the posterior axillary line. Place a linear probe parallel to the ribs and scan the intercostal space of each region using a two-dimensional view sequentially from right to left, cranial to caudal, and anterior to posterior within 2 minutes.Each region will be categorised and assigned into four scores(0-3) based on B-lines.Add the scores in all twelve regions to get total lung sonography scores(LUS). Finally get a score between 0 (no atelectasis) and 36 (complete atelectasis).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>LUS scores in 6 chest regions(scans 1-6) at T2</measure>
    <time_frame>T2：at the time of tracheal intubation</time_frame>
    <description>Using SonoSite M-Turbo with a 5-12 MHz linear transducer,patients will be scanned and scored in the supine position following the lung ultrasound method described by Sun L and colleagues. Briefly, six regions will be scanned on in each hemithorax. Scans 1 and 2 will be performed at the midline of the clavicle, scans 3 and 4 will be performed in the axilla midline. The intercostal scans (Scans 5-6) will be performed in the fifth and sixth intercostal spaces of the posterior axillary line. Place a linear probe parallel to the ribs and scan the intercostal space of each region using a two-dimensional view sequentially from right to left, cranial to caudal, and anterior to posterior within 2 minutes.Each region will be categorised and assigned into four scores(0-3) based on B-lines. Finally get six sets of data betweem 0(no atelectasis) and 6 (complete atelectasis).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>total LUS scores at T3</measure>
    <time_frame>T3：5min before extubation</time_frame>
    <description>Using SonoSite M-Turbo with a 5-12 MHz linear transducer,patients will be scanned and scored in the supine position following the lung ultrasound method described by Sun L and colleagues. Briefly, six regions will be scanned on in each hemithorax. Scans 1 and 2 will be performed at the midline of the clavicle, scans 3 and 4 will be performed in the axilla midline. The intercostal scans (Scans 5-6) will be performed in the fifth and sixth intercostal spaces of the posterior axillary line. Place a linear probe parallel to the ribs and scan the intercostal space of each region using a two-dimensional view sequentially from right to left, cranial to caudal, and anterior to posterior within 2 minutes.Each region will be categorised and assigned into four scores(0-3) based on B-lines. Finally get a score between 0 (no atelectasis) and 36 (complete atelectasis).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>arterial blood-gas analysis results (PaCO2, PaO2) and PaO2/FiO2 at T2 and T3</measure>
    <time_frame>after tracheal intubation (T2) and 5min before extubation (T3)</time_frame>
    <description>arterial blood samples will be obtained through radial artery puncture and blood-gas measurements will be performed immediately using a standard technique (ABL800) to get arterial blood-gas analysis results (PaCO2, PaO2) and PaO2/FiO2 at T2 and T3</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>plateau pressure and dynamic lung compliance (Cdyn) at T2 and T3</measure>
    <time_frame>after tracheal intubation (T2) and 5min before extubation (T3)</time_frame>
    <description>[Cdyn = tidal volume/(PIP-PEEP)]</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the incidence of postoperative complications associated with S-ketamine 2 and 24 hours after surgery</measure>
    <time_frame>2 and 24 hours after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>visual impairment, dizziness, pathological irritability, nightmares and hallucinations</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the incidence of postoperative pulmonary complications (PPCs)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 and 24 hours after surgery</time_frame>
    <description>the clinical outcome defifinitions of PPCs will adopt European joint taskforce guidelines published in 2015 which include respiratory infection; respiratory failure; atelectasis; pleural effusion; pneumothorax; bronchospasm, aspiration pneumonia; pulmonary edema; ARDS; tracheobronchitis; pulmonary oedema; exacerbation of pre-existing lung disease; pulmonary embolism</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Atelectasis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>S-ketamine group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>saline group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>S-ketamine</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive the label-covered trial agent covered by the label after premedication 5 min before induction. Agent preparation method of S-ketamine group (Group S): Draw the dosage of S-ketamine 0.25mg ·kg -1 and dilute it with normal saline to 5ml in opaque 5-ml syringes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>S-ketamine group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>normal saline group</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will receive the label-covered trial agent covered by the label after premedication 5 min before induction. Normal saline group (Group N): 5ml of normal saline, labeled as &quot;study agents&quot;.</description>
    <arm_group_label>saline group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age of 18 - 60 years;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. American Society of Anesthesiologists (ASA) physical status of I - II;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Patients scheduled for urinary, obstetrics and gynecology surgery in supine position&#xD;
             or lithotomy position under general anesthesia, and the expected operation time is&#xD;
             more than 1 hour;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Patients and their authorized surrogates have signed the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients who have difficulty in applying pulmonary ultrasound, such as chest&#xD;
             fractures, surgical history, etc;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients who have a history of upper respiratory tract infection one month before&#xD;
             surgery, or a history of smoking more than 6 packs/year;&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Preoperative chest X-ray or CT abnormalities, including atelectasis, pneumothorax,&#xD;
             pleural effusion or pneumonia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. BMI&gt;30kg/㎡;&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Expected difficulty in intubation or mask ventilation;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Patients with significant increase in intraocular pressure and intracranial pressure&#xD;
             before surgery;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Patients allergic to S-ketamine, propofol and opioids.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with a positive history of psychiatric disorders.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>atelectasis</keyword>
  <keyword>S-ketamine</keyword>
  <keyword>ultrasound</keyword>
  <keyword>RCT</keyword>
  <keyword>protocol</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pulmonary Atelectasis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Ketamine</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Esketamine</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

