<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04747418</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>7975-20-SMC</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04747418</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Uterine Inflammatory Characteristics</brief_title>
  <official_title>Uterine Inflammatory Characteristics Following Cesarean Delivery</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Sheba Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Sheba Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Data regarding fertility following niche repair is limited. It has been reported that a niche&#xD;
      can reduce the chances of embryo implantation and may lead to spontaneous miscarriages if the&#xD;
      implantation is close to or in the niche. One possible theory refers to inflammatory process&#xD;
      at the area of the niche that harms the endometrial environment. Due to the aforementioned,&#xD;
      the aim of our study is to compare the inflammatory characteristics of women with cesarean&#xD;
      uterine scar to those without.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Background As the rate of caesarean section continues to increase, concern regarding the&#xD;
      association between delivery by caesarean section and long-term maternal morbidity has been&#xD;
      growing . In the past decade, several articles have described a defect that can be seen on&#xD;
      ultrasound at the site of the caesarean delivery scar, known as a 'niche' . A 'niche'&#xD;
      describes the presence of a hypoechoic area within the myometrium of the lower uterine&#xD;
      segment, reflecting a discontinuation of the myometrium at the site of a previous cesarean&#xD;
      delivery. An incompletely healed scar is a long-term complication of cesarean delivery and is&#xD;
      associated with symptoms such as postmenstrual spotting, dysmenorrhoea, chronic pelvic pain&#xD;
      dyspareunia and subfertility. Furthermore, it can increase rates of complications during&#xD;
      gynaecological procedures and it is associated with higher complication rate in subsequent&#xD;
      pregnancy including: risk of rupture and morbidly adherent placenta.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Lately, a surgical resection of the abnormal myometrial area has been proposed mainly for&#xD;
      symptomatic women, or for women that are planning future pregnancy. Different techniques have&#xD;
      been used including hysteroscopy, laparoscopy and vaginal repair. Consideration of the&#xD;
      surgical approach is usually determined by the patient's plans for fertility and by niche&#xD;
      thickness. For women who do not desire pregnancy and whose niche thickness is &gt;3 mm, a&#xD;
      hysteroscopic approach is considered. Patients who desire future fertility, especially those&#xD;
      with &lt;3 mm of myometrium at the niche site, is usually recommended laparoscopic resection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data regarding fertility following niche repair is limited. It has been reported that a niche&#xD;
      can reduce the chances of embryo implantation and may lead to spontaneous miscarriages if the&#xD;
      implantation is close to or in the niche. One possible theory refers to inflammatory process&#xD;
      at the area of the niche that harms the endometrial environment. Additional theories address&#xD;
      the mechanical changes influencing the myometrium and the discontinuation of the endometrium&#xD;
      at the site of the niche. Gurol Urganci et al. reported in a meta-analysis including 16&#xD;
      studies, that caesarean delivery reduces the probability of subsequent pregnancy by 10%&#xD;
      [relative risk (RR) 0.91; 95% 0.87-0.95] on average, compared with a previous vaginal&#xD;
      delivery, however, none of the studies included in the meta-analysis evaluated the relation&#xD;
      between subsequent fertility and the presence of a niche. So far there is no definite proof&#xD;
      for niche as a cause of infertility. Should this be supported by randomized controlled&#xD;
      trials, it would be grounds for providing treatment that will expectedly lead to beneficial&#xD;
      effects on reproductive outcomes. This yet needs to be proven in.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to the aforementioned, the aim of our study is to compare the inflammatory&#xD;
      characteristics of women with cesarean uterine scar to those without.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and Methods This is a prospective study including all women visiting hysteroscopy&#xD;
      ambulatory clinics for diagnostic hysteroscopy . All women meeting inclusion criteria will&#xD;
      sign informed consent prior to the hysteroscopy after given explanation by one of the&#xD;
      research team. During hysteroscopy 5 cc of the flushed water, that usually is drilled into a&#xD;
      collecting bin that is thrown away, will be collect threw a small outlet port using a syringe&#xD;
      connected to the outlet port of the hysteroscope. Women with normal diagnostic hysteroscopy&#xD;
      will be included in the study. Those with low segment cesarean deliver scar will comprise the&#xD;
      study arm and will be compared to women with no uterine scar (controls). Samples will be send&#xD;
      to the IVF laboratory for analyzing inflammatory characteristics. Date regarding&#xD;
      demographics, obstetrical and gynecological history will be collected from women's medical&#xD;
      records. Primary outcome is defined as the level of inflammatory cytokines as a composite&#xD;
      outcome&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">February 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Level of inflammatory cytokines ( Granulocyte Macrophage colony stimulating factor(GM-CSF), Interferone-GAMMA, Interleukin(IL)-1,IL-2,IL-5,IL-6,IL-7,IL13,IL-15, IL-17, IL-22, IL-23,IL-31,IL-33,IL-36, Tumor Necrosis Factor (TNF) -ALPHA )</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an estimated period of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>All parameters will be evaluated in picogram/milliliter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Niche characteristics-Residual myometrial thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>During sonographic evaluation performed immediately following diagnostic hysteroscopy</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated in millimeters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Niche characteristics-Adjacent myometrial thickness</measure>
    <time_frame>During sonographic evaluation performed immediately following diagnostic hysteroscopy</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated in millimeters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Niche characteristics-Depth</measure>
    <time_frame>During sonographic evaluation performed immediately following diagnostic hysteroscopy</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated in millimeters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Niche characteristics-Length</measure>
    <time_frame>During sonographic evaluation performed immediately following diagnostic hysteroscopy</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated in millimeters</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">160</enrollment>
  <condition>Cesarean Section Complications</condition>
  <condition>Fertility Disorders</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group: Women with low segment uterine scar following cesarean delivery</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women with low segment uterine scar following cesarean delivery, with no other abnormalities observed during diagnostic hysteroscopy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort Group: Women with no uterine scar</arm_group_label>
    <description>Women with no uterine scar, with no other abnormalities observed during diagnostic hysteroscopy</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Diagnostic Hysteroscopy</intervention_name>
    <description>Collection of first 5 cc of normal saline from the output port during diagnostic hysteroscopy</description>
    <arm_group_label>Cohort Group: Women with no uterine scar</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group: Women with low segment uterine scar following cesarean delivery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Trans-vaginal ultrasound</intervention_name>
    <description>Trans vaginal ultrasound performed immediately following the diagnostic hysteroscopy ( as sonohysterography)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Study Group: Women with low segment uterine scar following cesarean delivery</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Women with low segment uterine scar following cesarean delivery ( Study group ) and women&#xD;
        with no uterine scar ( Controls), that have no abnormal finding on diagnostic hysterocopy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fertility age 18-45&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No abnormal finding during hysteroscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women with other uterine scars (following myomectomy, T/J scar)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>45 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aya M Mohr-Sasson, M.D</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Sheba Medical Center, Tel-Hashomer</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aya M Mohr-Sasson, M.D</last_name>
    <phone>0523692906</phone>
    <email>mohraya@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Aya M Mohr- Sasson, M.D</last_name>
    <phone>0523692906</phone>
    <email>mohraya@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Sheba Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ramat Gan</city>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Aya Mohr Sasson, M.D</last_name>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>van der Voet LF, Bij de Vaate AM, Veersema S, Brölmann HA, Huirne JA. Long-term complications of caesarean section. The niche in the scar: a prospective cohort study on niche prevalence and its relation to abnormal uterine bleeding. BJOG. 2014 Jan;121(2):236-44. doi: 10.1111/1471-0528.12542.</citation>
    <PMID>24373597</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Naji O, Abdallah Y, Bij De Vaate AJ, Smith A, Pexsters A, Stalder C, McIndoe A, Ghaem-Maghami S, Lees C, Brölmann HA, Huirne JA, Timmerman D, Bourne T. Standardized approach for imaging and measuring Cesarean section scars using ultrasonography. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2012 Mar;39(3):252-9. doi: 10.1002/uog.10077. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>21858885</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Roberge S, Boutin A, Chaillet N, Moore L, Jastrow N, Demers S, Bujold E. Systematic review of cesarean scar assessment in the nonpregnant state: imaging techniques and uterine scar defect. Am J Perinatol. 2012 Jun;29(6):465-71. doi: 10.1055/s-0032-1304829. Epub 2012 Mar 7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>22399223</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vervoort AJ, Uittenbogaard LB, Hehenkamp WJ, Brölmann HA, Mol BW, Huirne JA. Why do niches develop in Caesarean uterine scars? Hypotheses on the aetiology of niche development. Hum Reprod. 2015 Dec;30(12):2695-702. doi: 10.1093/humrep/dev240. Epub 2015 Sep 25.</citation>
    <PMID>26409016</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Wang CB, Chiu WW, Lee CY, Sun YL, Lin YH, Tseng CJ. Cesarean scar defect: correlation between Cesarean section number, defect size, clinical symptoms and uterine position. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2009 Jul;34(1):85-9. doi: 10.1002/uog.6405.</citation>
    <PMID>19565535</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Brown K, Tkacz Z. Hysteroscopic and laparoscopic management of caesarean scar (niche) defects in symptomatic patients. J Obstet Gynaecol. 2018 Jul;38(5):730. doi: 10.1080/01443615.2018.1444394.</citation>
    <PMID>29944046</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vervoort AJ, Van der Voet LF, Witmer M, Thurkow AL, Radder CM, van Kesteren PJ, Quartero HW, Kuchenbecker WK, Bongers MY, Geomini PM, de Vleeschouwer LH, van Hooff MH, van Vliet HA, Veersema S, Renes WB, van Meurs HS, Bosmans J, Oude Rengerink K, Brölmann HA, Mol BW, Huirne JA. The HysNiche trial: hysteroscopic resection of uterine caesarean scar defect (niche) in patients with abnormal bleeding, a randomised controlled trial. BMC Womens Health. 2015 Nov 12;15:103. doi: 10.1186/s12905-015-0260-8.</citation>
    <PMID>26563197</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>van der Voet LF, Vervoort AJ, Veersema S, BijdeVaate AJ, Brölmann HA, Huirne JA. Minimally invasive therapy for gynaecological symptoms related to a niche in the caesarean scar: a systematic review. BJOG. 2014 Jan;121(2):145-56. doi: 10.1111/1471-0528.12537. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24373589</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Hemminki E. Impact of caesarean section on future pregnancy--a review of cohort studies. Paediatr Perinat Epidemiol. 1996 Oct;10(4):366-79. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>8931052</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Naji O, Wynants L, Smith A, Abdallah Y, Saso S, Stalder C, Van Huffel S, Ghaem-Maghami S, Van Calster B, Timmerman D, Bourne T. Does the presence of a Caesarean section scar affect implantation site and early pregnancy outcome in women attending an early pregnancy assessment unit? Hum Reprod. 2013 Jun;28(6):1489-96. doi: 10.1093/humrep/det110. Epub 2013 Apr 12.</citation>
    <PMID>23585560</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gurol-Urganci I, Bou-Antoun S, Lim CP, Cromwell DA, Mahmood TA, Templeton A, van der Meulen JH. Impact of Caesarean section on subsequent fertility: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Hum Reprod. 2013 Jul;28(7):1943-52. doi: 10.1093/humrep/det130. Epub 2013 May 3. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>23644593</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vissers J, Hehenkamp W, Lambalk CB, Huirne JA. Post-Caesarean section niche-related impaired fertility: hypothetical mechanisms. Hum Reprod. 2020 Jul 1;35(7):1484-1494. doi: 10.1093/humrep/deaa094.</citation>
    <PMID>32613231</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Vitale SG, Ludwin A, Vilos GA, Török P, Tesarik J, Vitagliano A, Lasmar RB, Chiofalo B. From hysteroscopy to laparoendoscopic surgery: what is the best surgical approach for symptomatic isthmocele? A systematic review and meta-analysis. Arch Gynecol Obstet. 2020 Jan;301(1):33-52. doi: 10.1007/s00404-020-05438-0. Epub 2020 Jan 27.</citation>
    <PMID>31989288</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Sheba Medical Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Aya Mohr-Sasson</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Cesarean Section Complications</keyword>
  <keyword>Fertility Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Inflammatory characteristics</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Will be available upon request</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

