<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04743219</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>0212202023220</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04743219</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Selective Removal Technique With or Without a Bioactive Material for Deep Caries Lesions</brief_title>
  <official_title>Selective Removal Technique With or Without the Use of a Bioactive Material for the Management of Deep Caries Lesions in Permanent Posterior Teeth With Close Apex. A Randomized Clinical Trial.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad Rey Juan Carlos</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad Rey Juan Carlos</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objectives: To evaluate and compare clinical and radiographic success of the selective&#xD;
      removal to soft dentine technique in one step using calcium silicate cement (Biodentine) vs.&#xD;
      no indirect pulp capping material in patients with deep caries lesions in mature permanent&#xD;
      posterior teeth with normal or reversible pulpitis after a 2 year follow-up. Evaluate the&#xD;
      integrity of the resin composite restorations using FDI criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Material and methods: selective removal to soft dentine in one visit will be performed in 104&#xD;
      blinded patients that will be randomly allocated into 2 study arms, 52 patients will&#xD;
      constitute the Biodentine group and 52 the No material group. Clinical examination will be&#xD;
      performed to obtain pre-, intra- and postoperative data, including vitality test results,&#xD;
      periapical status and risk of caries of the patients. Periapical and bitewing radiographs&#xD;
      will be taken before treatment (T-0), at 1 month (T-1), 6 months (T-2), 12 months (T-3) and&#xD;
      24 months (T-4). Restorations will be assessed using the FDI criteria at the same follow up&#xD;
      periods.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized clinical trial</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical success</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical success is defined as healthy pulp, determined by a normal positive not prolonged response in the clinical examination to the cold test and the electrical test, negative response to percussion, absence of symptoms or signs of infection (abscess, fistula, swelling or inflammation) and absence of spontaneous pain.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Radiographic success</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>Radiographic success is defined as the absence of widening of the periodontal ligament space (twice the equivalent of the adjacent healthy tooth) and the absence of a periapical or furcal lesion on radiographic examination. A periapical lesion is considered to be a radiolucency associated with the radiographic apex of the root of a size greater than twice the width of the periodontal ligament space.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Failure composite resin restorations</measure>
    <time_frame>2 years</time_frame>
    <description>FDI criteria will be used to assess the integrity of the composite resin restorations,It will be considered a restoration failure when the restoration presents a property classified as clinically unsatisfactory or poor. Thus, body fracture or loss of restoration, damage to the margin, weak contact point or food impaction, marginal or large gap, secondary caries or if the patient is not satisfied.</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">104</enrollment>
  <condition>Deep Caries</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Biodentine Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Biodentine group: patients with mature permanent posterior teeth with deep caries lesions treated with the selective removal technique to soft dentin with Biodentine as indirect pulp capping material before placement of a definitive direct composite resin restoration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>No base Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The experimental group or No Base group: patients with mature permanent posterior teeth with deep caries lesions treated with the selective removal technique to soft dentin without the placement of a bioactive material as a base and restored directly with a definitive direct composite resin restoration.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Selective removal to soft dentin, Biodentine</intervention_name>
    <description>Carious tissue removed until its complete elimination from the lateral walls of the cavity using a round tungsten carbide bur at low speed until consistency of hard dentin around perimeter. With a manual excavator, the central cariogenic biomass will be removed, specifically the superficial part of the necrotic and demineralized caries dentin.&#xD;
In the Biodentine group, Biodentine (Septodont) will be placed on the base of the cavity with a thickness of 2 mm.&#xD;
The last step will be to perform a definitive direct resin restoration according to clinical indication.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Biodentine Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Selective removal to soft dentin, No Base</intervention_name>
    <description>Carious tissue removed until its complete elimination from the lateral walls of the cavity using a round tungsten carbide bur at low speed until consistency of hard dentin around perimeter. With a manual excavator, the central cariogenic biomass will be removed, specifically the superficial part of the necrotic and demineralized caries dentin.&#xD;
In the No base group, no bioactive material will be placed as a liner, the 3M Scothcbonf Universal Plus adhesive will be placed directly over the remaining dentin surface.&#xD;
The last step will be to perform a definitive direct resin restoration according to clinical indication.</description>
    <arm_group_label>No base Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients older than 15 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Parents or guardians of patients under 18 years of age, but over 15 years of age, and&#xD;
             patients over 18 years of age who demonstrate understanding of the study and&#xD;
             willingness to participate as evidenced by signing the voluntary informed consent and&#xD;
             who receive a signed and dated copy of the informed consent form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Occlusal or occlusal-proximal caries lesions, Class I or Class II, in molars or&#xD;
             premolars with enamel margins and affecting maximum one proximal wall.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Molar or premolar with deep caries lesion, involving equal to or greater than two&#xD;
             thirds of dentin in depth, with a radiographically identifiable band of healthy dentin&#xD;
             separating the pulp chamber roof from the caries lesion.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Normal response to tests of sensitivity (normal pulp) or discomfort when cold stimulus&#xD;
             is applied that disappears in a couple of seconds after the elimination of the&#xD;
             stimulus (reversible pulpitits).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Teeth with negative percussion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients immunosuppressed or with severe systemic diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Teeth with root or cervical resorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Teeth with obliteration of the pulp chamber.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Periapical or furcal radiolucency.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with periodontal disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with spontaneous acute pain, prolonged excruciating pain and / or pain that&#xD;
             disturbs night sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have an allergy to any of the materials used in the treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with caries lesions that during the treatment of their removal a pulp&#xD;
             exposure is performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with inadequate initial radiographs for analysis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of pre-cancerous or cancerous lesions.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have taken antibiotics in the last two weeks.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>15 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Laura Ceballos</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Universidad Rey Juan Carlos</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Patricia Terceño</last_name>
    <phone>659053538</phone>
    <email>ptercenojimenez@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Laura Ceballos</last_name>
    <phone>667056606</phone>
    <email>laura.ceballos@urjc.es</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Universidad Rey Juan Carlos</name>
      <address>
        <city>Alcorcón</city>
        <state>Madrid</state>
        <zip>28922</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Patricia Terceño Jiménez</last_name>
      <phone>659053538</phone>
      <email>ptercenojimenez@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Laura Ceballos García</last_name>
      <phone>659053538</phone>
      <email>laura.ceballos@urjc.es</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Patricia Terceño</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Laura Ceballos</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gonzalo Olivieri</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidad Rey Juan Carlos</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Patricia Terceño Jiménez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>DDS, MS</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

