<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04749576</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HowardU</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04749576</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Saffron as Anti Inflammatory Agent In Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease</brief_title>
  <official_title>Efficacy of Nutritional Saffron Supplement As An Anti Inflammatory Agent In Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Howard University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Howard University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Nutritional Saffron supplement has been widely used as food supplement and has known&#xD;
      anti-depressant and anti-inflammatory activities. It is generally consumed as stigmas in&#xD;
      drinks or dishes. The investigators use saffron extract in patients with colitis for 8 weeks.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The patients invited to participate in a research study on Inflammatory Bowel Diseases (IBD)&#xD;
      and saffron as a nutritional anti-inflammatory supplement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IBD) is composed of Crohn's Disease (CD) and Ulcerative Colitis&#xD;
      (UC). Continuous altered immune responses and inflammation associate with this disease. More&#xD;
      than two-thirds of patients reported that IBD-associated symptoms negatively affected their&#xD;
      quality of life and their performance at work.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Patients with IBD are generally put on immunosuppressants (that block or slow&#xD;
           participants' immune system to lower the level of inflammation). Long-term use of these&#xD;
           immunosuppressants have some serious side effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The goal of this protocol is to lower the need for these immunosuppressants by giving&#xD;
           saffron as capsules in two different doses. The investigators will assess whether the&#xD;
           addition of saffron will improve the overall patient's status and decrease the need for&#xD;
           immunosuppressants. If participants have been prescribed immunosuppressants by the&#xD;
           participant's doctor, saffron will be added to the participants' treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The investigators request that the subject answer as many questions as they can during&#xD;
           this visit. If they are unable to complete the questionnaires during this visit, the&#xD;
           investigators ask them to please return them within 7 days. If the investigators do not&#xD;
           receive the questionnaires, the investigators will make one phone call to remind the&#xD;
           subjects to send the questionnaires back.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The subject medical record and colonoscopy report will be used to determine IBD or&#xD;
           health status, the blood sample will be used to assess immune markers (inflammatory and&#xD;
           antiinflammatory), stool sample will be used to assess some inflammation markers and&#xD;
           saffron effect on the intestinal bacterial composition, a saliva sample will be used to&#xD;
           assess whether saffron selectively affects the intestinal bacteria but not the saliva&#xD;
           bacteria and the urine sample will be used to assess saffron release in body fluids.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Participants are being asked to participate in this research project because&#xD;
           participants are having a normal colonoscopy for screening, or IBD.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  If a biopsy is taken at colonoscopy. a pathologist will use a portion to make a&#xD;
           diagnosis. The investigators are requesting permission to use a portion of the excess&#xD;
           tissue that the pathologist does not need, for this research project.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Samples will be collected at baseline (day 0) and 8 weeks later after saffron capsules&#xD;
           utilization.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  This is a double-blind clinical trial, you will not know whether participants are given&#xD;
           a placebo (capsule without saffron) or saffron dose 1 or 2. This is important for&#xD;
           participants and for the study process, to avoid any psychological effect on the&#xD;
           expected saffron effect.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  However, by the end of the 8 weeks and after collecting and analyzing the data from all&#xD;
           participants, the investigators will inform the subject of what the subjects were given&#xD;
           and potential next steps.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 15, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 10, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 10, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>randomize double placebo</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
    <masking_description>Both patients and care provider does not know whether the participant receiving placebo or saffron</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>inflammatory markers assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Serum anti-inflammatory and pro-inflammatory markers measures in 8 weeks compared to baseline improving the blood immune marker in the normal range for contributing factors which consist of TNF-α (8.1 pg/mL).IL-1β (&lt;5 pg/mL), IL-6(5-15 pg/ml)., and IL-10 (4.8-9.8 pg/ml), The units in the parenthesis are the normal range for each marker</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>stool frequency assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 week</time_frame>
    <description>will be assessed by decreasing less than 2 per day</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>stool consistency assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 week</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement to median score 4 to normal stool consistency. Bristol score: Improvement in stool consistency measures in 8 weeks in our study compared to baseline (Bristol score: The ideal stool is generally type 3 or 4, easy to pass without being too watery too solid. Type 1 or 2, it is sign of constipation. Types 5, 6, and 7 tend toward diarrhea)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>fecal calprotectin assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Decrease in calprotectin levels. Fecal calprotectin normal range to be 10 to 60 μg/mg</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>C reactive protein assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 week</time_frame>
    <description>change on C reactive protein level reading is less than 10 milligram per liter</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>erythrocyte sedimentation rate assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>maintaining erythrocyte sedimentation rate with the normal range of 0 to 22 mm/hr for men and 0 to 29 mm/hr for women.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Pro-inflammatory assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>improving the blood immune marker in the normal range for contributing factors which consist of TNF-α (8.1 pg/mL).IL-1β (&lt;5 pg/mL), IL-6(5-15 pg/ml)., IL-10 (4.8-9.8 pg/ml), and Th17 (221.6±90.2/µl). The units in the parenthesis are the normal range for each marker</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum Anti-inflammatory assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>improve the IL-10 level to at least reach the normal level of ranged from 4.8-9.8 pg/ml</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Ulcerative Colitis Colonoscopic Index of Severity scores</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Decrease of 2 or more unit in the Ulcerative Colitis Colonoscopic Index of Severity score. The Ulcerative Colitis Colonoscopic Index of Severity scores for mild colitis is 3-5, and for moderate is 5-9</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>endoscopy colitis assessment</measure>
    <time_frame>8-12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Secondary endpoints will be endoscopy remission at week 8-12 according to gastroenterologist preference</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Ulcerative Colitis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Low dose saffron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>healthy, mild-moderate ulcerative colitis for low dose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>High dose Saffron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>healthy, mild-moderate ulcerative colitis for high dose</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>healthy, mild-moderate ulcerative colitis for placebo</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>saffron supplement for IBD</intervention_name>
    <description>anti inflammatory effect</description>
    <arm_group_label>High dose Saffron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Low dose saffron</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Male or female patients aged &gt;18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Have UC diagnosed at least 3 months prior to screening? The diagnosis of UC must be&#xD;
             confirmed by endoscopic and histologic evidence.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Men and women of childbearing potential must agree to use adequate birth control&#xD;
             measures during the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Ability to provide written informed consent and to be compliant with the schedule of&#xD;
             protocol assessments, treatment plan, laboratory tests, and other study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. UC patients with mild, mod, severity as assess by the 4 scale assessment (Normal,&#xD;
             mild, mod, severe).&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Treatment naïve subjects diagnosed with ulcerative colitis (without previous exposure&#xD;
             to treatment).&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. UC patients already on a treatment might be considered, with saffron as an add-on 8. UC&#xD;
        patients who displayed no improvement with any available treatment might be considered for&#xD;
        saffron as an alternative treatment in this option.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Patients taking immunosuppressive medicine for a disease other than UC&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Rheumatologic disease and other underlying diseases that can interfere with the study&#xD;
             process.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If the UC has been present for &gt; 10 years, a colonoscopy with biopsy has to be&#xD;
             performed to rule-out dysplasia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. A subject who had surgery as a treatment for ulcerative colitis or likely to require&#xD;
             surgery during the study period.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects with evidence of liver disease or abnormal liver enzymes and function tests&#xD;
             (e.g. total bilirubin, aspartate aminotransferase (AST) or alanine aminotransferase&#xD;
             (ALT) higher than the upper limit of normal) at the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Subjects who have any condition possibly affecting oral nutritional supplement&#xD;
             absorption.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Any other condition which in the opinion of the investigators would make the subject&#xD;
             unsuitable for inclusion in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Patients with known active or untreated GI infections including C. difficile, CMV,&#xD;
             HSV, HIV&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>80 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hassan Ashktorab</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Howard Uinversity</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Hassan Ashktorab</last_name>
    <phone>2028066121</phone>
    <email>hashktorab@howard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Hassan Brim</last_name>
    <phone>2028064198</phone>
    <email>hbrim@howard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Howard University Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Washington</city>
        <state>District of Columbia</state>
        <zip>20059</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Hassan Ashktorab</last_name>
      <phone>202-806-6121</phone>
      <email>hashktorab@howard.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Hassan Brim</last_name>
      <phone>2028064198</phone>
      <email>hbrim@howard.edu</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>1 Ghosh S, Mitchell R. Impact of inflammatory bowel disease on quality of life: Results of the European Federation of Crohn's and Ulcerative Colitis Associations (EFCCA) patient survey J Crohns Colitis. 2007;1:10-20. 2 Jess T, Gamborg M, Munkholm P, Sorensen TI. Overall and cause-specific mortality in ulcerative colitis: meta-analysis of population-based inception cohort studies Am J Gastroenterol. 2007;102:609-617. 3 Tanaka T. Colorectal carcinogenesis: Review of human and experimental animal studies J Carcinog. 2009;8:5. 4 Torres J, Burisch J, Riddle M, Dubinsky M, Colombel JF. Preclinical disease and preventive strategies in IBD: perspectives, challenges and opportunities Gut. 2016;65:1061-1069. 5 Dahlhamer JM, Zammitti EP, Ward BW, Wheaton AG, Croft JB. Prevalence of Inflammatory Bowel Disease Among Adults Aged &gt;/=18 Years - United States, 2015 MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2016;65:1166-1169. 6 Nguyen DL, Parekh N, Bechtold ML, Jamal MM. National Trends and In-Hospital Outcomes of Adult Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease Receiving Parenteral Nutrition Support JPEN J Parenter Enteral Nutr. 2016;40:412-416. 7 Kappelman MD, Rifas-Shiman SL, Porter CQet al. . Direct health care costs of Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis in US children and adults Gastroenterology. 2008;135:1907-1913. 8 Blakeley-Ruiz JA, Erickson AR, Cantarel BLet al. . Metaproteomics reveals persistent and phylum-redundant metabolic functional stability in adult human gut microbiomes of Crohn's remission patients despite temporal variations in microbial taxa, genomes, and proteomes Microbiome. 2019;7:18. 9 Ashktorab H, Soleimani A, Singh Get al. . Saffron: The Golden Spice with Therapeutic Properties on Digestive Diseases Nutrients. 2019;11. 10 Mashmoul M, Azlan A, Khaza'ai H, Yusof BN, Noor SM. Saffron: A Natural Potent Antioxidant as a Promising Anti-Obesity Drug Antioxidants (Basel). 2013;2:293-308. 11 Hosseinzadeh H, Talebzadeh F. Anticonvulsant evaluation of safranal and crocin from Crocus sativus in mice Fitoterapia. 2005;76:722-724. 12 Hosseinzadeh H, Modaghegh MH, Saffari Z. Crocus sativus L. (Saffron) extract and its active constituents (crocin and safranal) on ischemia-reperfusion in rat skeletal muscle Evid Based Complement Alternat Med. 2009;6:343-350. 13 El-Maraghy SA, Rizk SM, Shahin NN. Gastroprotective effect of crocin in ethanol-induced gastric injury in rats Chem Biol Interact. 2015;229:26-35. 14 Hosseinzadeh H, Sadeghnia HR. Safranal, a constituent of Crocus sativus (saffron), attenuated cerebral ischemia induced oxidative damage in rat hippocampus J Pharm Pharm Sci. 2005;8:394-399. 15 Lee IA, Lee JH, Baek NI, Kim DH. Antihyperlipidemic effect of crocin isolated from the fructus of Gardenia jasminoides and its metabolite Crocetin Biol Pharm Bull. 2005;28:2106-2110. 16 Abdullaev FI, Espinosa-Aguirre JJ. Biomedical properties of saffron and its potential use in cancer therapy and chemoprevention trials Cancer Detect Prev. 2004;28:426-432. 17 Abdullaev FI. Cancer chemopreventive and tumoricidal properties of saffron (Crocus sativus L.) Exp Biol Med (Maywood). 2002;227:20-25. 18 Singh G, Brim H, Ashktorab H, Habtezion A. Protective effect of Saffron in mouse model colitis through immune modulation DDW Gasteroenrology, City;2020. 19 Yoshino F, Yoshida A, Umigai N, Kubo K, Lee MC. Crocetin reduces the oxidative stress induced reactive oxygen species in the stroke-prone spontaneously hypertensive rats (SHRSPs) brain J Clin Biochem Nutr. 2011;49:182-187. 20 Rahaiee S, Moini S, Hashemi M, Shojaosadati SA. Evaluation of antioxidant activities of bioactive compounds and various extracts obtained from saffron (Crocus sativus L.): a review J Food Sci Technol. 2015;52:1881-1888. 21 Hosseinzadeh H, Younesi HM. Antinociceptive and anti-inflammatory effects of Crocus sativus L. stigma and petal extracts in mice BMC Pharmacol. 2002;2:7. . 34 Maleki I, Taghvaei T, Barzin M, Amin K, Khalilian A. Validation of the Persian version of the inflammatory bowel disease questionnaire (IBDQ) in ulcerative colitis patients Caspian J Intern Med. 2015;6:20-24. 35 McGahuey CA, Gelenberg AJ, Laukes CAet al. . The Arizona Sexual Experience Scale (ASEX): reliability and validity J Sex Marital Ther. 2000;26:25-40. 36 Brim H, Yooseph S, Lee Eet al. . A Microbiomic Analysis in African Americans with Colonic Lesions Reveals Streptococcus sp.VT162 as a Marker of Neoplastic Transformation Genes (Basel). 2017;8. 37 Tabtabaei S, D'Archivio AA, Maggi MAet al. . Geographical classification of Iranian and Italian saffron sources based on HPLC analysis and UV-Vis spectra of aqueous extracts Eur Food Res Technol. 2019;245:2435-2446.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colitis, Ulcerative</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>After completing the tials we will share the data</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

