<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04746885</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DHA in preterm</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04746885</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of DHA on Proinflammatory Cytokines Including Platelets Activating Factor (PAF) in Preterm Neonates</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of DHA on Proinflammatory Cytokines Including Platelets Activating Factor (PAF) and it's Role in Prevention of Necrotizing Enterocolitis in Preterm/Very Low Birth Weight Neonates</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ain Shams University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ain Shams University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The purpose of this study is to determine whether docosahexaenoic acid is effective in the&#xD;
      prevention or reducing severity of necrotizing enterocolitis in preterm/low birth weight&#xD;
      neonates.Necrotizing enterocolitis (NEC) is the most devastating gastrointestinal disease in&#xD;
      neonates. The pathogenesis of NEC is not well defined but evidence strongly suggests that it&#xD;
      is multifactorial . prematurity and enteral feeding are major risk factors for NEC. An&#xD;
      excessive inflammatory response by the immature intestine to external stimuli, impaired&#xD;
      intestinal barrier integrity and / or abnormal bacterial colonization are key factors&#xD;
      implicated in pathophysiology of NEC.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Inclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients are eligible for inclusion if they meet the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preterm neonates having a gestational age equal or less than 32 weeks at birth, admitted in&#xD;
      Ain Shams University NICU'S.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weight (less than or equal 1.500 KG) Clinically stable to begin enteral feeding All Genders&#xD;
      (Male, Female) Written informed consent by parents Sepsis will not be considered as exclusion&#xD;
      criteria (according to SNAP 11; this score considers six physiologic variables such as blood&#xD;
      pressure, temperature, the Po2/Fio2 ratio, serum PH, seizures and urine output, Töllner score&#xD;
      (table 3) and Rodwell score (table 4)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Persistent bleeding at any level. Receiving medication to avoid coagulation. Persistent&#xD;
      vomiting. Gastrointestinal malformations. Mother taking Omega-3 supplements and planning to&#xD;
      breastfed. The enrolled patients will be subdivided into two groups; group A are infants&#xD;
      receiving DHA, group B are infants receiving placebo (physically matched solution).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our patient will be classified into two groups:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group A (interventional group/ DHA):&#xD;
&#xD;
      A minimum of 40 preterm infants will be included to receive 100mg DHA daily administered by&#xD;
      enteral route for 30 days. This group will be subdivided into breast fed / artificially fed&#xD;
      infants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group B (control group / Placebo):&#xD;
&#xD;
      40 of preterm infant controls will be included to receive placebo (physically matched&#xD;
      solution). This group will be subdivided into breast fed / artificially fed infants.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size is calculated for the two groups receiving DHA versus Placebo. The sample&#xD;
      size is calculated using the incidence densities of NEC reported in the literature of&#xD;
      4.4/1000 and 17.3/1000 baby day. At least 20 babies should be included in each arm to reach&#xD;
      an effect size of 0.8 with alpha error = 0.05 and power 0.80 (G*Power 3.1.7, Franz Faul,&#xD;
      Universität Kiel, Germany, 2013).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Randomization and blinding:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group A and B assigned according to a predetermined schedule generated from random numbers&#xD;
      based on a computer-generated randomization sequence into either DHA or Placebo.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods All infants will receive the standard neonatal care and will undergo follow-up from&#xD;
      birth until reach 37 weeks corrected gestational age, discharge or death whichever comes&#xD;
      first.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Feeding protocol: (Ellard and Anderson, 2012):&#xD;
&#xD;
      Begin as early as the neonate can tolerate.(when hemodynamically stable.) Start with low&#xD;
      volume 0.5 to 1 ml/6 hours, increasing gradually according to the tolerance (trophic feeding&#xD;
      10-20 ml/kg) start deduction of feds from total fluid intake thereafter Gut priming is not&#xD;
      used in patients with severe hemodynamic instability, suspected or confirmed NEC Increment&#xD;
      from 10 to 20 ml/kg/day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      DHA supplementation:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group (A): 100 mg DHA will be given to all neonates in group A as soon as possible with the&#xD;
      enteral feeding for 30 days (subtracted from the total volume of the feed).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Group (B): will predominantly receive placebo (physically matched solution) together with&#xD;
      their regular feeding.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All patients and controls subjected to:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data Collection: Careful history taking Antenatal history including: rupture of membrane,&#xD;
      Chorioamnionitis, history of urinary tract infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Natal history including: mode of delivery, place of delivery, the need for resuscitation,&#xD;
      recorded Apgar score at 1minute and 5 minutes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postnatal history including: age of admission in neonatal intensive care unit, symptoms&#xD;
      suggest infection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Thorough clinical assessment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Weight, length and OFC (twice weekly). Complete examination including cardiovascular,&#xD;
      respiratory, and neurological examination.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abdominal examination will done focusing on: signs of feeding intolerance including:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Measurement of abdominal girth Intestinal sounds Passage of stool Prescence of gastric&#xD;
      residual Abdominal tenderness and rigidity NEC BELL'S criteria; as an objective tool for&#xD;
      diagnosis and staging of NEC.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Laboratory investigations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Complete blood picture, C-reactive protein, bleeding profile. Blood culture and sensitivity.&#xD;
      Quantitative ELISA technique for PAF done for both cases and controls done twice. beseline&#xD;
      sample will be withdrawn once NEC is suspected and the other one will be withdrawn 10 days&#xD;
      from the first sample.( to assess the decrease in PAF levels).&#xD;
&#xD;
      BLOOD SAMPLES:&#xD;
&#xD;
      10ml of venous blood were withdrawn from each subject .they were divided into: 2ml collected&#xD;
      on EDTA tube for CBC 1.8ml collected on sodium citrate for PT, PC and INR. The remaining part&#xD;
      was collected in aplain tube, left to clot for 10-20 min at room temperature before&#xD;
      centrifugation for 10 mins at the spend of 2000-3000 r.p.m., then serum was separated and&#xD;
      divided into 2 aliquots, one for the blood chemistry which was assayed on the same day of&#xD;
      sample collection, the second sample was stored at -20 C till the time of assay.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Radiological investigations:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Abdominal X-ray Erect &amp; Supine (when necrotizing enterocolitis is suspected). Abdominal&#xD;
      ultrasound (when necrotizing enterocolitis is suspected). MRI brain as an assessment tool for&#xD;
      cerebral white matter abnormalities (White matter abnormalities scoring system).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up and end-point of the study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Primary outcome:&#xD;
&#xD;
           All infants will undergo follow-up from birth until reach 37 week corrected gestational&#xD;
           age, discharge or death whichever comes first. The following primary outcome data will&#xD;
           be recorded:&#xD;
&#xD;
           Clinical examination and radiological investigations when clinically indicated for&#xD;
           evidence of NEC.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. A secondary outcome measure :&#xD;
&#xD;
           Arthropemetric measures as weight increment per kg per week, length, OFC, duration of&#xD;
           hospitalization, mortality if any, monitoring adverse effects of treatment (if any);&#xD;
           such as emesis, increased gastric residuals, increased abdominal girth, diarrhea, skin&#xD;
           rash. Long term outcome includes necrotizing enterocolitis, bronchopulmonary dysplasia&#xD;
           and intracranial hemorrhage.&#xD;
&#xD;
           At term equivalent, all preterm infants underwent a structural MRI scan that was&#xD;
           analysed qualitatively for the prescence and severity of cerebral white matter&#xD;
           abnormalities, including cysts, signal abnormalities, loss of white matter volume,&#xD;
           ventriculomegally, and corpus callosal thinning/myelination. (Each infant's scan was&#xD;
           then graded using a qualitative scoring system consisting of five 3-point scales&#xD;
           assessing the presence and severity of periventricular white matter volume loss, white&#xD;
           matter signal abnormality, the presence of cystic abnormalities, ventricular dilation,&#xD;
           and thinning of the corpus callosum and reduced myelination . children were classified&#xD;
           as follows: 1) no abnormalities (score of 5 to 6) ; 2) mild abnormalities (score of 7 to&#xD;
           9) ; 3) moderate abnormalities (score of 10 to12) ; or 4) severe abnormalities (score&#xD;
           &gt;12).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Tertiary outcome:&#xD;
&#xD;
      After discharge, all children underwent a comprehensive neurodevelopmental assessment using&#xD;
      Bayley scale of infant and Toddler Development -111 (Bayley-111)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 21, 2017</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 12, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>DEVELOPMENT OF NEC</measure>
    <time_frame>3-10 DAYS</time_frame>
    <description>All infants will undergo follow-up from birth until reach 37 week corrected gestational age, discharge or death whichever comes first. The following primary outcome data will be recorded:&#xD;
Clinical examination and radiological investigations when clinically indicated for evidence of NEC.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">80</enrollment>
  <condition>Neonatal Disease</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>(interventional group/ DHA): A minimum of 40 preterm infants will be included to receive 100mg DHA daily administered by enteral route for 30 days. This group will be subdivided into breast fed / artificially fed infants.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>(control group / Placebo): 40 of preterm infant controls will be included to receive placebo (physically matched solution). This group will be subdivided into breast fed / artificially fed infants.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DHA</intervention_name>
    <description>Oral supplement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Preterm neonates having a gestational age equal or less than 32 weeks at birth,&#xD;
             admitted in Ain Shams University NICU'S.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Weight (less than or equal 1.500 KG) Clinically stable to begin enteral feeding All Genders&#xD;
        (Male, Female) Written informed consent by parents Sepsis will not be considered as&#xD;
        exclusion criteria (according to SNAP 11; this score considers six physiologic variables&#xD;
        such as blood pressure, temperature, the Po2/Fio2 ratio, serum PH, seizures and urine&#xD;
        output, Töllner score (table 3) and Rodwell score&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Persistent bleeding at any level. Receiving medication to avoid coagulation.&#xD;
             Persistent vomiting. Gastrointestinal malformations. Mother taking Omega-3 supplements&#xD;
             and planning to breastfed.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>28 Days</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ain Shams University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Cairo</city>
        <zip>11566</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Aderem A, Ulevitch RJ. Toll-like receptors in the induction of the innate immune response. Nature. 2000 Aug 17;406(6797):782-7. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>10963608</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Meguro A, Kuribayashi R, Sakurada T, Sekine T, Aida H, Abe T. [Intravascular hemolysis due to residual shunt after patch closure of VSD: a case report]. Kyobu Geka. 1992 Jun;45(6):537-40. Japanese.</citation>
    <PMID>1602686</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Axelsson A, Lindgren F. [Firecrackers--a risk of hearing injuries?]. Lakartidningen. 1987 Apr 15;84(16):1341-6. Swedish.</citation>
    <PMID>3586783</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Miles EA, Calder PC. Modulation of immune function by dietary fatty acids. Proc Nutr Soc. 1998 May;57(2):277-92. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>9656331</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infant, Newborn, Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

