<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04744844</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BF 13.1.2021:51</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04744844</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>DNA Amplification in Blastocoel Fluid</brief_title>
  <official_title>Does Absence of DNA Amplification in Blastocoel Fluid Enhance Conventional Blastocyst Selection and IVF Outcome?</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Antalya IVF</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Antalya IVF</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Introduction: Although innovative procedural changes in frozen embryo transfer (FET) cycles&#xD;
      have increased the implantation rate of blastocysts transferred significantly, blastocyst&#xD;
      selection remains a significant limiting factor in implantation outcomes. To improve&#xD;
      implantation rates requires conventional microscopic blastocyst morphology scoring/selection&#xD;
      technique to be replaced by an enhanced blastocyst selection technique or for the&#xD;
      conventional morphology selection technique to be strengthened by novel supplementary&#xD;
      selection techniques. Blastocoel fluid biopsy with DNA amplification is a minimally invasive&#xD;
      (mi) technique that may supplement a blastocyst morphology score variables with a genetic&#xD;
      variable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: In the present randomized controlled trial (RCT), DNA amplification in blastocoel&#xD;
      fluid biopsies (BF-biopsy) will be investigated as a supplementary measure to select&#xD;
      blastocysts for transfer in conjunction with blastocyst morphology scores. The objective will&#xD;
      be to develop a minimally invasive blastocyst selection technique, which will improve&#xD;
      selection and increase clinical implantations, while not increasing costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Materials and Methods: A single IVF centre double-blind randomised controlled trial, with&#xD;
      patients recruited having female age 18 to 35 years from infertile patients presenting for&#xD;
      freeze-all-IVF treatment. Enrolled patients (N = 500) with ≥five 2PN zygotes after ICSI will&#xD;
      be randomised (1:1) to the two arms of the trial (i.e., test and control arm). In the test&#xD;
      arm, 3 blastocysts will undergo blastocoel fluid biopsy (BF-biopsy) and whole-genomic&#xD;
      amplification. Single blastocysts with no DNA amplification will be transferred in FETs of&#xD;
      the test arm and single top-scoring blastocysts will be transferred in FETs of the control&#xD;
      arm. The primary outcome measure of the trial will be clinical implantation (i.e.,&#xD;
      gestational sac with fetal heartbeat).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results: The clinical implantation outcomes of FETs in which score-selected single blastocyst&#xD;
      with no DNA amplification and score-selected single blastocysts were transferred will be&#xD;
      compared.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction The goal of assisted reproductive technology (ART) is the delivery of a healthy&#xD;
      singleton, with the treatment strategy in IVF having the best chance being the transfer of&#xD;
      the single most viable embryo from a patient's embryo cohort. Embryo selection, therefore, is&#xD;
      paramount to the success of this goal. The microscopic assessment and scoring of embryo&#xD;
      morphology was developed as an embryo selection technique in the early years of IVF (Veeck,&#xD;
      1991) and has ever since remained the most widely practised embryo selection technique.&#xD;
      However, the technique's limited ability to maximise embryo implantation rates has for long&#xD;
      been lamented and, therefore, more enhanced embryo selection techniques have for long been&#xD;
      sought. Time-lapse monitoring and scoring (Paulson et al., 2018) and euploid embryo transfer&#xD;
      using PGT-A (preimplantation genetic testing for aneuploidy; Gleicher et al., 2017) are&#xD;
      recent innovations that have become contenders to replace conventional microscopic assessment&#xD;
      and scoring of embryo morphology. An advantage of PGT-A is its independence of embryo&#xD;
      development and morphological feature assessments, as euploid blastocysts implant at the same&#xD;
      rate irrespective of blastocyst morphology score (Capalbo et al., 2014). Moreover, besides&#xD;
      PGT-A's technical and biological limitations, the costs of implementation PGT-A as an embryo&#xD;
      selection technique may be regarded prohibitive by many.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the evolution of PGT in human IVF, PGT has progressed from PGT-v1 to PGT-v2 based on the&#xD;
      adverse outcomes of biopsying 1-2 blastomeres from cleavage-stage embryos (PGT-v1) and the&#xD;
      improvement in blastocyst development conditions. The evidence suggested that PGT-v.1 posed a&#xD;
      significant risk to embryo viability, with no benefit resulting from the transfer of euploid&#xD;
      embryos (Gleicher et al., 2017). The majority of studies have reported that PGT-v2, which&#xD;
      requires the biopsying of 5-10 trophectoderm (TE) cells, poses no significant risk to the&#xD;
      developmental potential (implantation viability) of biopsied blastocysts. However, recently&#xD;
      there have been reports, suggesting that TE biopsy may not be completely free of risk&#xD;
      (Gleicher et al., 2017, Ozgur et al., 2019). Currently, PGT-A faces four challenges&#xD;
      preventing its routine use as a blastocyst selection technique; (1) the need for high&#xD;
      technical expertise, (2) the invasiveness of TE biopsy, (3) the cost of the full technique,&#xD;
      and (4) that TE biopsy is subject to sampling bias - a single TE biopsy of 5-10 cells may not&#xD;
      accurately represent the ploidy of the whole blastocyst.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A spin-off of conventional PGT is the analysis of DNA in blastocoel fluid (BF). This&#xD;
      phenomenon was first reported by Palini et al. (2013). The origin of the DNA in BF has been&#xD;
      suggested to be the result of embryo euploidisation, i.e., the elimination of aneuploidy DNA&#xD;
      or aneuploidic cells through regulatory processes such as apoptosis and or necrosis (Leaver&#xD;
      and Wells, 2019). The practice of blastocyst collapse before vitrification (Mukaida et al.,&#xD;
      2006, Iwayama et al., 2011) provides the opportunity to perform minimally invasive PGT-A&#xD;
      (miPGT-A), i.e., the biopsying BF. In a study to investigate ploidy concordance between PGT-A&#xD;
      with TE biopsy and PGT-A with BF biopsy, the authors found that the clinical pregnancy rate&#xD;
      was 77% for blastocysts with no DNA amplification were transferred and 37% for blastocysts&#xD;
      with DNA amplification (Magli et al., 2018). The mere accumulation of DNA in the BF,&#xD;
      therefore, could be used as a supplementary measure to prioritise blastocysts for transfer.&#xD;
      Implementing BF-biopsy and whole-genomic amplification (WGA) as a supplementary selection&#xD;
      measure limits/reduces three of PGT-A's main challenges; (1) technical expertise, (2)&#xD;
      invasiveness, and (3) costs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the present randomized controlled trial (RCT), the investigators will investigate DNA&#xD;
      amplification in blastocyst fluid biopsies (BF-biopsy) as a supplementary selection technique&#xD;
      to select blastocysts for transfer in conjunction with blastocyst morphology scores. The&#xD;
      clinical implantation outcomes of FETs in which score-selected single blastocyst with no DNA&#xD;
      amplification and score-selected single blastocysts were transferred will be compared.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A single IVF centre double-blind randomised controlled trial.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Care Provider)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>clinical implantation</measure>
    <time_frame>Transvaginal ultrasound examinations will be performed after 5 weeks of gestation</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical implantation will be defined as a cycle with an ultrasound confirmed normal gestational sac and heartbeat.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>Blood serum pregnancy tests will be performed 9 days after blastocyst transfer</time_frame>
    <description>Pregnancy will be defined as a cycle with an arbitrary serum βHCG level of &gt;30 mIU/mL</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ongoing pregnancy</measure>
    <time_frame>Transvaginal ultrasound examinations will be performed after 12 weeks of gestation</time_frame>
    <description>Ongoing pregnancy will be defined as a cycle with an ultrasound confirmed normal gestational sac and heartbeat.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">500</enrollment>
  <condition>Clinical Pregnancy</condition>
  <condition>Embryo Implantation</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>DNA-amplification selection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the experimental arm, all blastocysts will undergo routine morphological assessment, with the 3 top-scoring blastocysts undergoing blastocoel fluid biopsy (BF-biopsy) and whole-genomic amplification. A single blastocyst with no DNA amplification will be selected for transfer in a frozen embryo transfer cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Morfological-score selection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the active comparator arm, all blastocysts will undergo routine morphological assessment. The (single) top-scoring blastocyst will be selected for transfer in a frozen embryo transfer cycle.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>blastocoel fluid biopsy</intervention_name>
    <description>In the present study, blastocoel fluid biopsy (BF-biopsy) and collapse will be performed using a microinjection pipette similar to that used to perform ICSI. The pipette will be pushed gently through the zona pellucida and TE, and up to 90% of the BF will be aspirated.</description>
    <arm_group_label>DNA-amplification selection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Morfological-score selection</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with female age 18≤35 years on the day of consultation (with the clinician&#xD;
             projecting female age to be ≤35 on the day of oocyte retrieval).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who provide informed consent to participate in the trial and for the use of&#xD;
             their anonymized data in research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with ≤2 previous IVF treatments.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients predicted to have single blastocyst transfers.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with female age &gt;35 years on the day of consultation.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients with insulin-dependent diabetes or non-insulin-dependent diabetes&#xD;
             mellitus and female patients with gastrointestinal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, liver&#xD;
             or kidney disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Female patients with any contraindications or allergies to the drugs used in routine&#xD;
             freeze-all-IVF.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients undergoing conventional PGT-A (aneuploidy) or PGT-M (monogenic disorders)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with less than 5 2-PN zygotes on day 1 of embryo development will be excluded&#xD;
             from randomization.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kemal Ozgur, MD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Antalya IVF</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kevin Coetzee, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Antalya IVF</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Antalya IVF</name>
      <address>
        <city>Antalya</city>
        <zip>07080</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Capalbo A, Rienzi L, Cimadomo D, Maggiulli R, Elliott T, Wright G, Nagy ZP, Ubaldi FM. Correlation between standard blastocyst morphology, euploidy and implantation: an observational study in two centers involving 956 screened blastocysts. Hum Reprod. 2014 Jun;29(6):1173-81. doi: 10.1093/humrep/deu033. Epub 2014 Feb 26.</citation>
    <PMID>24578475</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Iwayama H, Hochi S, Yamashita M. In vitro and in vivo viability of human blastocysts collapsed by laser pulse or osmotic shock prior to vitrification. J Assist Reprod Genet. 2011 Apr;28(4):355-61. doi: 10.1007/s10815-010-9522-4. Epub 2010 Dec 9.</citation>
    <PMID>21152966</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Magli MC, Albanese C, Crippa A, Tabanelli C, Ferraretti AP, Gianaroli L. Deoxyribonucleic acid detection in blastocoelic fluid: a new predictor of embryo ploidy and viable pregnancy. Fertil Steril. 2019 Jan;111(1):77-85. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2018.09.016. Epub 2018 Dec 5.</citation>
    <PMID>30528055</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Ozgur K, Berkkanoglu M, Bulut H, Yoruk GDA, Candurmaz NN, Coetzee K. Single best euploid versus single best unknown-ploidy blastocyst frozen embryo transfers: a randomized controlled trial. J Assist Reprod Genet. 2019 Apr;36(4):629-636. doi: 10.1007/s10815-018-01399-1. Epub 2019 Jan 7.</citation>
    <PMID>30617927</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Palini S, Galluzzi L, De Stefani S, Bianchi M, Wells D, Magnani M, Bulletti C. Genomic DNA in human blastocoele fluid. Reprod Biomed Online. 2013 Jun;26(6):603-10. doi: 10.1016/j.rbmo.2013.02.012. Epub 2013 Mar 13.</citation>
    <PMID>23557766</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Veeck LL: Atlas of the Human Oocytes and Early Conceptus. 1991, Vol. 2. Baltimore, Williams &amp; Willkins Co.</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Paulson RJ, Reichman DE, Zaninovic N, Goodman LR, Racowsky C. Time-lapse imaging: clearly useful to both laboratory personnel and patient outcomes versus just because we can doesn't mean we should. Fertil Steril. 2018 Apr;109(4):584-591. doi: 10.1016/j.fertnstert.2018.01.042.</citation>
    <PMID>29653705</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Gleicher N, Metzger J, Croft G, Kushnir VA, Albertini DF, Barad DH. A single trophectoderm biopsy at blastocyst stage is mathematically unable to determine embryo ploidy accurately enough for clinical use. Reprod Biol Endocrinol. 2017 Apr 27;15(1):33. doi: 10.1186/s12958-017-0251-8.</citation>
    <PMID>28449669</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Mukaida T, Oka C, Goto T, Takahashi K. Artificial shrinkage of blastocoeles using either a micro-needle or a laser pulse prior to the cooling steps of vitrification improves survival rate and pregnancy outcome of vitrified human blastocysts. Hum Reprod. 2006 Dec;21(12):3246-52. Epub 2006 Aug 26.</citation>
    <PMID>16936299</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Antalya IVF</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Kevin Coetzee</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Scientific officer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>DNA</keyword>
  <keyword>amplification</keyword>
  <keyword>blastocyst fluid</keyword>
  <keyword>blastocyst selection</keyword>
  <keyword>frozen embryo transfer</keyword>
  <keyword>minimally invasive</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The IPD plan sharing plan:&#xD;
The protocol will be published (word document) on the completion of registration on ClinicalTrials.gov The relevant clinical data will be published on journal acceptance of the study (excel spreadsheet)</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Clinical Study Report (CSR)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>To be published immediately after publication acceptance.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Open access at the Mendeley Data at the URLs provided</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

