<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04749693</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>RCB 2020-A 02808-31</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04749693</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Observational Study of the Use of DBLG1 System in Real Life</brief_title>
  <acronym>SP12</acronym>
  <official_title>Observational Study of the Use of DBLG1 System in Real Life</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Diabeloop</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Diabeloop</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study will be conducted on human subjects and is observational, prospective and&#xD;
      uncontrolled, defined as a category 3 according to the Jardé Law (RIPH3). It is a national&#xD;
      and multicentric study. Enrolled patients are Type 1 Diabetes (T1D) patients who receive the&#xD;
      DBLG1 System (CE marked medical device) to be treated. Patients have their regular visits&#xD;
      with their own clinician. No change from their usual care must and will be done, including&#xD;
      trainings and treatment. At the end of the study, patients will keep their system for their&#xD;
      usual care and will continue having usual follow-up visits with their clinician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data related to their glycemia, complications and quality of life will be collected for 1&#xD;
      year from the beginning of their treatment. A comparison with data collected during the 2&#xD;
      weeks of run-in period, prior to the activation of loop mode, is planned. In case the run-in&#xD;
      phase lasts longer than 2 weeks, data collected from the two last weeks only will be kept for&#xD;
      analysis and comparison.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study is completed when all patients have their &quot;end of study&quot; file completed in the&#xD;
      electronic Case Report Form (eCRF).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The study is designed to address the specific requirements from National Commission for the&#xD;
      Evaluation of Medical Devices and Health Technologies (CNEDiMTS) and to complete data&#xD;
      obtained up to now, with a larger cohort and in real life settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In order to increase variability in the profiles of patients included and to be as&#xD;
      representative as possible of all eligible patients, 20 centers will participate in the&#xD;
      study, both private and public, with a mix of university and regional centers and 348&#xD;
      patients will be included consecutively.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The inclusion period lasts 6 months and each patient will be included in the study for a&#xD;
      period of 2 weeks of run-in and 1 year of treatment. An inclusion period of 6 months is&#xD;
      enough according to investigation site data and estimation of inclusion over 6 months&#xD;
      (detailed in part Healthcare professional and investigation centers recruitment).&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study is observational. Patients included follow their usual medical care and will only&#xD;
      be asked for the specific need of the study to answer two questionnaires (at the beginning&#xD;
      and at the end of the study) and give their HbA1c results performed in their current medical&#xD;
      follow-up. As it is a post-registration study, medical devices are provided to patients on&#xD;
      medical prescription by healthcare providers, which have signed a distribution agreement with&#xD;
      and have been trained by Diabeloop. Patients have their system for 4 a maximum of 4 years&#xD;
      (life duration of the medical device (DBLG1 System)).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Patients follow-up visits are not mandatory and no frequency is imposed. Investigators,&#xD;
      according to their habits, have follow-up visits corresponding to what they usually propose&#xD;
      to patients having a new treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the whole study and apart from scheduled visits (inclusion, beginning of run-in,&#xD;
      beginning of treatment , enf of study), each patient may contact his/her clinician&#xD;
      investigator in case of issue he/she judges as serious, for questions, etc. In that case, the&#xD;
      clinician may program a visit with the patient and deal with adverse events. Phone calls are&#xD;
      recorded in Case Report Form (CRF), as well as on-site visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Note: with Yourloops; investigators may follow the state of their patients, regarding the&#xD;
      time in range, mean glycemia value etc. Based on this, they may require a visit at their&#xD;
      convenience with the patient in order to change parameters of the system, discuss adverse&#xD;
      events, etc.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives are the following To evaluate improvement in blood glucose control with use of&#xD;
      DBLG1 System after one year in real life.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To evaluate details of glycemic control improvement, safety and adverse events due to the&#xD;
      DBLG1 System, evolution of quality of life after one year in real life and healthcare&#xD;
      professional support.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study endpoints Improvement of the time in glycemic range 70 - 180 mg/dL, in percentage, on&#xD;
      24hours and nighttime.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HbA1c Mean CGM glucose - on 24hours and nighttime Time in 70 - 140 mg/dL range on 24hours and&#xD;
      nighttime only Time in hypoglycemia (under 70 mg/dL, 60 mg/dL and 50 mg/dL) - on 24hours and&#xD;
      nighttime Time in hyperglycemia (above 180 mg/dL, 250 mg/dL and 300 mg/dL) - on 24hours and&#xD;
      nighttime Percentage of time using activated loop mode vs. deactivated loop mode Standard&#xD;
      Deviation (SD) and Coefficient of variation (CV) of Continuous Glucose Monitoring (CGM)&#xD;
      values on 24hours and nighttime Number and type of adverse events Overall and&#xD;
      diabetic-specific quality of life Quantification of the healthcare professional support&#xD;
      required&#xD;
&#xD;
      An descriptive interim analysis will be made on the first 100 enrolled patients after 6&#xD;
      months of use of the DBLG1.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 17, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 15, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 15, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>time in 70 - 180 mg/dL glycemic range</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>Improvement of the time in glycemic range 70 - 180 mg/dL, in percentage, on 24hours and nighttime</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>HbA1c HbA1c HbA1c</measure>
    <time_frame>at the beginning and at the end of the study (1 year between each value)</time_frame>
    <description>change in the HbA1c after 1 year of use of the device</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>mean CGM</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>change of mean CGM glucose on 24hours and nighttime</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>time in 70 - 140 mg/dL glycemic range</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>change of time in 70 - 140 mg/dL range on 24hours and nighttime</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>time in hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>change of time in hypoglycemia, under 70 mg/dL, 60 mg/dL and 50 mg/dL on 24hours and nighttime</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>time in hyperglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>change of time in hyperglycemia above 180 mg/dL, 250 mg/dL and 300 mg/dL on 24hours and nighttime</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>use of loop mode</measure>
    <time_frame>treatment period, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>percentage of time using activated loop mode vs. deactivated loop mode</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>SD and CV of CGM values</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>change of SD and CV of CGM values on 24hours and nighttime</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>adverse event</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>number of adverse events</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Health Survey</measure>
    <time_frame>at the beginning and at the end of the study (1 year between each value)</time_frame>
    <description>change of the patient health, evaluated by questionnaire Short Form 12 Health Survey filled in at the beginning and at the end of the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fear of hypoglycemia</measure>
    <time_frame>at the beginning and at the end of the study (1 year between each value)</time_frame>
    <description>change of the patient fear of hypoglycemia, evaluated by questionnaire Hypoglycemia fear survey filled in at the beginning and at the end of the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Patient stress status</measure>
    <time_frame>at the beginning and at the end of the study (1 year between each value)</time_frame>
    <description>change of the patient stress status, evaluated by questionnaire Diabetes distress scale, filled in at the beginning and at the end of the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acceptability of the device</measure>
    <time_frame>at the beginning and at the end of the study (1 year between each value)</time_frame>
    <description>change of the patient's satisfaction of previous vs. DBLG1 System devices, evaluated by questionnaire patient stress status, filled in at the beginning and at the end of the study</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>incidence of the system on the necessary healthcare professional charge</measure>
    <time_frame>through study completion, an average of 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>questionnaire at each visit (duration and type of visit, number and type of healthcare professional required for the visit)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">348</enrollment>
  <condition>Type1diabetes</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with HbA1c &gt;= 8% despite the use of insulin pump and frequent glycemic control</arm_group_label>
    <description>only group included in the study</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>DBLG1 System</intervention_name>
    <description>Use of DBLG1 System in real life condition</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patient with HbA1c &gt;= 8% despite the use of insulin pump and frequent glycemic control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adults with type 1 diabetes equal or more than 18 years old, with Hb1Ac ≥ 8%&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients with type 1 diabetes;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who are at least 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients total daily dose required must be less than 90 units (U);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients accepting to be treated with 100 U/mL rapid-acting insulin analog&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients having a HbA1c ≥ 8% despite of the use of a pump for at least 6 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients performing glucose self-monitoring several times ( ≥ 4) a day&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patient accepting the technology&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients agreeing to use the system with activated loop mode during at least 75% of&#xD;
             the&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  total time of use, this will be analyzed after 1 year of use.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients must be affiliated to any kind of social security&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients receiving a total daily dose of insulin lower than 8 U;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients suffering from a serious illness or having a treatment that might&#xD;
             significantly impair diabetes physiology (iSGLT2, steroids, metformin), i.e.&#xD;
             glucose-insulin interactions, that might interfere with the medical device (for&#xD;
             example treatment by steroids with variable dosage during the study period);&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients having severe uncorrected problems of hearing and/or visual acuity preventing&#xD;
             proper use of DBLG1 System;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients unable to understand and perform all of the instructions regarding the&#xD;
             devices and the clinical investigation provided by Diabeloop.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients planning to perform during the year of study repeated magnetic resonance&#xD;
             imaging (MRI), computed tomography (CT) scan, or high-frequency electrical heat&#xD;
             (diathermy) treatment. The G6 has not been tested in those situations. The magnetic&#xD;
             fields and heat could damage the components of the Dexcom G6, which may cause it to&#xD;
             display inaccurate sensor glucose readings (readings) or may prevent alerts. Without&#xD;
             G6 readings or alarm/alert notifications, patients might be exposed to severe low or&#xD;
             high glucose events;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients who are unwilling or unable to maintain contact with the healthcare&#xD;
             professional;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients willing to use any insulin that is not 100 U/mL rapid-acting insulin analog&#xD;
             with the system (for example regular insulin; long-acting insulin analog; 200 U/mL&#xD;
             rapid-acting insulin analog)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Pauline Schaepelynck</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>APHM Hôpital Sud Sainte Marguerite</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Lucy Chaillous</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Nantes</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Hélène Hanaire</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Toulouse</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sandrine Lablanche</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital, Grenoble</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alfred Penfornis</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CH Sud Francilien</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Yves Reznik</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>CHU Caen</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marion Chassouant</last_name>
    <phone>0767417660</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>clinical-trial@diabeloop.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Erik Huneker</last_name>
    <email>erik@diabeloop.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CHU Grenoble</name>
      <address>
        <city>Grenoble</city>
        <zip>38000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sandrine Lablanche, Dr</last_name>
      <phone>+33 (0)4 76 76 83 88</phone>
      <email>SLablanche@chu-grenoble.fr</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Pierre-Yves Benhamou, Pr</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hôpital Sainte Marguerite - APHM</name>
      <address>
        <city>Marseille</city>
        <zip>13005</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Not yet recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Pauline Schaepelynck</last_name>
      <email>Pauline.SCHAEPELYNCK@ap-hm.fr</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>May 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 8, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>May 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>May 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">May 19, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Type 1 Diabetes</keyword>
  <keyword>HbA1c &gt; 8%</keyword>
  <keyword>Closed loop system</keyword>
  <keyword>insulin pump</keyword>
  <keyword>Algorithm</keyword>
  <keyword>Real life</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Diabetes Mellitus, Type 1</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

