<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04741399</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MP-32-2021-2198</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04741399</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Experiences and Attitudes Towards Agitated Behaviours in TBI ICU Patients: a Protocol for an Interprofessional Mixed-method Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>EXSTATIC</acronym>
  <official_title>EXperienceS and aTtitudes Towards Agitated Behaviours in Tbi ICu Patients (EXSTATIC): a Protocol for an Interprofessional Mixed-method Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Integre Universitaire de Sante et Services Sociaux du Nord de l'ile de Montreal</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Centre Universitaire de Santé McGill</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Integre Universitaire de Sante et Services Sociaux du Nord de l'ile de Montreal</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      EXSTATIC is a multicenter mixed methods convergent study exploring experiences and attitudes&#xD;
      of ICU healthcare professionals caring of agitated traumatic brain injury (TBI) patients. The&#xD;
      study aims to explore the experiences and attitudes of ICU nurses and other ICU healthcare&#xD;
      professionals on the management of agitation in acute TBI patients. This project includes&#xD;
      three qualitative methods and one quantitative method. First step consists in structured&#xD;
      observations of the daily routine of ICU healthcare professionals when TBI patient admitted&#xD;
      in the ICU develops agitation. This step will allow us to raise emerging research questions&#xD;
      from the field and to develop subsequent steps. Secondly, we will conduct semi-structured&#xD;
      interviews with ICU nurses. Themes emerged in the interviews are essential to understand&#xD;
      nurses' experiences and attitudes towards TBI agitated patients and describe their relational&#xD;
      role amongst patients, other professionals and families. A retrospective cohort of TBI&#xD;
      patients gathered through medical files will follow aiming to document in which way&#xD;
      observations in the two first phases are reflected in the clinical notes. Finally, different&#xD;
      ICU healthcare professionals will be invited to participate in focus groups to identify&#xD;
      further themes in semi-structured interviews in nurses, compare them and prioritize which are&#xD;
      the most relevant to nurses experiences and which ones need to be addressed for their future&#xD;
      practice. The integration of the different methods will be done using sequential steps of the&#xD;
      research (the previous informing the next one) and by the integration of results for each&#xD;
      step. Qualitative data will be evaluated following the grounded theory using thematic&#xD;
      analysis. Quantitative data will be analysed using descriptive statistics. Qualitative and&#xD;
      quantitative results will be combined in a convergent interactive interpretative design. Race&#xD;
      and gender perspective will be integrated in collection, analysis and interpretation of data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A convergent design will be performed using three qualitative research methods (structured&#xD;
      observations, semi-structured interviews and focus groups) and a quantitative research method&#xD;
      (retrospective observational study).&#xD;
&#xD;
      First, a researcher will observe the daily ICU routine, in two ICU units, when a TBI-patient&#xD;
      is admitted. In this first step, the specific objective is to observe the care of TBI&#xD;
      patients during periods of agitation, to understand how it affects the actions of healthcare&#xD;
      professionals and their interactions with each other and other actors present in the unit.&#xD;
      These observations will enable researchers to detect non-verbal expression of feelings,&#xD;
      interactions and communication between patients, their family and health professionals as&#xD;
      well as interactions between health professionals at the bedside. The observations will also&#xD;
      enable us to map bedside clinical activities made by health professionals and the time spent&#xD;
      doing them. The goal is to develop a repertoire of situations combining the degree of&#xD;
      agitation, the resources present, the experience and the effects on the staff, the patient&#xD;
      and their relatives, the actions and medical decisions in response to agitation. The data&#xD;
      gathered in this phase will inform the interview guide for the semi-structured interviews.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the second phase, we will conduct semi-structured interviews with ICU nurses to explore&#xD;
      their experiences and attitudes towards the care of TBI patients with agitated behaviours.&#xD;
      Nurses will be interviewed as they are the healthcare professionals most present at the&#xD;
      bedside of TBI patients and their families. Semi-structured interviews enable to explore&#xD;
      nurse's perspectives and experiences. This will also allow us to investigate how these&#xD;
      experiences can predict their reactions to agitated behaviours, and how these reactions are&#xD;
      shared between different health professionals or also with hospital health personnel. This&#xD;
      particular phase enables us to uncover unanticipated themes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will then undertake a retrospective observational study aiming to describe the&#xD;
      documentation of agitated behaviours in TBI patients and interventions to manage them. In&#xD;
      this step, the objective is to substantiate the documentation of the significant elements&#xD;
      identified in the first two phases of the study. This third phase will be complementary to&#xD;
      the previous two phases and will allow to document in which way observations in the first two&#xD;
      phases are reflected in the clinical notes. A convenience sample of consecutive admissions&#xD;
      for TBI with an abnormal CT-scan will be reviewed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally, interprofessional focus groups will be conducted in order to gain insights into ICU&#xD;
      healthcare professionals experiences and explore their attitudes and needs when TBI patients&#xD;
      develop agitation. Group process can help people to explore and clarify their views and to&#xD;
      share ideas and perceptions. All healthcare professional who participate in the care of TBI&#xD;
      patients in the ICU will be solicited for participation. Specifically, the aim is to discuss&#xD;
      the various themes identified in the previous steps and understand their relational dimension&#xD;
      among different healthcare professionals.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The integration of the different methods will be done by the connection of the different&#xD;
      steps and by the integration of results for each step. This multistep approach allows to&#xD;
      identify organizational, cultural factors and to better understand social interactions as&#xD;
      well as health care delivery process.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">February 10, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To explore the experiences and attitudes of the healthcare professionals managing agitation of TBI patients in two ICUs of level-1 Canadian trauma hospitals</measure>
    <time_frame>December 2020-October 2021</time_frame>
    <description>To unveil the perceptions, the practices, the consequences and the risks of handling TBI agitated patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">98</enrollment>
  <condition>Trauma Injury</condition>
  <condition>Intensive Care Neurological Disorder</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        ICU healthcare professionals ICU TBI patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All professionals belonging to the intensive care team (nurses, occupational&#xD;
             therapists, beneficiary attendants, ICU physicians, physiotherapists, respiratory&#xD;
             therapists, pharmacists, unit coordinators), employed full-time or part-time in any&#xD;
             shift with a minimum of 1 year of trauma intensive care experience can be included to&#xD;
             participate in the semi-structured interviews and focus groups&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All patients suffering from a TBI with an abnormal CT scan admitted to the ICU will be&#xD;
             included for the structured observation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  In the retrospective observational study, a convenience sample of 25 patients per&#xD;
             centre (50 patients in total) admitted six months before the observational period will&#xD;
             be included for data collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Temporary staff, students or residents will be excluded from semi-structured&#xD;
             interviews and focus groups&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 4, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Agitation</keyword>
  <keyword>Healthcare professionals</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Nervous System Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Psychomotor Agitation</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

