<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04745169</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-009666</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04745169</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Home-Based Exercise as an Intervention to Treat Decreased Physical Function in Patients With Varying Levels of Kidney Function</brief_title>
  <official_title>Home-Based Exercise as an Intervention to Treat Decreased Physical Function in Patients With Varying Levels of Kidney Function</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Mayo Clinic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Mayo Clinic</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators will conduct a pilot study to determine whether home-based exercise is an&#xD;
      effective intervention to improve decreased physical function in kidney transplant&#xD;
      candidates. The investigators will determine if home-based exercise improves frailty&#xD;
      parameters and SPPB scores. The investigators will also determine if home-based exercise&#xD;
      improves health-related quality of life (HRQOL), body composition, physical activity, and&#xD;
      adverse clinical outcomes, including hospitalizations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Screening and Recruitment:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential participants undergoing outpatient kidney transplant evaluation at Mayo Clinic&#xD;
      Rochester will be identified. Patients who express interest in the study will go through the&#xD;
      informed consent process with a member of the study team, and patients wishing to participate&#xD;
      in the study will complete written consent. If patients have not had frailty and SPPB testing&#xD;
      within the two weeks prior to consent, the study team member will perform frailty and SPPB&#xD;
      testing at baseline in a supervised setting. Patients who are not frail or pre-frail and have&#xD;
      a SPPB score &gt; 10 will be ineligible for study participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exercise Intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be provided with a pedal exerciser, resistance bands, and exercise&#xD;
      pamphlets. Participants will be asked to complete an 8-week home-based exercise program with&#xD;
      a focus on the core components of physical activity counseling and exercise training&#xD;
      according to guidelines from the American Heart Association and the American Association of&#xD;
      Cardiovascular and Pulmonary Rehabilitation. Participants will receive an individualized&#xD;
      exercise prescription. Recommended aerobic exercises will include arm and/or leg ergometry&#xD;
      using a pedal exerciser, and recommended resistance training will include resistance bands.&#xD;
      During the program, participants will receive weekly semi-scripted phone calls from an&#xD;
      exercise physiologist and gradual increases in the volume of physical activity will be&#xD;
      recommended over time. Participants will be asked to log information regarding their exercise&#xD;
      sessions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Measures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete the Short Physical Performance Battery (SPPB), and Fried Frailty&#xD;
      phenotype at baseline and after completion of the exercise intervention. The SPPB consists of&#xD;
      gait speed, balance, and repeat chair stand tests. The Fried Frailty Phenotype consists of&#xD;
      gait speed and grip strength tests, in addition to self-reported measurement of physical&#xD;
      activity, weight loss, and exhaustion. Participants will also be asked to complete a body&#xD;
      composition scan, complete questionnaires, and wear a physical activity monitor at baseline&#xD;
      and after completion of the exercise intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 21, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a pilot study to be conducted at Mayo Clinic in Rochester, MN examining the feasibility, safety, acceptability, and preliminary efficacy of home-based exercise on frailty parameters and SPPB score in patients with varying levels of kidney function. The effects of exercise on HRQOL, body composition, physical activity, and adverse outcomes including hospitalizations, will also be explored.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Short Physical Performance Battery score</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks of home-based exercise</time_frame>
    <description>The Short Physical Performance Battery consists of gait speed, balance, and repeated chair stand tests. The minimum score is 0, and the maximum score is 12. Higher scores indicate better physical function.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in grip strength</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Grip strength will be measured using a hand-held dynamometer.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in gait speed</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Gait speed at the participant's self-selected walking speed will be measured.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in exhaustion</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Patients will self-report their level of exhaustion using the Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale (CES-D) which consists of a 4-point scale. Items on the CES-D are scored from minimum to maximum values (1 point to 4 points) which are indicated on the CES-D as &quot;rarely or none of the time,&quot; &quot;some or a little of the time,&quot; &quot;occasionally or a moderate amount of time,&quot; &quot;most or all of the time,&quot; respectively. A higher number of points indicates a worse outcome.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in physical activity</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Energy expenditure will be measured using an activity monitor worn on the wrist for 7 days. Low activity is defined as activity in the lowest 20% (&lt;383 Kcals/week for men or &lt;270 Kcals/week for women). Patients will also self-report their activity level using the Minnesota Leisure Time Physical Activity Questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Wasting</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Wasting is defined as an unintentional weight loss of 10 or more pounds in one year.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in quality of life</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life will be measured using the Kidney Disease Quality of Life Short Form. This questionnaire includes scales with minimum values of 0 and maximum values of 100. Higher scores indicate better quality of life.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in free fat mass</measure>
    <time_frame>8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Free fat mass will be assessed using a body composition scan utilizing electrical impedance.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-transplant 30-day rehospitalizations</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year</time_frame>
    <description>The relationship between exercise, physical function, and post-transplant 30-day rehospitalizations will be examined for patients who receive a kidney transplant within 1 year of enrolling in this study.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Kidney Transplant Candidates</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants will be asked to complete an 8-week home-based exercise intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>8 week home-based exercise program</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be asked to complete an 8-week home-based exercise program according to guidelines from the American Heart Association and the American Association of Cardiovascular and Pulmonary Rehabilitation. At study baseline, participants will receive exercise equipment and an individualized exercise prescription from an exercise physiologist followed by 8 weekly phone calls from an exercise physiologist. Participant safety will be monitored.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Consenting to research&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Approved for kidney transplant at Mayo Clinic -OR- Chronic kidney disease (stages 1-5)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An SPPB score ≤10 or considered frail or pre-frail according to the Fried Frailty&#xD;
             Phenotype&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Younger than 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients being evaluated for combined organ transplantation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant comorbidities that limit rehabilitation potential including pulmonary&#xD;
             disease requiring continuous oxygen supplementation, active angina, critical aortic&#xD;
             sclerosis, decompensated heart failure, or known ventricular arrhythmia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An SPPB score &gt;10 or not considered frail or pre-frail by the Fried Frailty Phenotype&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-English speaker without availability of adequate interpreter services (safety&#xD;
             concern)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Failure to pass submaximal exercise test in patients not approved for kidney&#xD;
             transplantation at our center&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Elizabeth C Lorenz, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Mayo Clinic</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Julie Gecox Hanson, CCRP</last_name>
    <phone>507-293-6592</phone>
    <email>gecox.julie@mayo.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Mayo Clinic</name>
      <address>
        <city>Rochester</city>
        <state>Minnesota</state>
        <zip>55905</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Julie Gecox Hanson, CCRP</last_name>
      <phone>507-293-6592</phone>
      <email>gecox.julie@mayo.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Elizabeth C Lorenz, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mayo.edu/research/clinical-trials</url>
    <description>Mayo Clinic Clinical Trials</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 9, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Mayo Clinic</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Elizabeth C. Lorenz</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

