<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04742309</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pecs vs PVB</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04742309</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pectoralis Block vs Paravertebral Nerve Blocks for Breast Surgery</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Subject-Masked, Active-Controlled, Parallel-Arm Clinical Trial Comparing Pecs-2 and Paravertebral Nerve Blocks</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Following painful surgical procedures of the breast, postoperative analgesia is often&#xD;
      provided with a nerve block called a &quot;paravertebral&quot; block. For intense, but shorter-duration&#xD;
      acute pain, a single-injection of numbing medicine is used which lasts about 12 hours.&#xD;
      Recently, a new type of block has been reported: the &quot;Pecs-2&quot; block. The theoretical benefits&#xD;
      include ease of administration since it is closer to the skin (less deep) compared with the&#xD;
      paravertebral block and therefore easier to identify and target with ultrasound (therefore&#xD;
      increasing success rate); and, a lower risk of complications. Lastly, it might be easier to&#xD;
      insert a tiny tube which would allow additional numbing medicine to be injected. There are,&#xD;
      therefore, multiple theoretical reasons to prefer the Pecs-2 over the paravertebral nerve&#xD;
      block. Unfortunately, it remains unknown if the pain control provided by this new type of&#xD;
      block is comparable to that provided with the older block. The investigators therefore&#xD;
      propose to compare these two blocks with a clinical study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This investigation will be a randomized, subject-masked, active-controlled parallel-arm,&#xD;
      human subjects clinical trial. Of note, the investigators will be using standard-of-care&#xD;
      local anesthetic under a Food and Drug Administration-approved purpose and do not plan to&#xD;
      research a possible change of indication or use of these medications as part of this research&#xD;
      project. The treatments in both groups are currently used at our institution and there is&#xD;
      true clinical equipoise at this time. The only difference in treatment between subjects who&#xD;
      enroll versus those not enrolled in this study will be those who enroll will have the&#xD;
      decision between which anatomic block location determined randomly, as opposed to the&#xD;
      physician simply choosing him/herself.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Enrollment. Consenting adults undergoing breast surgery with a planned single-injection&#xD;
      regional analgesic will be offered enrollment. Patients undergoing breast surgery with a&#xD;
      planned perineural catheter regional analgesic will be excluded. Study inclusion will be&#xD;
      proposed to eligible patients prior to surgery. If a patient desires study participation,&#xD;
      written, informed consent will be obtained using a current University of California San Diego&#xD;
      Institutional Review Board-approved informed consent form. Selection for inclusion will not&#xD;
      be based on gender, race, or socioeconomic status. The study population of interest includes&#xD;
      men and women of all races and socioeconomic status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Preoperative Procedures. Following written, informed consent, the investigators will collect&#xD;
      baseline anthropomorphic information (e.g., age, sex, height, and weight). All subjects will&#xD;
      have a peripheral intravenous catheter inserted, standard noninvasive monitors applied,&#xD;
      supplemental oxygen administered via a nasal cannula or face mask, and placed in the sitting&#xD;
      position. Intravenous midazolam and fentanyl will be titrated for patient comfort, while&#xD;
      ensuring that patients remain responsive to verbal cues. Both possible block locations will&#xD;
      be viewed with ultrasound. If one or both of the locations is unacceptable for block&#xD;
      placement in the clinician's opinion, the subject will not be randomized and will not proceed&#xD;
      further with the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects will then be randomized using a computer-generated list and opaque, sealed envelopes&#xD;
      to one of two treatment groups: (blocks of 4, stratified for unilateral vs. bilateral&#xD;
      surgery): (1) Pecs-2 or (2) paravertebral block. All blocks will be placed by a regional&#xD;
      anesthesia fellow or resident under the direct supervision and guidance of a regional&#xD;
      anesthesia attending (or by the attending themselves).&#xD;
&#xD;
      For paravertebral blocks, a total of 18 mL of ropivacaine 0.5% with epinephrine will be&#xD;
      administered per side (90 mg). An equivalent mass of ropivacaine will be administered for the&#xD;
      Pecs-2 blocks (90 mg), but since more volume is required (30 mL per treated side), the&#xD;
      concentration will be decreased to 0.3% ropivacaine (with epinephrine). Therefore, for&#xD;
      bilateral procedures, 90 mg will be administered to each side (180 mg total, with&#xD;
      epinephrine). The area of needle insertion will be cleaned with chlorhexidine gluconate and&#xD;
      isopropyl alcohol. All blocks will be placed using standard UCSD ultrasound-guided techniques&#xD;
      as previously described.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For Pecs-2 blocks, the needle will be advanced to the tissue plane between the pectoralis&#xD;
      major and minor muscles at the vicinity of the pectoral branch of the acromiothoracic artery&#xD;
      where 10 mL of local anesthetic will be deposited. In a similar manner, 20 mL will be&#xD;
      deposited at the level of the third rib above the serratus anterior muscle with the intent of&#xD;
      spreading injectate to the axilla.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For paravertebral blocks, ropivacaine 0.5% 9 mL will be administered at each of two levels&#xD;
      per side: the T3 and T5 levels for sides without axillary involvement; and at the T2 and T4&#xD;
      level for sides with axillary involvement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Single-injection blocks will be considered successful if, within 30 minutes, the subject&#xD;
      experiences decreased sensation to cold temperature with an alcohol pad over the approximate&#xD;
      level of the ipsilateral 4th thoracic dermatome. Misplaced blocks will be replaced&#xD;
      successfully, or the patient excluded from further study participation. For subjects&#xD;
      undergoing bilateral surgical procedures, a block using the same protocol will be&#xD;
      administered on the contralateral side.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intraoperatively, all subjects will receive a general anesthetic using inhaled and&#xD;
      intravenous anesthetic and oxygen. Intravenous fentanyl will be administered for&#xD;
      cardiovascular responsiveness to noxious stimuli at the discretion of the anesthesia&#xD;
      provider.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Postoperatively: Subjects will be discharged with a prescription for oxycodone 5 mg tablets&#xD;
      for supplementary analgesia and instructed to record the time at which they take their first&#xD;
      opioid tablet as well as the time at which they believe the block starts to wear off.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Outcome measurements (end points). Pain scores will be recorded using the Numeric Rating&#xD;
      Scale. Within the recovery room, pain scores, opioid requirements, and antiemetic&#xD;
      administration will be recorded by nursing staff masked to treatment group. The morning&#xD;
      following surgery, all subjects will be contacted by phone or in person [if hospitalized] to&#xD;
      record lowest, average, highest, and current pain scores; sleep disturbances, and nausea&#xD;
      using a 0-10 Likert scale (0 = no nausea; 10 = vomiting). For outpatients, opioid&#xD;
      requirements will be recorded while inpatients will have opioid requirements extracted from&#xD;
      the electronic medical record. In addition, the investigators will extract antiemetic use&#xD;
      from the electronic record. The investigators will collect the times at which subjects felt&#xD;
      their block resolve and they consumed their first opioid analgesic pills following recovery&#xD;
      room discharge.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 1: Following breast surgery, analgesia will be non-inferior in the recovery room&#xD;
      with a Pecs-2 block compared with a paravertebral block as measured with the Numeric Rating&#xD;
      Scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis 2: For breast surgery, opioid consumption will be non-inferior in the operating&#xD;
      and recovery rooms with a Pecs-2 block compared with a paravertebral block (primary:&#xD;
      cumulative intravenous morphine equivalents).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary end point: In order to claim that Pecs-2 blocks are non-inferior to paravertebral&#xD;
      blocks, both Hypotheses 1 and 2 must be at least non-inferior.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical methods. Descriptive statistics will be provided by arm and in aggregate.&#xD;
      Baseline characteristics of arms will be compared using the Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney and&#xD;
      Fisher's Exact tests. Key characteristics that are significantly different (p&lt;0.05) will be&#xD;
      included as covariates in the analysis models.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Primary aim. The investigators will test the noninferiority of the Pecs-2 nerve block&#xD;
      compared to the paravertebral nerve block. The 95% confidence interval (CI) associated with&#xD;
      the Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney test will be derived for the group difference (paravertebral minus&#xD;
      serratus) in median pain scores within the recovery room. If the lower limit of the 95% CI is&#xD;
      greater than -1.25, the investigators will conclude noninferiority. If there are significant&#xD;
      differences between the groups in any key characteristics, these characteristics will be&#xD;
      included as covariates in a linear model. The same noninferiority margin (-1.25) will be&#xD;
      applied to the 95% CI for the covariate adjusted group difference in mean pain derived from&#xD;
      the linear model.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The noninferiority of the Pecs-2 nerve block with regard to total opioid consumption within&#xD;
      the operating and recovery rooms will be tested in the same manner as pain, i.e. comparing&#xD;
      the limits of a 95% confidence interval associated with the Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney test to a&#xD;
      predefined noninferiority margin (in this case 2 mg). Covariate adjusted linear models will&#xD;
      again be applied in the event that key characteristics are significantly different between&#xD;
      the groups.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Sample size justification. Power for the Wilcoxon-Mann-Whitney derived noninferiority testing&#xD;
      is based on 10,000 simulated trials. The investigators simulated pain scores from a discrete&#xD;
      distribution with median of 3 (interquartile range of 2-5). Between the quartiles, the&#xD;
      probability of each score was assumed constant. The distribution for each group was assumed&#xD;
      to be the same. The sample size of n=50 per group provides 82% power to detect noninferiority&#xD;
      in pain with a margin of 1.25. Similarly, opioid consumption was assumed to follow a&#xD;
      truncated normal distribution with mean 2.5 mg and standard deviation 2 mg, and minimum value&#xD;
      0 mg. The sample size of n = 50 per group provides at least 95% power to detect&#xD;
      noninferiority with margin 2 mg. However, the investigators will increase the number of&#xD;
      enrolled subjects to account for an unanticipated higher variability for both outcomes.&#xD;
      Therefore, the investigators will enroll 75 subjects for each of two treatments with primary&#xD;
      end point values for a total enrollment of 150 subjects with a primary end point. To allow&#xD;
      for dropouts, the investigators request a maximum enrollment of 175 subjects. Noninferiority&#xD;
      in pain is tested first, and if significant, noninferiority in opioid consumption is tested.&#xD;
      Under this hierarchical testing framework, no adjustment in alpha is necessary to control&#xD;
      Type 1 error.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 25, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 2, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Anesthesia teams in the operating rooms and recovery room nurses will be masked to treatment group assignment (therefore, the primary outcome measure collection). Outcomes assessor for the questionnaire involving secondary outcomes on the day following surgery will not be masked to treatment group, although subjects will remain masked.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Recovery Room Numeric Rating Scale Pain Scores</measure>
    <time_frame>From arrival in the recovery room until recovery room discharge, assessed up to 12 hours total</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale: the NRS is a segmented numeric version of the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) in which the study subject selects a whole number (0-10 integers) that best reflects the intensity of his/her pain. This 11-point numeric scale ranges from 0 representing &quot;no pain&quot; to 10 representing &quot;worst imaginable pain.&quot; Higher numeric scores represent increased pain and thus worse outcomes. Of note, in order to claim that Pecs-2 blocks are non-inferior to paravertebral blocks, both Hypotheses 1 and 2 must be at least non-inferior.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative Operating and Recovery Room Opioid Consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>From entering the operating room until recovery room discharge, assessed up to 24 hours</time_frame>
    <description>The morphine equivalents consumed in both the operating and recovery rooms. Of note, in order to claim that Pecs-2 blocks are non-inferior to paravertebral blocks, both Hypotheses 1 and 2 must be at least non-inferior.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Nausea and vomiting</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>0-10 Likert scale (0 = no nausea; 10 = vomiting)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of first opioid use</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Time of block resolution</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Opioid consumption</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Worst pain measured using the Numeric Rating Scale pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale: the NRS is a segmented numeric version of the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) in which the study subject selects a whole number (0-10 integers) that best reflects the intensity of his/her pain. This 11-point numeric scale ranges from 0 representing &quot;no pain&quot; to 10 representing &quot;worst imaginable pain.&quot; Higher numeric scores represent increased pain and thus worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lowest pain measured using the Numeric Rating Scale pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale: the NRS is a segmented numeric version of the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) in which the study subject selects a whole number (0-10 integers) that best reflects the intensity of his/her pain. This 11-point numeric scale ranges from 0 representing &quot;no pain&quot; to 10 representing &quot;worst imaginable pain.&quot; Higher numeric scores represent increased pain and thus worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Average pain measured using the Numeric Rating Scale pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>Recovery room discharge until data collection call on Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale: the NRS is a segmented numeric version of the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) in which the study subject selects a whole number (0-10 integers) that best reflects the intensity of his/her pain. This 11-point numeric scale ranges from 0 representing &quot;no pain&quot; to 10 representing &quot;worst imaginable pain.&quot; Higher numeric scores represent increased pain and thus worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Current pain measured using the Numeric Rating Scale pain score</measure>
    <time_frame>Postoperative Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Numeric Rating Scale: the NRS is a segmented numeric version of the Visual Analog Scale (VAS) in which the study subject selects a whole number (0-10 integers) that best reflects the intensity of his/her pain. This 11-point numeric scale ranges from 0 representing &quot;no pain&quot; to 10 representing &quot;worst imaginable pain.&quot; Higher numeric scores represent increased pain and thus worse outcomes.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Awakenings due to pain</measure>
    <time_frame>Evening of surgery</time_frame>
    <description>The number of times subject recalls awakening from sleep due to pain</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Breast Surgery</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Pecs-2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>For Pecs-2 blocks, the needle will be advanced to the tissue plane between the pectoralis major and minor muscles at the vicinity of the pectoral branch of the acromiothoracic artery where 10 mL of local anesthetic will be deposited. In a similar manner, 20 mL will be deposited at the level of the third rib above the serratus anterior muscle with the intent of spreading injectate to the axilla. The study fluid will be ropivacaine 0.3% with epinephrine.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Paravertebral</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>For paravertebral blocks, ropivacaine 0.5% (with epinephrine) 9 mL will be administered at each of two levels per side: the T3 and T5 levels for sides without axillary involvement; and at the T2 and T4 level for sides with axillary involvement.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pecs-2 block (single injection)</intervention_name>
    <description>For Pecs-2 blocks, the needle will be advanced to the tissue plane between the pectoralis major and minor muscles at the vicinity of the pectoral branch of the acromiothoracic artery where 10 mL of local anesthetic will be deposited. In a similar manner, 20 mL will be deposited at the level of the third rib above the serratus anterior muscle with the intent of spreading injectate to the axilla. The study fluid will be ropivacaine 0.3% with epinephrine.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Pecs-2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Paravertebral block (single injection)</intervention_name>
    <description>For paravertebral blocks, ropivacaine 0.5% (with epinephrine) 9 mL will be administered at each of two levels per side: the T3 and T5 levels for sides without axillary involvement; and at the T2 and T4 level for sides with axillary involvement.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Paravertebral</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Undergoing unilateral or bilateral breast surgery with at least moderate postoperative&#xD;
             pain anticipated.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Analgesic plan includes a single-injection peripheral nerve block(s).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Age 18 years or older.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Morbid obesity as defined by a body mass index &gt; 40 (BMI=weight in kg / [height in&#xD;
             meters]2).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Renal insufficiency ( abnormal preoperative creatinine or eGFR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Chronic opioid use (daily use within the 2 weeks prior to surgery and duration of use&#xD;
             &gt; 4 weeks).&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. History of opioid abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Any comorbidity which results in moderate or severe functional limitation inability to&#xD;
             communicate with the investigators or hospital staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Inability to communicate with the investigators or hospital staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Planned regional analgesic with perineural catheter placement&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Incarceration&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Known allergy to amide local anesthetics.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Brian M Ilfeld, MD,MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UCSD Medical Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University Of California San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Bashandy GM, Abbas DN. Pectoral nerves I and II blocks in multimodal analgesia for breast cancer surgery: a randomized clinical trial. Reg Anesth Pain Med. 2015 Jan-Feb;40(1):68-74. doi: 10.1097/AAP.0000000000000163.</citation>
    <PMID>25376971</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 26, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Brian M. Ilfeld, MD, MS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Anesthesiology, In Residence</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Regional Anesthesia</keyword>
  <keyword>Pecs-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Paravertebral nerve block</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

