<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04820478</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KETO-ALS V 1.41</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04820478</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Efficacy and Tolerability of Beta Hydroxybutyrate in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS)</brief_title>
  <acronym>KETO-ALS</acronym>
  <official_title>Efficacy and Tolerability of Beta Hydroxybutyrate in Patients With Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Ulm</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Ulm</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Weight loss is a known negative prognostic factor in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). One&#xD;
      potential mechanism of weight loss in ALS is a disturbance of the mitochondrial complex I&#xD;
      which causes an energy deficit in affected cells. Over the last years, various interventional&#xD;
      studies targeting the energy deficit in ALS yielded promising results; however,it is still&#xD;
      unclear which kind of nutrition or nutritional supplement is most beneficial. Ketone bodies&#xD;
      represent a logical therapeutic option in ALS as ketone bodies are an extremely&#xD;
      high-energetic substrate which yields the double amount of adenosine triphosphate (ATP) per&#xD;
      mole compared to glucose. The human liver is able to synthesize ketone bodies&#xD;
      (beta-hydroxybutyrate, acetone, and aceto-acetate) from fat in times of glucose shortage, for&#xD;
      example after a prolonged period of fasting. This metabolic shift is the underlying principle&#xD;
      of the ketogenic diet, a carbohydrate-free, fat-rich diet which has been successfully tested&#xD;
      in other neurodegenerative diseases such as Alzheimer's and Parkinson's disease. In the ALS&#xD;
      mouse model, a ketogenic diet was associated with a slower decline of motor function.&#xD;
      However, a ketogenic diet is difficult to implement in ALS as it requires a long-term change&#xD;
      of eating habits, which is difficult to achieve due to progressive dysphagia, fast worsening&#xD;
      of general condition, and limited survival. Therefore, the direct administration of ketone&#xD;
      bodies yields a more realistic alternative in ALS as it is easy to apply and allows to&#xD;
      maintain the usual eating habits. In this study, we hypothesize that the administration of 3&#xD;
      x 15.6 g beta hydroxybutyrate per day (in addition to normal food intake and the standard&#xD;
      medication of 2 x 50 mg riluzole) slows down disease progression as measured by neurofilament&#xD;
      light chains (NfL) in serum after 6 months compared to placebo. Power calculation relies on&#xD;
      the results of the lipids and calories for ALS (LIPCAL-ALS) study which tested the effect of&#xD;
      a high-caloric fatty nutritional supplement in ALS. The study revealed that NfL serum values&#xD;
      declined significantly in the intervention group while remaining stable in the placebo group&#xD;
      over the course of the study. Assuming a similar effect size for ketone bodies, we calculated&#xD;
      that 76 patients had to be included in the current trial.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>placebo-controlled study, using a placebo with similar look and taste in similar bottles; the study is double-blinded, i.e. patients and study personnel are masked</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurofilament Light Chain</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Neurofilament Light Chain (NfL) serum levels</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Survival</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Survival (time to death or tracheostomy)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale Revised</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale Revised (ALSFRS-R) score, measured as individual slope (loss of points per month)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Mass Index</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Body Mass Index (BMI), weight (in kg) and height (in m) will be combined to report BMI in kg/m^2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Slow Vital Capacity</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Slow Vital Capacity (sVC)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Resting Energy Expenditure</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Resting Energy Expenditure (REE), measured by indirect calorimetry</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fatt mass</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Fat mass (% of total body mass), measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Total Body Water</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>total body water (% of total body mass), measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Muscle Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>muscle mass (% of total body mass) measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fat Free Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>fat free mass (% of total body mass), measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Body Cell Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>body cell mass (% of total body mass), measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Extracellular Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>extracellular mass (% of total body mass), measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Lean Body Mass</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>lean body mass (% of total body mass), measured by bioelectrical impedance analysis (BIA)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Individual Quality of Life</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Individual Quality of Life, measured by The Schedule for the Evaluation of Individual Quality of Life questionnaire (SEIQoL-Q) index</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Neurofilament Phosphorylated Heavy Chain</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Neurofilament Phosphorylated Heavy Chain (pNfH) in cerebrospinal fluid (CSF)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Beta Hydroxybutyrate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Beta Hydroxybutyrate serum levels</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Acetone</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Acetone concentration in urine</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Appetite</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Appetite, measured by the Council of Appetite Questionnaire (CNAQ)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Eating Habits</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Eating Habits, evaluated by the Ulm Nutrition Questionnaire (UNQ; see LIPCAL study)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Adverse Events</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Terms and frequencies of Adverse Events (AEs) and Serious Adverse Events (SAEs)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">76</enrollment>
  <condition>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Beta Hydroxybutyrate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3 x 40 ml (= 3 x 15.6 g) beta hydroxybutyrate per day, mixed with acidic juice (e.g. orange juice), in addition to normal food intake and standard therapy (2 x 50 mg riluzole per day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>3 x 40 ml placebo per day, mixed with acidic juice (e.g. orange juice), in addition to normal food intake and standard therapy (2 x 50 mg riluzole per day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Beta Hydroxybutyrate</intervention_name>
    <description>see arm/group description</description>
    <arm_group_label>Beta Hydroxybutyrate</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Probable (clinically or laboratory) or definite ALS according to the revised version&#xD;
             of the El Escorial World Federation of Neurology criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  loss of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis Functional Rating Scale Revised (ALSFRS-R) of ≥&#xD;
             0.33 points per month since onset (first paresis), based on the formula: (48 - score&#xD;
             at screening visit) / (months between onset and screening visit)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  continuously treated with 100 mg riluzole per day for at least 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  capable of thoroughly understanding all information given and giving full informed&#xD;
             consent according to good clinical practice (GCP)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  hyperinsulinism&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pyruvate decarboxylase deficit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  disturbance of fatty acid oxidation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  disturbance of gluconeogenesis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  acute porphyria&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  metabolism disorders which prevent utilization or degradation of ketone bodies&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe gastro-esophageal reflux&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  severe renal insufficiency&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  previous participation in another interventional study within the preceding 4 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  tracheostomy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  pregnancy or breast-feeding females&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  evidence of a major psychiatric disorder or clinically evident dementia&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Johannes Dorst, Prof</last_name>
    <phone>+49 731 177 5285</phone>
    <email>johannes.dorst@uni-ulm.de</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of Ulm</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ulm</city>
        <state>Baden-Wurttemberg</state>
        <zip>89081</zip>
        <country>Germany</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Johannes Dorst, Prof</last_name>
      <phone>+49 731 177 5285</phone>
      <email>johannes.dorst@uni-ulm.de</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Germany</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Brooks BR, Miller RG, Swash M, Munsat TL; World Federation of Neurology Research Group on Motor Neuron Diseases. El Escorial revisited: revised criteria for the diagnosis of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Other Motor Neuron Disord. 2000 Dec;1(5):293-9. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>11464847</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dupuis L, Oudart H, René F, Gonzalez de Aguilar JL, Loeffler JP. Evidence for defective energy homeostasis in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: benefit of a high-energy diet in a transgenic mouse model. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2004 Jul 27;101(30):11159-64. Epub 2004 Jul 19.</citation>
    <PMID>15263088</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Truong TC, Vallat JM, Sautereau D, Couratier P. Nutritional status is a prognostic factor for survival in ALS patients. Neurology. 1999 Sep 22;53(5):1059-63.</citation>
    <PMID>10496266</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Desport JC, Preux PM, Magy L, Boirie Y, Vallat JM, Beaufrère B, Couratier P. Factors correlated with hypermetabolism in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. Am J Clin Nutr. 2001 Sep;74(3):328-34.</citation>
    <PMID>11522556</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dorst J, Cypionka J, Ludolph AC. High-caloric food supplements in the treatment of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a prospective interventional study. Amyotroph Lateral Scler Frontotemporal Degener. 2013 Dec;14(7-8):533-6. doi: 10.3109/21678421.2013.823999. Epub 2013 Aug 14.</citation>
    <PMID>23944684</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wills AM, Hubbard J, Macklin EA, Glass J, Tandan R, Simpson EP, Brooks B, Gelinas D, Mitsumoto H, Mozaffar T, Hanes GP, Ladha SS, Heiman-Patterson T, Katz J, Lou JS, Mahoney K, Grasso D, Lawson R, Yu H, Cudkowicz M; MDA Clinical Research Network. Hypercaloric enteral nutrition in patients with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2 trial. Lancet. 2014 Jun 14;383(9934):2065-2072. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(14)60222-1. Epub 2014 Feb 28.</citation>
    <PMID>24582471</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dorst J, Schuster J, Dreyhaupt J, Witzel S, Weishaupt JH, Kassubek J, Weiland U, Petri S, Meyer T, Grehl T, Hermann A, Jordan B, Grosskreutz J, Zeller D, Boentert M, Schrank B, Prudlo J, Winkler AS, Gorbulev S, Roselli F, Dupuis L, Otto M, Ludolph AC. Effect of high-caloric nutrition on serum neurofilament light chain levels in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2020 Sep;91(9):1007-1009. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2020-323372. Epub 2020 Aug 11.</citation>
    <PMID>32788256</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Steinacker P, Feneberg E, Weishaupt J, Brettschneider J, Tumani H, Andersen PM, von Arnim CA, Böhm S, Kassubek J, Kubisch C, Lulé D, Müller HP, Muche R, Pinkhardt E, Oeckl P, Rosenbohm A, Anderl-Straub S, Volk AE, Weydt P, Ludolph AC, Otto M. Neurofilaments in the diagnosis of motoneuron diseases: a prospective study on 455 patients. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2016 Jan;87(1):12-20. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2015-311387. Epub 2015 Aug 21.</citation>
    <PMID>26296871</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grammatikopoulou MG, Goulis DG, Gkiouras K, Theodoridis X, Gkouskou KK, Evangeliou A, Dardiotis E, Bogdanos DP. To Keto or Not to Keto? A Systematic Review of Randomized Controlled Trials Assessing the Effects of Ketogenic Therapy on Alzheimer Disease. Adv Nutr. 2020 Nov 16;11(6):1583-1602. doi: 10.1093/advances/nmaa073.</citation>
    <PMID>32597927</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Phillips MCL, Murtagh DKJ, Gilbertson LJ, Asztely FJS, Lynch CDP. Low-fat versus ketogenic diet in Parkinson's disease: A pilot randomized controlled trial. Mov Disord. 2018 Aug;33(8):1306-1314. doi: 10.1002/mds.27390. Epub 2018 Aug 11. Erratum in: Mov Disord. 2019 Jan;34(1):157.</citation>
    <PMID>30098269</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhao Z, Lange DJ, Voustianiouk A, MacGrogan D, Ho L, Suh J, Humala N, Thiyagarajan M, Wang J, Pasinetti GM. A ketogenic diet as a potential novel therapeutic intervention in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis. BMC Neurosci. 2006 Apr 3;7:29.</citation>
    <PMID>16584562</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Clarke K, Tchabanenko K, Pawlosky R, Carter E, Todd King M, Musa-Veloso K, Ho M, Roberts A, Robertson J, Vanitallie TB, Veech RL. Kinetics, safety and tolerability of (R)-3-hydroxybutyl (R)-3-hydroxybutyrate in healthy adult subjects. Regul Toxicol Pharmacol. 2012 Aug;63(3):401-8. doi: 10.1016/j.yrtph.2012.04.008. Epub 2012 May 3.</citation>
    <PMID>22561291</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Stubbs BJ, Cox PJ, Evans RD, Santer P, Miller JJ, Faull OK, Magor-Elliott S, Hiyama S, Stirling M, Clarke K. On the Metabolism of Exogenous Ketones in Humans. Front Physiol. 2017 Oct 30;8:848. doi: 10.3389/fphys.2017.00848. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29163194</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Poffé C, Ramaekers M, Van Thienen R, Hespel P. Ketone ester supplementation blunts overreaching symptoms during endurance training overload. J Physiol. 2019 Jun;597(12):3009-3027. doi: 10.1113/JP277831. Epub 2019 May 22.</citation>
    <PMID>31039280</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hashim SA, VanItallie TB. Ketone body therapy: from the ketogenic diet to the oral administration of ketone ester. J Lipid Res. 2014 Sep;55(9):1818-26. doi: 10.1194/jlr.R046599. Epub 2014 Mar 5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>24598140</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>September 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>September 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">September 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Ulm</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Albert Christian Ludolph, Prof.</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Prof.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>nutrition</keyword>
  <keyword>beta hydroxybutyrate</keyword>
  <keyword>high-caloric</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Motor Neuron Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Individual participant data after de-identification as well as the study protocol will be available. Data will be available beginning 3 months and ending 5 years following article publication. Data will be shared with researchers who provide a methodologically sound proposal. Data will be shared for analyses to achieve the aims provided in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to johannes.dorst@uni-ulm.de; to gain access, data requestors will need to sign a data access agreement.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>3 months to 5 years following article publication</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Data will be shard for analyses to achieve the aims provided in the approved proposal. Proposals should be directed to johannes.dorst@uni-ulm.de; to gain access, data requestors will need to sign a data access agreement.</ipd_access_criteria>
    <ipd_url>https://www.uniklinik-ulm.de/neurologie.html</ipd_url>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

