<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04822207</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>JIAI 2021-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04822207</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Acupuncture on the Clinical Outcome of IVF-ET in Patients With Recurrent Implantation Failure</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Acupuncture on the Clinical Outcome of IVF-ET in Patients With Recurrent Implantation Failure: a Multicenter Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>ShangHai Ji Ai Genetics &amp; IVF Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>ShangHai Ji Ai Genetics &amp; IVF Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In order to explore the effect of acupuncture on the clinical outcome of IVF-ET in patients&#xD;
      with recurrent implantation failure, the patients divide into the experimental group or the&#xD;
      control group. In the experimental group, those patients undergo acupuncture at the beginning&#xD;
      of embryo transfer cycle three times a week until 14 days after embryo transfer. In the&#xD;
      control group, those patients do not receive any treatments during embryo transfer cycle.&#xD;
      Statistical analysis of the two groups of primary endpoint and secondary endpoint are done.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      In the field of assisted reproduction techonology, there are still 10% of patients with&#xD;
      recurrent implantation failure. In order to explore the effect of acupuncture on the clinical&#xD;
      outcome of IVF-ET in patients with recurrent implantation failure, the patients divide into&#xD;
      the experimental group or the control group. In the experimental group, those patients&#xD;
      undergo acupuncture at the beginning of embryo transfer cycle three times a week until 14&#xD;
      days after embryo transfer. In the control group, those patients do not receive any&#xD;
      treatments during embryo transfer cycle. Both of two group patients are checked including&#xD;
      endometrial receptivity index and fill in SAS anxiety scale form. Statistical analysis of the&#xD;
      two groups of primary endpoint (clinical pregnancy rate) and secondary endpoint (embryo&#xD;
      implantation rate, biochemical pregnancy rate, early pregnancy loss rate, ongoing pregnancy&#xD;
      rate, live birth rate)are done.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical pregnancy will be defined as ultrasonographic evidence of an intrauterine sac with or without a fetal heart at the 6th gestational week.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>embryo implantation rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>The embryo implantation rate (IR) will be calculated as the number of gestational sacs per embryo transferred</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>biochemical pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Biochemical pregnancy will be defined by a serum HCG level ≥5.0 mIU/ml approximately 14 days after embryo transfer</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>early pregnancy loss rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>Early pregnancy loss will be considered pregnancy loss occurring after detection of a clinical pregnancy up to the 12th week of pregnancy</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>ongoing pregnancy rate</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months</time_frame>
    <description>OPR was calculated by considering all viable intrauterine pregnancy progressing beyond 12 weeks of gestation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>live birth rate</measure>
    <time_frame>12 mongths</time_frame>
    <description>Live birth rates were calculated based on the total number of live births &gt; 20 weeks' gestation over the total number of ongoing pregnancies.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">310</enrollment>
  <condition>Acupuncture</condition>
  <condition>Recurrent Implantation Failure</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the acupuncture group, those patients undergo acupuncture at the beginning of embryo transfer cycle three times a week until 14 days after embryo transfer. These patients should be checked including endometrial receptivity index and fill in SAS anxiety scale form.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the control group, these patients do not receive any treatments during embryo transfer cycle. These patients should be checked including endometrial receptivity index and fill in SAS anxiety scale form.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>acupuncture</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients undergo acupuncture at the beginning of embryo transfer cycle three times a week until 14 days after embryo transfer. Every acupuncture lasts 20 minutes.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Acupuncture group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. A: ≥ 3 times embryo transfer failures，and at least accumulated 4 high-quality embryos&#xD;
        were transferred&#xD;
&#xD;
        B: Two times consecutive embryo transfers failures, at least accumulated 4 high-quality&#xD;
        embryos were transferred&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Undergo IVF / ICSI / PGT;&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Transfer 1-2 D3 cleavage embryos or blastocysts in IVF / ICSI and transfer 1 blastocyst&#xD;
        in PGT;&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. 20-38 years old female&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Sign the informed consent voluntarily.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Contraindications for pregnancy or assisted reproductive technology;&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Chromosome abnormality of husband or wife (except polymorphism);&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Abnormal gene diseases;&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Untreated of uterine diseases that affect the uterine cavity morphology (uterine&#xD;
             malformation, submucous myoma, adenomyosis, endometriosis and endometriosis etc.);&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. AMH &lt; 1.1ng/ml or AFC &lt; 7;&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. The most thickness of endometrium is less than 7 millimeter;&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Those who have more than 2 times clinical pregnancy abortion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients with serious primary diseases including cardiovascular, cerebrovascular,&#xD;
             liver, kidney and hematopoietic system and mental diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. The treatment (such as acupuncture and traditional Chinese Medicine) related to help&#xD;
             pregnancy had been carried out in the last 3 months.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>38 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Xiaoxi Sun</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Obstetrics and Gynecology Hospital affiliated to Fudan University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Wenbi Zhang, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>+8602163459977</phone>
    <email>jackeyzhang0905@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>He Li, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>+8602163459977</phone>
    <email>lihe198900@163.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Shanghai Ji Ai Genetics &amp; IVF Institute, Obstetrics and Gynecology Hospital of Fudan University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Shanghai</city>
        <state>Shanghai</state>
        <zip>200011</zip>
        <country>China</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Wenbi Zhang, Doctor</last_name>
      <email>jackeyzhang0905@163.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>China</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Westergaard LG, Mao Q, Krogslund M, Sandrini S, Lenz S, Grinsted J. Acupuncture on the day of embryo transfer significantly improves the reproductive outcome in infertile women: a prospective, randomized trial. Fertil Steril. 2006 May;85(5):1341-6. Epub 2006 Apr 5.</citation>
    <PMID>16600232</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Paulus WE, Zhang M, Strehler E, El-Danasouri I, Sterzik K. Influence of acupuncture on the pregnancy rate in patients who undergo assisted reproduction therapy. Fertil Steril. 2002 Apr;77(4):721-4.</citation>
    <PMID>11937123</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dieterle S, Ying G, Hatzmann W, Neuer A. Effect of acupuncture on the outcome of in vitro fertilization and intracytoplasmic sperm injection: a randomized, prospective, controlled clinical study. Fertil Steril. 2006 May;85(5):1347-51. Epub 2006 Apr 17.</citation>
    <PMID>16616748</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>August 8, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>August 8, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">August 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>acupuncture</keyword>
  <keyword>recurrent implantation failure</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

