<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04820569</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GaCCoR-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04820569</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Long-term Heart-specific Mortality in the Presence of Competing Risks Among Patients With Non-metastatic Gastric Adenocarcinoma Undergoing Resection and Chemotherapy</brief_title>
  <acronym>GaCCoR-01</acronym>
  <official_title>Long-term Heart-specific Mortality in the Presence of Competing Risks Among Patients With Non-metastatic Gastric Adenocarcinoma Undergoing Resection and Chemotherapy A Population-based Cohort Study of 21,257 Cases, 2004-2016</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this population-based cohort study, data on patients diagnosed with nmGaC in 2004 through&#xD;
      2016, managed with resection and chemotherapy, followed up until the end of 2016, and&#xD;
      surviving ≥1 month were retrieved from the US Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results-18&#xD;
      Program. Cumulative mortality functions were calculated. Prognostic factors for&#xD;
      heart-specific mortality were evaluated using both multivariable-adjusted Fine-Gray&#xD;
      subdistribution and cause-specific hazard functions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2004</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 31, 2016</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>12 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Cumulative mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 12, 2020-Mar 5, 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Cumulative incidence functions (CIFs), which, unlike the standard Kaplan-Meier method, allow for estimation of the incidence of the occurrence of an event while taking competing risks from other causes of death into account, were computed and plotted for cause-specific mortalities.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prognostic factors for disease-specific mortalities</measure>
    <time_frame>Jan 12, 2020-Mar 5, 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated using both multivariable-adjusted Fine-Gray subdistribution and cause-specific hazard functions.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">21257</enrollment>
  <condition>Long-term Heart-specific Mortality in the Presence of Competing Risks Among Patients With Gastric Adenocarcinoma Undergoing Resection and Chemotherapy</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Resection and chemotherapy</intervention_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Cases of non-metastatic gastric adenocarcinoma (nmGaC) were defined as patients with&#xD;
        microscopically-confirmed first primary invasive adenocarcinoma of the stomach&#xD;
        (International Classification of Diseases for Oncology, Third Edition (ICD-O-3) code: C16)&#xD;
        without distant metastasis. Only those who underwent resection in January 2004 through&#xD;
        December 2016 were included.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Cases of non-metastatic gastric adenocarcinoma (nmGaC) were defined as patients with&#xD;
        microscopically-confirmed first primary invasive adenocarcinoma of the stomach&#xD;
        (International Classification of Diseases for Oncology, Third Edition (ICD-O-3) code: C16)&#xD;
        without distant metastasis. Only those who underwent resection in January 2004 through&#xD;
        December 2016 were included. Cancers of other histology types including squamous cell&#xD;
        carcinoma, gastrointestinal stromal tumor or sarcoma, neuroendocrine tumor or carcinoid,&#xD;
        lymphoma, and germ-cell tumor were ineligible, as were patients with non-gastric cancers&#xD;
        involving the stomach, with benign or in situ tumors, or with other malignancies before&#xD;
        gastric cancer. We further excluded patients with diagnosis based on death certificate only&#xD;
        or autopsy, with missing follow-up period, survival status, or cause of death, or with&#xD;
        unknown metastasis status. Cancers with distant metastasis were excluded since resection is&#xD;
        not routinely recommended for them. Data before 2004 were not included, as the TNM stage&#xD;
        information was unavailable. To minimize the effect of perioperative events on survival, we&#xD;
        excluded patients surviving &lt;1 month. No restrictions were applied to age, and patients ≥80&#xD;
        years only comprised 5% of those receiving both resection and chemotherapy.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 29, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>The First Affiliated Hospital of Anhui Medical University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Lei Huang</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Dr.</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Adenocarcinoma</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>The Surveillance, Epidemiology, and End Results Program data are available upon reasonable request and with permission of the registry.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

