<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04829968</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>PERIHIV2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04829968</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Peri-implantitis in HIV-positive Patients</brief_title>
  <acronym>PERIHIV2</acronym>
  <official_title>Valutazione Del Profilo di Emergenza e Del Sovracontorno in Corone Protesiche Complete su Denti Naturali Preparati Senza Linea di Finitura (BOPT): Studio Retrospettivo</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Università Vita-Salute San Raffaele</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Università Vita-Salute San Raffaele</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Objectives: This study aimed to assess the prevalence of peri-implantitis in human&#xD;
      im-munodeficiency virus (HIV) -positive patients and the presence of a possible correlation&#xD;
      between the immunological profile and serological values, of peri-implantitis, and of&#xD;
      pos-sible differences between all-on-4 and single crown/bridge prostheses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Subjects and methods: This retrospective study included 58 adult HIV-positive patients (222&#xD;
      implants) with either all-in-4 prostheses or single crowns/bridges on at least one dental&#xD;
      implant loaded for more than a year who were followed for at least one year. Data pertaining&#xD;
      to the probing pocket depth (PPD), bleeding on probing, and immunological and systemic&#xD;
      profile were collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Results: Patients with single crown/bridge implant rehabilitation showed higher preva-lence&#xD;
      of peri-implantitis (34%) than patients with all-on-4 rehabilitation (0%) (p=0.012). Patients&#xD;
      with all-on-4 rehabilitation were significantly older than those with single crowns/bridges&#xD;
      (p=0.004). Patients with peri-implantitis had implants for a significantly longer duration&#xD;
      than those without (p=0.001), implying that the probability of peri-implantitis increases as&#xD;
      the age of implant increases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Conclusions: The prevalence of peri-implantitis was 26% in HIV-positive patients and 8% in&#xD;
      dental implants. No correlation was found between patients' immunological and se-rological&#xD;
      factors and peri-implantitis. The most important risk factor for peri-implantitis and&#xD;
      mucositis was implant age.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      2.1 Type and sample of the study This retrospective monocentric observational study assessed&#xD;
      the prevalence of peri-implant disease in HIV-positive patients treated at the department of&#xD;
      dentistry of our hos-pital. At the same hospital, the HIV-positive patients were undergoing&#xD;
      antiretroviral treat-ment. This study included 58 adult patients with at least one dental&#xD;
      implant and a total of 222 implants followed for at least one year. Demographic, clinical,&#xD;
      and laboratory infor-mation of the patients was collected. All procedures were approved by&#xD;
      the appropriate lo-cal ethics committee. Appropriate informed consent forms were provided to&#xD;
      all patients and were signed if the patients agreed to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study has been reported according to the STrengthening the Reporting of OBserva-tional&#xD;
      studies in Epidemiology (STROBE) guidelines and checklist.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.2 Study design All included patients were divided into two groups, according to the type of&#xD;
      prosthesis in-serted after implant placement (all-on-4 prosthesis versus single&#xD;
      crowns\bridges), to as-sess the differences between the two types of prostheses in the&#xD;
      inflammatory state, and therefore, in the presence of mucositis and peri-implantitis as well&#xD;
      as in the variables ana-lysed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As shown in Table 1, the data related to the immunological and systemic profile of the&#xD;
      pa-tients (HIVRNA load, CD4+ level, CD8+ level, haemoglobin level, and platelet count) were&#xD;
      collected through the database of the hospital.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3 Case definition for peri-implant condition: The clinical and radiological data for the&#xD;
      diagnosis of peri-implant disease were collected according to the criteria laid in the&#xD;
      Periodontology World Workshop in 2017 by Renvert et al. (2018).&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.3.1 Clinical Examination Data&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Peri-implant mucositis: It was diagnosed on the basis of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Visual inspection demonstrating the following signs of inflammation in the&#xD;
                peri-implant region: red as opposed to pink colour, swollen tissues as opposed to&#xD;
                no swelling, and soft as opposed to firm tissue consistency.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Presence of profuse (line or drop) bleeding and/or suppuration on probing.&#xD;
&#xD;
             3. An increase in probing pocket depths (PPDs) compared to baseline.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Peri-implantitis: It was diagnosed on the basis of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Visual inflammatory changes in the peri-implant soft tissues combined with bleeding&#xD;
                on probing and/or suppuration.&#xD;
&#xD;
             2. Increasing PPDs as compared to measurements recorded at the time of placement of&#xD;
                supra-structures.&#xD;
&#xD;
                2.3.2 Radiological Examination Data Intraoral periapical radiographs are considered&#xD;
                gold standard for radiological evaluation and were used in this study. The&#xD;
                radiographic data were collected from the records of the patient. The position of&#xD;
                the marginal bone was measured manually on an ultraspeed radio-graphic film (Ultra&#xD;
                speed, Kodak, USA) using a dental calliper (0 to 10 mm). The distance to the&#xD;
                marginal bone was measured from the mesial and distal aspects of the implants. The&#xD;
                implant platform was used as a reference for the measurements. Two vertical lines&#xD;
                were drawn parallel to a vertical line passing through the centre of the implant.&#xD;
                The largest value was considered for statistical analysis. All assessments were&#xD;
                performed by a single inves-tigator (LC).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Peri-implantitis:&#xD;
&#xD;
             1. Progressive bone loss in relation to the radiographic bone level assessment&#xD;
                performed after one year following the delivery of the implant-supported&#xD;
                prosthesis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inclusion criteria All patients (&gt;18 years old), who were undergoing antiretroviral therapy&#xD;
      at the same hos-pital, who had undergone prosthetic rehabilitation using one or more dental&#xD;
      implants, with at least one year of follow-up after loading, and who had returned for a&#xD;
      maintenance ap-pointment were considered for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Exclusion criteria Patients who discontinued antiretroviral therapy, patients not undergoing&#xD;
      therapy, patients whose previous radiographs and data on bleeding on probing and PPD at&#xD;
      gingival level were unknown, patients with decompensated systemic diseases (for example,&#xD;
      decompen-sated diabetes mellitus), patients treated with drugs that affect the bone turnover&#xD;
      (for ex-ample, bisphosphonates), and patients under 18 years of age were not included in this&#xD;
      study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      2.4 Statistical analysis A descriptive analysis was performed to assess all the obtained&#xD;
      data. Continuous quantita-tive variables were described as medians and interquartile ranges,&#xD;
      and categorical qualita-tive variables as frequencies and percentages (%). The continuous&#xD;
      variables are graphical-ly represented using boxplots [the box shows the first (Q1), second&#xD;
      (median), and third quartiles (Q3), and as whiskers, the values correspond to 1.5 times &lt;Q1&#xD;
      and 1.5 times&gt; Q3] and categorical variables using bar graphs. The quantitative variables&#xD;
      were compared using the non-parametric Mann-Whitney test and qualitative variables using the&#xD;
      chi-square test or Fisher's exact test. Stepwise multivariate logistic regression analysis&#xD;
      was used to calculate the adjusted risks (odds), respective 95% confidence intervals, and&#xD;
      probability (p-value) of developing peri-implantitis and mucositis. All analyses were&#xD;
      performed using SAS for Windows Software (Version 9.4, SAS Institute). All statistical tests&#xD;
      were ap-plied to 2 sails, and values were considered significant if the calculated&#xD;
      probability was &lt;0.05. The following two types of analyses were performed: the first analysed&#xD;
      the varia-bles individually in the entire study population and the other in the population&#xD;
      divided into 2 groups according to the type of implant-prosthetic rehabilitation performed.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 1, 2015</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">November 30, 2019</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">November 1, 2019</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Only</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>3 Years</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Peri-implantitis prevalence</measure>
    <time_frame>3 years</time_frame>
    <description>This study aimed to assess the prevalence of peri-implantitis in HIV-positive patients and to evaluate the presence of a possible correlation between the immunological profile and serological values of the same HIV-positive patients, of peri-implantitis, and of possible differences between all-on-4 and single crown/bridge prostheses in terms of peri-implant disease and the variables analyzed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">58</enrollment>
  <condition>Peri-Implantitis</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>gingival conditions control</intervention_name>
    <description>Peri-implant mucositis: It was diagnosed on the basis of the following criteria:&#xD;
Visual inspection demonstrating the following signs of inflammation in the peri-implant region: red as opposed to pink colour, swollen tissues as opposed to no swelling, and soft as opposed to firm tissue consistency.&#xD;
Presence of profuse (line or drop) bleeding and/or suppuration on probing.&#xD;
An increase in probing pocket depths (PPDs) compared to baseline. • Peri-implantitis: It was diagnosed on the basis of the following criteria:&#xD;
1. Visual inflammatory changes in the peri-implant soft tissues combined with bleeding on probing and/or suppuration.&#xD;
2. Increasing PPDs as compared to measurements recorded at the time of placement of supra-structures.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        58 HIV-positive patients&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inclusion criteria All patients (&gt;18 years old), who were undergoing antiretroviral&#xD;
             therapy at the same hos-pital, who had undergone prosthetic rehabilitation using one&#xD;
             or more dental implants, with at least one year of follow-up after loading, and who&#xD;
             had returned for a maintenance ap-pointment were considered for inclusion.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion criteria Patients who discontinued antiretroviral therapy, patients not&#xD;
        undergoing therapy, patients whose previous radiographs and data on bleeding on probing and&#xD;
        PPD at gingival level were unknown, patients with decompensated systemic diseases (for&#xD;
        example, decompen-sated diabetes mellitus), patients treated with drugs that affect the&#xD;
        bone turnover (for ex-ample, bisphosphonates), and patients under 18 years of age were not&#xD;
        included in this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Luca Casula</name>
      <address>
        <city>Monza</city>
        <state>Monza E Della Brianza</state>
        <zip>20900</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Università Vita-Salute San Raffaele</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Luca Casula</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, MSc resident in Oral Surgery</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>peri-implantitis</keyword>
  <keyword>mucositis</keyword>
  <keyword>HIV-positive patients</keyword>
  <keyword>All-on-4</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Peri-Implantitis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

