<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04827355</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>201945</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>K23DK125266</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04827355</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Reflux Band in Laryngopharyngeal Reflux</brief_title>
  <official_title>Randomized Sham-Controlled Trial of the Reflux Band in Laryngopharyngeal Reflux (LPR)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases (NIDDK)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of California, San Diego</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This 12 week biomarker targeted double blind randomized controlled trial (RCT) will enroll&#xD;
      subjects with salivary pepsin positive laryngopharyngeal reflux (LPR) to assess efficacy of&#xD;
      the external upper esophageal sphincter (UES) compression device, also known as the Reflux&#xD;
      Band. Subjects will be randomized to one of two arms: control or experimental. Following the&#xD;
      8 week intervention period subjects in both arms will continue in a 4 week unblinded period.&#xD;
      The primary hypothesis is that a significantly higher proportion of subjects in the&#xD;
      experimental arm will meet the primary endpoint for symptom response, compared to subjects in&#xD;
      the control arm.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study seeks to understand if the Reflux Band is an effective treatment for&#xD;
      laryngopharyngeal reflux (LPR) in comparison to a sham device. LPR is a syndrome in which&#xD;
      acid that is made in the stomach travels up the esophagus and into the throat, causing&#xD;
      chronic symptoms including throat clearing, voice hoarseness, sore throat, etc. Participation&#xD;
      in the study may or may not benefit you directly, and may result in new knowledge that may&#xD;
      help others.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participation in this study involves: 3 - 4 in person visits (2 of which are part of standard&#xD;
      of care) ranging from 30 - 45 minutes each and 2 virtual visits, either by phone or video,&#xD;
      each 15 minutes. Participants are assigned with a 50/50 chance (similar to a coin flip) via a&#xD;
      computer generator to receive the Reflux Band or sham device (a device that will not provide&#xD;
      you medical therapy) which they will wear around their neck nightly while sleeping (6+ hours)&#xD;
      over a duration of 8 weeks. The Reflux Band, which has been cleared for use by the FDA,&#xD;
      applies pressure to the outside of the neck at the cricoid cartilage, at the middle of the&#xD;
      neck, and increases the internal pressure of the muscle separating the throat from the&#xD;
      esophagus (upper esophageal sphincter). Participants will only wear the band while sleeping&#xD;
      at night and remove in the morning upon waking. The in person visits will occur at one of&#xD;
      these UCSD La Jolla locations: the Perlman Medical Office Gastroenterology clinic, the Center&#xD;
      for Voice and Swallowing, Altman Clinical and Translational Research Institute (ACTRI)&#xD;
      Clinic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is an optional 4 week extension at the end of this study in which the Reflux Band will&#xD;
      be refit (if sham) to provide the manufacturer's specified pressure. This portion contains 1&#xD;
      virtual follow up during week 10 and an in person follow up during week 12, at which time&#xD;
      study participation will conclude.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The most commonly expected risks of the study are skin reaction, discomfort, and difficulty&#xD;
      sleeping. These were generally mild and short in duration. No serious risks were observed&#xD;
      when the Reflux Band was worn around the neck in previous studies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2026</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2026</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Subjects will be randomized to one of two arms: control or experimental. Randomization will be 1:1 to control (sham, known not to provide intervention) and experimental (fit to manufacturer guidelines).</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure response to the UES Compression Device in pepsin positive LPR.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Change in reflux symptom index score (primary outcome) between intervention versus sham arm will determine device efficacy.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure pepsin response to the UES Compression Device in pepsin positive LPR.</measure>
    <time_frame>5 years</time_frame>
    <description>Change in salivary pepsin concentration between pre and post treatment.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">72</enrollment>
  <condition>Laryngopharyngeal Reflux</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Sham Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants allocated to the control arm will be fit with the UES Compression Device at a pressure known not to provide intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants allocated to the experimental arm will be fit with the UES Compression Device according to manufacturer guidelines.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>External Upper Esophageal Sphincter (UES) Compression Device</intervention_name>
    <description>External Upper Esophageal Sphincter (UES) Compression Device fit to manufacturer guidelines.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Reflux Band</other_name>
    <other_name>Reza Band</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sham Device</intervention_name>
    <description>External Upper Esophageal Sphincter (UES) Compression Device fit to pressure known not to provide treatment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adults between 18-99, English or Spanish speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ≥8 weeks of laryngeal symptoms (dysphonia, throat clearing, cough, globus, and/or sore&#xD;
             throat)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current use of double dose PPI* (equivalent to: omeprazole 40mg daily, lansoprazole&#xD;
             30mg daily, esomeprazole 40mg daily, dexlansoprazole 60mg daily, rabeprazole 20mg&#xD;
             daily, or pantoprazole 80mg daily)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laryngoscopic exam within 12 months prior to screening with reflux finding score &gt;7&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting salivary pepsin concentration of ≥25 ng/mL at screening or within 4 months of&#xD;
             enrollment&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior use of Reflux Band (UES Compression Device)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Sino-pulmonary conditions (such as asthma, COPD, post-nasal drip, heavy voice use) as&#xD;
             primary etiology of laryngeal symptoms as deemed by treating gastroenterologist and /&#xD;
             or laryngologist&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Laryngeal mass or lesion on laryngoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to consent in English or Spanish&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Imprisoned&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  PPI intolerance&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a prior foregut surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a known achalasia diagnosis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to fast for 4 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active tobacco use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Supplemental oxygen use&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contraindication to UES Compression Device manufacturer guidelines:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with implants or implant parts that reside in the area where Reflux Band is&#xD;
             applied: implanted pacemarker, implanted cardioverter defibrillator (ICD), vagus nerve&#xD;
             stimulator (VNS), or other such devices implanted in the neck&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients diagnosed with glaucoma.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who had a malignancy of the neck, including neck surgery.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that may have an altered mental status including due to the use of sedative&#xD;
             drugs or narcotics.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with carotid artery disease, uncontrolled thyroid disease, a history of&#xD;
             cerebrovascular disease, or connective tissue disorder of Marfan's Syndrome or&#xD;
             Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who use nocturnal NIV machines such as CPAP or BiPAP.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rena Yadlapati, MD, MSHS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UC San Diego Health</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Esophageal Research Coordinator</last_name>
    <phone>8582465236</phone>
    <email>mgreytak@ucsd.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of California, San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>La Jolla</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92037</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Esophageal Research Coordinator</last_name>
      <phone>858-246-5236</phone>
      <email>mgreytak@ucsd.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Rena Yadlapati, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Vakil N, van Zanten SV, Kahrilas P, Dent J, Jones R; Global Consensus Group. The Montreal definition and classification of gastroesophageal reflux disease: a global evidence-based consensus. Am J Gastroenterol. 2006 Aug;101(8):1900-20; quiz 1943.</citation>
    <PMID>16928254</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Olson NR. Laryngopharyngeal manifestations of gastroesophageal reflux disease. Otolaryngol Clin North Am. 1991 Oct;24(5):1201-13.</citation>
    <PMID>1754220</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Cohen SM, Pitman MJ, Noordzij JP, Courey M. Management of dysphonic patients by otolaryngologists. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2012 Aug;147(2):289-94. doi: 10.1177/0194599812440780. Epub 2012 Feb 24.</citation>
    <PMID>22368039</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ruiz R, Jeswani S, Andrews K, Rafii B, Paul BC, Branski RC, Amin MR. Hoarseness and laryngopharyngeal reflux: a survey of primary care physician practice patterns. JAMA Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg. 2014 Mar;140(3):192-6. doi: 10.1001/jamaoto.2013.6533.</citation>
    <PMID>24481258</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Litvinov AV. [Method of tracheobronchial spraying of drugs in aerosols]. Vestn Khir Im I I Grek. 1976 Jan;116(1):100-1. Russian.</citation>
    <PMID>1020172</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>de Bortoli N, Nacci A, Savarino E, Martinucci I, Bellini M, Fattori B, Ceccarelli L, Costa F, Mumolo MG, Ricchiuti A, Savarino V, Berrettini S, Marchi S. How many cases of laryngopharyngeal reflux suspected by laryngoscopy are gastroesophageal reflux disease-related? World J Gastroenterol. 2012 Aug 28;18(32):4363-70. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v18.i32.4363.</citation>
    <PMID>22969200</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Shaker R, Babaei A, Naini SR. Prevention of esophagopharyngeal reflux by augmenting the upper esophageal sphincter pressure barrier. Laryngoscope. 2014 Oct;124(10):2268-74. doi: 10.1002/lary.24735. Epub 2014 Jun 27.</citation>
    <PMID>24782387</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Slivers SL, Vaezi MF, Vakil MB, et al. Prospective study of upper esophageal sphincter assist device for treating extraesophageal reflux. Otolaryngol Open J. 2016; 2(1): 31-38. doi: 10.17140/OTLOJ-2-109</citation>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Yadlapati R, Craft J, Adkins CJ, Pandolfino JE. The Upper Esophageal Sphincter Assist Device Is Associated With Symptom Response in Reflux-Associated Laryngeal Symptoms. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018 Oct;16(10):1670-1672. doi: 10.1016/j.cgh.2018.01.031. Epub 2018 Jan 31.</citation>
    <PMID>29408585</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>October 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 29, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>October 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">October 28, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of California, San Diego</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rena Yadlapati</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor of Clinical Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Proton Pump Inhibitor (PPI)</keyword>
  <keyword>Upper Esophageal Sphincter (UES) Compression Device</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Gastroesophageal Reflux</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Laryngopharyngeal Reflux</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>IPD will not be shared with other researchers.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>July 22, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/55/NCT04827355/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

