<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04828551</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2019P002092</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04828551</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Noninvasive Biomarkers of Metabolic Liver Disease 1.1</brief_title>
  <official_title>Noninvasive Biomarkers of Metabolic Liver Disease 1.1</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Massachusetts General Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of California, San Diego</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Foundation for the National Institutes of Health</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Massachusetts General Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      NIMBLE is a comprehensive, five-year collaborative effort to standardize, compare, validate,&#xD;
      and advance the regulatory qualification of imaging and circulating biomarkers to diagnose&#xD;
      and stage nonalcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH), and to predict and assess response to&#xD;
      therapeutic intervention (https://fnih.org/what-we-do/biomarkers-consortium/programs/nimble)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study, Study 1.1, is a prospective, observational, two-center, short- term&#xD;
      cross-sectional study to assess the reproducibility and repeatability of a set of specified&#xD;
      ultrasound-based quantitative imaging biomarkers. The primary focus will be on imaging&#xD;
      biomarkers of the liver fibrosis component of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD),&#xD;
      rather than the steatosis or inflammation component. The rationale is that the fibrosis&#xD;
      component is linked most closely to survival and other clinical outcomes. Study 1.1 will also&#xD;
      collect data to explore vendor- or device-specific investigational biomarkers on other&#xD;
      components of NAFLD such as steatosis and possibly inflammation. The data collected will be&#xD;
      used to inform a decision of which of these biomarkers have sufficient precision to be&#xD;
      advanced to NIMBLE Stage 2.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 18, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Diagnostic</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>Study participants will not be randomized to individual treatment groups or be blinded. In order to ensure a uniform distribution of scanner combinations, participants will follow a block-randomization pattern with different scanner combinations for different participants, however, patients and operators will not be blinded to ultrasound scanners being used.&#xD;
All efforts will be made to keep ultrasound operators blinded to clinical and laboratory data, however, it is not believed that this will significantly affect the ultrasound acquisition. The Visit 2 operator will be asked to not review the Visit 1 exam results.&#xD;
Central analysts will be blinded to key clinical and laboratory findings to minimize potential bias. Blinding of the central analysts will be outlined in a separate Image Review Charter.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pooled different-day, different-operator change of shear wave speed and transient elastography measurements in 2 separate visits</measure>
    <time_frame>(2 visits, baseline + up to 7days). Outcome measure will be assessed after pooling all measurements from all study subjects.</time_frame>
    <description>As the measurement tool, the results of ultrasound measurements will be pooled and analyzed.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of pooled same-day, same-operator repeatability of shear wave speed</measure>
    <time_frame>(2 visits, baseline + up to 7days). Outcome measure will be assessed after pooling all measurements from all study subjects.</time_frame>
    <description>As the measurement tool, the results of ultrasound measurements will be pooled and analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of pooled different-scanner, same-day reproducibility of shear wave elastography.</measure>
    <time_frame>(2 visits, baseline + up to 7days). Outcome measure will be assessed after pooling all measurements from all study subjects.</time_frame>
    <description>As the measurement tool, the results of ultrasound measurements will be pooled and analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of same-day, same-operator repeatability of transient elastography</measure>
    <time_frame>(2 visits, baseline + up to 7days). Outcome measure will be assessed after pooling all measurements from all study subjects.</time_frame>
    <description>As the measurement tool, the results of transient elastography measurements will be pooled and analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of different-day, different-operator reproducibility of transient elastography</measure>
    <time_frame>(2 visits, baseline + up to 7days). Outcome measure will be assessed after pooling all measurements from all study subjects.</time_frame>
    <description>As the measurement tool, the results of transient elastography measurements will be pooled and analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Precision and other reliability metrics of vendor- or device-specific investigational measurements of other components of NAFLD such as steatosis and possibly inflammation.</measure>
    <time_frame>(2 visits, baseline + up to 7days). Outcome measure will be assessed after pooling all measurements from all study subjects.</time_frame>
    <description>As the measurement tool, the results of transient elastography and ultrasound measurements will be pooled and analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Nonalcoholic Steatohepatitis</condition>
  <condition>Nonalcoholic Fatty Liver</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>MGH and UCSD Study subjects</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>This study will enroll patients with suspected or confirmed diagnosis of NAFLD. Based on protocol-specified FIB-4 values, about one-third are expected to have low, one-third to have intermediate, and one-third to have high likelihood of advanced fibrosis.&#xD;
Sex: 50:50 - Note- no stratification will be done based on sex Age: ≥ 18 yrs Demographic group: Patients with a high probability of NAFLD based on the eligibility criteria General health status: Patients with suspected or confirmed diagnosis of NAFLD Geographic location: Boston, MA (greater metropolitan areas) and San Diego, CA (greater metropolitan areas)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ultrasound based shear wave speed and fat quantification methods</intervention_name>
    <description>Ultrasound based imaging parameters will be collected from all patients in two visits. These will include but may not be limited to SWE results, Quantitative ultrasound parameters,where available,including Attenuation Coefficient, Backscatter Coefficient, Shear Wave Dispersion, Speed of Sound, Ultrasound derived fat fraction Conventional Bmode (gray-scale) and Doppler ultrasound images,including An image of the liver and right kidney on the same image for hepatorenal index calculation Right liver lobe for skin to liver capsule distance calculation Portal vein Doppler for portal vein pulsatility index measurement VCTE and Controlled Attenuation Parameter measurements with the Fibroscan system</description>
    <arm_group_label>MGH and UCSD Study subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Blood collection</intervention_name>
    <description>Blood will be collected by trained phlebotomists at each site using routine methods and standard collection tubes.&#xD;
Total volume is expected to be about 10 mL or less Blood collected at MGH will be analyzed by the MGH clinical laboratory. Blood collected at UCSD will be analyzed by the UCSD clinical laboratory. Blood results obtained within the 3-month interval prior to the screening visit at the MGH or UCSD laboratories will be considered acceptable for study analyses and may be used at PI discretion. For each laboratory, the normal ranges for each blood test will be recorded and filed</description>
    <arm_group_label>MGH and UCSD Study subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical measurements</intervention_name>
    <description>Height will be recorded at Screening. Weight and vital signs will be recorded at each visit. Body mass index will be calculated at each visit. All measurements will be made by trained coordinators using standard and calibrated instruments.</description>
    <arm_group_label>MGH and UCSD Study subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Clinical history and medication reviews</intervention_name>
    <description>The following questionnaires will be administered at Screening:&#xD;
Medical history questionnaire Medication use questionnaire Alcohol consumption questionnaire Physical activity questionnaire&#xD;
The following questionnaires will be administered at Visit 1 and Visit 2:&#xD;
Interim medical history questionnaire Change in medication use questionnaire Change in alcohol consumption will be recorded using a modified version of the alcohol use followback. Alcohol use for the 7 day period prior to Visit 1 and for all days between Visit 1 and Visit 2 will be recorded. Change in physical activity questionnaire</description>
    <arm_group_label>MGH and UCSD Study subjects</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult (age ≥ 18 years)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known or suspected NAFLD based on prior biopsy ≤ 36 months consistent with NAFLD OR&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Abnormal ALT (&gt;30 U/L for men, &gt; 19 U/L for women) without other common causes such as&#xD;
             HCV, HBV, AND meets criteria within 36 months for ATP III criteria (2005 revision) for&#xD;
             metabolic syndrome with any 3 of the 5:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Waist circumference (WC) &gt; 102 cm (M) or &gt; 88 cm (F)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fasting glucose ≥ 100 mg/dL or Rx&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  TG≥150mg/dLorRx&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  SBP &gt; 130 mmHg&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  DBP&gt;85mmHg or Rx&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able and willing to participate, including maintaining steady-state: physical&#xD;
             activity, alcohol use, medications&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Classifiable into one of the following enrollment categories by FIB-4 (ALT, AST,&#xD;
             platelets, date of birth) collected at screening visit if not available already within&#xD;
             3 months prior:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Low likelihood of advanced fibrosis: FIB-4 ≤ 1.3 (about one-third of enrolled participants,&#xD;
        minimum 8, maximum 18), Intermediate likelihood of advanced fibrosis: 1.3 &lt; FIB-4 &lt; 2.67&#xD;
        (about one-third of enrolled participants, minimum 8, maximum 18), High likelihood of&#xD;
        advanced fibrosis: FIB-4 ≥ 2.67: (about one-third of enrolled participants, minimum 8,&#xD;
        maximum 18)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Liver disease other than NAFLD&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Excess alcohol consumption (≥ 2 units/day for women and ≥ 3 units/day for men)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current diagnosis of drug induced liver injury&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Receiving drug or placebo in treatment trial now or within 30 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Weight loss or gain of ≥ 5 kg in prior 3 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other factors that in the judgment of the principal investigator might preclude study&#xD;
             completion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Women who state they are pregnant. Women who state they are pregnant will be excluded&#xD;
             in an abundance of caution, since pregnancy might increase intra-abdominal pressure&#xD;
             which in turn might affect the assessment of the different-day reproducibility&#xD;
             coefficient of ultrasound and VCTE measurements. Women who state they might be&#xD;
             pregnant will be required to do a urine pregnancy test to establish eligibility.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with active implants such as pacemakers or defibrillators or any other&#xD;
             contraindication to ultrasound or VCTE scanning.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Anthony E Samir, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Kathryn Fowler, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>UC San Diego</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Anthony E Samir, MD, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>617-643-2009</phone>
    <email>asamir@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>UC San Diego</name>
      <address>
        <city>San Diego</city>
        <state>California</state>
        <zip>92103</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Kathryn Fowler, MD</last_name>
      <email>k1fowler@health.ucsd.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Massachusetts General Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Boston</city>
        <state>Massachusetts</state>
        <zip>02114</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Anthony E Samir, MD, MPH</last_name>
      <email>asamir@mgh.harvard.edu</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Massachusetts General Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Anthony Samir</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Radiologist, Service Chief, Body Ultrasound Imaging Services</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Liver Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Fatty Liver</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Non-alcoholic Fatty Liver Disease</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

