<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04824053</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>F19-028.0</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04824053</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effects of UNICLA-A2 Dairy Products on Patients at High-risk of Colorectal Cancer Development</brief_title>
  <official_title>Comparative Analysis of the Effects of UNICLA-A2 Against Conventional Dairy Products Administered Daily in Patients at High-risk Colorectal Cancer Development Who Have Undergone Polypectomy</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Instituto de Investigación Sanitaria Aragón</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>FEIRACO LACTEOS SL</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Clínico Universitario Lozano Blesa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Instituto de Investigación Sanitaria Aragón</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Dietary intervention with UNICLA-A2 milk products containing beta casein A2 protein, and&#xD;
      higher levels of omega-3 fatty acids and selenium may contribute to maintain the intestinal&#xD;
      integrity, reduce inflammatory processes, normalize the immune system, protect against&#xD;
      oxidative damage and equilibrate the gut microbiota in high-risk colorectal cancer patients&#xD;
      who have undergone polypectomy&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Colorectal cancer (CRC) is one of the most frequent cancers in the world and has a&#xD;
      significant impact in terms of mortality and health costs. It is estimated that CRC causes&#xD;
      around 900,000 deaths annually, mainly due to diagnoses made in advanced stages. Colorectal&#xD;
      adenomas (CRA) are precancerous lesions that develop into colorectal cancer following a&#xD;
      well-known process into the adenoma-carcinoma sequence. Prevention programs include screening&#xD;
      for CRA and removing precancerous lesions by polypectomy, but the high recurrence rates after&#xD;
      polypectomy makes it necessary to research on potential chemopreventive agents that may&#xD;
      reduce this risk. Dietary recommendations or chemoprevention with different nutritional&#xD;
      substances (diets rich in fiber, or poor in red meat, etc) or pharmacological substances&#xD;
      including vitamin D, calcium, fatty acids, salicylic acetyl acid, nonsteroidal&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory agents (NSAIDs), etc) have been studied. In this way, it seems reasonable&#xD;
      to evaluate the effect caused by the administration of certain nutrients that affect lipid&#xD;
      and protein metabolism involved in cellular homeostasis, in the preservation of the colonic&#xD;
      mucosa or the development of lesions may have in populations at risk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      UNICLA A2 dairy products have a different nutrient profile than conventional ones. UNICLA A2&#xD;
      products have higher content in unsaturated fats, that is to say, increased content of&#xD;
      healthy fatty acids such as oleic, linolenic, eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), docosahexaenoic&#xD;
      acid (DHA) and conjugated linoleic acid (CLA). Previous studies have suggested a contribution&#xD;
      of ω-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs) to reduce pro-inflammatory markers and, have shown&#xD;
      they have antimicrobial and negative properties in relation to biofilm formation. These types&#xD;
      of biofilm structures are characteristic of proximal CRC. For these reason, ω-3 PUFAs it is&#xD;
      thought that they could modify the altered intestinal microbiota in patients at high risk of&#xD;
      CRC towards a less pathogenic environment, correcting the gut dysbiosis. Moreover, they have&#xD;
      higher selenium levels (Se), an element with essential biological functions which has been&#xD;
      suggested improving effects in combination with other anticancer agents in CRC and taking&#xD;
      part in the modulation of several processes, such as the immune response, apoptotic cell&#xD;
      death, DNA repair, response to oxidative stress, carcinogenic metabolism, tumorigenesis and&#xD;
      angiogenesis. Finally, they contain type A2 beta casein, which differs from A1 beta casein by&#xD;
      a single amino acid at position 67 of a 107 amino acid chain. This fact is very important&#xD;
      because beta casein contains a chain of amino acids called &quot;beta casomorphin&quot; (BCM7) with&#xD;
      negative health effects reported. The proline 67 in beta casein A2 has a strong bond with&#xD;
      BCM7 that does not allow it to separate and flow freely in milk to be absorbed. However, the&#xD;
      mild bond due to histidine 67 in beta casein A1 allows BCM7 to reach the intestinal wall and&#xD;
      be absorbed, being associated with intestinal discomfort, gastrointestinal transit time and&#xD;
      stool consistency disturbances, abdominal pain and, increased levels of some inflammatory&#xD;
      markers.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For these reasons, in this proposal the investigators aim to determine whether the change&#xD;
      from conventional dairy products to UNICLA-A2 products but maintaining the habitual&#xD;
      consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater&#xD;
      consumption, will have positive effects on maintaining the intestinal integrity by reducing&#xD;
      the inflammatory profile, and leading the gut microbiota to a less pathogenic environment in&#xD;
      patients at high-risk of CRC development.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 15, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 30, 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline levels in pro-inflammatory circulating markers C-reactive protein (CRP), interleukin (IL)-6, macrophage inhibitory cytokine 1 (MIC-1) and tumour necrosis factor alpha (TNFα), as well as in fecal calprotectin.</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, at 3 months and through study completion, an average of 1 year after the colonoscopy that motivated the patient´s inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>The C-reactive protein and calprotectin are measured by conventional methods in the University Clinic Hospital Lozano Blesa and the circulating biomarkers IL-6, MIC-1 and TNFα by enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change from baseline in fecal microbiota.</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline, at 3 months and through study completion, an average of 1 year after the colonoscopy that motivated the patient´s inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Stool samples are collected for DNA extraction and ulterior metagenomic analysis of the fecal microbiota's composition. Library construction is carried out with the Ion 16S™ Metagenomics Kit which permits PCR amplification of hypervariable regions of the 16S rDNA gene from bacteria and the material obtained is subjected to next-generation sequencing (NGS) to see the proportions of the main groups of microorganisms in the sample.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To assess the effect of treatment on colorectal adenoma recurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, an average of 1 year after the initial colonoscopy that motivated the suitability of patients inclusion.</time_frame>
    <description>The number of participants in each arm who develop one or more colorectal adenomas is determined in the follow-up colonoscopy (adenoma detection rate), as well as the presence of advanced or not advanced adenomas, serrated polyps, subtype, location and the total number of adenomas per participant.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">34</enrollment>
  <condition>Colorectal Polyp</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>UNICLA-A2 milk and its subproducts</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants (n=17) ingest milk and dairy products made from cows homozygous for beta casein A2 during 3 months. These products are also enriched in insaturated fatty acids and selenium. The daily intake reflects the habitual consumption habits. Recommended amounts are 250 mL of milk, a yogurt and 50 g fresh cheese per day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Participants (n=17) ingest conventional dairy products and milk daily during 3 months. As happens in the UNICLA-A2 arm, the daily intake reflects habitual dairy consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, recommended amounts are 250 mL of milk, a yogurt and 50 g fresh cheese per day.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Milk from genetically selected homozygous- β-casein-A2 cows fed with forages and a concentrate enriched on linseed and selenized yeast as sources of PUFAs and selenium</intervention_name>
    <description>The daily intake should reflect habitual consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, patients will be recommended a daily intake of 250 mL of milk. The intervention duration will be 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>UNICLA-A2 milk and its subproducts</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>UNICLA-A2 milk</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conventional milk</intervention_name>
    <description>The daily intake should reflect habitual consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, patients will be recommended a daily intake of 250 mL of milk. The intervention duration will be 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Yogurt made from milk of genetically selected homozygous- β-casein-A2 cows fed with forages and a concentrate enriched on linseed and selenized yeast as sources of PUFAs and selenium</intervention_name>
    <description>The daily intake should reflect habitual consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, patients will be recommended a daily intake of one yogurt. The intervention duration will be 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>UNICLA-A2 milk and its subproducts</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>UNICLA-A2 yogurt</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conventional yogurt</intervention_name>
    <description>The daily intake should reflect habitual consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, patients will be recommended a daily intake of one yogurt. The intervention duration will be 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Fresh cheese made from milk of genetically selected homozygous- β-casein-A2 cows fed with forages and a concentrate enriched on linseed and selenized yeast as sources of PUFAs and selenium</intervention_name>
    <description>The daily intake should reflect habitual consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, patients will be recommended a daily intake of 50 g of fresh cheese. The intervention duration will be 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>UNICLA-A2 milk and its subproducts</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>UNICLA-A2 fresh cheese</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Conventional fresh cheese</intervention_name>
    <description>The daily intake should reflect habitual consumption habits in &quot;real life&quot; conditions, without forcing or inducing greater consumption. Therefore, patients will be recommended a daily intake of 50 g of fresh cheese. The intervention duration will be 3 months</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Participants diagnosed with high-risk polyps in the colorectal cancer screening&#xD;
             programme or in the relative's colon cancer prevention program or patients who are in&#xD;
             follow-up due to prior detection of polyps with any of the following characteristics:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 10 adenomas&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 5 proximal serrated polyps (PSP)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  At least 2 serrated polyps with diameters ≥10 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Serrated Polyposis Syndrome (SPS)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Early invasive CRC (stage pT1) endoscopically resected (surgery not required)&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  A sessile or flat lesion ≥ 20 mm with fragmented resection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Patients with previous resection of polyps in which the resection margin was not&#xD;
                  assessable and are considered susceptible to repeat colonoscopy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Regular consumer of milk and dairy products.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Informed consent form signed.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. History of allergic reaction attributed to compounds of similar chemical composition&#xD;
             to the study agents.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Incomplete colonoscopy or with poor quality criteria, Boston &lt;6.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Concomitant acetylsalicylic acid (ASA), NSAIDs, misoprostol, corticosteroids or&#xD;
             statins needed on a regular or predictable basis during the time of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous gastrointestinal surgery (colon or small intestine or gastric) that affects&#xD;
             the absorption of nutrients.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. History of familial adenomatous polyposis.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>75 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Angel Lanas Arbeloa, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University Hospital Lozano Blesa. IIS Aragón. CIBER de Enfermedades Hepáticas y Digestivas.</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Angel Lanas Arbeloa, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0034 976 76 57 86</phone>
    <email>alanas@unizar.es</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Pilar Irun, PhD</last_name>
    <email>mpirun.uit@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Angel Lanas Arbeloa</name>
      <address>
        <city>Zaragoza</city>
        <zip>50009</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Angel Lanas Arbeloa, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <phone>+34 976 76 57 86</phone>
      <email>alanas@unizar.es</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Pilar Irun, PhD</last_name>
      <email>mpirun.uit@gmail.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://medlineplus.gov/colorectalcancer.html</url>
    <description>MedlinePlus is a service of the National Library of Medicine (NLM), the world's largest medical library, which is part of the National Institutes of Health (NIH).</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>July 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>July 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">July 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Instituto de Investigación Sanitaria Aragón</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ángel Lanas Arbeloa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of Digestive Service (University Clinic Hospital Lozano Blesa) and Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>polyp</keyword>
  <keyword>inflammation</keyword>
  <keyword>fecal microbiota</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Colorectal Neoplasms</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Selenium</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Caseins</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

