<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04821752</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20-1672</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04821752</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Environmental Toxicants Avoidance Study</brief_title>
  <acronym>NPETA-GD</acronym>
  <official_title>Non-Persistent Environmental Toxicants Avoidance Study for Individuals With Glucose Dysregulation Who Are Not Using Insulin (NPETA-GD)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Bastyr University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Bastyr University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This study is designed to test whether non-persistent environmental chemicals (PECs) are&#xD;
      elevated in people with glucose dysregulation. The primary aim is to measure whether this&#xD;
      toxicant burden can be reduced using a dietary and lifestyle modification intervention. The&#xD;
      secondary aim is to observe any changes in glucose response pre and post-intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The primary aim will be measured using a commercially-available screening test for urinary&#xD;
      toxicant metabolites. The toxicant burden will be measured by a percentile score of each&#xD;
      metabolite and summing all percentile values. A risk level of each metabolite will be&#xD;
      normalized by the percentile score in order to calculate the total toxic burden for an&#xD;
      individual. Wilcoxon-ranked sum non-parametric calculations will be used to evaluate whether&#xD;
      pre and post-intervention reduction has occurred. Because this is a single-arm trial, any&#xD;
      reduction in the toxicant burden will be correlated with the relative improvement of the&#xD;
      secondary endpoint and will be measured using Kendall's tau-beta ranked correlation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary aim will assess each participant's glucose response to an oral glucose&#xD;
      tolerance test (OGTT) pre and post-intervention. Because this study is not powered, the&#xD;
      estimated man reduction from baseline cannot be estimated. Any reduction in OGTT mean values&#xD;
      will allow us to calculate an effect size for future investigation. The ranking of the&#xD;
      improvement in glucose response (AUC) will be tested by ranking the reduction of the toxic&#xD;
      burden by a correlation analysis using Kendall's tau-beta ranked correlation described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Each participant is provided with the first baseline in-person assessment, two online&#xD;
      avoidance education sessions and the last in-person assessment sessions. The topics of the&#xD;
      avoidance educational sessions will be individualized. A survey questionnaire assessing&#xD;
      knowledge, attitude and behavior (KAB) regarding avoidance of environmental toxicants will be&#xD;
      administered pre and post-intervention.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This is a single-arm trial with rolling enrollment</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in percentile score of urinary excretion of toxicant marker metabolites pre and post three-week dietary and lifestyle intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>The primary aim will be measured using a commercially-available screening test for urinary toxicant metabolites. The toxicant burden will be measured by a percentile score of each metabolite and summing all percentile values. A risk level of each metabolite will be normalized by the percentile score in order to calculate the total toxic burden for an individual. Wilcoxon-ranked sum non-parametric calculations will be used to evaluate whether pre and post-intervention reduction has occurred. Because this is a single-arm trial, any reduction in the toxicant burden will be correlated with the relative improvement of the secondary endpoint and will be measured using Kendall's tau-beta ranked correlation.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in immediate glucose response measured by an oral glucose tolerance test (OGTT) pre and post three-week dietary and lifestyle intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>3 months</time_frame>
    <description>A secondary endpoint is to observe each participant's glucose response to an OGTT. Because this is not powered, the estimated mean reduction from the baseline to the ending of the trial cannot be estimated. Any reduction in the OGTT mean values allows us to calculate the effect size for future investigation. The ranking of the improvement in glucose response (smaller AUC) is tested with the ranking of the reduction of toxic burden by a correlation analysis described the above.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">25</enrollment>
  <condition>Pollution; Exposure</condition>
  <condition>Glucose Intolerance</condition>
  <condition>Glycemic Control</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Toxicant avoidance and glucose dysregulation</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>To investigate whether or not the excretion of urinary toxicant metabolites is reduced by dietary modification and lifestyle intervention in people with glucose dysregulation; whether the participant's ranked glucose dysregulation correlates with the amount and/or type of toxic metabolites excreted at baseline; and whether the body's immediate response to glucose is improved by the reduction of toxicant burden.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Avoidance Education</intervention_name>
    <description>Dietary modification and lifestyle interventions</description>
    <arm_group_label>Toxicant avoidance and glucose dysregulation</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 years old or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to complete the remote informed consent process.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Glucose dysregulation with FBG &gt;= 100 mg/dL and/or HbA1c &gt;= 5.7%) at the first visit&#xD;
             (with overnight fasting)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If the glucose dysregulation measurement for HbA1c is greater than 6.5% or the fasting&#xD;
             blood glucose is greater than 125 mg/dL, and the potential participant is not already&#xD;
             receiving standard care for diabetes from a physician, participants must see their&#xD;
             primary care provider for diabetes standard care before enrollment in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Use of insulin or insulin analog medications (Appendix J: Insulin and Insulin Analogs)&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Planning to have elective surgery, diagnostic procedures, dental, or cosmetic&#xD;
             procedures during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Unable or unwilling to stop recreational drug use during the study period&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Unable or unwilling to modifying dietary habits or lifestyle to increase organic&#xD;
             sources&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Unable or unwilling to only use cosmetics and hygiene products made up of natural&#xD;
             ingredients during the study period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>100 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Erin Sweet, ND, MPH</last_name>
    <phone>425 602 3000</phone>
    <phone_ext>3363</phone_ext>
    <email>esweet@bastyr.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Masa Sasagawa, ND, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>425 602 3000</phone>
    <phone_ext>3164</phone_ext>
    <email>msasagawa@bastyr.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Bastyr University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Kenmore</city>
        <state>Washington</state>
        <zip>98928</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Erin Sweet, ND, MPH</last_name>
      <phone>425-602-3000</phone>
      <phone_ext>3363</phone_ext>
      <email>esweet@bastyr.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Erin S Sweet, ND, MPH</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Masa Sasagawa, ND, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 22, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Bastyr University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Erin Sweet</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Clinical Scientist</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Glucose Intolerance</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

