<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04829253</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>210330008</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04829253</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness of a Short and Telematic Version of Cognitive-behavioral Treatment for Borderline Personality Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of a Short and Telematic Version of Cognitive-behavioral Treatment for Borderline Personality Disorder: an Open-label, Non-inferiority Randomized Clinical</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University Diego Portales</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Standard Dialectical Behavioral Therapy (DBT)is an effective treatment for Borderline&#xD;
      Personality Disorder (BPD), particularly for patients with significant behavioral and&#xD;
      affective dysregulation, including suicidality. However, DBT in its original format is&#xD;
      delivered in 12 months, and even though currently there are shorter versions of the treatment&#xD;
      being developed and tested, in the context of public mental health care in Chile a shorter,&#xD;
      intensive and lighter version of the treatment is likely needed to help patients seeking help&#xD;
      for BPD symptoms. This study will test whether a 3 month, intensive and simplified version of&#xD;
      DBT is at least equivalent to standard six months DBT with all its components (skills&#xD;
      training, individual therapy, coaching calls, and treatment-team consulting). 120 patients&#xD;
      diagnosed with BPD we'll be randomly assigned to receive either the short, intensive 3-month&#xD;
      intervention or the longer standard 6-month DBT intervention. Baseline measures will be taken&#xD;
      pre-treatment, upon treatment completion, and at a 4-month follow-up. Session-to-session&#xD;
      change in BPD symptoms will also be measured throughout the treatments. Primary outcomes for&#xD;
      the study are BPD symptoms, frequency, and intensity of suicidal activity. Secondary outcome&#xD;
      measures include depression scores, quality of life, and ER visits, and days in inpatient&#xD;
      care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">November 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">November 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Outcome assessors will not be therapists in the study and will be blind to treatment allocation. The only exception involves assessors in charge of evaluating care usage (e.g. ER visits and inpatient) as they will probably find out the treatment condition. These assessors will not participate in the assessment of primary or other secondary outcome measures.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in Borderline Personality Disorder Symptoms as measured by the Zanarini Rating Scale for Borderline Personality Disorder - ZAN-BPD</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then weekly until 3 months or 6 months depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>We will capture incremental change in affect dysregulation, behavioral dysregulation, interpersonal functioning, and cognitive/self functioning</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in the intensity and frequency of suicidal and self-harming activity, measured by a Spanish version of the Suicide Attempt Self-Injury Interview (SASII)</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then at treatment completion, which is at the 3 month mark or 6 month mark depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment recovers detailed information about frequency, topography, severity, social context, intent, precipitating events, concurrent events and outcomes of suicidal and self-harming behavior during a three-month period.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression Symptomatology measured through the Patient Health Questionnaire - PHQ-9</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then at treatment completion, which is at the 3 month mark or 6 month mark depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Self-assessment of DMS-IV symptoms of depression.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Reasons for Living measured though the RFL</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then at treatment completion, which is at the 3 month mark or 6 month mark depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Self-report scale that measures reasons an individual has to live and thus prevents him/her from potentially engaging in suicidal activity</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life measured through the World Health Organization Quality of Life brief version; WHOQOL-BREF</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then at treatment completion, which is at the 3 month mark or 6 month mark depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Measures overall satisfaction with life</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Emergency Room Visit measured by the integrated electronic records.</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then at treatment completion, which is at the 3 month mark or 6 month mark depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Indicates number of visits to the ER in a target 3 month period as documented in electronic records</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Psychiatric inpatient days measured by the integrated electronic records.</measure>
    <time_frame>Administered pre-treatment and then at treatment completion, which is at the 3 month mark or 6 month mark depending on thr study arm. Follow-up assessment at month 7 or month 10 depending on study arm.</time_frame>
    <description>Indicates number of days spent in psychiatric inpatient care in a target 3 month period as documented in electronic records</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">240</enrollment>
  <condition>Borderline Personality Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>b-DBT (Brief Dialectical Behavioral Therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>3 months of and intensive modified DBT intervention.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>s-DBT (standard Brief Dialectical Behavioral Therapy)</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>6 months of a standard DBT intervention (this is a shorter version of the original 12-month DBT, but includes all four active components delivered over 6 months)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dialectical Behavior Therapy -3-months</intervention_name>
    <description>Modification of affect regulation, behavioral regulation, interpersonal functioning and identity functioning through the use of skills training, phone check-ins, crisis management and individual initial assessment.</description>
    <arm_group_label>b-DBT (Brief Dialectical Behavioral Therapy)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Dialectical Behavior Therapy -6-months</intervention_name>
    <description>Modification of affect regulation, behavioral regulation, interpersonal functioning and identity functioning through the use of skills training, individual psychotherapy, coaching calls and treatment-team consultation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>s-DBT (standard Brief Dialectical Behavioral Therapy)</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  BPD diagnosis according to DSM-IV criteria, evaluated through a SCID-II structured&#xD;
             interview.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  History of suicide attempt or self-harm operationalized as at least two episodes of&#xD;
             suicide or self-harm in the last 24 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Provide signed informed consent to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participant has not received more than 8 weeks of DBT in the past 24 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Fulfill diagnostic criteria for psychotic disorders classified in ICD-10 (F20-F29),&#xD;
             evaluated through the MINI interview.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of Antisocial Personality Disorder evaluated through the SCID-II.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active substance use disorder within the last 3 months, assessed by ASSIST.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Harmful use or problem dependence on alcohol assessed through AUDIT.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Meet criteria for Bipolar Affective Disorder type I assessed through the MINI Mania&#xD;
             module.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Significant cognitive impairment assessed through Moca (Moca&gt; 21).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis recorded in the clinical record of intellectual-cognitive disability.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Recording in the clinical record of medical or surgical problems that could imply a&#xD;
             probable hospitalization within one year of the start of the study (for example,&#xD;
             cancer, coronary heart disease, etc.).&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alex Behn, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Millennium Institute for Research in Depression and Personality</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alex J Behn, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+56942152484</phone>
    <email>albehn@uc.cl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Matias Correa, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+56995568763</phone>
    <email>matiascorrearamirez@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Complejo Asistencial Dr. Sótero del Río</name>
      <address>
        <city>Santiago</city>
        <state>Región Metropolitana</state>
        <country>Chile</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matías Correa, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Alex J Behn, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matias Correa, MD</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Chile</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 2, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Personality Disorders</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Borderline Personality Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>No plans to share IPD at this point.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

