<clinical_study>
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on November 19, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04823637</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>AZ 1232</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04823637</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Evaluating for a Correlation Between Osteopathic Examination and Ultrasonography on Thoracic Spine Asymmetry</brief_title>
  <acronym>USOMM</acronym>
  <official_title>Evaluating for a Correlation Between Osteopathic Examination and Ultrasonography on Thoracic Spine Asymmetry</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Midwestern University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Midwestern University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Context: Thoracic spine is a common area of focus in osteopathic manipulative medicine (OMM)&#xD;
      for a variety of conditions. Thoracic spine somatic dysfunction diagnosis is achieved by&#xD;
      palpating for asymmetry at the tips of the transverse processes. Previous studies reveal&#xD;
      that, instead of following the rule of threes, the transverse processes of a given thoracic&#xD;
      vertebra generally align with the spinous process of the vertebra above. Ultrasonography has&#xD;
      been widely used as a diagnostic tool to monitor musculoskeletal conditions. Ultrasound has&#xD;
      the advantage of absence of radiation, and has shown comparable results to gold standard&#xD;
      modalities like MRI in some areas of the spine. In the case of thoracic somatic dysfunction,&#xD;
      ultrasound can be used to determine the location of each vertebral transverse process and its&#xD;
      relationship with the spinous process. Previous studies have investigated the correlation&#xD;
      between osteopathic manipulative medicine and ultrasonography of the cervical, lumbar, and&#xD;
      sacral regions. However, no study has yet compared osteopathic structural examination with&#xD;
      ultrasonographic examination of the thoracic vertebral region.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective: To determine whether there is a dependable correlation of osteopathic palpatory&#xD;
      findings of the thoracic transverse processes with the measurements of ultrasonography.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: Subjects were student volunteers recruited from the Midwestern University - Glendale&#xD;
      campus. A non-toxic, non-permanent marker was used to mark bony landmarks on the skin to be&#xD;
      used by the osteopathic examiners. Two osteopathic physicians (OMM1, OMM2) separately&#xD;
      performed structural exams by palpating T2-T5 transverse processes to determine vertebral&#xD;
      rotation. Two trained sonographers (US1, US2) separately scanned and measured the distance&#xD;
      from the tip of the spinous process to the adjacent transverse processes of the vertebral&#xD;
      segment below. Demographic variables were summarized with mean and standard deviation.&#xD;
      Interexaminer reliability was assessed with percent agreement, Cohen's Kappa, and Fleiss'&#xD;
      Kappa. Recruitment and protocols were approved by the MWU Institutional Review Board.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 10, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 13, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Interexaminer reliability</measure>
    <time_frame>Through study completion, which was an average of about 1 year</time_frame>
    <description>We looked at the interexaminer reliability between ultrasound and osteopathic structural exam of the thoracic spine.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">74</enrollment>
  <condition>Osteopathic Manipulative Treatment</condition>
  <condition>Ultrasonography</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Ultrasonography vs Osteopathic manipulative medicine structural exam</intervention_name>
    <description>Structural examination of the thoracic spine using ultrasound and osteopathic palpatory examination on skin.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Subjects are Midwestern University students who were recruited via email announcements,&#xD;
        with responses recorded via secure Google Form that was accessible only to the Midwestern&#xD;
        University network.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The overall demographics of participants showed 31 (47.0%) males and 35 (53.0%) females.&#xD;
        Race and ethnicity were not collected for the purpose of this study as it was not a&#xD;
        variable being evaluated or investigated. The subjects' age range is 22-35 years of age,&#xD;
        with the mean age as 26.61 (SD = 3.1) for males and 25.71 (SD = 2.7) for females. The BMI&#xD;
        range is 15.9 - 36.9kg/m2, with the mean BMI as 24.13 (SD = 4.2) overall, 25.46 (SD = 3.5)&#xD;
        for males and 22.95 (SD = 4.5) for females.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  First- and Second-year osteopathic medical students who received an email notification&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Masters program students who received an email notification&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - A history of or currently diagnosed with scoliosis, spondylosis, spondylolisthesis,&#xD;
        herniated disc, spinal fracture, or surgery to the spine&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Randall Nydam, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Midwestern University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Midwestern University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Glendale</city>
        <state>Arizona</state>
        <zip>85308</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Midwestern University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Randall Nydam</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD, Associate Dean</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

